<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Characterization of individual polymer molecules based on monomer- interface interactions
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1956367A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHURCH GEORGE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DEAMER DAVID W [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHURCH, GEORGE
</Name>
<Name>
DEAMER, DAVID W
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HARVARD COLLEGE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIV CALIFORNIA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PRESIDENT AND FELLOWS OF HARVARD COLLEGE
</Name>
<Name>
THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1956367
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080010129
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
1996-03-01
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP19960909569
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1996-03-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19950405735
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1995-03-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C07K14/705
</Class>
<Class>
C12N9/12
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68
</Class>
<Class>
G01N15/10
</Class>
<Class>
G01N15/12
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/04
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K14/705
</Class>
<Class>
C12N9/12J
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68E
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/487B5
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention provides 1 method for determining the duration of interaction of a polymer with a nanopore or ion permeable passage, the method comprising the steps of: (a) providing a structure comprising a nanopore connecting a first pool and a second pool, wherein a polymer to be analyzed is placed in the first pool;  , (b) causing the polymer to traverse the ion permeable passage;  and (c) measuring the duration of step (b).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for determining the duration of interaction of a polymer with a nanopore, the method comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing a structure comprising a nanopore connecting a first pool and a second pool, wherein a polymer to be analyzed is placed in the first pool;
</P>
<P>
(b) causing the polymer to traverse the ion permeable passage; and
</P>
<P>
(c) measuring the duration of step (b).
</P>
<P>
2. A method for determining the duration of interaction of a polymer with a ion permeable passage, the method comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing a structure comprising an ion permeable passage connecting a first pool and a second pool, wherein a polymer to be analyzed is placed in the first pool;
</P>
<P>
(b) causing the polymer to traverse the ion permeable passage; and
</P>
<P>
(c) measuring the duration of step (b).
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the structure further comprises a molecular motor.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein a protein comprises the nanopore or ion permeable passage.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the structure comprises a lipid bilayer.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 3, wherein the molecular motor comprises a DNA polymerase, a RNA polymerase, an exonuclease, or a ribosome.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 6, wherein the DNA polymerase is an E. coli DNA polymerase I or a T7 DNA polymerase.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 6, wherein the RNA polymerase is T7 RNA polymerase.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 6, wherein the exonuclease is exonuclease Lambda.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the nanopore or ion permeable passage has a diameter of about 1.0 to 4.0 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the nanopore or ion permeable passage has a diameter of about 0.5 to 2 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the polymer comprises a polynucleotide.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the structure further comprises a DNA binding protein.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the measuring detects an electrical property of the structure while the polymer traverses the nanopore or ion permeable passage.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein a protein does not comprise the nanopore or ion permeable passage.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US6015714A;US5795782A;WO9629593A1;EP0815438A1;EP0815438A4;EP0815438B1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
