<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
A method of producing a film of carbon nanotubes on a substrate
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1955780A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FORD WILLIAM E [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
JURINA WESSELS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
AKIO YASUDA [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
FORD, WILLIAM E
</Name>
<Name>
JURINA WESSELS
</Name>
<Name>
AKIO YASUDA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SONY DEUTSCHLAND GMBH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
SONY DEUTSCHLAND GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1955780
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070002290
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-02-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070002290
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B05D1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B05D7/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B05D1/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B05D7/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a method of producing a film of carbon nanotubes on a substrate, to a film produced by such method, and to uses of such film.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of producing a film of carbon nanotubes on a substrate, comprising the steps:
</P>
<P>
a) providing a substrate having a surface,
</P>
<P>
b) treating said surface with a polyhydric compound, to yield a treated surface having hydrogen-bond forming groups,
</P>
<P>
c) providing a solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes and applying a layer of such solution or suspension on said treated surface, drying said layer or allowing said layer to dry, said layer thereby forming a film of carbon nanotubes on said surface of said substrate.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1, wherein said treated surface has a static contact angle of water in the range of from 0 degrees to 90 degrees, preferably from 10 degrees to 90 degrees, more preferably from 30 degrees to 90 degrees and even more preferably from 50 degrees to 90 degrees.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to any of claims 1 and 2, wherein said hydrogen-bond forming groups of said polyhydric compound are OH-groups, preferably hydroxyl groups of organic alcohols.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to any of claims 1 - 2, wherein said polyhydric compound comprises a polyhydric polymer.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 4, wherein said polyhydric polymer is a polymer comprising polyvinyl alcohol.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to any of claims 4 - 5, wherein said polyhydric polymer is polyvinyl alcohol.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to any of claims 5 - 6, wherein said polyvinyl alcohol has the formula [-CH2CHOH-] n, wherein n is selected from the range 50 to 5000.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any of claims 5-6, wherein said polyvinyl alcohol has the formula [-CH2CHOR-] n, wherein n is selected from the range 50 to 5000, and wherein R is either H or -COCH3 (acetyl) and the percentage of R that is H is selected from the range of 50% to 100%.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to any of claims 5 - 8, wherein said polyvinyl alcohol has a molecular weight in the range of from 4000 - 200 000, preferably 4000 - 40 000, more preferably 11 000 - 24 000.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein step b) occurs by applying a solution, preferably an aqueous solution, of said polyhydric compound onto said surface.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to claim 10, wherein said applying occurs by a technique selected from spin coating, dipping, drop casting, spraying. , and printing, including ink-jet printing and microcontact printing.
</P>
<P>
12. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein, prior to step b), said substrate having a surface is a substrate having a static contact angle of water in the range of from 60 degrees to 120 degrees, preferably from 65 degrees to 105 degrees.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said substrate is a polymeric substrate.
</P>
<P>
14. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said substrate comprises at least one polymer or polymer blend having carbonyl groups in the backbone or in a side group of said polymer or polymer blend.
</P>
<P>
15. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said substrate comprises at least one polymer or a polymer blend, said polymer and/or said polymer blend being selected from the group comprising polyesters of carboxylic acids, polyanhydrides of carboxylic acids, polycarbonates, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said substrate comprises at least one polymer selected from the group comprising poly(methyl methacrylate), polyethylene terephthalate, cellulose acetate and poly(oxycarbonyloxo-1,4-phenylene-isopropylidene-1,4-phenylene) (polycarbonate).
</P>
<P>
17. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said carbon nanotubes are dissolved or suspended in water with a concentration in the range of from 0.01 g/l to 10 g/l, or are dissolved or suspended in methanol or ethanol with a concentration in the range, of from 0.1 g/l to 1 g/l, to provide a solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes to be used in step c).
</P>
<P>
18. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said carbon nanotubes have hydrogen-bond forming groups on their surface(s), with said hydrogen-bond forming groups preferably being carbonyl groups.
</P>
<P>
19. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said carbon nanotubes have carboxyl (-COOH), amido (-NHCO-) and/or ureido (-NHCONH-) groups on their surface(s).
</P>
<P>
20. The method according to claim 19, wherein said carbon nanotubes have primary amido (-CONH2) and/or primary ureido (-NHCONH2) groups on their surface(s).
</P>
<P>
21. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes is an aqueous solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes, or an alcoholic, preferably methanolic or ethanolic or a mixture thereof, solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes, or a mixture of an aqueous and alcoholic solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
22. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said carbon nanotubes, prior to dissolving or suspending them in an appropriate medium, such as an aqueous or alcoholic solvent, have been prepared by heating them in the presence of urea, optionally also in the presence of at least one aldehyde.
</P>
<P>
23. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said carbon nanotubes are single-walled, double-walled or multi-walled nanotubes or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
24. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said applying a layer of a solution or suspension of carbon nanotubes in step c) on said treated surface occurs by a technique selected from spin coating, dipping, drop casting, spraying, and printing, including ink-jet printing or microcontact printing.
</P>
<P>
25. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said film of carbon nanotubes on said surface is a film having a coverage in the range of from submonolayer to multilayer.
</P>
<P>
26. The method according to any of the foregoing claims, wherein said film deposited in several layers.
</P>
<P>
27. A film of carbon nanotubes on a surface, prepared by the method according to any of the foregoing claims.
</P>
<P>
28. The film according to claim 27, wherein said film has a coverage in the range of from submonolayer to multilayer.
</P>
<P>
29. The film according to any of claims 27-28, which is a two-dimensional network of carbon nanotubes deposited on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
30. The film according to any of claims 27 - 29, which comprises an electrically conductive two-dimensional network of carbon nanotubes deposited on a substrate with an optical absorbance at 550 nm in the range of from 0.001 to 1 and with a sheet resistance in the range of from 10 per square to 10 M per square.
</P>
<P>
31. The film according to any of claims 27-29, which comprises an electrically non-conductive two dimensional network of carbon nanotubes deposited on a substrate with an optical absorbance at 550 nm of less than 0.01.
</P>
<P>
32. Use of a film according to any of claims 27-31 as or in an electrically conductive surface or electrode, or, as or in an electrically semiconductive surface.
</P>
<P>
33. Use according to claim 32, wherein said film is used for applications including energy applications such as solar cells, solid state lighting, electronics, such as passive and active matrix displays, thin film speakers, pick-up stick transistors, smart windows, appliances, such as touch screens, defrosting windows, and security applications, such as RFID tags, electromagnetic shielding and sensors.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010102280A1;JP2010517900A;WO2008092696A1;CN101657266A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
