<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
COLORED POLYMER COMPOSITION
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1950252A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HANDA KOICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA TAKAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO TSUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN JIAYI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAUCHI AKIRA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAGASHIMA MANABU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA, KOICHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA, TAKAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO, TSUYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN, JIAYI
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAUCHI, AKIRA
</Name>
<Name>
NAGASHIMA, MANABU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RES INST INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI BUSSAN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RESEARCH INSTITUTE INC
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI &amp; CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1950252
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060822608
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP321679
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050317262
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/04F
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127B2
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127F
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The disclosed is a colored polymer composition which includes carbon fibrous structures and a coloring agent in a polymer matrix, wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers. It is the colored polymer composition which includes novel carbon fibrous structures having preferable physical properties as a filler for composite material, and of being able to improve electrical, mechanical and thermal properties of a matrix while maintaining other properties of the matrix, in a small adding amount, and which can show a color as pleases. When a white coloring agent is used as the coloring agent, the darkness in color tone of the polymer which is due to the addition of the carbon fibrous structure can be easily corrected by adding a relatively small amount of the white coloring agent as the coloring agent.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Colored polymer composition which includes carbon fibrous structures and a coloring agent in a polymer matrix, wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers.
</P>
<P>
2. The colored polymer composition according to Claim 1, wherein the coloring agent is a white coloring agent.
</P>
<P>
3. The colored polymer composition according to Claim 1, wherein as the coloring agent a white coloring agent and other color&apos;s coloring agent are contained.
</P>
<P>
4. The colored polymer composition according to one of Claims 1 - 3, wherein the carbon fibrous structures and the white coloring agent are contained at a rate of 0.01 - 3 % by weight, and at a rate of 10 - 60 % by weight, respectively, based on the total weight of the polymer composition.
</P>
<P>
5. The colored polymer composition according to one of Claims 1 - 4, wherein the carbon fibrous structures have an area-based circle-equivalent mean diameter of 50 - 100 m.
</P>
<P>
6. The colored polymer composition according to one of Claims 1 - 5, wherein the carbon fibrous structures have a bulk density of 0.0001 - 0.05g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
7. The colored polymer composition according to one of Claims 1-6, wherein the carbon fibrous structures have ID/IG ratio determined by Raman spectroscopy of not more than 0.2.
</P>
<P>
8. The colored polymer composition according to one of Claims 1-7, wherein the carbon fibrous structures are produced using as carbon sources at least two carbon compounds which have mutually different decomposition temperatures.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009131575A1;WO2007052616A1;JP2007119693A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
