<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING 3- DIMENSIONAL MOLD, PROCESS FOR PRODUCING MICROFABRICATION PRODUCT, PROCESS FOR PRODUCING MICROPATTERN MOLDING, 3- DIMENSIONAL MOLD, MICROFABRICATION PRODUCT, MICROPATTERN MOLDING AND OPTICAL DEVICE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1930776A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TANIGUCHI JUN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANIGUCHI, JUN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV TOKYO SCI EDUC FOUND [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TOKYO UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1930776
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060797710
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-08
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP317856
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-08
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050262519
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060051070
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C33/38
</Class>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/18
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/075
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/20
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B81C99/00R6
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/18M
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/36
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process for producing a 3-dimensional mold, including irradiating a resist layer of a processing object having the resist layer made of an organopolysiloxane on a substrate with an electron beam, and developing, by thermal desorption treatment, the resist layer after the irradiation with an electron beam to form protrusions and depressions in the resist layer;  a process for producing a microfabrication product by using the 3-dimensional mold;  a process for producing a micropattern molding by using the 3-dimensional mold or the microfabrication product;  and a 3-dimensional mold, a microfabrication product and a micropattern molding which are finely formed by these production processes, as well as an optical device.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for producing a 3-dimensional mold, comprising:
</P>
<P>
irradiating a resist layer of a processing object having the resist layer made of an organopolysiloxane on a substrate with an electron beam, and
</P>
<P>
developing the resist layer after the irradiation with an electron beam to form protrusions and depressions in the resist layer,wherein the development is development by thermal desorption treatment.
</P>
<P>
2. The process for producing a 3-dimensional mold according to claim 1, wherein the organic group in the organopolysiloxane is a methyl group or a phenyl group.
</P>
<P>
3. The process for producing a 3-dimensional mold according to claim 1, wherein the organic group in the organopolysiloxane is a methyl group.
</P>
<P>
4. The process for producing a 3-dimensional mold according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the heating temperature in the thermal desorption treatment is not more than the glass transition temperature of the organopolysiloxane.
</P>
<P>
5. The process for producing a 3-dimensional mold according to claim 4, wherein the heating temperature in the thermal desorption treatment is 600 deg. C or less when the organic group in the organopolysiloxane is a methyl group and simultaneously the content of the organic group in the organopolysiloxane is 5 to 25% by mass.
</P>
<P>
6. A 3-dimensional mold of 100 nm or less in line width produced by the process according to any one of claims 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
7. A process for producing a microfabrication product comprising a substrate having protrusions and depressions, the process comprising irradiating with an ion beam a resist layer of a 3-dimensional mold produced by the process for producing a 3-dimensional mold, in which a resist layer having protrusions and depressions is provided on a substrate, according to any one of claims 1 to 5, whereby protrusions and depressions are formed on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
8. A microfabrication product having a processed portion of 100 nm or less in line width produced by the process according to claim 7.
</P>
<P>
9. The microfabrication product according to claim 8, which comprises diamond, silicon, glass, sapphire, glassy carbon, or silicon carbide.
</P>
<P>
10. A process for producing a micropattern molding, comprising:
</P>
<P>
transferring a pattern through molding to a resin by pressing the resin against a 3-dimensional mold produced by the process according to any one of claims 1 to 5, and
</P>
<P>
releasing the pressed resin from the 3-dimensional mold.
</P>
<P>
11. A process for producing a micropattern molding, comprising:
</P>
<P>
transferring a pattern through molding to a resin by pressing the resin against a microfabrication product produced by the process according to claim 7, which is used as a mold, and
</P>
<P>
releasing the pressed resin from the microfabrication product.
</P>
<P>
12. A micropattem molding having a processed portion of 100 nm or less in line width produced by the process according to claim 10 or 11.
</P>
<P>
13. An optical device having a 3-dimensional mold produced by the process of any one of claims 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
14. An optical device having a microfabrication product produced by the process of claim 7.
</P>
<P>
15. An optical device having a micropattern molding produced by the process of claim 10 or 11.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1930776A4;US2009176060A1;WO2007029810A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
