<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Acid-Based Polymeric Dispersants With 2- [2-(2-Methoxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetic Acid
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1990395A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MERCANDO LISA ANN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
QUAY JEFFREY RAYMOND [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MERCANDO, LISA ANN
</Name>
<Name>
QUAY, JEFFREY RAYMOND
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AIR PROD &amp; CHEM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AIR PRODUCTS AND CHEMICALS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1990395
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080154788
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070913852P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080099438
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09K3/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/16
</Class>
<Class>
C01G19/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/16
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The disclosure relates to acid-based polymeric dispersants containing 2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxylacetic acid for dispersing metal oxide nanoparticles in organic solvents such as methyl ethyl ketone (MEK) and butyl acetate.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
i) about 1:10 to about 5:1 ratio of at least one surface treating agent 2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetic acid to nanoparticle based on weight; and,
</P>
<P>
ii) about 1:10 to about 5:1 of at least one acid functional polymeric dispersant to nanoparticle based on weight.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition of Claim 1 further comprising at least one organic solvent.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition of Claim 2 wherein said organic solvent comprises at least one of methyl ethyl ketone, toluene, butyl cellosolve acetate and butyl acetate.
</P>
<P>
4. The composition of any one of Claims 1 to 3 wherein the at least one acid functional polymeric dispersant comprises at least one members selected from the group consisting of saturated phosphate polyester or copolymer with acidic groups.
</P>
<P>
5. A dispersion comprising:
</P>
<P>
i) about 1:10 to about 5:1 ratio of at least one surface treating agent 2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetic acid to nanoparticle based on weight; and,
</P>
<P>
ii) about 1:10 to about 5:1 of at least one acid functional polymeric dispersant to nanoparticle based on weight.
</P>
<P>
iii) nanoparticles, and,
</P>
<P>
iv) at least one solvent.
</P>
<P>
6. The dispersion of Claim 5 wherein the nanoparticles comprises metal nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
7. The dispersion of Claim 5 or 6 wherein the nanoparticles comprise at least one of metal oxide and nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
8. The dispersion of Claim 7 wherein the metal oxide nanoparticles comprise indium tin oxide nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
9. The dispersion of Claim 8 wherein the solvent omprises at least one of methyl ethyl ketone, toluene, butyl cellosolve acetate and butyl acetate.
</P>
<P>
10. A dispersion comprising:
</P>
<P>
i) 2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetic acid;
</P>
<P>
ii) at least one acid functional polymeric dispersant;
</P>
<P>
iii) at least one organic carrier,
</P>
<P>
iii) nanoparticles; wherein the amount of acid and dispersant are sufficient to form a dispersion.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1990395B1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
