<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
RECYCLED COMPOSITE MATERIAL
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1950253A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HANDA KOICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA TAKAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO TSUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN JIAYI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAUCHI AKIRA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAGASHIMA MANABU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA, KOICHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA, TAKAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO, TSUYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN, JIAYI
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAUCHI, AKIRA
</Name>
<Name>
NAGASHIMA, MANABU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RES INST INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI BUSSAN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RESEARCH INSTITUTE INC
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI &amp; CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1950253
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060832850
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-17
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP322971
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050334471
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B09B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/76
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/80
</Class>
<Class>
C08J11/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/00
</Class>
<Class>
C22C47/06
</Class>
<Class>
C22C49/14
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
C22C101/10
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/622A
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/80B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/80D
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/83
</Class>
<Class>
C08J11/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/04F
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
C22C47/06
</Class>
<Class>
C22C49/14
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127F
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An recycled composite material is disclosed, which is prepared by using as a raw material a waste composite material which comprises a matrix component and carbon fibrous structures added to the matrix, and adding an additionalmatrix component which is homogeneous and/or heterogeneous with the matrix of the spent composite material, and then kneading them together;  wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers, each carbon fiber having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, and a granular part, at which the fibers are bound in a state that the carbon fibers extend outwardly therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers. The recycled composite material performs much the same with the original composite material, and is produced briefly at a low cost.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Recycled composite material which is prepared by using as a raw material a waste composite material which comprises a matrix component and carbon fibrous structures added to the matrix, and adding an additional matrix component which is homogeneous and/or heterogeneous with the matrix of the spent composite material, and then kneading them together; wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers, each carbon fiber having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, and a granular part, at which the fibers are bound in a state that the carbon fibers extend outwardly therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers.
</P>
<P>
2. The recycled composite material according to Claim 1, wherein the carbon fibrous structures included in the wastes as the raw material have an area-based circle-equivalent mean diameter of 50 - 100 m.
</P>
<P>
3. The recycled composite material according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein said carbon fibrous structures included in the wastes as the raw material have a bulk density of 0.0001 - 0.05g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
4. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 -3, wherein said carbon fibrous structures included in the wastes as the raw material have an ID/IG ratio determined by Raman spectroscopy of not more than 0.2.
</P>
<P>
5. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 - 4, wherein the carbon fibrous structures included in the wastes as the raw material have a combustion initiation temperature in air of not less than 750 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
6. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 - 5, wherein the particle diameter of the granular part at a binding portion for carbon fibers in the carbon fibrous structure included in the wastes as the raw material is larger than the outside diameters of the carbon fibers.
</P>
<P>
7. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 -6, wherein the carbon fibrous structures included in the wastes as the raw material are produced using as carbon sources of at least two carbon compounds, which have different decomposition temperatures.
</P>
<P>
8. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 -7, wherein the matrix component included in the wastes as the raw material and the additional matrix component comprise an organic polymer.
</P>
<P>
9. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 -7, wherein the matrix component included in the wastes as the raw material and the additional matrix component comprise an inorganic material.
</P>
<P>
10. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 -7, wherein the matrix component included in the wastes as the raw material and the additional matrix component comprise a metal.
</P>
<P>
11. The recycled composite material according to one of Claims 1 -10, wherein the matrix component included in the wastes as the raw material and the additional matrix component further include at least one of filler selected from the group consisting of metallic fine particles, silica, calcium carbonate, magnesium carbonate, carbon black, glass fiber and carbon fibers in the matrix.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1950253A4;US2009226712A1;WO2007058298A1;JP2007138039A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
