<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FLUID HANDLING DEVICE WITH DIRECTIONALLY- BIASED WETTING SURFACE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1927149A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
EXTRAND CHARLES W [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WRIGHT MICHAEL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
EXTRAND, CHARLES, W
</Name>
<Name>
WRIGHT, MICHAEL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ENTEGRIS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ENTEGRIS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1927149
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060814765
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-15
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US36081
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-15
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050228866
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050229080
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050229478
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B05D5/12
</Class>
<Class>
F15D1/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01M8/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
F15C5/00
</Class>
<Class>
F16K99/00M
</Class>
<Class>
F16K99/00M2F
</Class>
<Class>
F16K99/00M4D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A fluid handling device with an anisotropic wetting surface including a substrate with a multiplicity of asymmetric substantially uniformly shaped asperities thereon. Each asperity has a first asperity rise angle and a second asperity rise angle relative to the substrate. The asperities are structured to present a desired retentive force ratio (f1/f2) greater or less than unity caused by asymmetry between the first asperity rise angle and the second asperity rise angle according to the formula: f3/f2 = sin(?3 + 1/2??0)/sin(?2+ 1/2??0)
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A fluid handling device having an anisotropic wetting surface portion, the anisotropic wetting surface portion comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate with a multiplicity of asymmetric substantially uniformly shaped microscale or nanoscale asperities thereon, each asperity defining a first asperity rise angle and a second opposing asperity rise angle relative to the substrate, the asperities being structured to present a retentive force ratio (f3/f2) greater or less than unity when the retentive force ratio (f3/f2) is determined according to the formula:
</P>
<P>
f3/f2 = sin([omega]3 + &amp;lt;1&amp;gt;/2[Delta][Theta]0)/sin([omega]2 + Y2AQ0)
</P>
<P>
where [omega]2 is the first asperity rise angle in degrees, [omega]3 is the second asperity rise angle in degrees, and [Delta][theta]o = (0a,o - #r,o) where [Theta]a,o is a true advancing contact angle of a fluid in contact with the surface in degrees, and 0r,o is a true receding contact angle of the fluid on the surface in degrees.
</P>
<P>
2. The fluid handling device of claim 1 , wherein the asperities are projections.
</P>
<P>
3. The fluid handling device of claim 2, wherein the asperities are polyhedrally shaped.
</P>
<P>
4. The fluid handling device of claim 2, wherein each asperity has a generally square transverse cross-section.
</P>
<P>
5. The fluid handling device of claim 2, wherein the asperities are cylindrical, cylindroidal, conical or frusto-conical in shape.
</P>
<P>
6. The fluid handling device of claim 1, wherein the asperities are cavities formed in the substrate.
</P>
<P>
7. The fluid handling device of claim 1, wherein the asperities are positioned in a substantially uniform array.
</P>
<P>
8. The fluid handling device of claim 7, wherein the asperities are positioned in a rectangular array.
</P>
<P>
9. The fluid handling device of claim 1, wherein the fluid handling device is a microfluidic device.
</P>
<P>
10 The fluid handling device of claim 1, wherein the fluid handling device is a fuel cell component.
</P>
<P>
11. A method of an anisotropic wetting surface on a fluid handling device, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a fluid handling device presenting a surface; and
</P>
<P>
disposing a multiplicity of substantially uniformly shaped microscale or nanoscale asperities on the surface of the fluid handling device to form the anisotropic wetting surface, each asperity having a first asperity rise angle and a second asperity rise angle relative to the surface, wherein the asperities are structured and disposed so as to present a retentive force ratio (f3/f2) greater or less than unity when the retentive force ratio (f3/f2) is determined according to the formula:
</P>
<P>
f3/f2 = sin([omega]3 + %[Delta][Theta]0)/sin([omega]2 + &amp;lt;1&amp;gt;AAQ0)
</P>
<P>
where [omega]2 is the first asperity rise angle in degrees, [omega]3 is the second asperity rise angle in degrees, and [Delta][theta]o = (0a,o - #r,o) where 0a,o is a true advancing contact angle of a fluid in contact with the surface in degrees, and 0r&amp;gt;0 is a true receding contact angle of the fluid on the surface in degrees
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 11, wherein the asperities are disposed using a photolithography process.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 11, wherein the asperities are disposed using a process selected from the group consisting of nanomachining, microstamping, microcontact printing, self-assembling metal colloid monolayers, atomic force microscopy nanomachining, sol-gel molding, self-assembled monolayer directed patterning, chemical etching, sol-gel stamping, printing with colloidal inks, and disposing a layer of parallel carbon nanotubes on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
14. A fluid handling device comprising an anisotropic wetting surface with a multiplicity of asymmetric substantially uniformly shaped asperities thereon, each asperity defining a first asperity rise angle and a second opposing asperity rise angle relative to the substrate, the asperities being structured to present a retentive force ratio (f3/f2) greater or less than unity when the retentive force ratio (f3/f2) is determined according to the formula:
</P>
<P>
f,/f2 = sin([omega]3 + &amp;lt;1&amp;gt;/2[Delta][Theta]0)/sin([omega]2 + V2AQ0)
</P>
<P>
where [omega]2 is the first asperity rise angle in degrees, [omega]3 is the second asperity rise angle in degrees, and [Delta][theta]o = ([theta]a,o - #r,0) where 0a,o is a true advancing contact angle of a fluid in contact with the surface in degrees, and 0r,o is a true receding contact angle of the fluid on the surface in degrees.
</P>
<P>
15. The fluid handling device of claim 14, wherein the fluid handling device is tubular in shape.
</P>
<P>
16. The fluid handling device of claim 14, wherein the fluid handling device is a valve.
</P>
<P>
17. The fluid handling device of claim 14, wherein the fluid handling device is a microfluidic device.
</P>
<P>
18 The fluid handling device of claim 1, wherein the fluid handling device is a fuel cell component.
</P>
<P>
19. A method of cleaning a fluid handling device, comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a fluid handling device presenting an anisotropic wetting surface, the anisotropic wetting surface comprising a substrate with a multiplicity of asymmetric substantially uniformly shaped asperities thereon, each asperity defining a first asperity rise angle and a second opposing asperity rise angle relative to the substrate, the asperities being structured to present a retentive force ratio (f3/f2) greater or less than unity when the retentive force ratio (f3/f2) is determined according to the formula: f3/f2 = sin([omega]3 + &amp;lt;1&amp;gt;/2[Delta][Theta]0)/sin([omega]2 + &amp;lt;1&amp;gt;AAe0)
</P>
<P>
where [omega]2 is the first asperity rise angle in degrees, [omega]3 is the second asperity rise angle in degrees, and [Delta][theta]o = ([theta]a$ - 0r&amp;gt;0) where 0a;0 is a true advancing contact angle of a fluid in contact with the anisotropic wetting surface in degrees, and [theta][tau][beta] is a true receding contact angle of the fluid on the anisotropic wetting surface in degrees; and
</P>
<P>
contacting the anisotropic wetting surface with the fluid.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19, further comprising imparting a force to the fluid handling device or the fluid to cause the fluid to move on the anisotropic wetting surface.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007035511A2;WO2007035511A3;US2009217981A1;US8028722B2;KR20080058398A;JP2009509104A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
