<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
A PROCESS FOR THE PRODUCTION OF TITANIUM PRODUCTS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1957408A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
VITNER ASHER [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
EYAL AHARON [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
MALI REVITAL [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
VITNER, ASHER
</Name>
<Name>
EYAL, AHARON
</Name>
<Name>
MALI, REVITAL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
JOMA INTERNAT AS [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
ASHER VITNER LTD [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
JOMA INTERNATIONAL AS
</Name>
<Name>
ASHER VITNER LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1957408
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060809756
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-15
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006IL01185
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-15
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
IL20050171363
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
IL20050171364
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
IL20060178477
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00K
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053B
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/14
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention provides a method for the Industrial purification of a titanium feed stream of purity P1 , by the formation of a titanium-double-salt precipitate of purity P2 and a titanium solution with purity P3, wherein P2&amp;gt;P1 &amp;gt;P3, the method comprising the steps of: i. forming, from the feed, a medium comprising water, titanium ion, a cation selected from the group consisting of ammonium, cations of alkali metals, protons and a combination thereof, and an anion selected from the group consisting of OH, SO4, HSO4, halides and a combination thereof, which formed medium is further characterized by the presence of (a) a double-salt precipitate comprising titanium ion, at least one of the cations and at least one of the anions;  and (b) a titanium solution;  and wherein the concentration of the anion in the titanium solution is higher than 15% and the ratio between the concentrations of the cation and the anion in the titanium solution is higher than 0.2 and lower than 1.6;  and ii. separating at least a portion of the precipitate from the solution.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for the Industrial purification of a titanium feed stream of purity P1 , by the formation of a titanium-double-salt precipitate of purity P2 and a titanium solution with purity P3, wherein P2&amp;gt;P1 &amp;gt;P3, said method comprising the steps of: i. forming, from said feed, a medium comprising water, titanium ion, a cation selected from the group consisting of ammonium, cations of alkali metals, protons and a combination thereof, and an anion selected from the group consisting of OH, SO4, HSO4, halides and a combination thereof, which formed medium is further characterized by the presence of (a) a double-salt precipitate comprising titanium ion, at least one of said cations and at least one of said anions; and (b) a titanium solution; and wherein the concentration of said anion in said titanium solution is higher than 15% and the ratio between the concentrations of said cation and said anion in said titanium solution is higher than 0.2 and lower than 1.6; and ii. separating at least a portion of said precipitate from said solution.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1 , further comprising the step of processing said precipitate to produce titanium oxide.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1 , further comprising the step of processing said precipitate to produce a titanium product other than titanium oxide.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to claim 1 , further comprising the step of processing said precipitate to produce titanium metal.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to claim 1 , wherein said titanium feed stream is an aqueous waste solution.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to claim 1 , wherein said titanium feed stream comprises at least 2wt% iron cations.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein said titanium feed is formed by leaching titanium ores with an acid solution.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein P1 is in the range of between about 10% and about 90%.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein P1 is lower than 60%.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein P1 is lower than 50%.
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the titanium feed stream comprises iron with a Fe/T[iota] molar ratio of at least 0.25 and wherein said ratio in said titanium double salt precipitate is less than 0.02.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to claim 1 , where P1 is less than 70% and P2 is greater than 95%.
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein said titanium feed stream comprises protons and at least one anion selected from the group consisting of halides, sulfate, bisulfate, nitrate and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein said titanium feed stream comprises a byproduct stream from an industrial process.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein said titanium feed stream comprises iron and wherein the Fe/Ti molar ratio in said feed stream is in a range between about 0.2:1 and about 3:1.
</P>
<P>
16. A method according to claim 15, wherein the Fe/Ti molar ratio in said double salt precipitate is smaller than that ratio in said feed stream by a factor of at least 5.
</P>
<P>
17. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein said cation in said double-salt is ammonium.
</P>
<P>
18. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the cation in said double-salt is selected from the group consisting of sodium and potassium.
</P>
<P>
19. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the anion in said double-salt is selected from the group consisting of OH, SO4, HSO4 and halides.
</P>
<P>
20. A. method according to Claim 1 , wherein said precipitate is selected from the group consisting of titanium double salts and titanium basic double salts.
</P>
<P>
21. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein said precipitate contains at least 80% of the titanium originally present in said feed stream.
</P>
<P>
22. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the ratio P2/P3 is greater than 2.
</P>
<P>
23. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the ratio P2/P3 is greater than 10.
</P>
<P>
24. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the temperature of said formed medium is in the range between 0-80&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
25. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the temperature of said formed medium is in the range between 10-50&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
26. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein the temperature of said formed medium is in the range between 20-40&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
27. A method according to Claim 1 , further comprising a step of processing said titanium solution to form a product selected from the group consisting of iron metal, an iron oxides, other iron product, products of other polyvalent cations present in said titanium feed solution and their combinations, which processing comprises crystallization.
</P>
<P>
28. A method according to Claim 1 further comprising the step of washing said separated precipitate to form washed precipitate with a purity of P4 and a wash solution with a purity of P5, wherein P4 &amp;gt; P2 &amp;gt; P5.
</P>
<P>
29. A method according to Claim 28, wherein said washing is with a solution comprising at least one cation and at least one anion selected from said groups of Claim 1 , and wherein the concentration of said anion is higher than 15% and the ratio between the concentrations of said cation and said anion in said &amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt; titanium solution is higher than 0.2 and lower than 1.6.
</P>
<P>
30. A method according to Claim 28, wherein said washing is with a solution comprising protons, ammonium and sulfate ions.
</P>
<P>
31. A method according to Claim 1 , further comprising the step of re-crystallizing said precipitate, optionally pre-washed, to form a precipitate with a purity of P6 and a mother liquor with a purity P7, wherein P6 &amp;gt; P2 &amp;gt; P7.
</P>
<P>
32. A method according to Claim 31 wherein said re-crystallization uses a solution comprising at least one cation and at least one anion selected from said groups of Claim 1.
</P>
<P>
33. A method according to Claim 1 , further comprising the steps of: a. dissolution of a titanium double-salt in aqueous solution; and b. inducing a change of the conditions to form a titanium oxide precipitation from said solution, wherein said change is selected from the group consisting of dilution, temperature elevation, increasing pH and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
34. A method according to Claim 2, wherein said titanium oxide contains at least 70% of the titanium originally present in said feed stream.
</P>
<P>
35. A method according to Claim 2, wherein said titanium oxide comprises nano- particles in mid size range of 5-100 nanometer.
</P>
<P>
36. A method according to Claim 2, wherein said titanium oxide comprises nano- particles in mid size range of 100-300 nanometer.
</P>
<P>
37. A method according to Claim 27, wherein said iron product is selected from the group consisting of a iron double salt, iron oxide and iron hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
38. A method according to Claim 37, wherein the anion of said iron double salt is selected from the group consisting of monovalent anions, divalent anions, halide anions, sulfate and bisulfate anions and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
39. A method according to Claim 37, wherein said iron double salt comprises a cation selected from the group consisting of ammonium, sodium and potassium.
</P>
<P>
40. A method according to Claim 27 wherein said compound of polyvalent cation is selected from the group consisting of neutral double salts, basic- double- salt, oxides, hydroxide and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
41. A method according to Claim 31 , wherein said re-crystallization is induced by an action selected from the group consisting of adding a salt of a monovalent-cation, adding a base of a monovalent-cation, increasing temperature, dilution and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
42. A method according to Claim 2, for the production of a titanium oxide from said titanium double-salt, comprising the steps of: a. dissolution of a titanium double-salt in aqueous solution; and b. inducing precipitation of titanium oxide from said solution by an action selected from the group consisting of dilution, temperature elevation, increasing pH and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
43. A method according to Claim 42, wherein said titanium oxide contains at least 80% of the titanium originally present in said double salt.
</P>
<P>
44. A method according to Claim 42, wherein said temperature elevation involves increasing the temperature to above 8O&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
45. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein P2 is greater than 80%.
</P>
<P>
46. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein P2 is greater than 85%.
</P>
<P>
47. A method according to Claim 1 , wherein P2 is greater than 95%.
</P>
<P>
48. A method according to Claim 2, wherein said titanium oxide contains at least 70% of the titanium that was present in said titanium feed stream solution.
</P>
<P>
49. A method according to Claim 42, wherein said temperature elevation refers to increasing the temperature to be in the range of 12O&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 25O&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1957408B1;WO2007043055A1;US2009158895A1;US7700057B2;SI1957408T1;NO20081773A;MX2008004728A;KR20080072645A;JP2009511413A;EA200800804A1;EA014448B1;CA2625487A1;BRPI0617302A2;AU2006300754A1;AT496871T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
