<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CONDUCTIVE COATING MATERIAL
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1956062A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HANDA KOICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA TAKAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO TSUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN JIAYI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAUCHI AKIRA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAGASHIMA MANABU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA, KOICHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA, TAKAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO, TSUYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN, JIAYI
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAUCHI, AKIRA
</Name>
<Name>
NAGASHIMA, MANABU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RES INST INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI BUSSAN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RESEARCH INSTITUTE INC
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI &amp; CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1956062
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060822100
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP321120
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050310302
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/10
</Class>
<Class>
C09D201/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/24
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/52
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N1
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12S
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The disclosed is a conductive coating material which includes an organic binder component and carbon fibrous structures, wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers;  and wherein the carbon fibrous structures are contained at a rate of 0.01 - 50 % by weight based on the total weight of the coating material. The conductive coating material gives a coated film which shows a high electrical conductivity and a good film strength, and also coordinates its color as an intended one easily.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Conductive coating material which comprises an organic binder component and carbon fibrous structures, wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers; and wherein the carbon fibrous structures are contained at a rate of 0.01 - 50 % by weight based on the total weight of the coating material.
</P>
<P>
2. The conductive coating material according to Claim 1, which is used for a conductive primer
</P>
<P>
3. The conductive coating material according to Claim 1, which is used for a conductive ink.
</P>
<P>
4. The conductive coating material according to one of Claims 1 - 3, wherein the carbon fibrous structures have an area-based circle-equivalent mean diameter of 50 - 100 m.
</P>
<P>
5. The conductive coating material according to one of Claims 1 - 4, wherein the carbon fibrous structures may have a bulk density of 0.0001 - 0.05g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
6. The conductive coating material according to one of Claims 1-5, wherein the carbon fibrous structures have ID/IG ratio determined by Raman spectroscopy of not more than 0.2.
</P>
<P>
7. The conductive coating material according to one of Claims 1-6, wherein the carbon fibrous structures are produced using as carbon sources at least two carbon compounds which have mutually different decomposition temperatures.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009152508A1;KR20080049850A;WO2007049588A1;JP2007119532A;CN101297007A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
