<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PATTERNING OLED DEVICE ELECTRODES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1929533A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NEWMAN DAVID A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TREDWELL TIMOTHY JOHN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
COK RONALD STEVEN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YANG ZHIHAO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NEWMAN, DAVID, A
</Name>
<Name>
TREDWELL, TIMOTHY, JOHN
</Name>
<Name>
COK, RONALD, STEVEN
</Name>
<Name>
YANG, ZHIHAO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
EASTMAN KODAK CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
EASTMAN KODAK COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1929533
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060815508
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US37558
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050241370
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L27/32
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/52
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/32M2B
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/52B2C
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/52B4C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of making an OLED display having a plurality of OLED devices includes providing a plurality of OLED devices on a substrate, such OLED devices sharing a common light-transmissive electrode;  forming a patterned conductive layer structure over the common light-transmissive electrode to define wells in alignment with emissive areas of one or more OLED devices;  and providing optical material into one or more wells
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of making an OLED display having a plurality of OLED devices comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing a plurality of OLED devices on a substrate, such OLED devices sharing a common light-transmissive electrode;
</P>
<P>
(b) forming a patterned conductive layer structure over the common light-transmissive electrode to define wells in alignment with emissive areas of one or more OLED devices; and
</P>
<P>
(c) providing optical material into one or more wells.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1 wherein the patterned conductive layer structure includes a patterned conductive layer in contact with the common light-transmissive electrode and a patterned insulating layer disposed over the patterned conductive layer.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 2 wherein the patterned conductive layer structure is formed by:
</P>
<P>
(i) depositing a conductive layer over the common light-transmissive electrode;
</P>
<P>
(ii) providing a patterned insulating layer over the conductive layer; and
</P>
<P>
(iii) using the patterned insulating layer as an etch mask to pattern the conductive layer to form the patterned conductive layer.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 3 wherein the patterned insulating layer is provided by uniformly coating a polymer layer and using laser ablation to pattern the polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 3 wherein the patterned insulating layer is provided by patterned thermal transfer of a polymer from a donor sheet.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 3 wherein the conductive layer is patterned by chemical etching or plasma etching.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to claim 1 wherein the optical material is provided into the one or more wells by ink jet deposition.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to claim 1 wherein the optical material is a color filter material, a color conversion material, a light-scattering material, or a lenslet.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to claim 8 wherein different color filter materials are deposited into different wells by ink jet deposition to provide a color filter array.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to claim 9 wherein the optical materials do not fill the well and the wells serve as barriers to prevent the diffusion of optical material from one well to another.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to claim 1 wherein the patterned conductive layer structure acts as a black matrix.
</P>
<P>
12. The method according to claim 1 wherein one or more barrier layers are provided after forming the patterned conductive layer structure but before providing optical materials into the one or more wells.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to claim 1 further comprising:
</P>
<P>
(d) providing one or more barrier layers over the optical material and the patterned conductive layer structure.
</P>
<P>
14. The method according to claim 1 wherein a light-transmissive cover is provided over the display.
</P>
<P>
15. The method according to claim 8 wherein the optical material includes a light scattering material, a light-transmissive cover is provided over the display and there is a gap of at least 0.5 microns between the light-scattering material and the cover, said gap is filled with air, inert gas, or a material having an optical refractive index lower than that of the light-transmissive cover and having an optical refractive index lower than that of any organic materials in the light-emissive layer(s) of the OLED.
</P>
<P>
16. The method according to claim 1 wherein the wells are greater than 0.5 microns deep.
</P>
<P>
17. The method according to claim 1 wherein the wells are greater than 5 microns deep.
</P>
<P>
18. The method according to claim 1 wherein the OLED display includes red, green, and blue, light-emitting pixels.
</P>
<P>
19. The method according to claim 18 further including white light-emitting pixels.
</P>
<P>
20. The method according to claim 1 wherein step (b) includes laser transfer of metal nanoparticles from a donor sheet to form the patterned conductive layer structure.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007077349A1;WO2007041116A1;KR20080053478A;JP2009510696A;CN101288172A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
