<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR DEPOSITING HIGH ASPECT RATIO MOLECULAR STRUCTURES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1991497A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KAUPPINEN ESKO [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
NASIBULIN ALBERT [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
BROWN DAVID [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
GONZALEZ DAVID [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
KAUPPINEN, ESKO
</Name>
<Name>
NASIBULIN, ALBERT
</Name>
<Name>
BROWN, DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
GONZALEZ, DAVID
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CANATU OY [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
CANATU OY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1991497
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070712601
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007FI00059
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
FI20060000227
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for depositing high aspect ratio molecular structures (HARMS), which method comprises applying a force upon an aerosol comprising one or more HARM-structures, which force moves one or more HARM-structures based on one or more physical features and/or properties towards one or more predetermined locations for depositing one or more HARM-structures in a pattern by means of an applied force.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method for depositing high aspect ratio molecular structures (HARMS) , charact eri sed in that the method comprises applying a force upon an aerosol comprising one or more HARM-structures, which force moves one or more HARM-structures based on one or more physical features and/or properties towards one or more predetermined locations for depositing one or more HARM-structures in a pattern by means of an applied force.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1, characteri sed in that the force is applied upon one or more bundled HARM-structures .
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1, characteri sed in that the force is applied upon one or more individual HARM-structures .
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to claim 1, characteri s ed in that the force is applied upon one or more bundled and individual HARM- structures, wherein the force moves the bundled and/or the individual HARM-structure based on one or more physical features and/or properties.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to any of claims 1 - 4, characteri s ed in that bundled or individual HARM-structure is deposited.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to any of claims 1 - 4 , charac teri s ed in that bundled and individual HARM-structures are deposited.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to any of claims 1 - 6, characteri sed in that the HARM-structure comprises a nanotube, a carbon nanotube, a fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube, a boron-nitride nanotube, a nanorod including carbon, phosphorous, boron, nitrogen and/or silicon containing nanorod, a filament and/or any other tube, tubular, rod and/or ribbon and/or any other high aspect ratio molecular structure in individual or bundled form.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any of claims 1 - 7, charact eri sed in that a HARM-structure is positively, negatively or neutrally charged.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to any of claims 1 - 8, charact eri s ed in that the force comprises an electrical, an electrostatic, a magnetic, an inertial, a photophoretic, a thermophoretic, a gravitational, a viscous and/or an acoustic force.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to any of claims 1 -
</P>
<P>
9, characteri sed in that the force comprises an electrical force moving a naturally charged bundled HARM-structure.
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to any of claims 1 -
</P>
<P>
10, characteri s ed in that the force comprises an inertial force moving a bundled HARM-structure .
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to any of claim 1 -
</P>
<P>
11, characteri sed in that the method further comprises adding one or more reactants, agents, coating materials, functionalizing materials, surfactants and/or dopants to the one or more HARM- structures .
</P>
<P>
13. The use of a method according to any of claims 1 - 12 in a continuous or batch process for the production, separation, modification, deposition and/or further processing of one or more HARM- structures .
</P>
<P>
14. The use of a method according to any of claims 1 - 12 in the preparation of a functional material .
</P>
<P>
15. The use of a method according to any of claims 1 - 12 in the preparation of a thick or thin film, a line, a wire, a pattern, a layered and/or three dimensional structure.
</P>
<P>
16. The use of a method according to any of claims 1 - 12 in the preparation of a device.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007101906A1;US2009304945A1;US2009280238A1;KR20080113224A;KR20080112274A;JP2009533227A;JP2009528971A;WO2007101907A1;FI121540B1;EP1991498A1;CN101400598A;CN101400597A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
