<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NEGATIVE INDEX MATERIAL WITH COMPENSATED LOSSES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1991496A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SHALAEV VLADIMIR M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DRACHEV VLADIMIR P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KLAR THOMAS A [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KILDISHEV ALEXANDER V [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SHALAEV, VLADIMIR, M
</Name>
<Name>
DRACHEV, VLADIMIR, P
</Name>
<Name>
KLAR, THOMAS, A
</Name>
<Name>
KILDISHEV, ALEXANDER, V
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
PURDUE RESEARCH FOUNDATION [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PURDUE RESEARCH FOUNDATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1991496
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070751884
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-02-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US05152
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060777873P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01J3/02
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/00M3
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/122P
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/122S
</Class>
<Class>
H01S3/063F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A composition of resonant passive metal-dielectric elements with gain medium results in a meta-material with an effective negative refractive index and compensated losses. To compensate for losses, additional energy is supplied using the stimulated emission from active elements made of a gain material. The overall objective is to overcome the fundamental threshold in resolution for conventional optical imaging limited to about a half-wavelength of incident light. The negative index material with compensated losses (NIMCOL) can be used in NIM-based optical imaging and sensing devices with enhanced sub-wavelength resolution. A lasing device based on overcompensating for the loss in NIM structures is disclosed as well.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims:
</P>
<P>
1. A device comprising a negative index material with compensated losses using artificial magnetism obtained from elementary optical metal- dielectric resonators and stimulated emission from gain material inclusions to achieve enhanced imaging resolution.
</P>
<P>
2. The device of claim 1 comprising a nanophotonic waveguide.
</P>
<P>
3. The device of claim 1 comprising a photon source and switch.
</P>
<P>
4. The device of claim 1 comprising an on-chip spectrophotometer.
</P>
<P>
5. The device of claim 1 comprising a lens for use in a nanolithographic system.
</P>
<P>
6. The device of claim 1 comprising a lens for use in a nanoscale sensing system.
</P>
<P>
7. The device of claim 1 comprising a lens for use in a nanoscale imaging system.
</P>
<P>
8. The device of claim 1 comprising a beam steering device.
</P>
<P>
9. The device of claim 1 comprising a nonlinear optical multifunctional element.
</P>
<P>
10. A device comprising a negative index material with compensated losses, the negative index material including pairs of shaped metal parts spaced from each other by a distance of between about 3 and 30 nanometers, and a dielectric gain material situated between the shaped metal parts.
</P>
<P>
11. A device of claim 10 wherein the shape of the metal parts is selected from rods, solid particles, and strips.
</P>
<P>
12. The device of claim 10 wherein the metal forming the shaped metal parts is selected from the group consisting of silver and gold.
</P>
<P>
13. The device of claim 12 further comprising a separation material between the pairs of shaped metal parts comprising AI2O3.
</P>
<P>
14. The device of claim 12 wherein the shaped metal parts are sandwiched between an upper and lower layer, each layer comprising InP covered by a positive index polymer matching the index of InP.
</P>
<P>
15. The device of claim 14 wherein at least one of the upper and lower layer includes a quantum well comprising InGaAsP.
</P>
<P>
16. The device of claim 10 wherein the gain material comprises gain beads.
</P>
<P>
17. The device of claim 16 wherein the gain beads are Erbium doped.
</P>
<P>
18. The device of claim 10 comprising a [pi] -conjugated polymer.
</P>
<P>
19. A device comprising a negative index material with compensated losses, the negative index material having a dielectric gain material containing at least one of: a hollow metal particle, a hollow metal rod, a hollow metal strip, or a metal film with random or periodic voids.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007103077A2;WO2007103077A3;US2009219623A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
