<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
WHITE LIGHT EMITTING DEVICES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1989725A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
COE-SULLIVAN SETH A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BULOVIC VLADIMIR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STECKEL JONATHAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BAWENDI MOUNGI G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ANIKEEVA POLINA O [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HALPERT JONATHAN E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
COE-SULLIVAN, SETH, A
</Name>
<Name>
BULOVIC, VLADIMIR
</Name>
<Name>
STECKEL, JONATHAN
</Name>
<Name>
BAWENDI, MOUNGI, G
</Name>
<Name>
ANIKEEVA, POLINA, O
</Name>
<Name>
HALPERT, JONATHAN, E
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MASSACHUSETTS INST TECHNOLOGY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
<Name>
MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1989725
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070750508
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-02-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US03677
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060773119P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060828909P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L21/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/50E
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A white light emitting semiconductor nanocrystal includes a plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A light emitting device comprising an emissive layer including a plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals, the plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals generating white light upon excitation.
</P>
<P>
2. A light emitting device comprising: a first electrode; a hole injection layer in contact with the first electrode; a hole transporting layer in contact with the hole injection layer; a hole blocking layer in contact with the hole transporting layer; an electron transporting layer in contact with the hole blocking layer; a second electrode in contact with the electron transporting layer; and a plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals between the electron transporting layer and the hole blocking layer, the plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals including at least two distinct color emissions when excited.
</P>
<P>
3. The device of claim 2, wherein the first electrode is a transparent electrode.
</P>
<P>
4. The device of any one of claims 2 or 3, wherein hole injection layer includes a conducting polymer.
</P>
<P>
5. The device of any one of claims 2-4, wherein the hole transporting layer includes a benzidine.
</P>
<P>
6. The device of any one of claims 2-5, wherein the hole blocking layer includes a triazole.
</P>
<P>
7. The device of any one of claims 2-6, wherein the electron transporting layer includes a metal complex.
</P>
<P>
8. The device of any one of claims 2-7, wherein the second electrode includes a metal.
</P>
<P>
9. The device of any one of claims 2-8, wherein the plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals can include at least three distinct color emissions when excited.
</P>
<P>
10. The device of any one of claims 1-9, wherein the plurality of nanocrystals includes red, green and blue light emitting nanocrystals.
</P>
<P>
11. The device of any one of claims 1-10, wherein a nanocrystal includes a core.
</P>
<P>
12. The device of any one of claims 1 -9 , further comprising an overcoating on the core, the overcoating including a second semiconductor material.
</P>
<P>
13. The device of any one of claims 1-12, wherein the device has an external quantum efficiency of at least 0.20%.
</P>
<P>
14. The device of any one of claims 1-13, wherein the device has CIE coordinates of (0.35, 0.41).
</P>
<P>
15. The device of any one of claims 1-14, wherein the device has a color rendering index (CRI) of 86 as compared to a 5500K black body reference.
</P>
<P>
16. A method of forming a device of any one of claims 1-15, comprising: placing a plurality of semiconductor nanocrystals between a first electrode and a second electrode.
</P>
<P>
17. A method of generating light comprising: applying a light-generating potential to a device of any one of claims 1-16.
</P>
<P>
18. A display including a plurality of light emitting devices of any one of claims 1-17.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1989725A4;WO2007095173A2;WO2007095173A3;US2010001256A1;KR20080103527A;JP2009527099A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
