<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Optical microcantilever, manufacturing method thereof, and optical microcantilever holder
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1975598A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NIWA TAKASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KATO KENJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ICHIHARA SUSUMU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
CHIBA NORIO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUOKA YASUYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OUMI MANABU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KASAMA NOBUYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NIWA, TAKASHI
</Name>
<Name>
KATO, KENJI
</Name>
<Name>
ICHIHARA, SUSUMU
</Name>
<Name>
CHIBA, NORIO
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUOKA, YASUYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
OUMI, MANABU
</Name>
<Name>
KASAMA, NOBUYUKI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SEIKO INSTR INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SEIKO INSTRUMENTS INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1975598
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080075627
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2000-03-06
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20000906740
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2000-03-06
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP19990072218
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-03-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20000040030
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2000-02-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01B11/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01B11/30
</Class>
<Class>
G01B21/30
</Class>
<Class>
G01B5/28
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q30/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/22
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/32
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/38
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q70/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/22
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/38
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An optical microcantilever capable of reducing loss when propagating light. An optical microcantilever 10 comprises a support 1, an optical waveguide 2, a light-blocking film 3, a reflecting film 4, a pointed tip 5, a microscopic aperture 6 formed at the end of the tip 5, and a mirror 7 for reflecting propagating light H propagated from a light input/output end 8 of the optical waveguide 2 towards the microscopic aperture 6.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An optical microcantilever employed in a scanning near field microscope, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate;
</P>
<P>
a cantilever-shaped optical waveguide formed at the substrate;
</P>
<P>
a light input/output end positioned at a side of the fixed end of the optical waveguide;
</P>
<P>
a tip provided at the side of the free end of the cantilever and having a microscopic aperture at an end thereof, and
</P>
<P>
light-blocking means for ensuring that light scattered by the light input/output end is not transmitted in the direction of the tip.
</P>
<P>
2. The optical microcantilever of claim 1, wherein at the optical microcantilever employed in a scanning near field microscope,
</P>
<P>
the light-blocking means is arranged above the substrate and the optical waveguide, and provides a wall for blocking the scattered light.
</P>
<P>
3. The optical microcantilever of claim 1, wherein at the optical microcantilever employed in a scanning near field microscope,
</P>
<P>
the light-blocking means comprises: a light-blocking agent located on the substrate and the optical waveguide; and
</P>
<P>
a light-blocking film located on the light-blocking agent,
</P>
<P>
and the light-blocking film is located in such a manner as to cover at least the light input/output end.
</P>
<P>
4. The optical microcantilever of claim 1, wherein at the optical microcantilever employed in a scanning near field microscope,
</P>
<P>
a light-blocking means comprises: a light-blocking film located on the substrate and the optical waveguide; and
</P>
<P>
a light-blocking agent arranged so as to cover at least part of an end of the light-blocking film,
</P>
<P>
and the light-blocking film is located in such a manner as to cover at least the light input/output end.
</P>
<P>
5. The optical microcantilever employed in a scanning near field microscope of claim 3 or claim 4, wherein the light-blocking film is movable.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1975598A3;EP1089066A1;EP1089066A4;EP1089066B1;US2005039523A1;US7150185B2;US2007211986A1;US7496250B2;US6834537B1;US2007062266A1;US7240541B2;KR20100039434A;KR101117870B1;JP2000329677A;WO0055597A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
