<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING CERIUM OXIDE NANOCRYSTALS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1945569A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HYEON TAEG-HWAN [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
YU TAEKYUNG [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
HYEON, TAEG-HWAN
</Name>
<Name>
YU, TAEKYUNG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SEOUL NAT UNIV IND FOUNDATION [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
SEOUL NATIONAL UNIVERSITY INDUSTRY FOUNDATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1945569
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060799075
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006KR03994
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20050094626
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-08
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20060096792
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F17/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F17/00F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a new method for the production of cerium oxide (CeO2) nanocrystals having various sizes and various shapes via hydrolytic sol-gel reactions or non-hydrolytic sol-gel reactions. More specifically, the method synthesizing cerium oxide nanocrystals comprises;  i) preparing a cerium-surfactant complex by reacting a cerium precursor and a surfactant in a organic solvent;  and ii) aging said cerium-surfactant complex in an ether at a temperature of 100  DEG C - 360  DEG C.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
[1] A process for the preparation of cerium oxide nanocrystals via a non-hydrolytic sol-gel reaction, which comprises the steps for i) the formation of a cerium- surfactant complex by heating the mixture of a cerium precursor and a surfactant under reduced pressure; and ii) aging of said cerium-surfactant complex in etheric compound at a predetermined temperature.
</P>
<P>
[2] The process according to Claim 1, wherein said mixture of a cerium precursor and a surfactant of the step i), further comprises organic solvents.
</P>
<P>
[3] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said cerium precursor is selected from the group consisting of cerium(III) acetate hydrate, cerium(III) acetylacetonate hydrate, cerium(III) bromide, cerium(III) carbonate hydrate, cerium(i[pi]) chloride, cerium(III) chloride heptahydrate, cerium(III) 2-ethylhexanoate, cerium(i[pi]) fluoride, cerium(IV) fluoride, cerium(IV) hydroxide, cerium(III) iodide, cerium(III) nitrate hexahydrate, cerium(III) oxalate hydrate, cerium(III) sulfate, cerium(III) sulfate hydrate and cerium(IV) sulfate.
</P>
<P>
[4] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said surfactant of the step i), is selected from the group consisting of oleic acid, octanoic acid, decanoic acid, stearic acid and trioctylphosphine oxide(TOPO), triphenylphosphine(TPP), trioctylphosphine(TOP), and alkyl amines (RNH ) wherein R is alkyl groups with 3 to 18 carbons such as oleylamine, octylamine, hexadecylamine, tri- alkylamine and the mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
[5] The method of Claim 1, wherein said solvent is selected from the group consisting of pyridine, tetrahydrofurane(THF), toluene, xylene, mesitylene, benzene, dimethyl sulfoxide(DMSO), dimethylformamide(DMF), alcoholic compounds such as octyl alcohol, decanol, hydrocarbons such as heptane, octane, decane, dodecane, tetradecane, hexadecane, and the mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
[6] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said temperature of step i) for formation of said cerium-surfactant complex, ranges from 100[deg.]C to 200[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
[7] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said etheric compound is selected from the group consisting of ethers with 3 to 18 carbons such as octyl ether, butyl ether, hexyl ether, phenyl ether, decyl ether, and the mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
[8] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said temperature for aging of said cerium-surfactant complex in etheric compound, ranges from 100[deg.]C to 360[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
[9] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said aging time at the pre-determined temperature, ranges from 10 seconds to 48 hours.
</P>
<P>
[10] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said cerium oxide nanocrystals are separated and retrieved by adding a poor solvent, followed by centrifugation.
</P>
<P>
[11] A process for the preparation of cerium oxide nanocrystals through a non- hydrolytic sol-gel reaction, which comprises the steps for i) the formation of a cerium-surfactant complex by heating the mixture of a cerium precursor and a surfactant under atmospheric pressure; and ii) aging of said cerium-surfactant complex in etheric compound at a predetermined temperature.
</P>
<P>
[12] The process according to Claim 11, wherein said mixture of a cerium precursor and a surfactant of the step i), further comprises organic solvents.
</P>
<P>
[13] The process according to Claim 11 or Claim 12, wherein said cerium precursor is selected from the group consisting of cerium(III) acetate hydrate, cerium(III) acetylacetonate hydrate, cerium(III) bromide, cerium(III) carbonate hydrate, cerium(i[pi]) chloride, cerium(III) chloride heptahydrate, cerium(III) 2-ethylhexanoate, cerium(i[pi]) fluoride, cerium(IV) fluoride, cerium(IV) hydroxide, cerium(III) iodide, cerium(III) nitrate hexahydrate, cerium(III) oxalate hydrate, cerium(III) sulfate, cerium(III) sulfate hydrate and cerium(IV) sulfate.
</P>
<P>
[14] The process according to Claim 11 or Claim 12, wherein said surfactant of the step i), is selected from the group consisting of oleic acid, octanoic acid, decanoic acid, stearic acid and trioctylphosphine oxide(TOPO), triph- enylphosphine(TPP), trioctylphosphine(TOP), and alkyl amines (RNH ) wherein R is alkyl groups with 3 to 18 carbons such as oleylamine, octylamine, hex- adecylamine, trialkylamine and the mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
[15] The method of Claim 11, wherein said solvent is selected from the group consisting of pyridine, tetrahydrofurane(THF), toluene, xylene, mesitylene, benzene, dimethyl sulfoxide(DMSO), dimethylformamide(DMF), alcoholic compounds such as octyl alcohol, decanol, hydrocarbons such as heptane, octane, decane, dodecane, tetradecane, hexadecane, and the mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
[16] The process according to Claim 11 or Claim 12, wherein said temperature of step i) for formation of said cerium-surfactant complex, ranges from 100[deg.]C to 200[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
[17] The process according to Claim 11 or Claim 12, wherein said etheric compound is selected from the group consisting of ethers with 3 to 18 carbons such as octyl ether, butyl ether, hexyl ether, phenyl ether, decyl ether, and the mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
[18] The process according to Claim 11 or Claim 12, wherein said temperature for aging of said cerium-surfactant complex in etheric compound, ranges from
</P>
<P>
100[deg.]C to 360[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
[19] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said aging time at the predetermined temperature, ranges from 10 seconds to 48 hours.
</P>
<P>
[20] The process according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said cerium oxide nanocrystals are separated and retrieved by adding a poor solvent, followed by centrifugation.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1945569A4;WO2007043774A1;US2007092423A1;US7867463B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
