<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METAL OXIDE WITH HIGH THERMAL STABILITY AND PREPARING METHOD THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1928787A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MYEONG WAN-JAE [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
LEE JOO-HYEONG [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
SONG KYU-HO [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
MYEONG, WAN-JAE
</Name>
<Name>
LEE, JOO-HYEONG
</Name>
<Name>
SONG, KYU-HO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HANWHA CHEMICAL CORP [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
HANWHA CHEMICAL CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1928787
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060798545
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-08-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006KR03373
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20050083800
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01D53/56
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/10
</Class>
<Class>
C01G99/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/00B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/10
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/03B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/36B
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/36H
</Class>
<Class>
C01G25/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed are metal oxide having high thermal stability and a preparation method thereof, specifically including continuously reacting a reaction mixture, composed of (i) water, (ii) a first metal salt including an aqueous cerium compound and (iii) a second metal salt including an aqueous aluminum compound, at 200~700  DEG C under pressure of 180-550 bar, the reaction product having a molar ratio of metal, other than aluminum, to aluminum of 0.1~10.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method of preparing metal oxide, comprising continuously reacting a reaction mixture, composed of (i) water, (ii) a first metal salt including an aqueous cerium compound, and (iii) a second metal salt including an aqueous aluminum compound, at 200~700[deg.]C under pressure of 180~550 bar, a reaction product thereof having a molar ratio of metal, other than aluminum, to aluminum of 0.1~10.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1, wherein the first metal salt further comprises a salt of at least one metal selected from among Ca, Sc5 Sr, Zr, Y and lanthanides other than Ce.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 1, wherein the first metal salt further comprises a zirconium salt.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 1, wherein the second metal salt further comprises a salt of at least one metal selected from among alkali earth metals, lantanides, and barium.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 1, wherein the reaction mixture further comprises an alkaline solution or an acidic solution which is added in an amount of
</P>
<P>
0.1-20 mol based on 1 mol of the metal salt, before or during the reacting.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 5, wherein the alkaline solution is ammonia water.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to claim 1, wherein the continuously reacting is performed by mixing and precipitating a pre-pressurized aqueous metal salt solution containing cerium and a pre-pressurized aqueous precipitant solution including ammonia water to thus prepare a first precipitate (pi), and further mixing and precipitating the first precipitate (pi) and a pre-pressurized aqueous aluminum salt solution to thus obtain a second precipitate (p2), which is then mixed and reacted with supercritical water or subcritical water.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to claim 1, further comprising at least one post- treatment among separation, drying, and calcination of the reaction product.
</P>
<P>
9. A mixture of metal oxides, prepared using the method of any one of claims 1 to 8 and having a specific surface area of at least 100 m /g before calcination and a specific surface area of at least 40 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g upon calcination at 1000[deg.]C for 6 hours in air.
</P>
<P>
10. A catalyst system for treatment of exhaust gas from an internal combustion engine using the mixture of metal oxides of claim 9.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1928787A4;WO2007029932A1;US2008242536A1;KR20070028975A;KR100713298B1;JP2009507750A;CN101263087A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
