<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR DEPOSITING REFLECTIVE MULTILAYER FILM OF REFLECTIVE MASK BLANK FOR EUV LITHOGRAPHY AND METHOD FOR PRODUCING REFLECTIVE MASK BLANK FOR EUV LITHOGRAPHY
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1945829A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SUGIYAMA TAKASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUGIYAMA, TAKASHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ASAHI GLASS CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ASAHI GLASS COMPANY, LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1945829
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060823435
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP322787
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050325769
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B24B37/04
</Class>
<Class>
C23C14/02
</Class>
<Class>
C23C14/34
</Class>
<Class>
G03F1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B24B37/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C14/22
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/08V
</Class>
<Class>
G03F1/08
</Class>
<Class>
G03F1/24
</Class>
<Class>
G21K1/06B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for depositing, on a substrate, a reflective multilayer film of a reflective mask blank for EUV lithography by sputtering, comprises: depositing a reflective multilayer film in such a state that a substrate has been deformed so as to be subjected to a stress, which is directed to the opposite direction to a stress applied to the substrate by deposition of the reflective multilayer film;  and returning the substrate to the shape before deformation, after deposition of the reflective multilayer film.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method for depositing a multilayer film on a substrate, comprising: depositing a multilayer film in such a state that a substrate has been deformed so as to be subjected to a stress, which is directed to the opposite direction to a stress applied to the substrate by deposition of the multilayer film; and returning the substrate to the shape before deformation, after deposition of the multilayer film.
</P>
<P>
2. A method for depositing, on a substrate, a reflective multilayer film of a reflective mask blank for EUV lithography by sputtering, comprising: depositing a reflective multilayer film in such a state that a substrate has been deformed so as to be subjected to a stress, which is directed to the opposite direction to a stress applied to the substrate by deposition of the reflective multilayer film,- and returning the substrate to the shape before deformation, after deposition of the reflective multilayer film.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to Claim 2, wherein the substrate that has been returned to the shape before deformation has a flatness of 100 nm or below. 4. The method according to Claim 2 or 3 , wherein in order to deposit the reflective multilayer film in such a state that the substrate has been deformed, the substrate is held by a first electrostatic chuck, which has a contact surface with the substrate, formed in a shape corresponding to the shape of the substrate after deformation. 5. The method according to Claim 4, wherein the first electrostatic chuck has a chucking force of 0.5 kPa or above and a Young&apos;s modulus of 10 GPa or above.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to Claim 4 or 5 , wherein the contact surface of the first electrostatic chuck, on which the substrate is held, has slightly smaller dimensions than those of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to any one of Claims 2 to 6 , wherein the substrate has a specific rigidity of 3.OxIO&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/s&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; or above and a Poisson&apos; s ratio of 0.16 to 0.25. 8. A method for producing a reflective mask blank for EUV lithography, comprising: depositing an absorbing layer on a reflective multilayer film by sputtering after depositing the reflective multilayer film on a substrate by the method for depositing a reflective multilayer film of a reflective mask blank for EUV lithography, defined in any one of Claims 2 to 7 ; the method further comprising: depositing the absorbing layer in such a state that the substrate has been deformed so as to be subjected to a stress, which is directed to the opposite direction to a stress applied to the substrate by deposition of the absorbing layer,- and returning the substrate to the shape before deformation, after deposition of the absorbing layer.
</P>
<P>
9. A method for producing a reflective mask blank for EUV lithography, comprising: depositing a buffer layer and an absorbing layer on a reflective multilayer film by sputtering after depositing the reflective multilayer film on a substrate by the method for depositing a reflective multilayer film of a reflective mask blank for EUV lithography, defined in any one of Claims 2 to 7 ; the method further comprising: depositing the buffer layer and the absorbing layer in such a state that the substrate has been deformed so as to be subjected to a stress, which is directed to the opposite direction to a stress applied to the substrate by deposition of the buffer layer and the absorbing layer; and returning the substrate to the shape before deformation, after deposition of the absorbing layer.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to Claim 8 or 9, wherein the substrate that has been returned to the shape before deformation has a flatness of 100 nm or below.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to Claim 8 or 9, wherein in order to deposit the absorbing layer in such a state that the substrate has been deformed, the substrate is held by a second electrostatic chuck, which has a contact surface with the substrate, formed in a shape corresponding to the shape of the substrate after deformation. 12. The method according to Claim 9 or 10, wherein in order to deposit the buffer layer and the absorbing layer in such a state that the substrate has been deformed, the substrate is held by a second electrostatic chuck, which has a contact surface with the substrate, formed in a shape corresponding to the shape of the substrate after deformation. 13. The method according to Claim 11 or 12, wherein the second electrostatic chuck has a chucking force of 0.5 kPa or above and a Young&apos;s modulus of 10 GPa or above.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007055401A1;KR20080066763A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
