<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR MAKING CHROMONIC NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1948558A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MORAN CRISTIN E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SAHOUANI HASSAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BOARDMAN LARRY D [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOHANTY SANAT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MORAN, CRISTIN E
</Name>
<Name>
SAHOUANI, HASSAN
</Name>
<Name>
BOARDMAN, LARRY D
</Name>
<Name>
MOHANTY, SANAT
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1948558
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060825762
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-11
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US39727
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050250290
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/02
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/14H4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51H2
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51P
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q19/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09K19/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A chrmonic nanoparticle mixture prepared by combining (i) a continuous water-soluble polymer phase and (ii) a discontinuous chromonic phase comprising a chromonic material;  and non-covalently crosslinking the resulting chromonic nanoparticles with a polyvalent cation salt.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
We claim:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of making a chromonic particle dispersion comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing an aqueous mixture comprising (i) a continuous water-soluble polymer phase and (ii) a discontinuous chromonic phase comprising a chromonic material;
</P>
<P>
(b) non-covalently crosslinking the resulting chromonic nanoparticles with a multivalent cation salt.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 wherein said particles are nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 2 comprising the further step of contacting the crosslinked chromonic nanoparticles with a solution of a surface modifying agent selected from an organic oxyacid of carbon, sulfur and phosphorus.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 2 wherein said aqueous mixture is prepared by combining an aqueous solution of water soluble polymer and a neutralized aqueous solution of chromonic material.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 2 wherein said mixture comprising (i) a continuous water-soluble polymer phase and (ii) a discontinuous chromonic phase comprising a chromonic material is added to an aqueous solution of said multivalent cationic salt.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 4 wherein said neutralized aqueous solution of chromonic material is prepared by treating a chromonic material with an alkali- or alkaline earth metal hydroxide or carbonate.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 2 wherein said multivalent cation of the multivalent cation salt is selected from Ca&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; , Fe&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; , Fe&amp;lt;3+&amp;gt; , Zn&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; , Mg&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; and Al&amp;lt;3+&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 2 wherein the weight ratio of said water soluble polymer to said chromonic material is from 5:1 to 99:1.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 2 wherein the weight ratio of said water soluble polymer to said chromonic material is from 5:1 to 15:1.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 2 wherein the concentration of the water-soluble polymer is from 15 to 25 wt. % of the aqueous mixture.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 2 wherein the concentration of chromonic material is from 0.25 to 7 wt. % of the aqueous mixture.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 2 wherein the chromonic nanoparticles are less than 1000 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 2 wherein said water-soluble polymer is selected from vinyl alcohol polymers, poly(aspartic acid), poly(acrylic acid), poly(methacrylic acid), poly(acrylamide), poly(vinyl pyrrolidone), poly(alkylene oxide)s, poly(vinyl methyl ether), sulfonated polyesters, complex carbohydrates, guar gum, gum arabic, gum tragacanth, larch gum, gum karaya, locust bean gum, agar, alginates, caragheenan, pectins, cellulose and cellulose derivatives, starches and modified starches, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13 wherein said water-soluble polymer is hydroxypropylmethyl cellulose.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 13 wherein said water-soluble polymer,is starch or modified starch.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 1 wherein said chromonic material is selected from one or more of the following general formulae:
</P>
<P>
EMI5.0
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
each R&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is independently selected from the group consisting of electron donating groups, electron withdrawing groups, and electron neutral groups, and
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;3 &amp;gt; is selected from the group consisting of substituted and unsubstituted heteroaromatic rings and substituted and unsubstituted heterocyclic rings, said rings being linked to the triazine group through a nitrogen atom within the ring of R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; ,
</P>
<P>
and zwitterions, proton tautomers, and salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 wherein said chromonic material is selected from one or more of the following general formulae:
</P>
<P>
EMI6.0
</P>
<P>
wherein X&amp;lt;-&amp;gt; is a counterion.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 2 wherein said aqueous composition further comprises a noble metal salt.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 18 wherein said metal salt is selected from the group consisting of silver salts, gold salts, platinum salts, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 18 said noble metal salt is contained in the crosslinked chromonic nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 20 comprising the further step of reducing the contained noble metal salt to an elemental noble metal to produce a suspension of elemental noble metal nanoparticles contained in said crosslinked chromonic nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 21 comprising the further step of contacting said crosslinked nanoparticles with an aqueous solution of a monovalent metal salt to reversed the crosslinking and release the contained elemental noble metal nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 2 wherein the metal nanoparticles are spherical.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 2 wherein the metal nanoparticles are acicular.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 20 wherein said crosslinked chromonic nanoparticles containing a noble metal salt is coated onto a substrate.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 25 further comprising the step of reducing said noble metal salt to produce a coated substrate comprising a continuous coating of water-soluble polymer and a discontinuous coating of elemental noble metal nanoparticles contained in said chromonic nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 26 comprising the further step of removing said water-soluble polymer from said coating.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 1 wherein said particles are less than 1000 nanometers average particle size.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of claim 1 wherein said particles are less than 500 nanometers average particle size.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 1 wherein said particles are less than 100 nanometers average particle size.
</P>
<P>
31. A chromonic nanoparticle dispersion comprising i) a continuous water-soluble polymer phase and (ii) a discontinuous chromonic phase comprising a chromonic material and a noble metal or noble metal salt incorporated therein.
</P>
<P>
32. The dispersion of claim 27 wherein the chromonic nanoparticle is surface modified.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007086964A1;US7629027B2;WO2007047307A1;JP2009512562A;CN101287674A;CN101287674B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
