<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Probe Module, Probe Array, and a Method of Assembling Probe Arrays
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1995737A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
AKIYAMA TERUNOBU [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
CLAVEL REYMOND [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
DAFFLON MELANIE [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
STAUFER URS [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
AKIYAMA TERUNOBU
</Name>
<Name>
CLAVEL REYMOND
</Name>
<Name>
DAFFLON MELANIE
</Name>
<Name>
STAUFER URS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
INST MICROTECHNIQUE DE L UNIVE [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
INSTITUT DE MICROTECHNIQUE DE L&apos;UNIVERSITE DE NEUCHATEL
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1995737
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070405154
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070405154
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G12B21/22
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q70/06
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention refers to a probe array, e.g. for scanning probe microscopes, which is assembled from individual probe modules. Such a probe module comprises a spring means (cantilever) and/or an actuator and handling means and is reversibly attached to a platform carrying the array. In a preferred embodiment the array is assembled out of individual probe modules, which may individually be replaced with identical or different probe modules.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A probe module comprising a spring means and/or an actuator and handling means for reversibly assembling said spring means and/or actuator, to a probe array.
</P>
<P>
2. A probe module according to claim 1, wherein the handling means include attaching means for reversibly attaching the probe module to a platform.
</P>
<P>
3. A probe module according to claim 1 or 2, wherein attaching means are spring clips, clamp means, magnetic elements or turn-lock fasteners, electrostatic clamps or a plasticiseable interface material.
</P>
<P>
4. A probe module according to any of claims 1 to 3, comprising an actuator, a spring means with a probing tip and electrical contacts for electrically connecting the probe module to the platform.
</P>
<P>
5. A probe array with a platform comprising a plurality of probes, wherein at least an individual probe or a sub-array of probes is reversibly attached to the platform.
</P>
<P>
6. A probe array according to claim 5, wherein the individual probe, the sub-array of probes or the platform comprise attaching means for the reversible attaching of the probe or the sub-array and the platform to each other.
</P>
<P>
7. A probe array with a platform comprising a plurality of spring means and/or actuators, wherein at least one spring means and/or actuator is a part of a probe module according to any one of claims 1 to 4.
</P>
<P>
8. A probe array according to claim 7, wherein at least two spring means and/or actuators are parts of probe modules and one probe module is different to the other probe module.
</P>
<P>
9. A probe array according to claim 8, wherein the difference of the probe modules is defined by one of the group of:
</P>
<P>
- different material;
</P>
<P>
- where applicable different actuator;
</P>
<P>
- different sensor;
</P>
<P>
- different physical functionality;
</P>
<P>
- different surface chemistry of a probing tip;
</P>
<P>
10. A probe array according to any one of claims 7 to 9, wherein all of the spring means and/or actuators are each a part of a probe module.
</P>
<P>
11. A probe array according to any one of claims 7 to 10, wherein the platform comprises attaching means for reversibly attaching the probe modules to the platform.
</P>
<P>
12. A probe array according to any one of claims 7-11, wherein several or all probe modules comprise at least one electrostatic comb-actuator.
</P>
<P>
13. A probe array according to any one of claims 7-12, wherein the platform and/or the probe module comprise mechanical reference structures for a positioning of a probe module on the platform blocking at least one degree of freedom of the probe module, preferably blocking all six degrees of freedom.
</P>
<P>
14. A method for assembling a probe array consisting of individual, exchangeable probe modules, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
a) taking a probe module, which comprises at least a cantilever and/or an actuator and handling means;
</P>
<P>
b) attaching the probe module to a platform;
</P>
<P>
c) repeating steps a) and b) until completion of a 1D or 2D probe array with a desired size.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to claim 14, wherein several probe modules are aligned into a sub-array before being attached to the platform.
</P>
<P>
16. A method according to claim 14 or 15, wherein a probe module or a sub-array is replaced by another probe module or sub-array, respectively.
</P>
<P>
17. A method according to any one of claims 14 to 16, comprising a first step of microfabricating the probe module.
</P>
<P>
18. A method according to claim 17, wherein the probe module is microfabricated in one plane, then turned out of this plane for being attached to the platform.
</P>
<P>
19. A method according to any one of claims 14 to 18, wherein different probe modules are attached to the platform to form a probe array.
</P>
<P>
20. A method according to any one of claims 14 to 19, wherein electronic chips are attached to the platform.
</P>
</Claims>
</BiblioData>
