<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
MICROFLUIDIC DEVICES AND METHODS OF USE IN THE FORMATION AND CONTROL OF NANOREACTORS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1984738A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LINK DARREN R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BOITARD LAURENT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BRANCIFORTE JEFFREY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHARLES YVES [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FEKE GILBERT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LU JOHN Q [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MARRAN DAVID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TABATABAI AHMADALI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WEINER MICHAEL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HINZ WOLFGANG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ROTHBERG JONATHAN M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LINK, DARREN, R
</Name>
<Name>
BOITARD, LAURENT
</Name>
<Name>
BRANCIFORTE, JEFFREY
</Name>
<Name>
CHARLES, YVES
</Name>
<Name>
FEKE, GILBERT
</Name>
<Name>
LU, JOHN, Q
</Name>
<Name>
MARRAN, DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
TABATABAI, AHMADALI
</Name>
<Name>
WEINER, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
HINZ, WOLFGANG
</Name>
<Name>
ROTHBERG, JONATHAN, M
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
RAINDANCE TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RAINDANCE TECHNOLOGIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1984738
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060844121
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-06-01
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US21280
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US00931
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060763524P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060771286P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J19/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07B61/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K1/04
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/536
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01F13/00M4A
</Class>
<Class>
B01F13/00M6A
</Class>
<Class>
B01J19/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/5027J4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K1/04C
</Class>
<Class>
C40B30/04
</Class>
<Class>
C40B40/04
</Class>
<Class>
C40B50/08
</Class>
<Class>
C40B60/08
</Class>
<Class>
C40B60/12
</Class>
<Class>
C40B70/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/536
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68A10
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides novel microfluidic devices, kits, and methods that are useful for performing high-throughput screening assays and diagnostics. Such diagnostic methods can include emulsifying an aqueous library of compounds with a set of uniquely dyecoded-labeled droplets in an inert fluorocarbon medium, thereby forming an interactor library, emulsifying an aqueous sample from a subject in an inert fluorocarbon medium, wherein said sample contains a compound that will react with at least one interactor molecule from the interactor library, coalescing the emulsions to form a nanoreactor, and screening the nanoreactors for a desirable reaction between the contents of the nanoreactor, herein one or more steps are performed on a microfluidic device, which can include a plurality of electrically addressable, channel bearing fluidic modules integrally arranged on a microfabricated substrate such that a continuous channel is provided for flow of immiscible fluids.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
L A method for performing a diagnostic, the method comprising: a) emulsifying an aqueous library of compounds with a set of uniquely dyecoded- labeled droplets in an inert fluorocarbon medium, thereby forming an interactor library; b) emulsifying an aqueous sample from a subject in an inert fluorocarbon medium, wherein said sample contains a compound that will react with at least one interactor molecule from the interactor library; c) coalescing the emulsions prepared in steps (a) and (b) to form a nanoreactor; and d) screening the nanoreactors for a desirable reaction between the contents of the nanoreactor, wherein one or more steps of (a) - (d) are performed on a microfluidic device.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein the library of compounds comprises antigens to various human allergens.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein the sample from a subject is serum.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, wherein said screening step is performed by fluorescent polarization.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 further comprising quantifying the amount of the compound in the nanoreactor.
</P>
<P>
6. A kit for performing the method of claim 1 , the kit comprising an emulsion library of compounds, wherein each emulsion has been uniquely labeled.
</P>
<P>
7. The kit of claim 6, wherein the library of compounds comprises antigens to various human allergens.
</P>
<P>
8. The kit of claim 6, wherein the label is a liquid label.
</P>
<P>
9. The kit of claim 8, wherein the liquid label is a quantum dot.
</P>
<P>
10. A kit for synthesizing a compound from two or more reactive substructures, the kit comprising an emulsion library of reactive substructures, wherein each emulsion has been uniquely labeled.
</P>
<P>
11. A kit for liquid labeling a library of compounds, the kit comprising an emulsionof unique liquid labels.
</P>
<P>
12. A kit for sequencing individual exons from individual chromosomes, the kit comprising: a) an emulsion library of specific primer-pairs to an exon and beads that can bind to said primer-pairs; and b) a chromosomal DNA emulsion.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007081387A1;WO2007081386A2;WO2007081386A3;WO2007081385A2;WO2007081385A3;WO2007081385A8;US2010137163A1;JP2009536313A;EP2363205A2;EP2364774A2;CA2636855A1;AU2006335290A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
