<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHODS AND APPARATUS FOR ASSAY MEASUREMENTS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1957981A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MASTERS BRETT P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MILLER MICHAEL F [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SAUER-BUDGE ALEXIS F [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MASTERS, BRETT, P
</Name>
<Name>
MILLER, MICHAEL, F
</Name>
<Name>
SAUER-BUDGE, ALEXIS, F
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BIOSCALE INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BIOSCALE, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1957981
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060838183
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US45057
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050739731P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060416999
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B06B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N29/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N29/02F
</Class>
<Class>
G01N29/036
</Class>
<Class>
G01N29/30
</Class>
<Class>
G01N29/44B4
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543K2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Methods and apparatuses for performing assays involving binding material elements with a plurality of bonds over a substantial area of a surface of a resonant device establishing a normalized exposure. The methods and apparatuses also involve controlling an external influence applied to the material elements over a first period of time and measuring a signal during a second period of time that is indicative of the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface relative to the normalized exposure. In some cases, the measured signals are integrated with respect to time to determine the time averaged amount of material elements bound to the surface.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for performing an assay, comprising:
</P>
<P>
binding material elements with a plurality of bonds over a substantial area of a surface of a resonant device establishing a normalized exposure;
</P>
<P>
controlling an external influence applied to the material elements over a first period of time; and
</P>
<P>
measuring a signal during a second period of time that is indicative of the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface relative to the normalized exposure.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, comprising determining the concentration of substances located between the material elements and the surface based on the change in the amount of the material elements bound to the surface during the second period of time relative to the normalized exposure.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 2 wherein the substances located between the material elements and the surface bind the material elements to the surface.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, comprising correlating the external influence with the amount of material elements that are released from the surface in response to the external influence.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1, comprising integrating values of the measured signal with respect to time to determine the time-averaged amount of material elements bound to the surface.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1 wherein controlling the external influence comprises changing the external influence.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 6 comprising correlating the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface with the change in the external influence.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises flowing a fluid over, through or across the material elements.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises producing relative acceleration between the material elements and the surface.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1 wherein the material elements are magnetic and applying an external influence comprises applying an opposing magnetic gradient to the material elements.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises exposing the material elements to a constant or time-varying electric field to induce an electrophoretic or dielectrophoretic force that acts on the material elements.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises exposing the material elements to an acoustic field or fluid flow field generated by the resonant device.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises altering binding force strength between the material elements and the surface.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13 wherein altering binding force strength comprises altering pH of a fluid, flowing a denaturant over the material elements, altering temperature of a fluid, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises increasing amplitude of the relative displacement between the material elements and the surface.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 1 wherein measuring a signal during a second period of time is performed using an apparatus selected from the group consisting of a surface plasmon resonance apparatus, resonant device, acoustic device, flexural plate wave device, quartz microbalance device, and microscope.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 wherein the surface is a surface of the apparatus.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 1 wherein applying the external influence further comprises varying the external influence over the second period or time.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 1 wherein measuring comprises continuously measuring the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface during the second period of time.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 1 wherein measuring the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface comprises measuring the rate at which the material elements bind to the surface during the first period of time.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 1 wherein the first period of time overlaps with the second period of time.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 1 wherein the material elements are magnetic particles, paramagnetic particles, gold particles, microspheres or beads.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 1 wherein the bonds comprise specific associations, non-specific associations, cross-reactive associations, ionic bonds, covalent bonds, van der Waals bonds, hydrogen bonds or polar bonds.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 2, wherein the material elements are exposed to the substances within a sample prior to binding the material elements to the surface of the resonant device.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 24, comprising determining the concentration of the substances located in the sample based on the concentration of the substances located between the material elements and the surface.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 1 wherein applying an external influence comprises generating a force on the material elements that competes with the binding between the material elements and the surface.
</P>
<P>
27. A method for performing an assay, comprising:
</P>
<P>
binding material elements with a plurality of bonds over a substantial area of a surface of a resonant device establishing a normalized exposure;
</P>
<P>
changing an external influence applied to the material elements over a first period of time; and
</P>
<P>
integrating a signal with respect to time during a second period of time to determine the time-averaged amount of material elements bound to the surface.
</P>
<P>
28. An apparatus for performing an assay, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a resonant device having a surface, wherein a binding substance or means for binding is capable of binding a plurality of material elements to the surface and of sandwiching a substance between the plurality of material elements and the surface to form a plurality of bonds between the substance and the plurality of material elements and to establish a normalized exposure;
</P>
<P>
a source for applying an external influence to the material elements over a first period of time; and
</P>
<P>
a measurement device for measuring a signal that is indicative of the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface relative to the normalized exposure.
</P>
<P>
29. The apparatus of claim 28 wherein the source for applying an external influence controls flow of a fluid over, through or across the material elements.
</P>
<P>
30. The apparatus of claim 28 wherein the material elements are magnetic and the source for applying an external influence applies an opposing magnetic gradient to the material elements.
</P>
<P>
31. The apparatus of claim 28 the source for applying an external influence exposes the material elements to a constant or time-varying electric field to induce an electrophoretic or dielectrophoretic force that acts on the material elements.
</P>
<P>
32. The apparatus of claim 28 the source for applying an external influence exposes the material elements to an acoustic field or fluid flow field generated by the resonant device.
</P>
<P>
33. The apparatus of claim 28 wherein the resonant device is an acoustic device, flexural plate wave device, surface acoustic wave device, lamb wave device, resonant cantilever device, shear harmonic surface acoustic wave device, acoustic plate mode device or quartz crystal microbalance device.
</P>
<P>
34. The apparatus of claim 28 wherein the measurement device is a surface plasmon resonance apparatus, resonant device, acoustic device, flexural plate wave device, quartz microbalance device, or microscope.
</P>
<P>
35. The apparatus of claim 28 wherein the material elements are magnetic particles, paramagnetic particles, gold particles, microspheres or beads.
</P>
<P>
36. The apparatus of claim 28 wherein the source for applying an external influence is also the measurement device.
</P>
<P>
37. A method for performing an assay, comprising:
</P>
<P>
binding material elements with a plurality of bonds over a substantial area of a surface establishing a normalized exposure;
</P>
<P>
applying an external influence to the -material elements over a first period of time;
</P>
<P>
measuring an optical signal during a second period of time that is indicative of the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface relative to the normalized exposure; and
</P>
<P>
integrating values of the optical signal with respect to time to determine the time-averaged amount of material elements bound to the surface.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of claim 37, comprising determining the concentration of substances located between the material elements and the surface based on the change in the amount of the material elements bound to the surface during the second period of time relative to the normalized exposure.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of claim 38 wherein the substances located between the material elements and the surface bind the material elements to the surface.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of claim 37, comprising correlating the external influence with the amount of material elements that are released from the surface in response to the external influence.
</P>
<P>
41. The method of claim 37 wherein applying an external influence comprises flowing a fluid over, through or across the material elements.
</P>
<P>
42. The method of claim 37 wherein applying an external influence comprises exposing the material elements to a constant or time-varying electric field to induce an electrophoretic or dielectrophoretic force that acts on the material elements.
</P>
<P>
43. The method of claim 37 wherein applying an external influence comprises exposing the material elements to an acoustic field or fluid flow field generated by the resonant device.
</P>
<P>
44. The method of claim 37 wherein applying an external influence comprises altering binding force strength between the material elements and the surface.
</P>
<P>
45. The method of claim 44 wherein altering binding force strength comprises altering pH of a fluid, flowing a denaturant over the material elements, altering temperature of a fluid, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
46. The method of claim 37 wherein measuring an optical signal during a second period of time is performed using an apparatus selected from the group consisting of a surface plasmon resonance apparatus, microscope, or fluorescence measurement apparatus.
</P>
<P>
47. The method of claim 46 wherein the surface is a surface of the apparatus.
</P>
<P>
48. The method of claim 37 wherein the material elements are magnetic particles, paramagnetic particles, gold particles, microspheres or beads.
</P>
<P>
49. The method of claim 37 wherein the material elements are fluorescent.
</P>
<P>
50. The method of claim 49 wherein measuring an optical signal comprises measuring reflectivity, transmission or fluorescence of the particles or a substance bound to the particles.
</P>
<P>
51. An apparatus for performing an assay, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a surface, wherein a binding substance or means for binding is capable of binding a plurality of material elements to the surface and of sandwiching a substance between the plurality of material elements and the surface to form a plurality of bonds between the substance and the plurality of material elements and to establish a normalized exposure;
</P>
<P>
a source for applying an external influence to the material elements over a first period of time; and
</P>
<P>
an optical measurement device for measuring a signal that is indicative of the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface relative to the normalized exposure, wherein integrating values of the optical signal with respect to time determines the time-averaged amount of material elements bound to the surface.
</P>
<P>
52. The apparatus of claim 51 wherein the source for applying an external influence controls flow of a fluid over, through or across the material elements.
</P>
<P>
53. The apparatus of claim 51 wherein the material elements are magnetic and the source for applying an external influence applies an opposing magnetic gradient to the material elements.
</P>
<P>
54. The apparatus of claim 51 the source for applying an external influence exposes the material elements to a constant or time-varying electric field to induce an electrophoretic or dielectrophoretic force that acts on the material elements.
</P>
<P>
55. The apparatus of claim 51 the source for applying an external influence exposes the material elements to an acoustic field or fluid flow field generated by a resonant device.
</P>
<P>
56. The apparatus of claim 51 wherein the optical measurement device is an apparatus selected from the group consisting of a surface plasmon resonance apparatus, microscope, or fluorescence measurement apparatus.
</P>
<P>
57. The apparatus of claim 51 wherein the particles are magnetic particles, paramagnetic particles, gold particles, microspheres or beads.
</P>
<P>
58. An apparatus for performing an assay, comprising:
</P>
<P>
means for binding material elements with a plurality of bonds over a substantial area of a surface of a resonant device establishing a normalized exposure;
</P>
<P>
means for controlling an external influence applied to the material elements over a first period of time; and
</P>
<P>
means for measuring a signal during a second period of time that is indicative of the change in the amount of material elements bound to the surface relative to the normalized exposure.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007117214A1;WO2007062038A1;US2007117216A1;JP2009517661A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
