<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
2-DIMENSIONAL PHOTONIC CRYSTAL SURFACE EMITTING LASER LIGHT SOURCE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1998420A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SAKAI KYOSUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MIYAI EIJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NODA SUSUMU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHNISHI DAI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KUNISHI WATARU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SAKAI, KYOSUKE
</Name>
<Name>
MIYAI, EIJI
</Name>
<Name>
NODA, SUSUMU
</Name>
<Name>
OHNISHI, DAI
</Name>
<Name>
KUNISHI, WATARU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV KYOTO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ROHM CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KYOTO UNIVERSITY
</Name>
<Name>
ROHM CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1998420
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070736925
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP00268
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060077472
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01S5/125
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/18
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/10
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/125
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/18
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An objective of the present invention is to provide a surface emitting laser capable of selectively generating a laser oscillation in the fundamental mode and thereby emitting a single-wavelength laser light. In a surface emitting laser including an active layer and a two-dimensional photonic crystal provided on one side of the active layer, a reflector 45 or 46 is provided at least at a portion of the circumference of the two-dimensional photonic crystal. The reflector has a reflectance distribution in which the reflectance has a maximum value at a position where the amplitude envelope of the fundamental mode of an internal resonance light created within the two-dimensional photonic crystal.;  This design strengthens the fundamental mode while suppressing the second mode, thus enabling the laser oscillation in the fundamental mode to be selectively obtained, so that a single-wavelength laser light can be emitted.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) an active layer;
</P>
<P>
b) a two-dimensional photonic crystal provided on one side of the active layer; and
</P>
<P>
c) a reflector provided at least at a portion of a circumference of the two-dimensional photonic crystal, the reflector having a reflectance distribution in which a reflectance has a maximum value at a position where an amplitude envelope of a fundamental mode of an internal resonance light created within the two-dimensional photonic crystal has a maximum value.
</P>
<P>
2. The two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to claim 1, wherein the reflector is created by providing a member for reflecting the internal resonance light only at one or more sections of a line surrounding the two-dimensional photonic crystal, each section including a position where the amplitude envelope of the fundamental mode has a maximum value.
</P>
<P>
3. The two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to claim 1 or 2, wherein a portion of the reflector is located inside an outer edge of the two-dimensional photonic crystal.
</P>
<P>
4. The two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the two-dimensional photonic crystal has an outer edge that is at least partially curved at a position other than the position where the amplitude envelope of the fundamental mode has a maximum value.
</P>
<P>
5. The two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to one of claims 1 to 4, wherein:
</P>
<P>
the two-dimensional photonic crystal is a slab-shaped body in which a plurality of areas whose refractive index differs from that of the body are arranged in a square lattice pattern;
</P>
<P>
the reflector is provided along a rectangle surrounding the two-dimensional photonic crystal; and
</P>
<P>
the reflectance distribution has a maximum value at a central portion of each side of the rectangle.
</P>
<P>
6. The two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to one of claims I to 5, wherein:
</P>
<P>
the two-dimensional photonic crystal is created in a slab-shaped member;
</P>
<P>
the reflector includes a plurality of grooves parallel to an outer edge of the two-dimensional photonic crystal; and
</P>
<P>
the reflectance distribution is created by changing the number of the grooves.
</P>
<P>
7. A two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) an active layer;
</P>
<P>
b) a two-dimensional photonic crystal provided on one side of the active layer; and
</P>
<P>
c) a reflector provided at least at a portion of a circumference of the two-dimensional photonic crystal, the reflector being formed so that a change in a phase of light that occurs when the light is reflected by the reflector is greater than -0.5 and less than 0.5 .
</P>
<P>
8. A super-resolution laser beam generator, comprising:
</P>
<P>
the two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to claim 7; and
</P>
<P>
a focusing lens for converging a laser beam generated by the two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser to a diameter equal to or smaller than a diffraction limit.
</P>
<P>
9. An optical pickup, wherein the super-resolution laser beam generator according to claim 8 is provided as a light source.
</P>
<P>
10. A laser-processing apparatus, wherein the two-dimensional photonic crystal surface emitting laser light source according to claim 7 is provided as a light source for irradiating a workpiece with light.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1998420A4;US2009285255A1;US7936801B2;WO2007119273A1;JP2007258262A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
