<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR FORMING INTERPENETRATING NETWORKS OF DISTINCT MATERIALS AND DEVICES THEREFROM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1952446A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RINZLER ANDREW G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RINZLER, ANDREW G
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV FLORIDA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA RESEARCH FOUNDATION, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1952446
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060844482
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US45118
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050738462P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L31/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/18
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/26
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0352
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M4D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/42H
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/42H2B
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E10/50
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An electrical or electro-optical device (100) includes a first layer (110) having a first composition. The first composition includes a plurality of electrically connected particles. A second layer (130) has a second composition, the second composition including a plurality of electrically connected particles. A composite layer (120) is disposed between the first and second layer. The composite layer is an interpenetrated network of a third and a fourth composition, wherein the third composition is different from the fourth composition. A first electrically interconnected network extends from the first composition in the first layer (110) to the third composition throughout a thickness of the composite layer (120), and a second electrically interconnected network extends from the second composition in the second layer (130) to the fourth composition throughout the thickness of the composite layer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. An electrical or electro-optical device, comprising: a first layer comprising a first composition, said first composition comprising a plurality of electrically connected particles; a second layer comprising a second composition, said second composition comprising a plurality of electrically connected particles; a composite layer disposed between said first and said second layer, said composite layer comprising an interpenetrated network of a third and a fourth composition, said third composition being different from said fourth composition, wherein a first electrically interconnected network extends from said first composition in said first layer to said third composition throughout a thickness of said composite layer, and a second electrically interconnected network extends from said second composition in said second layer to said fourth composition throughout said thickness of said composite layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The device of claim 1, wherein at least one of said compositions comprises nanotubes, nanowires, or nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
3. The device of claim 2, wherein said first layer, said second layer, and said composite layer comprise said nanowires, wherein said nanowires are preferentially oriented to generally lie along a plane.
</P>
<P>
4. The device of claim 1, wherein at least one of said first, said second, and said composite layers are porous layers.
</P>
<P>
5. The device of claim 4, further comprising a polymeric continuous phase infiltrating said porous layer.
</P>
<P>
6. The device of claim 1, wherein a concentration of said third and said fourth composition in said composite layer is stepwise graded.
</P>
<P>
7. The device of claim 1, wherein said second composition is different from said first composition.
</P>
<P>
8. The device of claim 1, wherein said first composition and said third composition are the same and said second and said fourth composition are the same.
</P>
<P>
9. The device of claim 1, wherein one of said third and fourth composition comprises a p-type semiconductor and the other of said third and fourth composition comprises an n-type semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
10. The device of claim 1, wherein said device comprises a solar cell.
</P>
<P>
11. The device of claim 1, wherein said device comprises a light emitting diode (LED).
</P>
<P>
12. The device of claim 1, wherein said device comprises a multi-component heterojunction structure, wherein said first layer, said second layer, and said composite layer comprise different compositions.
</P>
<P>
13. The device of claim 12, wherein said composite layer either develops a built- in potential for charge separation for photovoltaic applications or comprises a light emitting device.
</P>
<P>
14. A method of forming a layer stack for an electronic or an electro-optical device, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing a porous membrane;
</P>
<P>
(b) dispersing a plurality of nanotubes, nanowires or nanoparticles of a first composition in a solution;
</P>
<P>
(c) applying said solution to said membrane, and
</P>
<P>
(d) removing said solution, wherein said nanotubes, nanowires or nanoparticles are forced onto a surface of said porous membrane to form a first composition comprising layer disposed on said membrane; repeating steps (b)-(d) using a plurality of nanotubes, nanowires or nanoparticles of a second and third composition, wherein composite layer comprising an interpenetrated network of said second and said third composition is formed on said first composition comprising layer, and repeating steps (b)-(d) using a plurality of nanotubes, nanowires or nanoparticles of a fourth composition to form a fourth composition comprising film layer formed on said composite layer.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14, wherein one of said second and third composition comprises ap-type semiconductor and the other of said second and third composition comprises an n-type semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 14, wherein said device includes a substrate, further comprising the steps of placing said layer stack on said substrate, and selectively removing said membrane.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 14, wherein said first, second and said composite layers are all porous layers.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 17, further comprising the step of infiltrating at least one of said porous layers with a polymeric material.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007062072A1;US2008236660A1;US8049106B2;KR20080075528A;JP2009516915A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
