<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
MANUFACTURING METHODS FOR NANOMATERIAL DISPERSION AND PRODUCTS THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1926691A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YADAV TAPESH [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YADAV, TAPESH
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NANOPRODUCTS CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NANOPRODUCTS CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1926691
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060851546
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-05-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US20794
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050157164
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-06-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01F3/12
</Class>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/14B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B20/00A
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Methods for manufacturing nanomaterial dispersions, such as nanomaterial concentrates, and related nanotechnology are provided. The nanomaterial concentrates provided can be more cheaply stored and transported compared to non-concentrate nanomaterial forms.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A composition of matter comprising
</P>
<P>
a concentrated dispersion of a nanomaterial and a solvent composition,
</P>
<P>
wherein the bulk density of the concentrated dispersion is at least three times higher than the bulk density of the nanomaterial in dry form,
</P>
<P>
wherein the concentrate requires less volume to store and transport over that required for dry nanomaterial, and
</P>
<P>
wherein the nanomaterial loading in the concentrated dispersion is at least 40% by weight.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition of matter of claim 1, wherein the nanomaterial is an oxide.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition of matter of claim 1, wherein the nanomaterial is a metal.
</P>
<P>
4. The composition of matter of claim 1, wherein the nanomaterial is a non-oxide.
</P>
<P>
5. The composition of matter of claim 1, wherein the solvent composition comprises an organic solvent.
</P>
<P>
6. The composition of matter of claim 1, wherein the solvent composition comprises an inorganic solvent.
</P>
<P>
7. The composition of matter of claim 1, wherein the nanomaterial loading in the concentrated dispersion is at least 60% by weight.
</P>
<P>
8. A product prepared using the composition of matter of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
9. A method for preparing a composition of matter comprising
</P>
<P>
providing a nanomaterial,
</P>
<P>
providing a solvent composition comprising one or more of a substance selected from the group consisting of organic solvents, inorganic solvents, aqueous solvents, monomers, polymers, solutions, oxygen comprising compositions, chalcogenides comprising compositions, boron comprising compositions, phosphorus comprising compositions, halogen comprising compositions, nitrogen comprising compositions, metal comprising compositions, carbon comprising compositions, molten metals and alloys and molten salts,
</P>
<P>
dispersing the nanomaterial in the solvent composition thereby forming a dispersion, and
</P>
<P>
wherein the solvent composition is selected such that the Hansen interface match index between the nanomaterial and the solvent composition is less than 20.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9 wherein the solvent composition comprises two or more substances selected from the group consisting of organic solvents, inorganic solvents, aqueous solvents, monomers, polymers, solutions, oxygen comprising compositions, chalcogenides comprising compositions, boron comprising compositions, phosphorus comprising compositions, halogen comprising compositions, nitrogen comprising compositions, metal comprising compositions, carbon comprising compositions, molten metals and alloys and molten salts.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9 wherein the d99 of the dispersion as measured by photocorrelation spectroscopy is less than 500 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 9 wherein the d99 of the dispersion as measured by photocorrelation spectroscopy is less than 250 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 9 wherein the d99 of the dispersion as measured by photocorrelation spectroscopy is less than 100 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 9 wherein the d99 of the dispersion as measured by photocorrelation spectroscopy is less than 50 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 9 wherein the nanomaterial is washed with a solvent prior to forming the dispersion.
</P>
<P>
16. A method for preparing a composition of matter comprising
</P>
<P>
providing a nanomaterial,
</P>
<P>
providing a solvent composition comprising one or more of a substance selected from the group consisting of water, methanol, ethanol, iso-propyl alcohol, octane, dodecane, heptane, hexane, acetone, gasoline, DOWANOL(R) solvents, glycols, glycerol, phenol, acetates, polyurethanes, acrylates, epoxies, aliphatic hydrocarbons, aromatic hydrocarbons, alcohols, aldehydes, ketones, ethers, acids, amines, quarternary compounds, alkalis, terpenols, liquids with boiling point greater than 400 K, UV curable liquids, plasma curable liquids, heat curable liquids, ionic liquids, molten polymers, molten metals, monomers, oils, silicones, ethylene glycol, diethylene glycol, ethanolamine, formic acid, acetonitrile, 1-propyl alcohol, acetic acid, 2-ethoxy ethanol, anhydrous isopropanol, DMSO, 1-butyl alcohol, tetrahydro furfuryl alcohol, n,n-dimethyl acetamide, diacetone alcohol, 2-methyl butanol, n-pentanol, acetone, 2-(2-butoxy ethoxy) ethanol, UCAR(R) Filmer IBT, cellosolve acetate, methotate, isophorone, methylethyl ketone, tetra hydrofuran, aniline, pyridine, methyl n-propyl ketone, UCAR(R) Ester EEP, UCAR(R) n-propyl propionate, primary amyl acetate, methyl isobutyl ketone, isobutyl acetate, UCAR(R) n-butyl propionate, n-butyl acetate, methyl isoamyl ketone, diisobutyl ketone, chloroform, 1,4 dioxane, trichloroethane, hydrochlorocarbons, hydrofluorocarbons, xylene, toluene, benzene, cyclohexane, hexane, carbon disulfide, carbon tetrachloride, methylene chloride, dimethylene chloride, n-butyl glycolate, glycolic acid, methyl glycolate, ethyl lactate, ethyl glycolate, ethylenediamine, butyrolactone, n-octanol, iso-octanol, gasoline, diesel, kerosene, jet fuel, m-cresol, phenol, biofluids, plant sap, alphahydroxy compounds, sea water, mineral oils, milk, fruit juices, plant-derived oils, and seed-derived oils or extracts,
</P>
<P>
dispersing the nanomaterial in the solvent composition thereby forming a dispersion, and
</P>
<P>
wherein the solvent composition is selected such that the Hansen interface match index between the nanomaterial and the solvent composition is less than 50.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2006016371A1;US7683098B2;WO2008030211A2;WO2008030211A3;RU2008102114A;RU2398621C2;KR20080050389A;CN101495218A;CA2612660A1;BRPI0612269A2;AU2006344096A1;AU2006344096B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
