<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
COATING METHOD OF METAL OXIDE SUPERFINE PARTICLES ON THE SURFACE OF METAL OXIDE AND COATING PRODUCED THEREFROM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1934384A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MYEONG WAN-JAE [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
LEE JOO-HYEONG [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
SONG KYU-HO [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
MYEONG, WAN-JAE
</Name>
<Name>
LEE, JOO-HYEONG
</Name>
<Name>
SONG, KYU-HO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HANWHA CHEMICAL CORP [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
HANWHA CHEMICAL CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1934384
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060798546
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-08-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006KR03374
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20050083801
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C23C22/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/10
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/626A16F
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628B2B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628B2D
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628B2H8
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628L
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628N
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628T
</Class>
<Class>
C04B41/00V
</Class>
<Class>
C04B41/45P
</Class>
<Class>
C04B41/81
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/06B
</Class>
<Class>
C23C18/02
</Class>
<Class>
C23C18/12C2D
</Class>
<Class>
C23C18/12J6D
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/36K2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed are a method of coating the surface of metal oxide with ultrafine metal oxide particles and a coating produced thereby. Specifically, the method of coating the surface of metal oxide with ultrafine metal oxide particles, according to this invention, includes i) bringing metal (Ml) oxide into contact with an aqueous solution of a metal (M2) salt to be applied thereon, and ii) continuously mixing and reacting the contacted metal oxide with water at a reaction temperature of 200~700 DEG C under pressure of 180~550 bar.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method of coating a surface of metal oxide with ultrafine metal oxide particles, comprising: i) bringing metal (Ml) oxide into contact with an aqueous solution of a metal (M2) salt to be applied thereon; and ii) continuously mixing and reacting the contacted metal oxide with water at a reaction temperature of 200~700[deg.]C under pressure of 180-550 bar.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1, further comprising adding a precipitant between the i) and the ii).
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 2, wherein the precipitant is ammonia water.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 1, wherein metal (Ml) of the metal (Ml) oxide is at least one selected from among Si, Al, Li, Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba, Y, Nb, La, Ti, Zr, Cr, Mo, W, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Ce, and Pr.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 1, wherein metal (M2) of the metal (M2) salt is at least one selected from among Si, Al, Sc, Ga, Li, Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba, Y, Nb, La, Ti, Zr, Cr,
</P>
<P>
Mo, W, Mn, Fe, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ir, Pt, Co, Ni, Cu, Ag, Zn, Cd, Ce, Pr, Nd, Sm, Eu, and Gd.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 1, wherein the metal (M2) salt is nitrate, oxalate, or citrate.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to claim 1, wherein the i) further comprises adding acrylic acid, carboxylic acid, amino acid, polymers or salts thereof, or mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to claim 1, wherein the ii) is performed using a continuous line mixer.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to claim 1, further comprising performing drying and calcination.
</P>
<P>
10. A coating, which is produced using the method of any one of claims 1 to 9 and has a structure of a core and a shell respectively comprising metal oxide and ultrafine metal oxide particles applied on a surface of the metal oxide, the metal oxide of the core having a particle size from 5 nm to 5 [mu]m, and the ultrafine metal oxide particles of the shell having a particle size from 1 nm to 100 nm.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1934384A4;EP1934384B1;WO2007029933A1;US2009226725A1;KR100691908B1;JP2009507751A;CN101258264A;CN101258264B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
