<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYMER COATED MICROPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1945271A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LEE GIL U [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SHANG HAO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHANG WON-SUK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LEE, GIL, U
</Name>
<Name>
SHANG, HAO
</Name>
<Name>
CHANG, WON-SUK
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MAGSENSE LIFE SCIENCES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MAGSENSE LIFE SCIENCES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1945271
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060851733
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US41475
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050729769P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K49/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K41/00M
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00U
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18R6
</Class>
<Class>
B01J13/12
</Class>
<Class>
B01J13/14
</Class>
<Class>
B01J2/06
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00E10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Methods for preparing uniformly sized microparticles, with an optional polymeric coating generally include: 1) providing nanoparticles, preferably having a size of between 1 nm and 100 nm;  2) adding a hydrophobic surface layer to the nanoparticles;  3) making a suspension of the hydrophobic nanoparticles and a polymerization initiator in an hydrophobic solvent;  4) dissolving a monomer in the hydrophobic solvent;  5) making an emulsion by dispersing droplets of the hydrophobic solvent in a continuous aqueous phase with an emulsifier;  6) sizing the first emulsion to provide a second emulsion of the same basic components but in which the droplets are substantially uniform and between 2 and 20 mum in size;  7) evaporating at least a substantial portion of the dispersed hydrophobic droplets to assemble nanoparticles to form microparticles suspended now in the aqueous phase;  8) optionally replacing the first surfactant with a second surfactant, which is preferably a polymerizable surfactant;  9) optionally adding a polymerizable monomer to the aqueous phase and allowing it to adsorb into the microparticle;  10) polymerizing the monomer(s) to provide a polymer layer on the microparticles;  and 11) functionalizing the polymer surface layer of the microparticles with one or more polymer, nanoparticle or biological macromolecular layers. In a related method the nanoparticles are provided with a hydrophilic surface layer, and the emulsion is made by dispersing the aqueous nanoparticles in a continuous hydrophobic phase. The microparticles have a polymeric coating and a magnetic core that comprises in excess of 50% of the particle&apos;s mass. The polymeric shell may contain one or more functional groups capable of forming chemical bonds useful in managing a variety of separations.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of preparing uniform microparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing starting nanoparticles having a hydrophobic surface and a particle diameter of between 1 and 100 nm;
</P>
<P>
(b) suspending said particles in an hydrophobic solvent to provide a suspension of the particles;
</P>
<P>
(c) mixing the suspension formed in step (b) with a aqueous phase in which the suspension is not miscible, thereby providing an emulsion of droplets of the suspension formed in step (b) dispersed in the aqueous phase;
</P>
<P>
(d) evaporating enough hydrophobic solvent from the emulsion to assemble microparticles from the nanoparticles, wherein after the evaporation the microparticles become suspended in the aqueous phase;
</P>
<P>
(e) providing a polymerizable monomer to the aqueous phase; and
</P>
<P>
(f) polymerizing the polymerizable monomer to provide a polymer layer on the microparticles.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 wherein said starting nanoparticles comprise a paramagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 wherein said starting nanoparticles comprise magnetite or maghemite.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1 wherein said starting nanoparticles comprise a material selected from the group consisting of Ni, Co, Mn, Sb, alumina, Cu, Ag, Au, Mg, and polymers.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 wherein said method further includes providing a polymerization initiator to the polymerizable monomer prior to polymerization.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 5 wherein said polymerization initiator is provided by adding polymerization initiator to the hydrophobic solvent prior to making emulsion.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 5 wherein said polymerization initiator comprises a ultraviolet light activated initiator.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 7 wherein said polymerization initiator comprises benzophenone.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1 wherein said method further includes providing a monomer soluble in hydrophobic solvent.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9 wherein the monomer soluble in hydrophobic solvent is provided by adding the monomer to the hydrophobic solvent prior to making emulsion.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10 wherein said monomer comprises styrene.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1 wherein said method further includes the step of sizing the emulsion formed in step (c) to provide an emulsion wherein at least 95% of the dispersed hydrophobic solvent droplets are sized between 2 and 10 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12 wherein said sizing step comprises passing the emulsion through a membrane.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13 wherein said membrane comprises pores having a size of 2 to 5 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 1 wherein said hydrophobic solvent and aqueous phase form an emulsion by being exposed to shear stress.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 15 wherein the aqueous medium is viscoelastic.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 wherein the aqueous medium contains 20-30% dextran.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 15 wherein the aqueous medium contains carboxymethylcellulose.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 15 wherein said shear stress is from 800 to 3500s&amp;lt;-1&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 1 wherein the liquid medium of step (b) is an aqueous phase comprising a first surfactant.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 20 wherein said first surfactant comprises SDS.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 1 wherein said method includes the step of washing the assembled particles of step (d) to replace the first surfactant with a second surfactant.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 1 wherein said monomer mixture is mixed with sodium hydroxide solution to adjust the pH to 2.8-3.3.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 1 wherein said method further includes the step of functionalizing the polymer layer of the microparticles.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 24 wherein said functionalizing comprises providing biological receptors to the polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 25 wherein said biological receptors are linked to the polymer layer through a covalent bond to the carboxylic acids by reacting with 1-ethyl-3-(3-dimethylaminopropyl)-carbodiimide hydrochloride (EDAC).
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 24 wherein said functionalizing comprises providing nanoparticles to the polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 27 wherein said nanoparticles are gold nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
29. A method of preparing uniform microparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) providing starting nanoparticles having either a hydrophobic surface or a hydrophilic surface, wherein said nanoparticles have a particle diameter of between 1 and 100 nm;
</P>
<P>
(b) suspending said particles in a first fluid phase to provide a suspension of the particles in said first fluid phase, wherein said first fluid phase comprises a hydrophobic solvent if the particles are hydrophobic, and wherein said first fluid phase comprises a hydrophilic solvent if the particles are hydrophilic;
</P>
<P>
(c) mixing the suspension formed in step (b) with a second fluid phase in which the first fluid phase is not miscible, thereby providing an emulsion of droplets of the suspension formed in step (b) dispersed in the second fluid phase, wherein said second fluid phase comprises an aqueous phase if the first fluid phase comprises hydrophobic particles suspended in a hydrophobic solvent, and wherein said second fluid phase comprises an organic phase if the first fluid phase comprises hydrophilic particles suspended in a hydrophilic solvent;
</P>
<P>
(d) evaporating enough of the hydrophobic or hydrophilic solvent from the emulsion to self-assemble nanoparticles to form microparticles suspended now in the second fluid phase;
</P>
<P>
(e) providing a polymerizable monomer to the second fluid phase; and
</P>
<P>
(f) polymerizing the polymerizable monomer to provide a polymer layer on the microparticles.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 29 wherein said first fluid phase comprises a hydrophobic solvent and wherein said second fluid phase comprises an aqueous phase.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 29 wherein said first fluid phase comprises a hydrophilic solvent and wherein said second fluid phase comprises an organic phase.
</P>
<P>
32. A particle made by the process of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
33. A plurality of particles made by the process of claim 1, wherein said plurality of particles comprises particles having a particle size of between 0.01 [mu]m and 10 [mu]m, said particles comprising a paramagnetic core and a polymeric shell, said paramagnetic core comprising at least 70% of the weight of the particle, and wherein the plurality of particles has a coefficient of size variance of less than 40%.
</P>
<P>
34. A particulate composition comprising a plurality of particles, wherein each particle in said plurality has a particle size of between 0.01 [mu]m and 10 [mu]m, and wherein each particle in said plurality comprises a paramagnetic core and a polymeric shell, wherein said paramagnetic core comprises at least 70% of the weight of the particle, and wherein the plurality of particles has a coefficient of size variance of less than 40%.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007172426A1;WO2008048271A2;WO2008048271A3
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
