<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Method of making titanium dioxide particles
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1990315A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TORARDI CARMINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI, CARMINE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E.I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1990315
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080251632
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070800958
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053D
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The disclosure provides a process for preparing nanocrystalline titanium dioxide, in particular rutile nanocrystalline titanium dioxide, comprising: (a) precipitating a mixture comprising hydrated titanium oxide and a separable filtering agent;  (b) filtering the precipitated mixture to form a filter cake comprising the precipitated hydrated titanium dioxide and a separable filtering agent, (c) calcining the precipitated hydrated titanium oxide and separable filtering agent at a temperature of greater than about 300 DEG C;  and (d) removing the separable filtering agent thereby recovering titanium dioxide particles.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for preparing nanocrystalline titanium dioxide comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) precipitating a mixture comprising hydrated titanium oxide and a separable filtering agent;
</P>
<P>
(b) filtering the precipitated mixture to form a filter cake comprising the precipitated hydrated titanium oxide and the separable filtering agent,
</P>
<P>
(c) calcining the precipitated hydrated titanium oxide and separable filtering agent at a temperature of greater than about 300 deg. C to form a mixture comprising titanium dioxide and the separable filtering agent; and
</P>
<P>
(d) removing the separable filtering agent to recover titanium dioxide particles.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture comprising hydrated titanium oxide and the separable filtering agent is prepared by reacting titanium tetrachloride or titanium oxychloride with MOH wherein M is selected from the group consisting of NH4, Group 1 metals, and mixtures thereof, in the presence of a solvent.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 2 wherein the Group 1 metals are selected from the group consisting of Na, K, Li and Rb.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of any preceding claim wherein the solvent is selected from the group consisting of water, water containing metal halides, water containing ammonium halides, neat alcohols, alcohols containing metal halides and alcohols containing ammonium halides, aldehydes, ketones, nitriles, ethers, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 4 wherein the alcohols are selected from the group of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, iso-propanol, butyl alcohol isomers, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of any preceding claim wherein the separable filtering agent is MCI wherein M is selected from the group consisting of NH4, Group 1 metals, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of any preceding claim wherein the Group 1 metals are selected from the group consisting of Na, K, Li and Rb.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 2 wherein the reaction takes place at a pH of about 1 to about 3.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of any preceding claim wherein the recovered titanium dioxide particles have a surface area of about 10 to about 90 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; /g.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of any preceding claim wherein the titanium dioxide particles are predominantly rutile.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of any preceding claim wherein the recovered titanium dioxide particles comprise primary particles.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 9 wherein the calcining temperature is above about 300 deg. C and below that at which the primary particle size exceeds about 100 nm
</P>
<P>
13. The process of any preceding claim wherein steps (c) and (d) occur simultaneously.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of claim 13 wherein the separable filtering agent is NH4Cl.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 12 wherein the separable filtering agent is removed by washing with water or a solution comprising water.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 12 wherein the titanium dioxide particles have a primary particle size of about 10-100 nm.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 16 wherein the primary particle size is about 15-50 nm.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008279760A1;US7858066B2;AU2008201928A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
