<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS AND APPARATUS FOR PRODUCING SUSPENSIONS OF SOLID MATTER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1948567A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
VIRTANEN PENTTI [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
VIRTANEN, PENTTI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NORDKALK OYJ ABP [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
NORDKALK OYJ ABP
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1948567
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060820061
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006FI00380
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
FI20050001182
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F11/18
</Class>
<Class>
C04B14/28
</Class>
<Class>
C01F
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F11/18A
</Class>
<Class>
C01F11/18B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Method for producing nanosized calcium hydroxide crystals or particles, according to which method the calcium oxide-bearing initial material is brought into contact with carbon dioxide in the aqueous phase. Calcium carbonate crystals or particles are produced in a mixture, the pH of which is below (7). Using the present invention, it is possible to combine the two stages of producing CaCO3 particles into one entity, in which case the overall processing time is shortened and the use of external energy is minimized.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of producing calcium carbonate crystals or particles, according to which method the calcium oxide-bearing initial material is brought in the aqueous phase into contact with carbon oxide, characterized in that the calcium carbonate crystals or particles are produced in a mixture, the pH of which is below 7, in which case the component which keeps the mixture acidic is calcium hydrogen carbonate, Ca(HCOs)2.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to Claim 1, characterized in that the pH of the calcium carbonate product mixture is 5.5-6.8, especially 5.8-6.5.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to Claim ^characterized in that the calcium hydrogen carbonate is produced continuously in the mixture by bringing CO2 gas into the mixture.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the quantity of the calcium carbonate crystals and particles and the time used for mixing them in the mixture are used to adjust their sizes.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterizedin that the quantity of the calcium hydroxide mixture which is brought into the process is the same as the slightly acidic CaCO3 mixture which is removed from the process.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the carbonation is carried out using sufficient quantity of Ca(HCO3)2 to prevent the pH value of the mixture from exceeding 7, preferably at maximum 6.8.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the calcium hydroxide crystals are carbonated in a reactor, in which a mixture having a slightly acidic pH value circulates, the solids percentage of which mixture determines the size of the CaCO3 particles.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the slightly acidic mixture is continuously removed from the reactor while a correspondingly equal quantity of Ca(OH)2 mixture is continuously fed into the reactor.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to Claim 8, characterized in that the pH value of the CaCO3 mixture to be removed is measured continuously and the quantity of the CaCO3 mixture to be removed is set so that the pH value of the mixture remains slightly acidic or essentially unchanged.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that overpressure, preferably 1.5-11 bar absolute pressure, is used in the process.
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that overpressure, preferably 1.5-11 bar absolute pressure, is used in the hydration of the calcium oxide.
</P>
<P>
12. The method according to Claim 11, characterized in that the hydration of the calcium hydroxide is carried out continuously, in which case the temperature of the hydration process is kept constant by adjusting the temperature of the hydration water.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to Claim 11 or 12, characterized in that the solids percentage of the calcium hydroxide suspension, which percentage is generated in the hydration, is adjusted by feeding cooling water into it, before the suspension is brought into contact with the carbon dioxide at the carbonation stage.
</P>
<P>
14. The method according to Claim 11-13, characterized in that the pressure in the hydration process is generated with CO2 gas.
</P>
<P>
15. The method according to any of Claims 11-14, characterized in that the hydration water comprises 1-16 g/1 of calcium hydrogen carbonate.
</P>
<P>
16. An apparatus for producing calcium carbonate which comprises
</P>
<P>
- a source of carbon dioxide and
</P>
<P>
- a carbonation unit for calcium hydroxide, which is equipped with an input nozzle for aqueous suspension of calcium oxide, an input nozzle for carbon dioxide which is connected to the carbon dioxide source, and an outlet nozzle for the aqueous suspension of the calcium carbonate which is generated m the carbonation of calcium oxide, characterized in that
</P>
<P>
- the carbonation unit is equipped with a recirculation pipe which is connected to the outlet nozzle for the calcium carbonate, through which pipe at least part of the product from the reactor can be recirculated in order to keep the pH value of the aqueous suspension at a value which is lower than 7, during the carbonation.
</P>
<P>
17. The apparatus according to Claim 16, characterized in that the carbonation unit comprises a closed reactor vessel, in which the carbonation reaction can be carried out at overpressure.
</P>
<P>
18. The apparatus according to Claim 16 or 17, characterized in that the carbonation unit comprises a wing mixer or a wing pump.
</P>
<P>
19. The apparatus according to any of Claims 16-18, characterized in that it is possible to arrange an internal circulation in the carbonation unit, and that the quantity of the product which is recirculated through it is 5-20 fold the hydrated calcium oxide which is fed into the carbonation unit.
</P>
<P>
20. The apparatus according to any of Claims 16-19, characterized in that the number of carbonation units is 1-10 and they are arranged in series or parallel to each other.
</P>
<P>
21. The apparatus according to any of Claims 16-20, c h a r a c t e r i z e d in that the apparatus comprises, arranged in series, a hydration unit for calcium oxide, a carbonation unit for hydrated calcium and a sedimentation unit, in which case at least the hydration unit and the carbonation unit comprise a closed space, in which it is possible to carry out the hydration and the carbonation at overpressure.
</P>
<P>
22. The apparatus according to any of Claims 16-21, characterized in that it is possible to generate overpressure in the carbonation unit, preferably approximately 1.5-11 bar absolute pressure.
</P>
<P>
23. The apparatus according to Claim 21 or 22, characterized in that it is possible to generate overpressure in the hydration unit, preferably approximately 1.5-11 bar absolute pressure.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007057509A1;US2009081112A1;FI122343B1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
