<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PLASMA COATING A NANOCOMPOSITE OBJECT
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1941072A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GARCES JUAN M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WEIKART CHRISTOPHER M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GARCES, JUAN, M
</Name>
<Name>
WEIKART, CHRISTOPHER, M
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DOW GLOBAL TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DOW GLOBAL TECHNOLOGIES INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1941072
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060825021
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-19
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US36496
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-19
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050718773P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B65D1/02
</Class>
<Class>
B65D23/02
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/26
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/40
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B05D1/62
</Class>
<Class>
B65D23/08B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/04D
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/40B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process for preparing a coating on an object by plasma polymerizing a first compound under conditions to deposit a layer onto the object, the object comprising a nanocomposite polymer. In addition, the object so coated.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A process for preparing a coating on an object, comprising the step of: plasma polymerizing a first
</P>
<P>
&amp;lt; compound under conditions to deposit a layer onto the object, the object comprising a nanocomposite polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of Claim 1, wherein the nanocomposite polymer comprises polypropylene.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of any of Claims 1 or 2 , wherein the layer is an amorphous carbon layer.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of any of Claims 1 or 2 , wherein the first compound is a first organosilicon compound and the layer is a polyorganosiloxane layer.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of any of Claims 1 or 2, wherein the first compound is a first organosilicon compound and the layer is a silicon oxide layer.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of Claim 4, further comprising the step of plasma polymerizing a second organosilicon compound, which second organosilicon compound may be the same as or different from the first organosilicon compound, to produce a silicon oxide layer on the polyorganosiloxane layer.
</P>
<P>
7. An object coated by plasma polymerizing a first compound under conditions to deposit a layer onto the object, the object comprising a nanocomposite polymer.
</P>
<P>
8. The object of Claim 7, wherein the nanocomposite polymer comprises polypropylene.
</P>
<P>
9. The object of any of Claims 7 or 8 , wherein the layer is an amorphous carbon layer.
</P>
<P>
10. The object of any of Claims 7 or 8, wherein the first compound is an organosilicon compound and the layer is a polyorganosiloxane layer.
</P>
<P>
11. The object of any of Claims 7 or 8 , wherein the first compound is an organosilicon compound and the layer is a silicon oxide layer.
</P>
<P>
12. The object of Claim 10, further comprising a silicon oxide layer on the polyorganosiloxane layer, the silicon oxide layer formed by plasma polymerizing a second organosilicon compound, which second organosilicon compound may be the same as or different from the first organosilicon compound, to produce the silicon oxide layer on the polyorganosiloxane layer.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007035741A2;WO2007035741A3;US2008268252A1;CA2622429A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
