<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
BEAD BASED ASSAYS USING A LIQUID CRYSTAL REPORTER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1971691A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ABBOTT NICHOLAS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MURPHY CHRISTOPHER [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ISREAL BARBARA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GHANTA JYOTHI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SOLTANINASSAB SYRUS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ABBOTT, NICHOLAS
</Name>
<Name>
MURPHY, CHRISTOPHER
</Name>
<Name>
ISREAL, BARBARA
</Name>
<Name>
GHANTA, JYOTHI
</Name>
<Name>
SOLTANINASSAB, SYRUS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
PLATYPUS TECHNOLOGIES LLC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PLATYPUS TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1971691
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060733654
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-01-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US00688
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09K19/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09K19/52
</Class>
<Class>
C12P19/12
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/13
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/542
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00E10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to the field of detection of analytes, and in particular to detection of viruses, cells, bacteria, lipid-membrane containing organisms, proteins, nucleic acids, carbohydrates and other biomolecules, organic molecules and inorganic molecules using a liquid crystal assay format.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A system comprising: a) magnetic beads functionalized with a recognition moiety; b) a substrate that orients liquids crystals.
</P>
<P>
2. The system of Claim 1 , further comprising a magnet.
</P>
<P>
3. The system of Claim 2, further comprising a tube and a pump, wherein said pump is fluidically connected to said tube and said tube is positioned to be exposed to said magnetic field of said magnet.
</P>
<P>
4. The system of Claim 3, wherein said tube has an inner surface with a diameter so that the surface tension energy of a fluid within the tube is larger than the surface energy of the tube so that a pressure gradient between the two ends of the tube induces movement of the fluid plugs inside the tube without wetting said inner surface.
</P>
<P>
5. The system of Claim 2, wherein said magnet is selected from the group consisting of a permanent magnet and electric magnet.
</P>
<P>
6. The system of Claim 3, wherein said tube is movable with respect to said magnet.
</P>
<P>
7. The system of Claim 6, wherein said tube is rotatable.
</P>
<P>
8. The system of Claim 3, wherein said magnetic beads are located in said tube so as to be attractable by said magnet.
</P>
<P>
. ii /&apos;&amp;lt;-&amp;gt; U a U to / it to
</P>
<P>
9. The system of Claim 1, wherein said substrate is selected from the group consisting of a polyimide coated substrate, an anisotropic gold substrate, a rubbed substrate.
</P>
<P>
10. The system of Claim 1, wherein said substrate comprises microfluidic channels that orient liquid crystals.
</P>
<P>
11. The system of Claim 1 , wherein said substrate comprises PDMS. .
</P>
<P>
12. The system of Claim 1, wherein said tube is made from a material selected from the group consisting of glass and plastic.
</P>
<P>
13. The system of Claim 1 , further comprising a stamp.
</P>
<P>
14. The system of Claim 1 , further comprising mesogens.
</P>
<P>
15. The system of Claim 14, wherein said mesogens are selected from the group consisting of 4-cyano-4&apos;-pentylbiphenyl, N-(4methoxybenzylidene)-4-butlyaniline and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The system of Claim 1, wherein said recognition moiety is selected from the group consisting of a protein, peptide, polypeptide, nucleic acid, carbohydrate and organic compounds.
</P>
<P>
17. The system of Claim 1 , wherein said Analyte is selected from the group consisting of a protein, peptide, polypeptide, nucleic acid, carbohydrate and organic compounds.
</P>
<P>
18. A method comprising : 1) providing , &quot;,
</P>
<P>
[&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;&quot;-&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt;&apos; Iin,,: ii / u :;:::i[iota] U 11&quot; ,/ H.,.[iota]i il.J ifcn &amp;lt;[beta]&amp;gt; o a) magnetic beads functionalized with a recognition moiety that binds an analyte; b) a substrate that orients liquid crystals; c) a sample suspected of containing an analyte; 5 d) a magnet; and e) mesogens;
</P>
<P>
2) contacting said magnetic beads with said sample under conditions such that said analate binds to said recognition moiety;
</P>
<P>
3) attracting said beads with said magnet; 10 4) washing said magnetic beads;
</P>
<P>
5) eluting said analyte from said beads onto to said substrate; and
</P>
<P>
6) contacting said substrate with said mesogens under conditions such that the presence of said Analyte on said substrate can be detected.
</P>
<P>
15 19. A kit comprising : a) magnetic beads functionalized with a recognition moiety; b) a substrate that orients liquids crystals.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007081326A2;WO2007081326A3;AU2006335329A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
