<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Extreme ultraviolet light source device and extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1976344A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HOSOKAI TOMONAO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HORIOKA KAZUHIKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MIZOKOSHI HIROSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YOKOYAMA TAKUMA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SEKI KYOHEI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HOSOKAI, TOMONAO
</Name>
<Name>
HORIOKA, KAZUHIKO
</Name>
<Name>
MIZOKOSHI, HIROSHI
</Name>
<Name>
YOKOYAMA, TAKUMA
</Name>
<Name>
SEKI, KYOHEI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOKYO INST TECH [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
USHIO ELECTRIC INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TOKYO INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
<Name>
USHIO DENKI KABUSHIKI KAISHA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1976344
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080005656
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070084595
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070257439
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H05G2/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/70B6
</Class>
<Class>
H05G2/00P2
</Class>
<Class>
H05G2/00P6
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
High temperature plasma raw material (21) is gasified by irradiation with a first energy beam (23). When the gasified raw material reaches the discharge region, pulsed power is applied between the electrodes (11, 12) and a second energy beam (24) irradiates. In this manner, the plasma is heated and excited and an EUV emission occurs. The emitted EUV emission is collected and extracted by EUV collector optics. Because of irradiation by the first and second energy beams (23, 24), a special distribution of high temperature plasma raw material density can be set to a specified distribution and demarcation of the position of the discharge channel can be set. Moreover, it is possible to lengthen pulses of extreme ultraviolet emission by supplying raw material gas of which the ion density in the discharge path is nearly the same as the ion density under EUV radiation emission conditions.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An extreme ultraviolet light source device that comprises
</P>
<P>
a vessel having a discharge region,
</P>
<P>
a raw material supply means for supplying liquid or solid raw materials that will emit extreme ultraviolet radiation to a space other than the discharge region and from which gasified raw material can reach the discharge region,,
</P>
<P>
a first energy beam irradiation means for gasifying the raw material by irradiating the raw material with a first energy beam directed toward the raw material supplied to said space from which the gasified raw material can reach the discharge region,
</P>
<P>
a pair of electrodes separated by a specified gap for heating and exciting the gasified raw material by discharge within said discharge region of the vessel and for generating a high temperature plasma,
</P>
<P>
a pulsed power supply means for supplying pulsed power to the electrodes,
</P>
<P>
a second energy beam irradiation means for initiating discharge in the discharge region and for demarcating a discharge path in a specified position of the discharge region by irradiating a second energy beam between the electrodes on which power is applied,
</P>
<P>
a collector optical means for collecting extreme ultraviolet radiation emitted from high temperature plasma generated by discharge in the discharge region of the pair of electrodes, and
</P>
<P>
an extreme ultraviolet radiation extraction area in which the collected extreme ultraviolet radiation is extracted.
</P>
<P>
2. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 1, wherein the first energy beam irradiation means and the second energy beam irradiation means each have means for an operational timing set so that the discharge current of the discharge generated in the discharge region is at or above a specified threshold value when at least part of the gasified raw material having a specified spatial density distribution reaches the discharge region.
</P>
<P>
3. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 1 or 2, wherein the raw material supply means is adapted to supply the raw material by dropping it in droplet form in a gravitational direction.
</P>
<P>
4. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 1 or 2, wherein the raw material supply means is adapted to put the raw material in wire form and continually move the raw material wire.
</P>
<P>
5. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 1 or 2, wherein the raw material supply means has a raw material supply disk, and is adapted to supply the raw material by putting the raw material in liquid form, supplying the liquid raw material to the raw material supply disk, and rotating the raw material supply disk to which the liquid raw material has been supplied to move the supplied portion of liquid raw material on the raw material supply disk to an irradiation position of the energy beam.
</P>
<P>
6. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 1 or 2, wherein the raw material supply means has a capillary, and is adapted to supply the raw material by putting the raw material in liquid form and supplying the liquid raw material to the irradiation position of the energy beam by way of the capillary.
</P>
<P>
7. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 1 or 2, wherein a tubular nozzle is fitted to an energy beam for raw material irradiation position, and wherein at least part of the gasified raw material is sprayed by the tubular nozzle.
</P>
<P>
8. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 7, wherein a constriction is provided within the tubular nozzle.
</P>
<P>
9. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in any one of claims 1 to 8, further comprising a magnetic field impression means that applies a magnetic field to the discharge region that is roughly parallel to a direction of discharge generated between the pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
10. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein the electrodes are disk-shaped electrodes and are driven to rotate so that the discharge generation position on the electrode surface changes.
</P>
<P>
11. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 10, wherein the disk-shaped electrodes are placed so that edge portions on the periphery of the electrodes are separated by a specified gap.
</P>
<P>
12. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein the energy beam irradiation means are lasers.
</P>
<P>
13. An extreme ultraviolet light source device that comprises
</P>
<P>
a vessel,
</P>
<P>
a raw material supply means that supplies liquid or solid raw materials so that extreme ultraviolet radiation will be emitted within the vessel,
</P>
<P>
a first energy beam irradiation means that gasifies the raw material by irradiating the raw material with a first energy beam,
</P>
<P>
a pair of electrodes separated by a specified gap to heat and excite the gasified raw material by discharge in a discharge region between the electrodes within the vessel and to generate a high temperature plasma,
</P>
<P>
a pulsed power supply means to supply pulsed power of 1 s or more to the electrodes,
</P>
<P>
a collector optical means that collects extreme ultraviolet radiation emitted from high temperature plasma generated by discharge in the discharge region of the pair of electrodes,
</P>
<P>
and
</P>
<P>
an extreme ultraviolet radiation extraction area that extracts the collected extreme ultraviolet radiation, and
</P>
<P>
a second energy beam irradiation means that initiates discharge in the discharge region and demarcates the discharge path in a specified position of the discharge region by irradiating a second energy beam between the electrodes to which power is applied,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first energy beam irradiation means irradiates a first energy beam toward raw material supplied to a space other than the discharge region from which the gasified raw material can reach the discharge region, and
</P>
<P>
wherein, after the discharge path is demarcated between the electrodes by the second energy beam irradiation means, raw material gas, having an ion density in the discharge path that is nearly the same as the ion density under extreme ultraviolet radiation emission conditions, is supplied to the discharge path.
</P>
<P>
14. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 13, wherein the first energy beam irradiation means and the second energy beam irradiation means each have means for an operational timing set so that the discharge current of the discharge generated in the discharge region is at or above a specified threshold value when at least part of the gasified raw material having a specified spatial density distribution reaches the discharge region.
</P>
<P>
15. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 13 or 14, wherein the raw material supply means is adapted to supply the raw material by dropping it in droplet form in a gravitational direction.
</P>
<P>
16. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 13 or 14, wherein the raw material supply means is adapted to put the raw material in wire form and continually move the raw material wire.
</P>
<P>
17. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 13 or 14, wherein the raw material supply means has a raw material supply disk, and is adapted to supply the raw material by putting the raw material in liquid form, supplying the liquid raw material to the raw material supply disk, and rotating the raw material supply disk to which the liquid raw material has been supplied to move the supplied portion of liquid raw material on the raw material supply disk to an irradiation position of the energy beam.
</P>
<P>
18. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 13 or 14, wherein the raw material supply means has a capillary, and is adapted to supply the raw material by putting the raw material in liquid form and supplying the liquid raw material to the irradiation position of the energy beam by way of the capillary.
</P>
<P>
19. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 13 or 14, wherein a tubular nozzle is fitted to an energy beam for raw material irradiation position, and wherein at least part of the gasified raw material is sprayed by the tubular nozzle.
</P>
<P>
20. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 19, wherein a constriction is provided within the tubular nozzle.
</P>
<P>
21. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in any one of claims 13 to 20, further comprising a magnetic field impression means that applies a magnetic field to the discharge region that is roughly parallel to a direction of discharge generated between the pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
22. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in any one of claims 13 to 21, wherein the electrodes are disk-shaped electrodes and are driven to rotate so that the discharge generation position on the electrode surface changes.
</P>
<P>
23. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in claim 22, wherein the disk-shaped electrodes are placed so that edge portions on the periphery of the electrodes are separated by a specified gap.
</P>
<P>
24. An extreme ultraviolet light source device as described in any one of claims 13 to 23, wherein the energy beam irradiation means are lasers.
</P>
<P>
25. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method that generates extreme ultraviolet radiation by using a first energy beam to irradiate and gasify a liquid or solid raw material supplied to a discharge region between a pair of electrodes within a vessel for the emission of extreme ultraviolet radiation, and heating and exciting the gasified raw material by generating a high temperature plasma with a discharge from the pair of electrodes, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
irradiating the first energy beam toward raw material supplied to a space, other than the discharge region, from which the gasified raw material can reach the discharge region,
</P>
<P>
irradiating the discharge region with a second energy beam so as to initiate discharge in the discharge region due to the paired electrodes, and so as to demarcate a discharge path in a specified position in the discharge region.
</P>
<P>
26. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method as described in claim 25, wherein the first energy beam and the second energy beam each have their irradiation timing set so that the discharge current of the discharge generated in the discharge region is at or above a specified threshold value when at least part of the gasified raw material having a specified spatial density distribution reaches the discharge region.
</P>
<P>
27. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method as described in claim 26, wherein time data on the start of discharge and time data on when the discharge current reaches the specified threshold value is acquired, and the irradiation timing of the first energy beam and of the second energy beam is modified on the basis of both of said time data.
</P>
<P>
28. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method as described in claim 27, wherein the first energy beam irradiates the raw material once prior to irradiation with the first energy beam and the second energy beam on the basis of said time data.
</P>
<P>
29. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method that generates extreme ultraviolet radiation by using a first energy beam to irradiate and gasify liquid or solid raw material supplied to a discharge region between a pair of electrodes within a vessel for the emission of extreme ultraviolet radiation, and heating and exciting the gasified raw material and generating a high temperature plasma with a discharge from the pair of electrodes, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
irradiating the first energy beam toward raw material supplied to a space, other than the discharge region, from which the gasified raw material can reach the discharge region,
</P>
<P>
irradiating the discharge region with a second energy beam so as to initiate discharge in the discharge region due to the paired electrodes, and so as to demarcate a discharge path in a specified position in the discharge region,
</P>
<P>
after the discharge path is demarcated between the electrodes, supplying raw material gas to the discharge path of which the ion density in the discharge path is nearly the same as the ion density under extreme ultraviolet radiation emission conditions, and
</P>
<P>
heating the raw material gas by the discharge to a temperature that fulfills conditions for extreme ultraviolet radiation emission and producing extreme ultraviolet radiation continuously for at least 200 ns.
</P>
<P>
30. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method as described in claim 29, wherein the first energy beam and the second energy beam each have their irradiation timing set so that the discharge current of the discharge generated in the discharge region is at or above a specified threshold value when at least part of the gasified raw material having a specified spatial density distribution reaches the discharge region.
</P>
<P>
31. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method as described in claim 30, wherein time data on the start of discharge and time data on when the discharge current reaches the specified threshold value is acquired, and the irradiation timing of the first energy beam and of the second energy beam is modified on the basis of both of said time data.
</P>
<P>
32. An extreme ultraviolet radiation generating method as described in claim 31, wherein the first energy beam irradiates the raw material once prior to irradiation with the first energy beam and the second energy beam on the basis of said time data.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1976344A3;EP1976344B1;US2008237501A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
