<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Superlattice strain relief layer for semiconductor devices
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1990841A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KNEISSL MICHAEL A [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
YANG ZHIHONG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WONG WILLIAM S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TEEPE MARK R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KNOLLENBERG CLIFFORD F [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KNEISSL, MICHAEL A
</Name>
<Name>
YANG, ZHIHONG
</Name>
<Name>
WONG, WILLIAM S
</Name>
<Name>
TEEPE, MARK R
</Name>
<Name>
KNOLLENBERG, CLIFFORD F
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
PALO ALTO RES CT INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PALO ALTO RESEARCH CENTER INCORPORATED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1990841
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080014020
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060123849
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050736362P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060356769
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L21/20
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/32
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4A1J
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4B1B1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4B5L3A
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1B1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/32
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A semiconductor light emitting diode structure of a type formed on a substrate is provided, wherein said substrate is removed and said semiconductor light emitting diode is bonded to a heat sink structure. The structure further comprises first and second index guiding layers and a multiple quantum well heterostructure of a composition including at least 25% aluminum, formed between said first and second index guiding layers, wherein said multiple quantum well heterostructure is substantially free from structural cracks.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A semiconductor light emitting diode structure of a type formed on a substrate, wherein said substrate is removed and said semiconductor light emitting diode is bonded to a heat sink structure, comprising:
</P>
<P>
first and second index guiding layers; and
</P>
<P>
a multiple quantum well heterostructure of a composition including at least 25% aluminum, formed between said first and second index guiding layers;
</P>
<P>
wherein said multiple quantum well heterostructure is substantially free from structural cracks.
</P>
<P>
2. The semiconductor light emitting diode structure of claim 1, wherein said structure is capable of emitting light at a wavelength of approximately 325 nm.
</P>
<P>
3. A semiconductor light emitting diode structure of a type formed on a substrate, wherein said substrate is removed and said semiconductor light emitting diode is bonded to a heat sink structure, wherein the structure comprises:
</P>
<P>
first and second index guiding layers; and
</P>
<P>
a multiple quantum well heterostructure of composition InwGaxAlyNz, where w+x+y+z = 1, and where y 0.35, formed between said first and second index guiding layers;
</P>
<P>
wherein said multiple quantum well heterostructure is substantially free from structural cracks.
</P>
<P>
4. The semiconductor light emitting diode structure of claim 3, wherein said structure is capable of emitting light at a wavelength of approximately 325 nm.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1990841A3;EP1786044A1;JP2007142397A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
