<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
AQUEOUS SUSPENSION BASED ON HYDRAULIC BINDER AND A PROCESS FOR THE PRODUCTION THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1954644A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
VIRTANEN PENTTI [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
VIRTANEN, PENTTI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NORDKALK OYJ ABP [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
NORDKALK OYJ ABP
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1954644
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060820062
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006FI00381
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
FI20050001183
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F11/18
</Class>
<Class>
C04B14/28
</Class>
<Class>
C04B28/02
</Class>
<Class>
C04B28/04
</Class>
<Class>
C04B40/00
</Class>
<Class>
C04B
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F11/18B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B28/02
</Class>
<Class>
C04B28/04
</Class>
<Class>
C04B40/00D4
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Method for producing an aqueous suspension, which is based on a hydraulic binder, and a hardened binder product. According to the invention, a composition of blending agents is added in the aqueous phase into the binder, which composition comprises calcium carbonate particles having an average particle size of 2-200 nm, in order to generate an aqueous suspension and, if needed, mineral fillers are added into this suspension, in order to produce a hardening plaster or concrete mixture. Besides calcium carbonate, the composition of blending agents can comprise calcium hydrogen carbonate and meta-kaolin sinter, too. By using the present invention, it is possible to improve the properties of products which are bound by hydraulic binders;  with the described combination of blending agents it is possible to affect for instance the early strength, the frost resistance, the phenomenon of bleading, the plasticizing, the size of the transition zone and the durability of concrete or plaster, and to reduce the quantity of the hydraulic binder.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of producing an aqueous suspension which is based on a hydraulic binder characterized in that the aqueous suspension of the binder is mixed with such a water- containing composition of blending agents which comprises particles of precipitated calcium carbonate having an average particle size of 2-1000 nm, and calcium hydrogen carbonatej and the pH value of the aqueous phase of which is below 7.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to Claim 1, characterized in that the composition of blending agents comprises calcium carbonate particles having an average particle size of approximately
</P>
<P>
10-200 nm.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to Claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the pH of the aqueous phase of the composition of blending agents is 5.5-6.5.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that meta- kaolin sinter particles, the quantity of which is after the addition 4-30 weight % of the quantity of binder, are added into the aqueous suspension of the binder.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to Claim 4, characterized in that the average particle size of the meta-kaolin sinter particles is at maximum approximately 100 [mu]m, preferably 90 % of the particles are smaller than 60 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to Claim 4 or 5, characterized in that the density of the meta- kaolin sinter particles is approximately 0.6-1.4 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; and in that they comprise 5-70 weight %, preferably 20-40 weight % of meta-kaolin.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that plasticizer is added into the aqueous suspension, which plasticizer is attached to the surface of the calcium carbonate particles.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the quantity of the plasticizer is 1-40 mg/m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;, preferably 4-9 mg/m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; of the surface area of the calcium carbonate particles.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that limestone powder having a grain size of 0.1-2 mm is added into the aqueous suspension.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to Claim 9, characterized in that limestone powder, which comprises at least 30 weight % of calcium carbonate, is added.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to Claim 9 or 10, characterized in that the quantity of the limestone powder is 0.2-4 fold, preferably approximately 0.5-3 fold the quantity of the hydraulic binder.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the quantity of the calcium carbonate is approximately 0.1-20 % of the quantity of the binder, especially approximately 0.5-15 weight %, more preferably approximately 1-10 weight %.
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the composition of blending agents, which comprises calcium carbonate particles and calcium hydrogen carbonate, is produced by bringing the calcium oxide-bearing initial material into contact with carbon dioxide in the aqueous phase, in which case the calcium carbonate crystals or particles are produced in a mixture, the pH of which is below 7.
</P>
<P>
14. The method according to Claim 13, characterized in that the composition of blending agents is produced
</P>
<P>
- by hydrating calcium oxide with water at a temperature exceeding 100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and at overpressure, in order to form calcium hydroxide, and
</P>
<P>
- by carbonating the generated calcium hydroxide in the aqueous phase at a temperature of approximately 20-100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and at overpressure, until the pH value of the mixture is below 7, in order to produce an aqueous suspension comprising calcium carbonate and calcium hydrogen carbonate.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that an aqueous suspension is produced, which comprises, as hydraulic binder, cement, such as portland, rapid or blast furnace slag cement.
</P>
<P>
16. A method according to any of the preceding claims, characterized in that the ratio between the parts by weight of water and binder (w/c) in the aqueous suspension is set at a value of approximately 0.3-0.5.
</P>
<P>
17. A method of producing a hardened stone material, characterized in that an aqueous suspension, which is based on a hydraulic binder, is produced with a method according to any of the Claims 1-16, and the aqueous suspension is allowed to harden.
</P>
<P>
18. The method according to Claim 17, characterized in that stone material is mixed into the aqueous suspension, and the generated mixture is allowed to harden.
</P>
<P>
19. The method according to Claim 18, characterized in that stone material, 90 % of the particles of which have an average particle size of less than 60 micrometres, is added into the aqueous suspension.
</P>
<P>
20. The method according to any of Claims 17-19, characterized in that a hardened plaster layer is produced.
</P>
<P>
21. An aqueous suspension of a hydraulic binder, which suspension comprises a hydraulic binder which is mixed in water, in which case the ratio between the parts per weight of the water and the binder (w/c) is approximately 0.3-0.6, characterized in that the suspension comprises 1-10 parts per weight of calcium carbonate particles, which have an average particle size of 2-200 nm, per 100 parts per weight of binder, and the pH value of which is below 7.
</P>
<P>
22. The aqueous suspension according to Claim 21, characterized in that it also comprises calcium hydrogen carbonate.
</P>
<P>
23. An aqueous suspension according to Claim 21 or 22, characterized in that the calcium carbonate particles are mixed into the suspension in the form of such a composition of blending agents, which comprises calcium carbonate particles and calcium hydrogen carbonate and the pH value of which is approximately 5.5-6.5.
</P>
<P>
24. An aqueous suspension according to any of Claims 21-23, characterized in that it is produced with a method according to any of Claims 1-16.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007057510A1;US2009090278A1;US8192542B2;RU2008123263A;RU2416579C2;JP2009515805A;FI122360B1;CN101400621A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
