<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
COMPUTE CLUSTERS EMPLOYING PHOTONIC INTERCONNECTIONS FOR TRANSMITTING OPTICAL SIGNALS BETWEEN COMPUTE CLUSTER NODES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1977572A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BRATKOVSKI ALEXANDRE M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BRATKOVSKI, ALEXANDRE, M
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HEWLETT PACKARD DEVELOPMENT CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HEWLETT-PACKARD DEVELOPMENT COMPANY, L.P
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1977572
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070762485
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-01-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US01862
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060337328
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-23
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G02B6/43
</Class>
<Class>
H04B10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H04L12/56
</Class>
<Class>
H04Q11/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/122P
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/43
</Class>
<Class>
G06N99/00K
</Class>
<Class>
H04B10/801
</Class>
<Class>
H04L12/56S8B
</Class>
<Class>
H04Q11/00P
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Various embodiments of the present invention are directed to photonic-interconnection-based compute clusters that provide high-speed, high-bandwidth interconnections between compute cluster nodes. In one embodiment of the present invention, the compute cluster includes a photonic interconnection having one or more optical transmission paths for transmitting independent frequency channels within an optical signal to each node in a set of nodes. The compute cluster includes one or more photonic-interconnection-based writers, each writer associated with a particular node, and each writer encoding information generated by the node into one of the independent frequency channels. A switch fabric directs the information encoded in the independent frequency channels to one or more nodes in the compute cluster.;  The compute cluster also includes one or more photonic-interconnection-based readers, each reader associated with a particular node, and each reader extracting the information encoded in the independent frequency channels directed to the node for processing.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A compute cluster comprising:
</P>
<P>
a photonic interconnection having one or more optical transmission paths for transmitting independent frequency channels within an optical signal to each node in a set of nodes;
</P>
<P>
one or more photonic-interconnection-based writers, each writer associated with a particular node, and each writer encoding information generated by the node into one of the independent frequency channels;
</P>
<P>
a switch fabric that directs the information encoded in the independent frequency channels to one or more nodes in the compute cluster; and
</P>
<P>
one or more photonic-interconnection-based readers, each reader associated with a particular node, and each reader extracting the information encoded in the independent frequency channels directed to the node for processing.
</P>
<P>
2. The compute cluster of claim 1 further comprising a clock signal source.
</P>
<P>
3. The compute cluster of claim 2 wherein the switch fabric further comprises one or more cyclic permutation networks for distributing continuous bit streams of information and one or more virtual output queues for queuing packets of information into one or more buffers.
</P>
<P>
4. The compute cluster of claim 1 wherein the nodes further comprise any one of a processor, memory, computer server, storage server, an external network connection, a data transmitting device or any electrical circuit or mosaic of electrical circuits.
</P>
<P>
5. The compute cluster of claim 4 where the electrical circuits have microscale dimensions or nanoscale dimensions.
</P>
<P>
6. The compute cluster of claim 1 wherein the photonic interconnection further comprises a two-dimensional photonic crystal with waveguides, a number of independent optical fibers, or free space.
</P>
<P>
7. The compute cluster of claim 1 wherein the photonic-interconnection-based writer further comprises:
</P>
<P>
a drop filter that extracts a frequency channel from the optical transmission path,
</P>
<P>
a local waveguide that extracts the frequency channel from the drop filter and
</P>
<P>
transmits the frequency channel,
</P>
<P>
a modulator that extracts the frequency channel from the local waveguide and
</P>
<P>
produces a modulated frequency channel by modulating the frequency channel, and
</P>
<P>
an add filter that extracts the modulated frequency channel and inserts the
</P>
<P>
modulated frequency channel into the optical transmission path.
</P>
<P>
8. The compute cluster of claim 1 wherein the photonic-interconnection-based reader further comprises:
</P>
<P>
a drop filter that extracts a frequency channel from the optical transmission path, and
</P>
<P>
a detector that extracts the frequency channel from the drop filter and demodulates the information encoded in the frequency channel.
</P>
<P>
9. A switch fabric comprising:
</P>
<P>
one or more optical transmission paths that each transmit a first set of independent frequency channels and a second set of independent frequency channels, the first set of independent frequency channels encoding information output by nodes in a compute cluster;
</P>
<P>
one or more photonic-interconnection-based readers, each reader extracting a frequency channel in the first set of independent frequency channels and encoding the information into one or more electronic input bit streams;
</P>
<P>
an electronic-based switch fabric that partitions and assembles the electronic input bit streams into electronic output bit streams, each electronic output bit stream directed to a particular node in the compute cluster; and
</P>
<P>
one or more photonic-interconnection-based writers, each encoding the information encoded in the electronic output bit streams into frequency channels in the second set of independent frequency channels.
</P>
<P>
10. The switch fabric of claim 9 further comprising a clock signal source.
</P>
<P>
11. The switch fabric of claim 10 wherein the switch fabric further comprises one or more cyclic permutation networks for distributing continuous bit streams of information and one or more virtual output queues for queuing packets of information into one or more buffers.
</P>
<P>
12. The switch fabric of claim 9 wherein the nodes further comprise any one of a processor, memory, computer server, storage server, an external network connection, a data transmitting device or any electrical circuit or mosaic of electrical circuits.
</P>
<P>
13. The switch fabric of claim 12 where the electrical circuits have microscale dimensions or nanoscale dimensions.
</P>
<P>
14. The switch fabric of claim 9 wherein the photonic interconnection further comprises a two-dimensional photonic crystal with waveguides, a number of independent optical fibers, or free space.
</P>
<P>
15. A method for transmitting data between nodes in a compute cluster, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a photonic interconnection having one or more optical transmission paths that lead to each node in the computer cluster;
</P>
<P>
providing an optical signal composed of a first of independent frequency channels and a second set of independent frequency channels, both sets of independent frequency channels are transmitted in the optical transmission paths to the nodes;
</P>
<P>
encoding information generated by the nodes into the frequency channels in the first set of independent frequency channels;
</P>
<P>
transmitting the encoded information to a switch fabric that partitions and assembles the information encoded in the first set of frequency channels and encodes the assembled information into the frequency channels of the second set of independent frequency channels; and
</P>
<P>
directing the second set of independent frequency channels to the nodes so that the assembled information can be processed.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 15 further comprising providing a clock signal that synchronizes transmission of information between nodes in the compute cluster.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 wherein providing the switch fabric further comprises providing one or more cyclic permutation networks for distributing continuous bit streams of data and one or more virtual output queues for queuing packets of data into one or more buffers.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 15 wherein the node further comprises any one of a processor, memory, computer server, storage server, an external network connection, a data transmitting device or any electrical circuit or mosaic of electrical circuits.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 18 where the electrical circuits have microscale dimensions or nanoscale dimensions.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 15 wherein the photonic interconnection further comprises a two-dimensional photonic crystal with waveguides, a number of independent optical fibers, or free space.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007172235A1;US7720377B2;WO2007087337A2;WO2007087337A3;JP2009524175A;JP4864098B2;CN101371533A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
