<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SYNTHESIS OF PURE RUTILE STRUCTURE TITANIUM OXIDE NANOSTRUCTURES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1940742A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
EDER DOMINIK [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
KINLOCH IAN A [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
WINDLE ALAN H [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
EDER, DOMINIK
</Name>
<Name>
KINLOCH, IAN, A
</Name>
<Name>
WINDLE, ALAN, H
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV CAMBRIDGE TECH [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
CAMBRIDGE ENTERPRISE LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1940742
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060779296
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006GB03277
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20050018139
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-06
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
H01G9/20
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6
</Class>
<Class>
H01G9/20D2
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E10/54D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for synthesising a titanium oxide nanostructures consisting at least predominantly of rutile phase comprises the steps of providing a nanostructured template;  coating the template with a titanium oxide containing colloidal phase, heat treating the titanium oxide coated template from to form a crystalline phase consisting at least predominantly of anatase phase;  further heat treating the titanium oxide coated template to convert the anatase phase into rutile phase.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims :
</P>
<P>
1. A method for synthesising a titanium oxide nanostructure which consists at least predominantly of rutile phase comprising the steps of: a) providing a nanostructured template; b) coating the template with a titanium oxide containing colloidal phase; c) first heat treatment of the titanium oxide coated template from b) to form a crystalline phase which consists at least predominantly of anatase phase; d) second heat treatment of the titanium oxide coated template from c) to convert the anatase phase into rutile phase.
</P>
<P>
2. A method as claimed in Claim 1 , wherein the product consists only of rutile phase.
</P>
<P>
3. A method as claimed in either one of the preceding claims, wherein the template comprises high aspect ratio cylinders or tubes.
</P>
<P>
4. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the template is of optionally doped carbon, a nitride, a sulfide, a carbide or gallium arsenide.
</P>
<P>
5. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the template is doped with nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
6. A method as claimed in Claim 4 or Claim 5, wherein the template comprises carbon nanotubes, carbon nanofibres, carbon herringbones, carbon onions or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. A method as claimed in Claim 6, wherein the template comprises single walled carbon nanotubes, multi-wall carbon nanotubes or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the template has a continuous or discontinuous coating of material .
</P>
<P>
9. A method as claimed in Claim 8 , wherein the coating material comprises a Group VIB transition metal, a Group VIIIB transition metal, a lanthanide series metal, an actinide series metal, or a mixture thereof .
</P>
<P>
10. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the template is of a defined architecture.
</P>
<P>
11. A method as claimed in Claim 8, wherein the template is a carbon nanotube mat.
</P>
<P>
12. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the components used to form the colloidal phase comprise titanium chloride, titanium isopropoxide, tetrabutyloxytitanate or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims wherein the components used to form the colloidal phase comprise water, alcohol, acetone, an organic particle shaper, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein step b) comprises causing a sol-gel transition of the colloidal phase.
</P>
<P>
15. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the first heat treatment is carried out at a temperature in the range of 200&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 500&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
16. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the first heat treatment is carried out under an oxidising atmosphere.
</P>
<P>
17. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the second heat treatment is carried out at a temperature in the range of 550&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 95O&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
18. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the second heat treatment is carried out under a non-oxidising atmosphere.
</P>
<P>
19. A method as claimed in Claim 18, wherein the atmosphere comprises nitrogen, inert gas or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. A method as claimed in Claim 18 or Claim 19, wherein the atmosphere comprises hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
21. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the second heat treatment is continuous or discontinuous.
</P>
<P>
22. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, further comprising the step of: e) removal of the template after step d) .
</P>
<P>
23. A method as claimed in Claim 22, wherein step e) is carried out by oxidation at high temperature or by the use of acid.
</P>
<P>
24. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, further comprising the step of: f) Coating the surface of the titanium oxide with a continuous or discontinuous coating of material after step d) or step e) .
</P>
<P>
25. A method as claimed in Claim 24, wherein the coating material comprises a Group VIB transition metal, a Group VIIIB transition metal, a lanthanide series metal, an actinide series metal, or a mixture thereof .
</P>
<P>
26. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, further comprising the step of: g) removing anatase phase.
</P>
<P>
27. A method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the wall thickness of the titanium oxide nanostructure is between 1 to 20 crystal layers .
</P>
<P>
28. A titanium oxide nanostructure synthesised by a method as claimed in any one of the preceding claims .
</P>
<P>
29. A titanium oxide-containing colloidal phase formed from components comprising: tetrabutyloxytitanate and/or titanium isopropoxide; benzylalcohol and/or acetone; and a solvent.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007028972A1;JP2009506975A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
