<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
INTERCONNECTS AND HEAT DISSIPATORS BASED ON NANOSTRUCTURES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1945840A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KABIR MOHAMMAD SHAFIQUL [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
KABIR, MOHAMMAD, SHAFIQUL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SMOLTEK AB [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
SMOLTEK AB
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1945840
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060850481
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-08-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006IB04279
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
SE20050001888
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-08-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060772449P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060412060
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/04
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/26
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/08
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01J1/304
</Class>
<Class>
H01J3/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01J9/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01L23/373
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/755
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/76
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/08
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01J1/304
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/768C3S6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/768C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L23/532M3
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides for nanostructures grown on a conducting substrate, and a method of making the same. The nanostructures grown according to the claimed method are suitable for interconnects and heat dissipators in electronic devices.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED
</P>
<P>
1. An integrated circuit, comprising: a substrate; a conducting layer, on the substrate; an interconnect supported by the conducting layer, wherein the interconnect comprises at least one nanostructure, and wherein the nanostructure comprises: a plurality of intermediate layers on the conducting layer, the plurality of intermediate layers including at least one layer that affects a morphology of the nanostructure and at least one layer that affects an electrical property of an interface between the conducting layer and the nanostructure.
</P>
<P>
2. The integrated circuit of claim 1 wherein the substrate comprises a metal.
</P>
<P>
3. The integrated circuit of claim 2 wherein the metal is selected from the group consisting of tungsten, molybdenum, niobium, platinum and palladium.
</P>
<P>
4. The integrated circuit of claim 1 wherein the plurality of intermediate layers comprises a metal layer and a layer of semiconducting material.
</P>
<P>
5. The integrated circuit of claim 4 wherein the layer of semiconducting material is amorphous silicon, or amorphous germanium.
</P>
<P>
6. The integrated circuit of claim 1, wherein the nanostructure is a carbon nanostructure.
</P>
<P>
7. The integrated circuit of claim 1 , wherein the nanostructure comprises a bundle of carbon nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
8. The integrated circuit of claim 1, wherein the nanostructure is made from a compound selected from the group consisting of: InP, GaAs, and AlGaAs.
</P>
<P>
9. The integrated circuit of claim 1 , wherein the plurality of intermediate layers form an Ohmic contact.
</P>
<P>
10. The integrated circuit of claim 1 , wherein the plurality of intermediate layers form a Schottky barrier.
</P>
<P>
11. The integrated circuit of claim 1 , wherein the semiconducting substrate is a wafer of silicon, or oxidized silicon.
</P>
<P>
12. The integrated circuit of claim 1, wherein the plurality of intermediate layers is between 1 nm and 1 [mu]m thick.
</P>
<P>
13. The integrated circuit of claim 1, wherein the intermediate layer adjacent to the nanostructure is a layer of catalyst, and wherein the catalyst is selected from the group consisting of: Ni, Fe, Mo, NiCr, and Pd.
</P>
<P>
14. The integrated circuit of claim 1 , further comprising a plurality of nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
15. The integrated circuit of claim 1 , further comprising at least one nanostructure configured to dissipate heat from the circuit.
</P>
<P>
16. An integrated circuit, comprising: a insulating substrate; a conducting layer, on the insulating substrate; a nanostructure embedded in the insulating layer, wherein the nanostructure is configured to dissipate heat from the integrated circuit into an area surrounding the circuit, and wherein the nanostructure comprises: a plurality of intermediate layers on the conducting layer, the plurality of intermediate layers including at least one layer that affects a morphology of the nanostructure and at least one layer that affects an electrical property of an interface between the conducting layer and the nanostructure.
</P>
<P>
17. An interconnect in an integrated circuit, the interconnect comprising: at least one nanostructure.
</P>
<P>
18. The interconnect of claim 16, wherein the nanostructure comprises: a conducting base layer; a layer of amorphous silicon on the conducting base layer; a layer of catalyst on the layer of amorphous silicon; and a carbon nanostructure disposed on the layer of catalyst.
</P>
<P>
19. The interconnect of claim 16, wherein the nanostructure comprises: a conducting base layer; a layer of amorphous germanium on the conducting base layer; a layer of catalyst on the layer of amorphous germanium; and a carbon nanostructure disposed on the layer of catalyst.
</P>
<P>
20. A method of forming an interconnect, the method comprising: depositing a layer of conducting material on a substrate; depositing a semiconducting layer on the conducting material; depositing a catalyst layer on the semiconducting layer; without first annealing the substrate, causing the substrate to be heated to a temperature at which a nanostructure can form; and growing the nanostructure on the catalyst layer at the temperature.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 20, further comprising forming a top metal contact, according to: depositing an insulator layer on top of the nanostructure; etching the insulating layer to expose the tip of the nanostructure; depositing a sacrificial layer on the insulating layer; forming a plurality of apertures in the sacrificial layer; depositing a metal material over the sacrificial layer and on the insulating layer in the apertures;
</P>
<P>
22. lifting off the sacrificial layer to leave portions of the metal layer corresponding to the apertures on the substrate. An interconnect formed by the method of claim 20.
</P>
<P>
23. A heat dissipator formed by the method of claim 16.
</P>
<P>
24. An integrated circuit comprising: at least one interconnect comprising a carbon nanostructure, wherein the integrated circuit may permit a current density of &amp;gt;10&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; A/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; when a current is flowing through it.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007024186A2;WO2007024186A3;RU2008111514A;KR20080064797A;JP2009508325A;WO2007119123A2;WO2007119123A3
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
