<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING CARBON NANOTUBE AND CATALYST FOR CARBON NANOTUBE PRODUCTION
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1977997A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SATO KENICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUJITA KEISUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MAEDA MASAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YOSHIKAWA MASAHITO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HIGUCHI KAZUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SATO, KENICHI
</Name>
<Name>
FUJITA, KEISUKE
</Name>
<Name>
MAEDA, MASAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
YOSHIKAWA, MASAHITO
</Name>
<Name>
HIGUCHI, KAZUYOSHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TORAY INDUSTRIES [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TORAY INDUSTRIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1977997
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060834408
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-11
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP324653
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050380679
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-29
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060088344
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060181440
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J21/10
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/745
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/10C4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Provided is a method for producing a carbon nanotube, wherein a catalyst for carbon nanotube production comprising a powdery catalyst supporting a metal on magnesia and having a bulk density of 0.30 g/mL to 0.70 g/mL, in a vertical reactor, is disposed over the whole area in a horizontal cross section direction of the reactor, in such state a carbon-containing compound flowed in a vertical direction inside the reactor is contacted with the catalyst at 500 to 1200 DEG C, thereby carbon nanotubes of uniformity and high quality are efficiently synthesized in a large amount.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for producing a carbon nanotube, wherein a catalyst for carbon nanotube production comprising a powdery catalyst supporting a metal on magnesia and having a bulk density of 0.30 g/mL to 0.70 g/mL, in a vertical reactor, is disposed over the whole area in a horizontal cross section direction of the reactor, and a carbon-containing compound is flowed in a vertical direction inside the reactor to contact said carbon-containing compound with said catalyst at 500 to 1200[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
2. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of claim 1, wherein the vertical reactor having a reactor installed in a vertical direction has a mechanism that a carbon-containing compound flows in a direction toward the other end from one end of said vertical reactor for said carbon-containing compound so as to pass through a catalyst layer formed by the catalyst for carbon nanotube production.
</P>
<P>
3. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of claim 1 or 2, wherein said vertical reactor is a fluid bed reactor.
</P>
<P>
4. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein said magnesia is light magnesia.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein said magnesia has a pore of 1 to 50 nm in diameter.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of claim 5, wherein a pore content of said magnesia is 0.10 mL/g or more.
</P>
<P>
7. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein said metal is a metal containing at least Fe.
</P>
<P>
8. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein said carbon-containing compound flows as a mixed gas, and a concentration of the carbon-containing compound in the mixed gas is 2 vol% or less.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein said carbon-containing compound contains at least one selected from methane, ethane, ethylene, acetylene, propane and propylene.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein said carbon nanotube is a carbon nanotube of 2 nm or less in inner diameter as the main product.
</P>
<P>
11. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein said carbon-containing compound is contacted with a catalyst for carbon nanotube production for the pyrolysis rate to be 10% or less.
</P>
<P>
12. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein a linear velocity of said carbon-containing compound flowed is 0.20 cm/sec or more.
</P>
<P>
13. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein said carbon-containing compound is a carbon-containing compound having carbon numbers of 2 or more.
</P>
<P>
14. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein said carbon-containing compound is methane or a mixture containing methane, which is contacted with a catalyst for carbon nanotube production at the linear velocity of 9.5*10&amp;lt;-3&amp;gt; cm/sec or less.
</P>
<P>
15. A catalyst for carbon nanotube production comprising a catalyst supporting a metal on magnesia and having a bulk density of 0.30 g/mL to 0.70 g/mL.
</P>
<P>
1. A method for producing a carbon nanotube, wherein a catalyst for carbon nanotube production comprising a powdery catalyst supporting a metal on magnesia and having a bulk density of 0.30 g/mL to 0.70 g/mL, in a vertical reactor, is disposed over the whole area in a horizontal cross section direction of the reactor, and a carbon-containing compound is flowed in a vertical direction inside the reactor to contact said carbon-containing compound with said catalyst at 500 to 1200[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
2. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of claim 1, wherein the vertical reactor having a reactor installed in a vertical direction has a mechanism that a carbon-containing compound flows in a direction toward the other end from one end of said vertical reactor for said carbon-containing compound so as to pass through a catalyst layer formed by the catalyst for carbon nanotube production.
</P>
<P>
3. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of claim 1 or 2, wherein said vertical reactor is a fluid bed reactor.
</P>
<P>
4. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein said magnesia is light magnesia.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein said magnesia has a pore of 1 to 50 nm in diameter.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of claim 5, wherein a pore content of said magnesia is 0.10 mL/g or more.
</P>
<P>
7. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein said metal is a metal containing at least Fe.
</P>
<P>
8. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein said carbon-containing compound flows as a mixed gas, and a concentration of the carbon-containing compound in the mixed gas is 2 vol% or less.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein said carbon-containing compound contains at least one selected from methane, ethane, ethylene, acetylene, propane and propylene.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein said carbon nanotube is a carbon nanotube of 2 nm or less in inner diameter as the main product.
</P>
<P>
11. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein said carbon-containing compound is contacted with a catalyst for carbon nanotube production for the pyrolysis rate to be 10% or less.
</P>
<P>
12. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein a linear velocity of said carbon-containing compound flowed is 0.20 cm/sec or more.
</P>
<P>
13. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein said carbon-containing compound is a carbon-containing compound having carbon numbers of 2 or more.
</P>
<P>
14. The method for producing a carbon nanotube of any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein said carbon-containing compound is methane or a mixture containing methane, which is contacted with a catalyst for carbon nanotube production at the linear velocity of 9.5*10&amp;lt;-3&amp;gt; cm/sec or less.
</P>
<P>
15. A catalyst for carbon nanotube production comprising a catalyst supporting a metal on magnesia and having a bulk density of 0.30 g/mL to 0.70 g/mL.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009022652A1;US7704482B2;KR20080083027A;WO2007074629A1;CN101351404A;CN101351404B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
