<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
HIGHLY FILLED DISPERSION CONTAINING TRANSITION ALUMINIUM OXIDE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1960312A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LORTZ WOLFGANG [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
LACH HEINZ [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
VON SEYERL JOACHIM [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
LORTZ, WOLFGANG
</Name>
<Name>
LACH, HEINZ
</Name>
<Name>
VON SEYERL, JOACHIM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
EVONIK DEGUSSA GMBH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
EVONIK DEGUSSA GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1960312
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060841305
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006EP69424
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
DE200510059960
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-15
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/111
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F7/02B8
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/626A10B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/626A10K
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/626A6B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/634B20
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/634D10
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/40F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Aqueous dispersion containing transition aluminium oxide as only solid and a dispersant, in which - the transition aluminium oxide is present in the form of aggregates of primary particles, the content of transition aluminium oxide in the dispersion is from 40 to 65% by weight, the aggregates in the dispersion have a mean aggregate diameter of less than 100 nm, - the dispersant contains polyaluminium hydroxychloride, polyaluminium hydroxynitrate and/or polyaluminium hydroxysulphate, the dispersion has a pH of from 3 to 5.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. Aqueous dispersion containing transition aluminium oxide as only solid and a dispersant, characterized in that
</P>
<P>
- the transition aluminium oxide is present in the form of aggregates of primary particles, the content of transition aluminium oxide in the dispersion is from 40 to 65% by weight, the aggregates in the dispersion have a mean aggregate diameter of less than 100 nm,
</P>
<P>
the dispersant contains polyaluminium hydroxychloride, polyaluminium hydroxynitrate and/or polyaluminium hydroxysulphate,
</P>
<P>
the dispersion has a pH of from 3 to 5.
</P>
<P>
2. Aqueous dispersion according to Claim 1, characterized in that the BET surface area of the transition aluminium oxide is from 20 to 150 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
3. Aqueous dispersion according to Claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the transition aluminium oxide contains theta- and/or delta-aluminium oxide as main constituent .
</P>
<P>
4. Aqueous dispersion according to Claim 1 to 3, characterized in that the dispersant is polyaluminium hydroxychloride, a mixture of polyaluminium hydroxychloride and a cationic polymer and/or a cocondensation product of polyaluminium hydroxychloride and a cationic dicyandiamide resin.
</P>
<P>
5. Aqueous dispersion according to any of Claims 1 to 4, characterized in that the proportion of dispersant is from 0.1 to 3% by weight, based on the total amount of the dispersion.
</P>
<P>
6. Process for producing the aqueous dispersion according to any of Claims 1 to 5, characterized in that the dispersant is, if appropriate, placed in water, transition aluminium oxide is added all at once, in portions or continuously and the mixture is dispersed by introduction of energy of more than 1000 kJ/m&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
7. Process according to Claim 6, characterized in that dispersion is firstly carried out at an energy input of less than 1000 kJ/m&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; to form a predispersion, the predispersion is divided into at least two substreams, these substreams are placed under a pressure of at least 500 bar in a high-energy mill, depressurized via a nozzle and the substreams are allowed to impinge on one another in a gas- or liquid-filled reaction space and, if appropriate, the high-energy milling is repeated one or more times.
</P>
<P>
8. Use of the aqueous dispersion containing aluminium oxide according to any of Claims 1 to 5 for producing further dispersions and for producing composites.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007068646A2;WO2007068646A3;US2008312067A1;US7615577B2;JP2009519197A;DE102005059960A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
