<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Carbon nanotubes, substrate and electron emission device with such carbon nanotubes and carbon nanotube sythesizing substrate as well as methods of and apparatus for making them
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1988056A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ANDO TOSHIHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAGAWA KIYOHARU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
GAMO MIKA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
GAMO HIDENORI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ANDO, TOSHIHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAGAWA, KIYOHARU
</Name>
<Name>
GAMO, MIKA
</Name>
<Name>
GAMO, HIDENORI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NAT INST FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TOPPAN PRINTING CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NATIONAL INSTITUTE FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE
</Name>
<Name>
TOPPAN PRINTING CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1988056
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080011320
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060833305
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050341181
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060070030
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060070031
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060231314
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01J1/304
</Class>
<Class>
H01J9/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J35/00D
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/00D4
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/14
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B2
</Class>
<Class>
H01J1/304
</Class>
<Class>
H01J9/02B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of synthesizing carbon nanotubes by solid-liquid interfacial contact cracking, wherein a substrate carrying a catalyst composed of a transition metal or a catalyst composed of a transition metal oxide is heated in an organic liquid of alcohol to synthesize carbon nanotubes on said substrate, comprises a first synthesis process in which they are synthesized at a low substrate temperature;  and a second synthesis process, split from the first synthesis process, in which they are synthesized at a high substrate temperature. The first synthesis process grows carbon nanotubes oriented perpendicular to the surface of the substrate, and the second synthesis process grows carbon nanotubes continued to the carbon nanotubes grown in the first synthesis process.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of synthesizing carbon nanotubes by solid-liquid interfacial contact cracking wherein a substrate carrying a catalyst composed of a transition metal or a catalyst composed of a transition metal oxide is heated in an organic liquid of alcohol to synthesize carbon nanotubes on said substrate, characterized in that it comprises:
</P>
<P>
a first synthesis process in which they are synthesized at a low substrate temperature; and
</P>
<P>
a second synthesis process split from the first synthesis process in which they are synthesized at a high substrate temperature, wherein
</P>
<P>
said first synthesis process grows carbon nanotubes oriented perpendicular to the surface of said substrate, and
</P>
<P>
said second synthesis process grows carbon nanotubes continued to the carbon nanotubes grown in said first synthesis process.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1, characterized in that said first synthesis process is performed at a substrate temperature of 500 deg. C to 700 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1 or claim 2, characterized in that said second synthesis process is performed at a substrate temperature of 750 deg. C to 1100 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to any of claims 1 to 3, characterized in that said first synthesis process is carried out for a synthesis time period of not less than 10 seconds.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1988056A3;EP1964809A1;EP1964809A4;US2010171409A1;KR20080072070A;WO2007061078A1;EP2014616A2;EP2014616A3
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
