<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYMERIC METERIALS INCORPORATING CARBON NANOSTRUCTURES AND METHODS FOR MAKING SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1981706A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ZHOU BING [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG CHENG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BALEE RAYMOND B [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FRANSSON MARTIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHOU, BING
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG, CHENG
</Name>
<Name>
BALEE, RAYMOND, B
</Name>
<Name>
FRANSSON, MARTIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HEADWATERS TECH INNOVATION LLC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HEADWATERS TECHNOLOGY INNOVATION LLC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1981706
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070811797
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-02-06
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US61655
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-06
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060351620
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060614006
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B32B9/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/18
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to novel composites that incorporate carbon nanospheres into a polymeric material. The polymeric material can be any polymer or polymerizable material compatible with graphitic materials. The carbon nanospheres are hollow, graphitic nanoparticles. The carbon nanospheres can be manufactured from a carbon precursor using templating catalytic nanoparticles. The unique size, shape, and electrical properties of the carbon nanospheres impart beneficial properties to the composites incorporating these nanomaterials.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A composite material comprising: a polymeric material comprising a polymer or a polymerizable material; and a plurality of carbon nanospheres dispersed in the polymeric material, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise at least about 0.1% by weight of the composite material.
</P>
<P>
2. A composite material as in claim 1, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise a hollow, multi-walled particle with an outer diameter of less than about 1 micron.
</P>
<P>
3. A composite material as in claim 1, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise at least about 0.5% by weight of the composite material.
</P>
<P>
4. A composite material as in claim 1, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise at least about 1% by weight of the composite material. 5. A composite material as in claim 1, further comprising carbon nanomaterials other than and in addition to the carbon nanospheres, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise at least about 2% by weight of the total amount of carbon nanomaterial in the composite.
</P>
<P>
6. A composite material as in claim 5, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise at least about 3% by weight of the total amount of carbon nanomaterial in the composite.
</P>
<P>
7. A composite material as in claim 5, wherein the carbon nanospheres comprise at least about 15% by weight of the total amount of carbon nanomaterial in the composite. 8. A composite material as in claim 1, wherein the polymeric material comprises a polymer selected from the group consisting of polyamines, polyacrylates, polybutadienes, polybutylenes, polyethylenes, polyethylenechlorinates, ethylene vinyl alcohols, fluoropolymers, ionomers, polymethylpentenes, polypropylenes, polystyrenes, polyvinylchlorides, polyvinylidene chlorides, polycondensates, polyamides, polyamide-imides, polyaryletherketones, polycarbonates, polyketones, polyetheretherketones, polyetherimides, polyethersulfones, polyimides, polyphenylene oxides, polyphenylene sulfides, polyphthalamides, polythalimides, polysulfones, polyarylsulfones allyl resins, melamine resins, phenol-formaldehyde resins, liquid crystal polymers, polyolefins, polyesters, silicones, polyurethanes, epoxies, cellulosic polymers, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. A composite material as in claim 1, wherein the polymeric material comprises a thermo-plastic polymeric material selected from the group consisting of acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene, acrylonitrile-ethylene/propylene-styrene, methylmethacrylate-butadiene-styrene, acrylonitrile-butadiene-methylmethacrylate- styrene, acrylonitrile-n-butylacrylate-styrene, rubber modified polystyrene, polyethylene, polypropylene, polystyrene, polymethyl-methacrylate, polyvinylchloride, cellulose-acetate resin, polyamide, polyester, polyacrylonitrile, polycarbonate, polyphenyleneoxide, polyketone, polysulphone, polyphenylenesulfide, fluoride resin, silicone, polyimide, polybenzimidazole, polyamide elastomer, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. A composite material as in claim 1, wherein the polymeric material comprises a thermo-setting polymeric material selected from the group consisting of phenol resin, urea resin, melamine-formaldehyde resin, urea- formaldehyde latex, xylene resin, diallylphthalate resin, epoxy resin, aniline resin, furan resin, polyurethane, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. A composite material comprising a polymer or a polymerizable material and a carbon nanomaterial mixed therewith, wherein the composite material is manufactured according to a method comprising: forming a precursor mixture comprising a carbon precursor and a plurality of templating nanoparticles, the templating nanoparticles comprising a catalytic metal; carbonizing the precursor mixture to form an intermediate carbon material comprising a plurality of carbon nanostructures, amorphous carbon, and optionally remaining catalytic metal; purifying the intermediate carbon material by removing at least a portion of the amorphous carbon and optionally a portion of remaining catalytic metal in to yield the carbon nanomaterial; and blending the carbon nanomaterial with a thermoplastic polymer or polymerizable material while in a liquid or plastic condition and allowing or causing the thermoplastic polymer or polymerizable material to solidify to yield the composite material.
</P>
<P>
12. A composite material as in claim 11, wherein the method of manufacturing the carbon nanomaterial further comprises removing functional groups from the surface of the purified intermediate carbon material by,
</P>
<P>
(i) heating the purified intermediate carbon material to a temperature greater than about 100 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C; and/or
</P>
<P>
(ii) treating the purified intermediate carbon material with a base.
</P>
<P>
13. A composite material as in claim 11, wherein the method of manufacturing the carbon nanomaterial comprises heating the purified intermediate carbon material to a temperature greater than about 200 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C. 14. A composite material as in claim 11 , wherein the method of manufacturing the carbon nanomaterial comprises heating the purified intermediate carbon material to a temperature greater than about 500 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
15. A composite material as in claim 11 , wherein the method of manufacturing the carbon nanomaterial comprises heating the purified intermediate carbon to a temperature greater than about 1000 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
16. A composite material as in claim 11, wherein the method of manufacturing the carbon nanomaterial comprises treating the purified intermediate carbon material with sodium hydroxide and/or potassium hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
17. A composite material as in claim 11, wherein the composite comprises a polymer selected from the group consisting of acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene, acrylonitrile-ethylene/propylene-styrene, methylmethacrylate-butadiene-styrene, acrylonitrile-butadiene-methylmethacrylate-styrene, acrylonitrile-n-butylacrylate- styrene, rubber modified polystyrene, polyethylene, polypropylene, polystyrene, polymethyl-methacrylate, polyvinyl chloride, cellulose-acetate resin, polyamide, polyester, polyacrylonitrile, polycarbonate, polyphenyleneoxide, polyketone, polysulphone, polyphenylenesulfide, fluoride resin, silicone, polyimide, polybenzimidazole, polyamide elastomer, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
18. A method of making a composite material, comprising providing a thermoplastic polymer or polymerizable material that is in a liquid or plastic condition; mixing between about 1% and about 50% by weight of a graphitic material into the thermoplastic polymer or polymerizable material, the graphitic material comprising greater than 3% by weight of carbon nanospheres; and allowing or causing the thermoplastic polymer or polymerizable material to solidify to yield the composite material.
</P>
<P>
19. A method as in claim 18, the composite material being formed from a thermoplastic polymer, the method further comprising heating the thermoplastic polymer to a temperature above a melting point or glass transition temperature of the thermoplastic polymer to the liquid or plastic condition prior to or while mixing with the graphitic material and then cooling the thermoplastic polymer to yield the composite material.
</P>
<P>
20. A method as in claim 19, wherein the thermoplastic polymer is selected from the group consisting of acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene, acrylonitrile- ethylene/propylene-styrene, methylmethacrylate-butadiene-styrene, acrylonitrile- butadiene-methylmethacrylate-styrene, acrylonitrile-n-butylacrylate-styrene, rubber modified polystyrene, polyethylene, polypropylene, polystyrene, polymethylmethacrylate, polyvinylchloride, cellulose-acetate resin, polyamide, polyester, polyacrylonitrile, polycarbonate, polyphenyleneoxide, poly ketone, polysulphone, polyphenylenesulfide, fluoride resin, silicone, polyimide, polybenzimidazole, polyamide elastomer, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
21. A method as in claim 18, the composite material being formed from a polymerizable material that is initially in the liquid or plastic condition and is subsequently polymerized to form a polymeric material.
</P>
<P>
22. A method as in claim 21, wherein the polymerizable material comprises a monomer or oligomer suitable for forming a polymeric material selected from the group consisting of polyacrylates, polybutadienes, polybutylenes, polyethylenes, polyethylenechlorinates, ethylene vinyl alcohols, fluoropolymers, ionomers, polymethylpentenes, polypropylenes, polystyrenes, polyvinylchlorides, polyvinylidene chlorides, polycondensates, polyamides, polyamide-imides, polyaryletherketones, polycarbonates, polyketones, polyetheretherketones, polyetherimides, polyethersulfones, polyimides, polyphenylene oxides, polyphenylene sulfides, polyphthalamides, polythalimides, polysulfones, polyarylsulfones allyl resins, melamine resins, formaldehyde resins, liquid crystal polymers, polyolefins, polyesters, silicones, polyurethanes, epoxies, cellulosic polymers, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
23. A method as in claim 18, wherein the carbon nanospheres are manufactured according to the following steps: (i) forming one or more intermediate carbon nanospheres by polymerizing a carbon precursor in the presence of a plurality of templating nanoparticles;
</P>
<P>
(ii) carbonizing the intermediate carbon nanospheres to form a plurality of composite nanostructures; and
</P>
<P>
(iii) optionally removing the templating nanoparticles from the composite nanostructures to yield the carbon nanospheres. 24. A method as in claim 23, wherein the templating nanoparticles comprise at least one of iron, nickel, or cobalt. 25. A method as in claim 23, wherein carbonization is carried out at a temperature between about 500 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and about 2500 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
26. A method as in claim 23, wherein the templating nanoparticles are removed from the composite nanostructure by etching with an acid, a base, or both.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1981706A4;WO2007143237A2;WO2007143237A3;KR20080098054A;JP2009538363A;CA2640107A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
