<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CERIUM CARBONATE POWDER, CERIUM OXIDE POWDER, METHOD FOR PREPARING THE SAME, AND CMP SLURRY COMPRISING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1948568A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
OH MYOUNG-HWAN [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
NHO JUN-SEOK [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM JONG-PIL [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM JANG-YUL [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
CHO SEUNG-BEOM [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
OH, MYOUNG-HWAN
</Name>
<Name>
NHO, JUN-SEOK
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, JONG-PIL
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, JANG-YUL
</Name>
<Name>
CHO, SEUNG-BEOM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LG CHEMICAL LTD [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
LG CHEM, LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1948568
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060812520
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006KR04686
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20050108721
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F17/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F17/00F
</Class>
<Class>
C01F17/00H
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/14B
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/14D2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is a method of preparing cerium carbonate powder by mixing a cerium precursor solution with a carbonate precursor solution and subjecting the mixture solution to a precipitation reaction, wherein the concentration of cerium in the cerium precursor solution ranges from IM to 1OM, the molar concentration ratio of the cerium precursor to the carbonate precursor ranges from 1:1 to 1:7, and the cerium precursor solution contains at least one additive selected from the group consisting of carbonate compounds, acrylic compounds, and sulfate ion-containing compounds.;  According to the disclosed invention, cerium carbonate powder having a uniform particle size of 0.05 to 1ú can be prepared through a liquid-phase process by controlling the concentration of the cerium precursor solution, the molar concentration ratio of the cerium precursor to the carbonate precursor solution, the kind of additives, and the like. Also, the cerium carbonate powder is enabled to have a uniform shape with an aspect ratio of 1 to 5, even though it has an orthorhombic crystal structure.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
[I] A method of preparing cerium carbonate powder by mixing a cerium precursor aqueous solution with a carbonate precursor aqueous solution and subjecting the mixture solution to a precipitation reaction, wherein the concentration of cerium in the cerium precursor aqueous solution ranges from IM to 1OM, the molar concentration ratio of the cerium precursor to the carbonate precursor ranges from 1:1 to 1:7, and the cerium precursor aqueous solution contains at least one additive selected from the group consisting of carbonate compounds, acrylic compounds, and sulfate ion-containing compounds.
</P>
<P>
[2] The method according to Claim 1, wherein the additive is itaconic acid or ammonium sulfate.
</P>
<P>
[3] The method according to Claim 1, wherein the additive is used in an amount of
</P>
<P>
0.05 to 2 parts by weight based on 100 parts by weight of the cerium precursor.
</P>
<P>
[4] The method according to Claim 1, wherein the cerium precursor is cerium nitrate or cerium acetate.
</P>
<P>
[5] The method according to Claim 1, wherein the carbonate precursor is urea.
</P>
<P>
[6] The method according to Claim 1, wherein the cerium carbonate has an or- thorhombic crystal structure.
</P>
<P>
[7] The method according to Claim 1, wherein the cerium carbonate has an average particle size of 0.05 to ID and an aspect ratio of 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
[8] Cerium carbonate powder, which has an orthorhombic crystal structure, an average particle size of 0.05 to ID, and an aspect ratio of 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
[9] The cerium carbonate powder according to Claim 8, which is prepared by the method as defined in any one of Claims 1 to 5, the method comprising a step of mixing a cerium precursor aqueous solution with a carbonate precursor aqueous solution and subjecting the mixture solution to a precipitation reaction, wherein the concentration of cerium in the cerium precursor aqueous solution ranges from IM to 1OM, the molar concentration ratio of the cerium precursor to the carbonate precursor ranges from 1:1 to 1:7, and the cerium precursor aqueous solution contains at least one additive selected from the group consisting of carbonate compounds, acrylic compounds, and sulfate ion-containing compounds.
</P>
<P>
[10] A method of preparing cerium oxide powder using the cerium carbonate powder as defined in Claim 8 as a raw material, wherein the cerium carbonate has an orthorhombic crystal structure, an average particle size of 0.05 to ID, and an aspect ratio of 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
[II] The method according to Claim 10, wherein the cerium carbonate powder is heat-treated at a temperature of 300-900[deg.]C for 10 to 60 minutes. [12] Cerium oxide powder, which has a cubic crystal structure, an average particle size of 0.05 to ID, and an aspect ratio of 1 to 5. [13] The cerium oxide powder according to Claim 12, which is prepared by the method as defined in Claims 10 or 11, the method using the cerium carbonate powder as a raw material, wherein the cerium carbonate has an orthorhombic crystal structure, an average particle size of 0.05 to ID, and an aspect ratio of 1 to 5. [14] A CMP slurry, which contains the cerium oxide powder as defined in Claim 12 as an abrasive,
</P>
<P>
The cerium oxide powder having a cubic crystal structure, an average particle size of 0.05 to ID, and an aspect ratio of 1 to 5. [15] The CMP slurry according to Claim 14, wherein the cerium oxide powder has a particle size distribution of 0.01 to 0.45D after milling. [16] The CMP slurry according to Claim 14, which contains a dispersant in an amount of 0.001 to 10 parts by weight based on 100 parts by weight of the abrasive containing the cerium oxide powder. [17] The CMP slurry according to Claim 16, wherein the dispersant is one or more selected from the group consisting of polyvinyl alcohol, ethylene glycol, glycerin, polyethylene glycol, polypropylene glycol, polyvinyl pyrrolidone, polyacrylic acid, ammonium polyacrylate, and polyacrylic maleic acid.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1948568A4;WO2007055523A1;WO2007055523A9;US2007107318A1;US7682584B2;TW200914379A;TWI306446B;KR20070051680A;KR100812052B1;JP2009515807A;CN101304947A;CN101304947B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
