<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PLATELET-TYPE SLIT VAPOR- GROWN CARBON FIBER AND PROCESS FOR PRODUCTION THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1980655A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YOSHIMURA MASAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUJI KATSUYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
AOKI TAKANORI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YOSHIMURA, MASAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
TSUJI, KATSUYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
AOKI, TAKANORI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SHOWA DENKO KK [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHOWA DENKO K.K
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1980655
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070707360
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-01-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP51113
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060012726
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J23/755
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J21/18
</Class>
<Class>
B01J21/18C
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/755
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02B12
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02B2
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02E
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/18
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for producing a platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber by bringing raw materials into contact with a catalyst in a heating zone, wherein the raw materials contain at least ethylene as a carbon source, and a platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber obtained by the method are disclosed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for producing a platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber by bringing raw materials into contact with a catalyst in a heating zone, wherein the raw materials contain at least ethylene as a carbon source.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1, wherein the catalyst is a supported type catalyst comprising a carrier and a catalyst component supported on the carrier.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 2, wherein the catalyst component contains at least metallic nickel and/or a nickel compound.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 3, wherein the nickel compound is selected from the group consisting of nickel nitrate, nickel chloride, nickel bromide, nickel iodide, nickel fluoride, nickel carbonate, nickel acetate and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to any one of claims 2 to 4, wherein the carrier contains at least a carbon material.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 5, wherein the carbon material is carbon black.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein the amount (% by mass) of the catalyst component supported by the supported type catalyst is represented by the following equation:
</P>
<P>
and
</P>
<P>
is from 1 to 65% by mass.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the raw materials further comprise water.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein the temperature of the heating zone is from 500 deg. C to 800 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein a platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber having a fiber diameter of 50 to 1,000 nm is produced.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein a platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber having the fiber diameter of from 50 to 1,000 nm is produced, and
</P>
<P>
wherein the catalyst is a supported type catalyst comprising a carrier and a catalyst component supported on the carrier,
</P>
<P>
the carrier is carbon black, and
</P>
<P>
the temperature of the heating zone is from 550 deg. C to 650 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
12. A platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber produced by the method according to any one of claims 1 to 11.
</P>
<P>
13. The platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber produced by the method according to claim 12, which has a BET surface specific area of 100 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; /g or more.
</P>
<P>
14. The platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber produced by the method according to claim 12 or 13, which has a fiber diameter of 50 to 1,000 nm.
</P>
<P>
15. The platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber produced by the method according to any one of claims 12 to 14, wherein an area of holes having a ratio of a major axis length to a fiber diameter of 80% or more accounts for 5 to 50% of an area of the carbon fiber when photographic observation is performed using a transmission electron microscope (TEM).
</P>
<P>
16. The platelet type slit-incorporated vapor grown carbon fiber produced by the method according to any one of claims 12 to 15, wherein a graphitized layer laminated in the direction which is perpendicular to a fiber direction is provided between slits.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1980655A4;US2010221535A1;KR20080078071A;KR101038231B1;WO2007083831A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
