<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Wear resistant coatings
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1927670A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KRISHNAMURTHY ANAND [IN]
</Name>
<Name>
BRUCE ROBERT WILLIAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SRINIDHI SAMPATH [IN]
</Name>
<Name>
SRINIVASAN DHEEPA [IN]
</Name>
<Name>
GRAY DENNIS MICHAEL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KRISHNAMURTHY, ANAND
</Name>
<Name>
BRUCE, ROBERT WILLIAM
</Name>
<Name>
SRINIDHI, SAMPATH
</Name>
<Name>
SRINIVASAN, DHEEPA
</Name>
<Name>
GRAY, DENNIS MICHAEL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
GEN ELECTRIC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1927670
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060125030
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060125030
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C22C19/07
</Class>
<Class>
C23C28/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C4/06
</Class>
<Class>
C23C4/12
</Class>
<Class>
F04D29/02
</Class>
<Class>
F16C33/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C28/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C28/3215
</Class>
<Class>
C23C28/324
</Class>
<Class>
C23C28/347
</Class>
<Class>
C23C28/42
</Class>
<Class>
C23C30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C4/06
</Class>
<Class>
C23C4/12D
</Class>
<Class>
C23C4/12L
</Class>
<Class>
F01D17/16B
</Class>
<Class>
F01D5/28F
</Class>
<Class>
F04D29/02C
</Class>
<Class>
F04D29/56C
</Class>
<Class>
F16C33/14
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A wear resistant coating (116) including a hard backing (118) including a metal alloy matrix dispersed with a plurality of hard particles;  and a plurality of nano-layers (120) disposed on the hard backing (118) is provided. The plurality of nano-layers (120) has different characteristics from one another. A method of making a wear resistant coating (116) is provided. The method includes the steps of providing a substrate;  disposing a hard backing (118);  and disposing a plurality of nano-layers (120) on the hard backing (118).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A wear resistant coating (116), comprising:
</P>
<P>
a hard backing (118) comprising a metal alloy matrix dispersed with a plurality of hard particles; and
</P>
<P>
a plurality of nano-layers (120) disposed on the hard backing (118), wherein the plurality of nano-layers (120) have different characteristics from one another.
</P>
<P>
2. The wear resistant coating (116) of claim 1, wherein the hard backing (118) has a hardness value of at least about 700 Vickers Hardness.
</P>
<P>
3. The wear resistant coating (116) of claim 1, wherein the metal alloy matrix comprises a material including cobalt, or cobalt chromium alloy, or cobalt alloy, or nickel alloy, or ferrous alloy, or nickel chromium aluminum alloy, or cobalt nickel chromium aluminum yttrium alloy, or nickel cobalt chromium tungsten alloy, or cobalt molybdenum chromium silicon alloy.
</P>
<P>
4. The wear resistant coating (116) of claim 1, wherein the plurality of hard particles comprise a material including tungsten carbide, or titanium carbide, or chromium carbide, or silicon carbide, or diamond, or titanium nitride, or silicon nitride, or cubic boron nitride, or titanium boride, or chromium oxide, or aluminium oxide, or zirconium oxide, or silicon oxide, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The wear resistant coating (116) of claim 1, wherein the nano-layer (120) comprises a material including a metal nitride, or a metal boride, or a metal carbide, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The wear resistant coating (116) of claim 1, wherein the hard backing (118) has a thickness in a range of from about 5 microns to about 500 microns.
</P>
<P>
7. A wear resistant coating (116) comprising:
</P>
<P>
a hard backing (118) comprising cobalt chromium alloy dispersed with nanoparticles of tungsten carbide; and
</P>
<P>
a plurality of alternate TiN and ZrN nano-layers disposed on the hard backing (118).
</P>
<P>
8. An article, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a component;
</P>
<P>
a wear resistant coating (116) disposed on the component, wherein the wear resistant coating (116) comprises a hard backing (118) comprising a metal alloy matrix dispersed with a plurality of hard particles; and a plurality of nano-layers (120) disposed on the hard backing (118).
</P>
<P>
9. The article of claim 8, wherein the article comprises an engine having the component.
</P>
<P>
10. The article of claim 9, wherein the engine comprises a turbine engine having a variable stator vane, wherein the variable stator vane comprises the component.
</P>
<P>
11. The article of claim 10, wherein the engine comprises a turbine engine having a variable stator vane comprising a trunnion and a bushing, wherein the bushing has an inner surface in contact with an outside surface of the trunnion, and wherein the inner surface of the bushing and the outer surface of the variable stator vane are coated with the wear resistant coating (116).
</P>
<P>
12. The article of claim 11, wherein the article comprises a transportation vehicle having the component.
</P>
</Claims>
</BiblioData>
