<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
HEAD USING NEAR- FIELD LIGHT AND INFORMATION RECORDER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1970903A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
OUMI MANABU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HIRATA MASAKAZU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
PARK MAJUNG [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OUMI, MANABU
</Name>
<Name>
HIRATA, MASAKAZU
</Name>
<Name>
PARK, MAJUNG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SEIKO INSTR INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SEIKO INSTRUMENTS INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1970903
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060834653
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP324899
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050377737
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01Q80/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B11/10
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q80/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/012
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/02
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/127P
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/31D8A2
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/1387
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention is a near-field optical head that generates near-field light to heat a predetermined area of a medium and applies a magnetic field to the predetermined area to record information, the head including an optical waveguide 103 having a path for propagating a pencil of light, and a tip 117 having an optical minute opening 118 at the position facing against the predetermined area and collecting the pencil of light emitted from the optical waveguide 103 and simultaneously propagating the collected pencil of light to the optical minute opening 118 to generate the near-field light. The optical minute opening 118 is formed by a magnetic pole that applies a magnetic field to the predetermined area.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Anear-field optical head that.generates near-field light to heat a predetermined area of a medium and applies a magnetic field to the predetermined area to record information, the head comprising:
</P>
<P>
an optical waveguide having a path for propagating a pencil of light; and
</P>
<P>
a near-field light generating element having a magnetic pole gap having an opening at the position facing against the predetermined area and collecting the pencil of light emitted from the optical waveguide and simultaneously propagating the collected pencil of light to the magnetic pole gap to generate the near-field light,wherein the magnetic pole gap is formed by a magnetic pole that applies a magnetic field to the predetermined area.
</P>
<P>
2. The near-field optical head according to Claim 1, wherein the near-field light generating element includes a pyramidal tip containing a transparent material, and the magnetic pole gap is formed at the pointed end of the pyramidal tip.
</P>
<P>
3. The near-field optical head according to Claim 2, wherein a part of the magnetic pole is provided at a part of a side of the pyramidal tip.
</P>
<P>
4. The near-field optical head according to Claim 1, the head further comprising a magnetic recording element having the magnetic pole and a coil that causes the magnetic pole to generate a magnetic field, wherein the near-field light generating element and the magnetic recording element are provided on a substantially flat-shaped substrate, the substrate has an air-bearing surface at the position where the substrate faces against the medium, and the air-bearing surface is formed such that the near-field light generating element and the magnetic recording element can levitate by keeping a predetermined distance from the surface of the medium by using the air-bearing force generated by the rotation of the medium.
</P>
<P>
5. The near-field optical head according to Claim 1, wherein the magnetic pole contains an opaque material.
</P>
<P>
6. The near-field optical head according to Claim 2, wherein a part of a side of the pyramidal tip has a metallic film.
</P>
<P>
7. The near-field optical head according to Claim 3, wherein the pyramidal tip has a quadrangular pyramid, and two facing sides of the four sides have a part of the magnetic pole.
</P>
<P>
8. The near-field optical head according to Claim 2, wherein the pyramidal tip has a quadrangular pyramid, and two facing sides of the four sides have a metallic film.
</P>
<P>
9. The near-field optical head according to Claim 4, further comprising a magneto-resistive element that reads information recorded on the medium,
</P>
<P>
wherein the magnetic tunnel junction is provided on the same substrate as that of the magnetic recording element.
</P>
<P>
10. An information recording apparatus comprising a light source, a medium that records information with the inversion of magnetization, a near-field optical head having a near-field light generating element that receives light from the light source and generates near-field light from an optical minute opening, a motor that rotates the medium, a suspension arm that brings the near-field optical head closely to the medium, and an actuator that moves the suspension arm to a predetermined position of the medium,
</P>
<P>
wherein the near-field optical head has a first magnetic pole and a second magnetic pole that faces against the first magnetic pole through a magnetic pole gap; and
</P>
<P>
the near-field optical head heats a surface of the medium by generating the near-field light from the optical minute opening and records information on the medium by inverting the magnetization with the magnetic field generated within the magnetic pole gap between the first magnetic pole and the second magnetic pole.
</P>
<P>
11. The information recording apparatus according to Claim 10, wherein the near-field light generating element has a pyramidal tip containing a transparent material, and the magnetic pole gap is provided at the pointed end of the pyramidal tip.
</P>
<P>
12. The information recording apparatus according to Claim 11, wherein a part of the first magnetic pole and the second magnetic pole is provided on a part of a side of the pyramidal tip.
</P>
<P>
13. The information recording apparatus according to Claim 10, the apparatus further comprising a light control section that controls the intensity of light from the light source, a magnetic field control section that controls the magnetic field generated from the magnetic pole gap and an apparatus control section that simultaneously performs modulation on the light control section and the magnetic field control section.
</P>
<P>
14. The information recording apparatus according to Claim 10, wherein the direction of the magnetization is substantially parallel to the surface of the medium.
</P>
<P>
15. The information recording apparatus according to Claim 10, wherein the direction of the magnetization is substantially perpendicular to the surface of the medium.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1970903A4;US2009028007A1;US8023366B2;WO2007074650A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
