<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
REACTANT LIQUID SYSTEM FOR FACILITATING THE PRODUCTION OF CARBON NANOSTRUCTURES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1928785A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WAGNER ANTHONY S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WAGNER, ANTHONY, S
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CLEAN TECHNOLOGIES INTERNAT CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CLEAN TECHNOLOGIES INTERNATIONAL CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1928785
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060851610
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-06-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US23962
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050173419
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-07-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/30
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B6
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B6
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/30
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method includes isolating carbon atoms as conditioned carbide anions below a surface of a reactant liquid. The conditioned carbide anions are then enabled to escape from the reactant liquid to a collection area where carbon nanostructures may form. A carbon structure produced in this fashion includes at least one layer made up of hexagonally arranged carbon atoms. Each carbon atom has three covalent bonds to adjoining carbon atoms and one unbound pi electron.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method including:
</P>
<P>
(a) introducing a carbon-bearing material into a reactant liquid;
</P>
<P>
(b) isolating carbon atoms from the carbon-bearing material as conditioned carbide anions located below a surface of the reactant liquid; and
</P>
<P>
(c) directing the conditioned carbide anions from the reactant liquid to a collection area.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 wherein the reactant liquid is made up of one or more liquid metals.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 2 wherein the reactant liquid includes predominantly aluminum.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 3 wherein the reactant liquid is held at a temperature of approximately 900 degrees Celsius.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 wherein the reactant liquid isolates carbon atoms from the carbon-bearing material by chemical reduction, chemical oxidation, or pyrolysis, or by reactions from acids, bases, or salts.
</P>
<P>
6. A method for placing carbon atoms in a state to facilitate carbon nanostructure assembly, the method including:
</P>
<P>
(a) isolating carbon atoms as conditioned carbide anions below a surface of a reactant liquid; and
</P>
<P>
(b) enabling the conditioned carbide anions to escape from the reactant liquid to a collection area.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 6 wherein the reactant liquid is made up of one or more liquid metals.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 7 wherein the reactant liquid includes predominantly aluminum.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 8 wherein the reactant liquid is held at a temperature of approximately 900 degrees Celsius.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 6 wherein the reactant liquid isolates carbon atoms from a carbon-bearing material by chemical reduction, chemical oxidation, or pyrolysis, or by reactions from acids, bases, or salts.
</P>
<P>
11. A carbon structure including at least one layer made up of hexagonally arranged carbon atoms, each carbon atom having three covalent bonds to adjoining carbon atoms and one unbound pi electron.
</P>
<P>
12. The carbon structure of claim 11 wherein the layer of hexagonally arranged carbon atoms is wrapped around a central axis to form a tubular shape.
</P>
<P>
13. The carbon structure of claim 12 further including at least one additional layer of hexagonally arranged carbon atoms, each carbon atom having one unbound pi electron and three covalent bonds to adjoining carbon atoms in the respective additional layer.
</P>
<P>
14. A method including:
</P>
<P>
(a) introducing a material made up of carbon nanostructures into a reactant liquid;
</P>
<P>
(b) separating carbon atoms from the carbon nanostructures and isolating the separated carbon atoms as conditioned carbide anions located below a surface of the reactant liquid; and
</P>
<P>
(c) directing the conditioned carbide anions from the reactant liquid to a recovery area.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14 wherein the step of directing the conditioned carbide anions from the reactant liquid to the recovery area includes causing the conditioned carbide anions to flow over a collection surface within the recovery area.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 14 wherein the step of directing the conditioned carbide anions from the reactant liquid to the recovery area includes causing the conditioned carbide anions to flow along a particle formation path through a phase changing area so that the liberated carbon atoms are enabled to phase change to the ground state in the phase changing area.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 14 wherein the reactant liquid is made up of one or more liquid metals.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 17 wherein the reactant liquid includes predominantly aluminum.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 18 wherein the reactant liquid is held at a temperature of approximately 900 degrees Celsius.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 14 wherein the reactant liquid isolates carbon atoms from the carbon nanostructures by chemical reduction, chemical oxidation, or pyrolysis, or by reactions from acids, bases, or salts.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1928785A4;US2006008403A1;WO2008036065A2;WO2008036065A3;US2008050303A1;US7815886B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
