<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Method for producing zirconia sol
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1994979A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KATO HIROKAZU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUIHIJI NATSUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHMORI YUTAKA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KATO, HIROKAZU
</Name>
<Name>
TSUIHIJI, NATSUMI
</Name>
<Name>
OHMORI, YUTAKA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NISSAN CHEMICAL IND LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NISSAN CHEMICAL INDUSTRIES, LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1994979
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080156809
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070136303
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-23
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J13/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J13/00B2
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G25/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A production method of a zirconia sol includes;  (A) mixing a dicarboxylic acid compound with a zirconium compound in an aqueous medium, in which a molar ratio of the dicarboxylic acid compound is more than 1 and less than or equal to 10 per mol of zirconium atom in the zirconium compound, and (B) adding 0.7-2.5 mol of a water-soluble organic base per mol of the dicarboxylic acid compound contained in a mixture obtained by the process (A) to the mixture and then treating hydrothermally the resultant mixture.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for producing a zirconia sol, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
(A) mixing a dicarboxylic acid compound with a zirconium compound in an aqueous medium, wherein a molar ratio of the dicarboxylic acid compound is more than 1 and less than or equal to 10 per mol of zirconium atom in the zirconium compound; and
</P>
<P>
(B) adding 0.7-2.5 mol of a water-soluble organic base per mol of the dicarboxylic acid compound contained in a mixture obtained by the process (A) to the mixture and then treating hydrothermally a resultant mixture.
</P>
<P>
2. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to claim 1, wherein a temperature of the hydrothermal treatment of the process (B) is 110-250 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
3. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to claim 1 or 2, further comprising washing and condensation after the process (B).
</P>
<P>
4. A method for producing a zirconia sol, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
(A) mixing a dicarboxylic acid compound with a zirconium compound in an aqueous medium, wherein a molar ratio of the dicarboxylic acid compound is more than 1 and less than or equal to 10 per mol of zirconium atom in the zirconium compound; and
</P>
<P>
(B&apos;) after heating a mixture obtained by the process (A) to 50-100 deg. C, adding 0.7-2.5 mol of a water-soluble organic base per mol of the dicarboxylic acid compound contained in the mixture to the mixture and then treating hydrothermally a resultant mixture.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to claim 4, wherein a temperature of the hydrothermal treatment of the process (B&apos;) is 110-250 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to claim 4 or 5, further comprising washing and condensation after the process (B&apos;).
</P>
<P>
7. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein at least one compound selected from a group consisting of oxalic acid, malonic acid, malic acid, tartaric acid, succinic acid, adipic acid, maleic acid and itaconic acid is used as the
</P>
<P>
8. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein at least one compound selected from a group consisting of zirconium nitrate, zirconium oxychloride, zirconium oxynitrate, zirconium oxysulfate and zirconium oxycarbonate is used as the zirconium compound.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein an organic amine compound or a quaternary ammonium hydroxide is used as the water-soluble organic base.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein at least one compound selected from a group consisting of methylamine, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, methanolamine, dimethanolamine, trimethanolamine, ethylamine, diethylamine, triethylamine, ethanolamine, diethanolamine, triethanolamine, N-methylethanolamine, N-methyldiethanolamine, dimethylethanolamine, n-propylamine, di-n-propylamine, tri-n-propylamine, n-propanolamine, di-n-propanolamine, tri-n-propanolamine, isopropylamine, diisopropylamine, triisopropylamine, isopropanolamine, diisopropanolamine, triisopropanolainine, n-butylamine, di-n-butylamine, n-butanolamine, di-n-butanolamine, tri-n-butanolamine, isobutylamine, diisobutylamine, isobutanolamine, diisobutanolamine, triisobutanolamine, benzylamine, phenylamine, piperazine, piperidine and ethylenediamine is used as the organic amine compound.
</P>
<P>
11. The method for producing a zirconia sol according to any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein at least one compound selected from a group consisting of tetrametlaylamrnonium hydroxide, tetraethylammonium hydroxide, tetrapropylammonium hydroxide, tetraisopropylammonium hydroxide, tetrabutylammonium hydroxide, monomethyltriethylammonium hydroxide, monomethyltriethanolammonium hydroxide, monomethyltributylammonium hydroxide, octyltrimethylammonium hydroxide, benzyltrimethylammonium hydroxide, benzyltrietbylamrnonium hydroxide, benzyltributylammonium hydroxide, phenyltrimethylammonium hydroxide and phenyltriethylammonium hydroxide is used as the quaternary ammonium hydroxide.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008293831A1;TW200911698A;KR20080103445A;JP2008290896A;CN101311121A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
