<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
INTERFACE CONDITIONING TO IMPROVE EFFICIENCY AND LIFETIME OF ORGANIC ELECTROLUMINESCENCE DEVICES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1938401A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHOONG VI-EN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOULIS STELIOS A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MATHAI MATHEW [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOONG, VI-EN
</Name>
<Name>
CHOULIS, STELIOS A
</Name>
<Name>
MATHAI, MATHEW
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
OSRAM OPTO SEMICONDUCTORS GMBH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
OSRAM OPTO SEMICONDUCTORS GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1938401
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060792069
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006EP08975
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050236176
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L51/50
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/50E
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
In at least one embodiment of the invention, an OLED device is disclosed in which the surface of one or more layers of the OLED are conditioned with metal nano-particles such that they are disposed along the interface between adjacent layers.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An electroluminescent device, comprising:
</P>
<P>
an anode layer;
</P>
<P>
a cathode layer; and
</P>
<P>
an stack of layers between said anode layer and said cathode layer, said stack of layers including at least one layer comprising organic material, wherein at least one nano-particle is disposed in at least one interface between layers in said stack of layers or between said stack of layers and said cathode layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The device according to claim 1 wherein said stack of layers includes at least one of:
</P>
<P>
an anode buffer layer disposed over said anode layer;
</P>
<P>
an emissive layer, said emissive layer capable of emitting light; and
</P>
<P>
a hole transporting interlayer.
</P>
<P>
3. The device according to claim 2 further wherein any of said layers in said stack of layers may also comprise a light emissive component.
</P>
<P>
4. The device according to claim 1 wherein any layers within said stack of layers are formed at least in part using at least one polymer organic material.
</P>
<P>
5. The device according to claim 1 wherein any layers within said stack of layers are formed at least in part using at least one small molecule material.
</P>
<P>
6. The device according to claim 2 wherein said emissive layer comprises a conjugated poly-p-phenylenevinylene polymer.
</P>
<P>
7. The device according to claim 2 wherein said emissive layer comprises a conjugated polyspiro polymer.
</P>
<P>
8. The device according to claim 2 wherein said emissive layer comprises a conjugated fluorene polymer.
</P>
<P>
9. The device according to claim 1 wherein said at least one nano-particle comprises at least one of Ag, Au, Ni, Fe, Co, Ge, Cu, Pt, Pd, Os, Ti, Si or compounds thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. The device according to claim 3 wherein said light emissive component comprises at least one phosphorescence-based emitter.
</P>
<P>
11. The device according to claim 3 wherein said light emissive component comprises at least one fluorescence-based emitter.
</P>
<P>
12. The device according to claim 3 wherein said light emissive component comprises at least one based-based emitter and at least one fluorescence-based emitter.
</P>
<P>
13. The device according to claim 1 wherein said at least one nano-particle is disposed by at least one of sputtering, spin coating, spray coating, or thermal evaporation.
</P>
<P>
14. The device according to claim 1 wherein said at least one nano-particle forms into an ultra-thin layer of nano-particles upon being disposed.
</P>
<P>
15. The device according to claim 1 wherein each of said at least one nano-particle has a size ranging from 0.01 to 10 nano-meters.
</P>
<P>
16. The device according to claim 1 wherein said at least one nano-particle comprises a core of a first material and a shell of a second different material.
</P>
<P>
17. The device according to claim 16 wherein said first material is silica.
</P>
<P>
18. The device according to claim 17 wherein said second material comprises at least one of Ag, Au, Ni, Fe, Co, Ge, Cu, Pt, Pd, Os, Ti, Si or compounds thereof.
</P>
<P>
19. The device of claim 1 wherein said at least one nano-particle has an absorption spectrum which overlaps the triplet exciton state of the material in either one of the layers defining the interface wherein said at least one nano-particle is disposed.
</P>
<P>
20. The device of claim 19 wherein said at least one nano-particle has a resonance with the triplet exciton state of the material in either one of the layers defining the interface wherein said at least one nano-particle is disposed.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007069199A1;US8101941B2;KR20080056746A;JP2009510746A;WO2007039062A1;DE112006002463T5;CN101292372A;CN101292372B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
