<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ABRASIVE PARTICULATE MATERIAL, AND METHOD OF PLANARIZING A WORKPIECE USING THE ABRASIVE PARTICULATE MATERIAL
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1934300A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HAERLE ANDREW G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WANG JUN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HAERLE, ANDREW, G
</Name>
<Name>
WANG, JUN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SAINT GOBAIN CERAMICS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SAINT-GOBAIN CERAMICS AND PLASTICS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1934300
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060825992
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-13
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US40295
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-13
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050251633
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09G1/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/14B
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/14D2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An abrasive particulate material is disclosed that includes alumina particles. The alumina particles include a transition alumina and at least 5.0 wt % of an amorphous phase. The transition alumina particles also have a density not greater than about 3.20 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An abrasive particulate material comprising:
</P>
<P>
alumina particles comprising transition alumina and at least 5.0 wt % of an amorphous phase, the alumina particles having a density not greater than about 3.20 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
2. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the transition alumina comprises at least one of gamma phase alumina and delta phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
3. The abrasive particulate material of claim 2, wherein the transition alumina comprises delta phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
4. The abrasive particulate material of claim 2, wherein the alumina particles comprise not less than about 20 wt % gamma phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
5. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the transition alumina comprises theta phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
6. The abrasive particulate material of claim 5, wherein the alumina particles comprise not less than about 5 wt % theta phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
7-11. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
12. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles comprise not less than about 5.0 wt % amorphous phase and not greater than about 40 wt % amorphous phase, the balance of the particles consisting essentially of the transition alumina.
</P>
<P>
13. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles have a density not greater than about 3.00 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
14. The abrasive particulate material of claim 13, wherein the alumina particles have a density not greater than about 2.95 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
15-16. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
17. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles have a specific surface area not less than about 100 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; /g
</P>
<P>
18. The abrasive particulate material of claim 17, wherein the specific surface area is not less than about 125 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; /g.
</P>
<P>
19. The abrasive particulate material of claim 18, wherein the specific surface area is not less than about 150 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; /g.
</P>
<P>
20. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles comprise an elongated morphology.
</P>
<P>
21. The abrasive particulate material of claim 20, wherein the alumina particles are platelet-shaped, having a primary aspect ratio not less than about 3:1 and a secondary aspect ratio not less than about 3:1
</P>
<P>
22. The abrasive particulate material of claim 20, wherein the alumina particles are needle-shaped, having a primary aspect ratio not less than about 3:1 and a secondary aspect ratio not greater than about 3:1
</P>
<P>
23. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles have an average primary particle size not greater than about 85 nm.
</P>
<P>
24. The abrasive particulate material of claim 23, wherein the average primary particle size is not greater than about 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
25. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
26. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles have an average secondary particle size not greater than about 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
27. The abrasive particulate material of claim 26, wherein the average secondary particle size is not greater than about 150 nm.
</P>
<P>
28. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
29. The abrasive particulate material of claim 1, wherein the abrasive particulate material comprises a slurry.
</P>
<P>
30-34. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
35. The abrasive particulate material of claim 29, wherein the slurry has a colloidal stability as determined by a sedimentation height of about 0.0 mm after 3 days.
</P>
<P>
36. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
37. An abrasive particulate material comprising:
</P>
<P>
alumina particles comprising transition alumina and at least 5.0 wt % of an amorphous phase, wherein the transition alumina includes theta phase and at least one of gamma phase and delta phase.
</P>
<P>
38. The abrasive particulate material of claim 37, wherein the alumina particles comprise not less than about 20% gamma phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
39. The abrasive particulate material of claim 37, wherein the transition alumina comprises delta phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
40. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
41. The abrasive particulate material of claim 37, wherein a majority of the transition alumina comprises at least one of or a combination of gamma phase and delta phase, the alumina particles comprising 30 to 70 wt % of at least one of or a combination of gamma phase and delta phase, and 5 to 45 wt % theta phase.
</P>
<P>
42. The abrasive particulate material of claim 37, wherein the alumina particles comprise not less than about 10 wt % amorphous phase.
</P>
<P>
43-55. (canceled)
</P>
<P>
56. A method of forming an abrasive particulate material comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing feedstock particles containing principally transition alumina; and
</P>
<P>
milling the feedstock particles to form alumina particles comprising transition alumina and not less than about 5.0 wt % of an amorphous phase, the alumina particles having a density not greater than about 3.20 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
57-85. (canceled)
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1934300B1;US2007084134A1;ZA200803185A;WO2007047547A2;WO2007047547A3;TWI308928B;RU2008114107A;RU2401856C2;NZ567318A;NO20082195A;MY145461A;KR20080066799A;JP2009511719A;CN101370896A;CA2625273A1;CA2625273C;BRPI0617413A2;AU2006304356A1;AU2006304356B2;AT555179T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
