<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOARRAYS OF BIOLOGICAL PARTICLES, METHODS FOR THE FABRICATION THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1931989A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MIRKIN CHAD A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
VEGA RAFAEL A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MASPOCH DANIEL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SALAITA KHALID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MIRKIN, CHAD, A
</Name>
<Name>
VEGA, RAFAEL, A
</Name>
<Name>
MASPOCH, DANIEL
</Name>
<Name>
SALAITA, KHALID
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV NORTHWESTERN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1931989
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060851430
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-08-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US32316
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050712432P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-08-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N33/50
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K31/70
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12N7/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/569K
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A novel coordination chemistry or metal ion binding approach to controlling the site-isolation and orientation of virus particles, such as TMV, on a nanoarray template generated by lithography including Dip Pen Nanolithography. By using the surface chemistry that is inherent in many viruses, metal-ion based or inorganic coordination chemistry was used to immobilize individual virus particles without the need for their genetic modification. Single particle control will enable a wide variety of studies involving viruses that are not possible with microarrays because of the size mismatch between the architecture of the virus and the features that make up such arrays.;  These include: single particle, single cell infectivity studies, the exploration of such structures as templates in materials synthesis and molecular electronics, and studies aimed at understanding how surface presentation can influence their bioactivity. This is a pioneering example of such control at the single-particle level, and therefore, commercial use of nanoarrays in biological systems.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. An array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate surface, wherein the substrate surface comprises virus binding sites and also sites which do not bind virus, wherein the virus binding sites on the substrate surface each have a shape and a size; and
</P>
<P>
one virus particle disposed on each of the binding sites, wherein the shape and the size of the virus binding site provides that only one virus particle is disposed on each binding site.
</P>
<P>
2. The array according to claim 1, wherein the substrate surface is substantially flat.
</P>
<P>
3. The array according to claim 1, wherein the sites which do not bind virus are passivated against virus binding.
</P>
<P>
4. The array according to claim 1, wherein the sites which do not bind virus are substantially free of virus.
</P>
<P>
5. The array according to claim 1, wherein the virus binding sites comprises ionic binding sites.
</P>
<P>
6. The array according to claim 1, wherein the virus binding sites comprise multivalent metallic ionic binding sites.
</P>
<P>
7. The array according to claim 1, wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of less than about 100,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
8. The array according to claim 1, wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of less than about 50,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
9. The array according to claim 1, wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of about 30,000 square nm to about 100,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
10. The array according to claim 1, wherein the shape of the virus binding sites is substantially a circle, a linear shape, a curvilinear shape, a square, or a rectangle.
</P>
<P>
11. The array according to claim 1, wherein the shape of the virus binding sites comprises a rectangle having a length of about 300 nm to about 600 nm, and a width of about 100 nm to about 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
12. The array according to claim 1, wherein the virus has an anisotropic shape.
</P>
<P>
13. The array according to claim 1, wherein the virus has a tubular shape.
</P>
<P>
14. The array according to claim 1, wherein the virus particle comprises an additional moiety bound to the virus.
</P>
<P>
15. The array according to claim 1, wherein the virus binding sites and sites which do not bind virus comprise a monolayer.
</P>
<P>
16. The array according to claim 1, wherein the shape and size of each of the virus binding sites are substantially the same, and the sites which do not bind virus are passivated against virus binding so that they are substantially free of virus.
</P>
<P>
17. The array according to claim 16, wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of less than about 100,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
18. The array according to claim 16, wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of less than about 50,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
19. The array according to claim 1, wherein the shape of the virus binding sites is substantially a circle, a linear shape, a curvilinear shape, a square, or a rectangle, and the shape and size of each of the virus binding sites are substantially the same.
</P>
<P>
20. An array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of virus binding sites on a substantially flat substrate surface, wherein the sites are surrounded by passivated substrate surface passivated against virus binding,
</P>
<P>
wherein the virus binding sites comprise ionic groups for binding virus and have a shape and size so that only one virus particle binds to each site, and
</P>
<P>
wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of about 30,000 square nm to about 100,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
21. The array according to claim 20, wherein the virus binding sites comprise metal ions.
</P>
<P>
22. The array according to claim 20, wherein the virus binding sites comprise transition metal ions.
</P>
<P>
23. The array according to claim 20, wherein the virus binding sites comprise divalent metal ions.
</P>
<P>
24. The array according to claim 20, wherein the array further comprises virus bound to the binding sites.
</P>
<P>
25. The array according to claim 24, wherein the virus is a wild type virus.
</P>
<P>
26. An array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of virus binding sites on a substantially flat substrate surface, wherein the sites are surrounded by passivated substrate surface passivated against virus binding,
</P>
<P>
wherein the virus binding sites have a shape and size so that only one virus particle binds to each site,
</P>
<P>
wherein the average size of the virus binding sites provides a surface area of about 30,000 square nm to about 100,000 square nm for each site,
</P>
<P>
one virus bound to each site, wherein the virus in an unbound shape presents a cross-sectional surface area which is less than about 100,000 square nm.
</P>
<P>
27. The array according to claim 26, wherein the virus is a wild type virus.
</P>
<P>
28. The array according to claim 26, wherein the binding sites comprising metal ions.
</P>
<P>
29. An array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate surface, wherein the substrate surface comprises binding sites for a biological particle and also sites which do not bind the biological particle, wherein the binding sites on the substrate surface each have a shape and a size; and
</P>
<P>
one biological particle disposed on each of the binding sites.
</P>
<P>
30. The array according to claim 29, wherein the biological particle is a virus, a protein, an antibody, or a cell.
</P>
<P>
31. The array according to claim 29, wherein the biological particle is an antibody.
</P>
<P>
32. The array according to claim 29, wherein the biological particle assumes a specific orientation.
</P>
<P>
33. An array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate surface, wherein the substrate surface comprises virus binding sites and also sites which do not bind virus, wherein the virus binding sites on the substrate surface each have a shape and a size; and
</P>
<P>
one virus particle disposed on each of the binding sites.
</P>
<P>
34. A method of making an array comprising the combination of steps:
</P>
<P>
providing a substrate surface,
</P>
<P>
modifying the substrate surface to provide virus binding sites and also sites which do not bind virus,
</P>
<P>
binding virus to the virus binding sites so that substantially only one virus particle binds to each site.
</P>
<P>
35. The method according to claim 34, wherein the virus binding sites comprise metal ion binding sites.
</P>
<P>
36. The method according to claim 34, wherein the virus binding sites comprise divalent cation metal binding sites.
</P>
<P>
37. The method according to claim 34, wherein the virus binding sites have a lateral dimension less than about one micron.
</P>
<P>
38. The method according to claim 34, wherein the virus binding sites provide a surface area of less than about 100,000 square nm for each site.
</P>
<P>
39. The method according to claim 34, wherein the virus is a wild type virus.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1931989B1;US2007129321A1;US7569340B2;WO2008020851A2;WO2008020851A3;KR20080046690A;JP2009521663A;ES2362797T3;AT502299T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
