<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING FULLERENE DISPERSION LIQUID, AND FULLERENE DISPERSION LIQUID
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1939140A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ASAHI TSUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MASUHARA HIROSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUGIYAMA TERUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
WANG YONG [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
RYO SEN-ICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ASAHI, TSUYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
MASUHARA, HIROSHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUGIYAMA, TERUKI
</Name>
<Name>
WANG, YONG
</Name>
<Name>
RYO, SEN-ICHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV OSAKA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ABSIZE INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ABSIZE INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1939140
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060782056
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-07-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP315178
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050232390
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-08-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J19/12B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
(Problems to be solved) The present invention provides a fullerene suspension and a method for producing a fullerene suspension having high dispersion stability without any chemical compound. Also, the fullerene suspension and its producing method makes it possible to be applied in various fields including the field of medical and pharmaceutical science and the field of foods and environment, in which the fullerene suspension obtained by the prior methods had not been applied. (Means for solving the problems) The fullerene is ground to form nanoparticles by irradiating a fullerene in a poor solvent with a laser. The pulse laser having a width of several-ten femtoseconds to several-hundred nanoseconds is appropriately applied.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for producing a fullerene suspension comprising:
</P>
<P>
irradiating fullerene in poor solvent with laser to crush the fullerene into the nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
2. The method for producing the fullerene suspension according to Claim 1, the step of irradiating fullerene in poor solvent with laser includes stirring the fullerene mixed with poor solvent.
</P>
<P>
3. The method for producing the fullerene suspension according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein pulse laser is used as the laser.
</P>
<P>
4. The method for producing the fullerene suspension according to Claim 3, wherein the pulse laser has a width of several-ten femtoseconds to several-hundred nanoseconds.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for producing the fullerene suspension according to Claim 3 or Claim 4, wherein the pulse laser is irradiated at an excitation light intensity of 30 to 50 mJ /cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing the fullerene suspension according to any one of Claim 1 to Claim 5, wherein the fullerene is C60 fullerene.
</P>
<P>
7. The fullerene suspension, wherein the methods in any one of Claim 1 to Claim 5 is applied for the produce.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1939140A4;US2008217445A1;US7900855B2;WO2007018068A1;JP2007045674A;CN101316793A;CA2618811A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
