<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ELECTROMAGNETIC WAVE ABSORBER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1947923A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
UMISHITA KAZUNORI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO TSUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UMISHITA, KAZUNORI
</Name>
<Name>
OKUBO, TSUYOSHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RES INST INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI BUSSAN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BUSSAN NANOTECH RESEARCH INSTITUTE INC
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI &amp; CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1947923
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060821927
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP320733
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050305072
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-19
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01Q17/00
</Class>
<Class>
H05K9/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01Q17/00C
</Class>
<Class>
H01Q17/00E
</Class>
<Class>
H05K9/00M4B
</Class>
<Class>
H05K9/00M4F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
By using a high electromagnetic wave absorbing loss material and adding it in a small amount to a matrix, an electromagnetic wave absorber useful for GHz band, which can demonstrate the electromagnetic wave absorption capability without ruining characteristics of the matrix, and can enjoy a good formability and a low manufacturing cost, is provided.;  The disclosed is an electromagnetic wave absorber which is characterized in that carbon fibrous structures are contained in the matrix, at a rate of 0.01 - 25 % by weight based on the total weight, wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Electromagnetic wave absorber which includes carbon fibrous structures, at a rate of 0.01 - 25 % by weight based on the total weight, in a matrix, wherein the carbon fibrous structure comprises a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers.
</P>
<P>
2. The electromagnetic wave absorber according to Claim 1, wherein the carbon fibrous structures have ID/IG ratio determined by Raman spectroscopy of not more than 0.2.
</P>
<P>
3. The electromagnetic wave absorber according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein the matrix comprises an organic polymer.
</P>
<P>
4. The electromagnetic wave absorber according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein the matrix comprises an inorganic material.
</P>
<P>
5. The electromagnetic wave absorber according to one of Claims 1-4, wherein a filling agent selected from the group consisting of metallic particles, silica, calcium carbonate, magnesium carbonate, carbon blacks, carbon fibers, glass fibers, and blends of two or more of these materials is further added therein.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1947923A4;US2009135042A1;WO2007046412A1;JP2007115854A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
