<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ABSORBENT ARTICLE COMPRISING A THIN FILM INCLUDING AN ACTIVE AGENT
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1931398A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BERLAND CAROLYN [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
ABBAS SHABIRA [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
BERLAND, CAROLYN
</Name>
<Name>
ABBAS, SHABIRA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SCA HYGIENE PROD AB [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
SCA HYGIENE PRODUCTS AB
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1931398
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20050805159
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2005-10-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2005EP10737
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61L15/22
</Class>
<Class>
A61L15/44
</Class>
<Class>
A61L15/46
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61L15/22M
</Class>
<Class>
A61L15/44
</Class>
<Class>
A61L15/46
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to an absorbent article such as a diaper, panty diaper, panty liner, sanitary napkin or incontinence device, wherein at least one part of said absorbent article carries a film comprising at least one monomolecular layer of a polymer having a functional group and an active agent, in particular to an absorbent article wherein the film is obtainable by layer-by-layer deposition of at least a first polymer having a first functional group and a second polymer having a second functional group capable of interacting with the first functional group. Moreover, the invention pertains to the use of a film obtainable by the layer-by-layer deposition of at least one first polymer having a first functional group and a second polymer having a second functional group capable of interacting with the first functional group for releasing an active agent contained in said film upon wetting of said film by body fluids. Preferably the first polymer having a first functional group is a polycationic polymer and the second polymer having a second functional group is a polyanionic polymer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
C L A I M S
</P>
<P>
1. Absorbent article such as a diaper, panty diaper, panty liner, sanitary napkin or incontinence device, wherein at least one part of said absorbent article carries a film comprising at least one monomolecular layer of a polymer having a functional group and an active agent.
</P>
<P>
2. Absorbent article according to claim 1, wherein the film is obtainable by layer-by-layer deposition of at least a first polymer having a first functional group and a second polymer having a second functional group capable of interacting with the first functional group.
</P>
<P>
3. Absorbent article according to claim 1 or 2 wherein the film is composed of 2 or more layers.
</P>
<P>
4. Absorbent article according to any of claims 1 to 3 , wherein the film has a thickness below 1 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
5. Absorbent article according to any of claims 1 to 4, wherein the functional group is selected from polar groups, in particular from anionic and cationic groups.
</P>
<P>
6. Absorbent article according to any of claims 2 to 5, wherein the interaction between the first functional group and the second functional group is selected from electrostatic attraction, donor/acceptor interaction, hydrogen bonding or specific recognition.
</P>
<P>
7. Absorbent article according to any of claims 1 to 6, wherein the active agent is selected from odour-controlling agents and/or skin care agents.
</P>
<P>
8. Absorbent article according to claim 7 wherein the skin care agents are selected from naturally occurring active agents or mixtures thereof .
</P>
<P>
9. Absorbent article according to claim 7, wherein the odour- controlling agents are selected from bacteriostatic or bactericidal agents, pH control agents, odour-absorbing particles, odour-decomposing catalysts and odour-masking compounds .
</P>
<P>
10. Absorbent article according to any of claims 2, 3 or 4 , wherein the first polymer is a polycationic polymer and the second polymer is a polyanionic polymer.
</P>
<P>
11. Absorbent article according to claim 10, wherein the polycationic polymer is selected from cationic or cationically modified polysaccharides, polyalIyIamine homo- or copolymers, polyvinylamines homo- or copolymers or polyethylenemine .
</P>
<P>
12. Absorbent article according to claim 10, wherein the polyanionic polymer is selected from (meth) acrylic acid homo- or copolymers, anionic starch derivatives and anionic cellulose derivatives .
</P>
<P>
13. Absorbent article according to any of claims 10, 11 or 12, wherein the film comprises at least one polycationic, at least one polyanionic polymer and a charged active agent .
</P>
<P>
14. Absorbent article according to claim 13, wherein the charged active agent is selected from active agents as defined in any of claims 7 , 8 or 9.
</P>
<P>
15. Absorbent article according to any of claims 2, 3 or 4 , wherein the first polymer is a hydrogen bond donor polymer and the second polymer a hydrogen bond acceptor polymer.
</P>
<P>
16. Absorbent article according to claim 15, wherein the hydrogen bond donor polymer is selected from polycarboxylic acid, a polynucleotide, a polymer of vinylnucleic acid, a polyaminoacid, a polyalcohol and a copolymer thereof.
</P>
<P>
17. Absorbent article according to claim 15, wherein the hydrogen bond acceptor polymer is selected from a polyether, polyketone, a polyaldehyde, a polyacrylamide, other polyamides, a polyamine, a polyurethane , a polyester, a polyphosphazene or polysaccharide or copolymer thereof .
</P>
<P>
18. Absorbent article according to any of claims 15, 16 or 17, wherein the film comprises at least one hydrogen bond donor polymer, at least one hydrogen bond acceptor polymer and an active agent comprising at least one hydrogen bond donor and/or acceptor moiety.
</P>
<P>
19. Absorbent article according claim 18, wherein the active agent comprising at least one hydrogen bond donor and/or acceptor moiety is selected from active agents as defined in any of claims 7, 8 or 9.
</P>
<P>
20. Absorbent article according to any of claims 10, 11 or 12 wherein at least one layer of alternating cationic and anionic polymers is replaced by a layer of inorganic particles or other charged active agents.
</P>
<P>
21. Absorbent article according to claim 20, wherein the particles are selected from bacteriostatic or bactericidal metal particles, odour-decomposing metal particles and odour absorbing particles .
</P>
<P>
22. Absorbent article according to any of claims 2, 3 or 4 , wherein the film obtainable by layer-by-layer deposition comprises at least one bacteriostatic or bactericidal polycationic polymer as active agent being present as upper layer of said film.
</P>
<P>
23. Absorbent article according to claim 16, wherein the bacteriostatic or bactericidal polycationic polymer is chitosan.
</P>
<P>
24. Absorbent article according to any of claims 10, 11 or 12, wherein the active agent comprises bacteriostatic or bactericidal metal ions such as silver ions or bacteriostatic or bactericidal metal particles such as silver particles dispersed through at least a part of the film.
</P>
<P>
25. Absorbent article according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the part comprising the film is selected from a topsheet, backsheet, layers arranged between topsheet and the absorbent layer, fibers or particles, a waistband and leg cuffs.
</P>
<P>
26. Absorbent article according to claim 25, wherein the absorbent article is a diaper or incontinence device and the part thereof carrying the film is selected from a topsheet, gasketing and/or front barrier cuffs, said film being as defined in claim 14, in claim 19, in claim 21, in claims 22 or 23 or in claim 24.
</P>
<P>
27. Absorbent article according to claim 1, 25 or 26, wherein the diaper part selected from a topsheet, gasketing and/or front barrier cuffs is made from a hydrophobic material and is subjected to corona or plasma treatment prior to deposition of the film.
</P>
<P>
28. Use of a film obtainable by the layer-by-layer deposition of at least one first polymer having a first functional group and a second polymer having a second functional group capable of interacting with the first functional group for releasing an active agent contained in said film upon wetting of said film by body fluids .
</P>
<P>
29. Use according to claim 28, wherein the first polymer having a first functional group is a polycationic polymer and the second polymer having a second functional group is a polyanionic polymer .
</P>
<P>
30. Use according to claim 28 or 29 wherein said film is carried by at least one part of an absorbent article, such as a diaper, panty diaper, panty liner, sanitary napkin or incontinence device.
</P>
<P>
31. Use according to claim 28 wherein said film is defined as in any of claims 3, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21 or 24.
</P>
<P>
32. Use according to claim 28, 29, 30 or 31, wherein the body- fluids are selected from urine, watery feces, menstrual fluid and female secretion.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007038966A1;US2009275906A1;JP2009509702A;CN101277727A;CA2624464A1;BRPI0520627A2;AU2005337071A1;AU2005337071B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
