<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
STABILIZATION OF POLYMERS WITH ZINC OXIDE NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1969046A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MIYATAKE NOBUO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SUE HUNG-JUE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LI YUNTAO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAGUCHI KATSUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MIYATAKE, NOBUO
</Name>
<Name>
SUE, HUNG-JUE
</Name>
<Name>
LI, YUNTAO
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAGUCHI, KATSUMI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TEXAS A &amp; M UNIV SYS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KANEKA CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
THE TEXAS A&amp;M UNIVERSITY SYSTEM
</Name>
<Name>
KANEKA CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1969046
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060845793
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-19
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US48387
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-19
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050312043
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B13/32
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/22
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/32
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A composition and method of making a stabilizer for polymers. The composition has zinc oxide (ZnO) nanoparticles dispersed and having an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers, wherein the ZnO nanoparticles are provided as an additive to a polymeric material, thereby forming a stabilized polymer composite in which the ZnO nanoparticles remain dispersed and have an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers. The stabilized polymer composite is stabilized against heat and ultraviolet light. The polymeric material can be a (meth)acrylic resin, a styrenic resin, a pre-cure epoxy resin, or combinations thereof. In a concentrated form, the composition has ZnO nanoparticles that are typically less than 20% of the stabilized polymer composite. The stabilizer is polymerizable and may include additional additives.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A stabilizer composition comprising: zinc oxide nanoparticles dispersed and having an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers, wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are provided as an additive to a polymeric material, thereby forming a stabilized polymer composite in which the zinc oxide nanoparticles remain dispersed and have an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
2. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the stabilized polymer composite is stabilized against heat and ultraviolet light.
</P>
<P>
3. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are less than about 20% of the stabilized polymer composite.
</P>
<P>
4. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the polymeric material is a (meth)acrylic resin, a styrenic resin, a pre-cure epoxy resin, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are modified on their surface to reduce aggregation.
</P>
<P>
6. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are about 2.5% of the stabilized polymer composite. 7. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the average size is three nanometers or less.
</P>
<P>
8. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein stabilizer composition is an additive.
</P>
<P>
9. The stabilizer composition of claim 1 , wherein the stabilizer composition further comprises a second additive selected from the group consisting of dispersant, thermal stabilizer, polymer processing aid, flame retardant, impact modifier, plasticizer, UV absorber, pigment, glass fiber, curing agent, lubricant, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. A stabilizer composition comprising: zinc oxide nanoparticles, dispersed and having an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers, wherein the metal oxide is formed from a zinc oxide precursor; and a polymeric material comprising a (meth)acrylic resin, a styrenic resin, a pre-cure epoxy resin, and combinations thereof, combined with the zinc oxide nanoparticles to form a stabilized polymer composite, wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles remain dispersed and have an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers. 11. The stabilizer composition of claim 10, wherein the stabilizer composition is an additive.
</P>
<P>
12. The stabilizer composition of claim 11 , wherein the additive is a stabilizer against heat and ultraviolet light.
</P>
<P>
13. The stabilizer composition of claim 10, wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are modified on their surface to reduce aggregation.
</P>
<P>
14. The stabilizer composition of claim 10, wherein the stabilizer composition further comprises a second additive selected from the group consisting of dispersant, thermal stabilizer, polymer processing aid, flame retardant, impact modifier, plasticizer, UV absorber, pigment, glass fiber, curing agent, lubricant, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
15. The stabilizer composition of claim 10, wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are less than about 20% of the stabilized polymer composite.
</P>
<P>
16. A method of providing a stabilizer composition comprising the steps of: dispersing zinc oxide nanoparticles having an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers in a polymeric material comprising (meth)acrylic resin, a styrenic resin, a pre-cure epoxy resin, and combinations thereof, thereby forming a stabilized polymer composite, wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles remain dispersed and have an average size of no more than about 15 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16, wherein the zinc oxide nanoparticles are modified on their surface to reduce aggregation. 18. The method of claim 16, wherein the average size is three nanometers or less.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 16, wherein the method further comprises adding an additive selected from the group consisting of dispersant, thermal stabilizer, polymer processing aid, flame retardant, impact modifier, plasticizer, UV absorber, pigment, glass fiber, curing agent, lubricant, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 16, wherein zinc oxide nanoparticles are iess than about 20% of the stabilized polymer composite.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1969046A4;WO2007075654A2;WO2007075654A3;US2006194910A1;JP2009520870A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
