<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Process for the preparation of fibrous carbon.
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1995360A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
EDWIN EMIL [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
ARNESEN TORE [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
AASER KNUT-IVAR [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
RYTTER ERLING [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
JOHANSEN JOHAN [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
EDWIN, EMIL
</Name>
<Name>
ARNESEN, TORE
</Name>
<Name>
AASER, KNUT-IVAR
</Name>
<Name>
RYTTER, ERLING
</Name>
<Name>
JOHANSEN, JOHAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
STATOILHYDRO ASA [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
STATOILHYDRO ASA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1995360
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080014202
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-11-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030778504
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-11-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2003GB05086
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-11-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B3/26
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B3/26
</Class>
<Class>
C01B3/50B2B
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127B
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127B2
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Process for the preparation of fibrous carbon which comprises contacting a metallic catalyst with a carbon-containing gas at elevated temperature, characterized in that said catalyst is sponge iron.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for the preparation of fibrous carbon which comprises contacting a metallic catalyst with a carbon-containing gas at elevated temperature, characterized in that said catalyst is sponge iron.
</P>
<P>
2. A method for the conversion into carbon of gaseous hydrocarbons extracted from a natural hydrocarbon reservoir, which method comprises contacting said gaseous hydrocarbon at an elevated temperature in a reactor with a catalyst capable of converting said hydrocarbon to carbon and hydrogen; separating hydrogen produced from unconverted hydrocarbon; burning said hydrogen to generate energy; and using the energy generated to heat said reactor or the gaseous hydrocarbon flow thereto, or to heat or power a heat or power consuming apparatus.
</P>
<P>
3. A method as claimed in claim 2 wherein the energy generated is used to heat said reactor or the gaseous hydrocarbon flow thereto.
</P>
<P>
4. A method as claimed in claim 2 wherein the energy generated is used to power an electricity generator.
</P>
<P>
5. A method as claimed in any one of claims 2 to 4, wherein said catalyst is particulate.
</P>
<P>
6. A method as claimed in any one of claims 2 to 5 wherein said catalyst is a Raney metal.
</P>
<P>
7. A method as claimed in any one of claims 2 to 5 wherein said catalyst comprises an element selected from Ni, Co and Fe.
</P>
<P>
8. A method as claimed in any one of claims 2 to 7 wherein said catalyst is particulate with a mode particle size of 1 to 300 m.
</P>
<P>
9. A method as claimed in any one of claims 2 to 8 wherein hydrogen is burned in an internal combustion engine.
</P>
<P>
10. A method as claimed in any one of claims 2 to 9 wherein the hydrogen is separated from the unconverted hydrocarbon using a hydrogen-permeable membrane.
</P>
<P>
11. An apparatus for the conversion of hydrocarbon gas to carbon, said apparatus comprising a reactor vessel (2) having a gas inlet port (18) and a gas outlet port (19);
</P>
<P>
a separator (4) for removing hydrogen from a hydrocarbon and hydrogen containing gas;
</P>
<P>
a gas conduit (3) from said gas outlet port to said separator;
</P>
<P>
a combustor (9) arranged to burn hydrogen from said separator to generate energy; and
</P>
<P>
an energy transferrer (11) arranged to transfer energy from said combustor to said reactor vessel or to a further heat or power consuming apparatus (20).
</P>
<P>
12. An apparatus as claimed in claim 11 further comprising an electricity generator (20) powered by energy from said combustor.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1995360A3;WO2005054124A1;US2007215520A1;SI1694599T1;PT1694599E;NO20062901A;KR20070017302A;KR101032168B1;JP2007527348A;ES2312832T3;EP1694599A1;EP1694599B1;EA200600926A1;EA011042B1;DK1694599T3;CN1886335A;CN100457602C;CA2545879A1;CA2545879C;BR0318614A;AU2003285506A1;AU2003285506B2;AT404496T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
