<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PHOTOINDUCED PHASE SEPARATION OF GOLD IN TWO- COMPONENT NANOPARTICLES TO FORM NANOPRISMS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1993758A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MIRKIN CHAD A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
METRAUX GABRIELLA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
JIN RONGCHAO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MIRKIN, CHAD, A
</Name>
<Name>
METRAUX, GABRIELLA
</Name>
<Name>
JIN, RONGCHAO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV NORTHWESTERN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1993758
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070752672
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-08
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US05988
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-08
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060782678P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/02
</Class>
<Class>
C22F3/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/02B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Nanoprisms containing silver and gold are disclosed. The nanoprisms exhibit the properties of pure silver nanoprisms, but are less susceptible to silver modification or reaction by a surrounding environment than pure silver nanoprisms due to the presence of the gold. The gold surface of the nanoprisms can be further modified, using known gold-modification techniques.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of preparing a nanoprism comprising the steps of a) admixing a silver nanoparticle and a gold source under conditions that deposit gold on a surface of the silver nanoparticle to form a two-metal nanoparticle; and b) irradiating the two-metal nanoparticle with a light source to form a nanoprism.
</P>
<P>
2. A method of preparing a nanoprism comprising the step of irradiating a nanoparticle of a silver-gold alloy with a light source to form the nanoprism.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the irradiating is for about 4 hours to about 500 hours.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the irradiating comprises a light source having a wavelength of about 400 nm to about 700 nm.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the molar ratio of silver to gold is about 1:1 to about 50:1.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the molar ratio of silver to gold is about 2:1 to about 30:1.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the molar ratio of silver to gold is about 10:1 to about 20:1.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1, wherein the two-metal nanoparticle exhibits a surface plasmon resonance of about 375 nm to about 425 nm.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the nanoprism exhibits an out-of-plane quadrupole resonance of about 325 nm to about 335 nm, an in-plane quadrupole resonance of about 445 nm to about 455 nm, an in-plane dipole resonance of about 640 nm to about 660 nm, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1 or 2 further comprising the step of: modifying the gold on a surface of the nanoprism with a protein, oligonucleotide, or combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. A nanoprism produced by the method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the prismatic properties of the silver are protected from a surrounding environment by the gold.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1 or 2 wherein the nanoprism is a silver nanoprism having gold nanoparticles on surfaces of the nanoprism.
</P>
<P>
13. The nanoprism of claim 1 1 or 12 having an out-of-plane quadrupole resonance of about 325 nm to about 335 nm, an in-plane quadrupole resonance of about 445 nm to about 455 nm, an in-plane dipole resonance of about 640 nm to about 660 nm, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The nanoprism of claim 1 1 or 12 having an edge length of about 70 nm to about 120 nm and a thickness of about 6.5 to about 10.5 nm.
</P>
<P>
15. The nanoprism of claim 11 or 12 having an edge length of about 90 nm to about 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
16. The nanoprism of claim 1 1 or 12 having a thickness of about 8.0 to about 9.0 nm.
</P>
<P>
17. The nanoprism of claim 11 or 12 having a surface modified with an oligonucleotide, a protein, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
18. A silver nanoprism having gold nanoparticles on the nanoprism surface.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007103536A2;WO2007103536A3;US2010133489A1;JP2009533545A;CN101415508A;CA2643691A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
