<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
HIERARCHICAL NANOPATTERNS BY NANOIMPRINT LITHOGRAPHY
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1948556A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ZHANG FENGXIANG [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
LOW HONG YEE [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG, FENGXIANG
</Name>
<Name>
LOW, HONG YEE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AGENCY SCIENCE TECH &amp; RES [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
AGENCY FOR SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY AND RESEARCH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1948556
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20050795286
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2005-10-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2005SG00364
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C59/02
</Class>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B81C99/00R4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for forming hierarchical patterns on an article by nanoimprinting is disclosed. The method includes using a first mould to form a primary pattern on the article at a first temperature and a first pressure, the first temperature and the first temperature being able to reduce the elastic modulus of the article;  and using a second mould to form a second pattern on the primary pattern at a second temperature that is below the article&apos;s glass transition temperature, the forming of the second pattern being at a second pressure.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
THE CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method for forming hierarchical patterns on an article by nanoimprinti&apos;ng, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) using a first mould to form a primary pattern on the article at a first temperature and a first pressure, the first temperature and the first pressure being able to reduce the elastic modulus of the article;
</P>
<P>
(b) using a second mould to form a second pattern on the primary pattern at a second temperature that is below the article&apos;s glass transition temperature, the forming of the second pattern being at a second pressure.
</P>
<P>
2. A method as claimed in claim 1, wherein the first temperature and pressure are also able to reduce the melt viscosity of the article.
</P>
<P>
3. A method as claimed in claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the first temperature is above the article&apos;s glass transition temperature.
</P>
<P>
4. A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the article is a polymer film.
</P>
<P>
5. A method as claimed in claim 4, wherein the polymer film is selected from the group consisting of: thermoplastic polymers, polycarbonate, polymethylmethacrylate, porous polymers, and polyimide with hydroxy! side groups.
</P>
<P>
6. A method as claimed in claim 4 or claim 5, wherein the polymer film is a polymer composite reinforced with particles selected from the group consisting of: calcium carbonate, carbon filler, glass filler, fibers, glass fibers, carbon fibers, and carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
7. A method as claimed in any one of claims 4 to 6, wherein the polymer film is on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
8. A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the secondary pattern is formed at an angle relative to the primary pattern, the angle being in the range 0[deg.] to 90[deg.].
</P>
<P>
9. A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein at least one of the first mould and the second mould is treated with a low surface energy coating for facilitating their release from the article.
</P>
<P>
10. A method as claimed in claim 9, wherein the coating is perfluorodecyltrichlorosilane.
</P>
<P>
11. A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein the first mould has a first grating for forming a first grating structure on the article, and the second mould has second grating for forming a second grating structure on the first grating structure.
</P>
<P>
12. A method as claimed in claim 11 , wherein the first grating is of a size relative to the second grating that is selected from the group consisting of: the same, larger, and smaller.
</P>
<P>
13. A method as claimed in claim 11 , or claim 12, wherein the first grating and the second grating have different geometries.
</P>
<P>
14. A method as claimed in any one of claims 11 to 13, wherein the first grating structure is protrusions and trenches on the article.
</P>
<P>
15. A method as claimed in claim 14 wherein the second grating is formed on the protrusions and in the trenches.
</P>
<P>
16. A method as claimed in any one of claims 11 to 15, wherein the first grating is of a 2 micrometers pitch and the second grating is of a 250 nanometers pitch.
</P>
<P>
17. A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 16, wherein:
</P>
<P>
(a) the first temperature is in the range of 120&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 200[deg.]C;
</P>
<P>
(b) the second temperature is in the range of 60&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 200&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C;
</P>
<P>
(c) the first pressure is in the range of 40 bar to 50 bar; and
</P>
<P>
(d) the second pressure is in the range of 10bar to 50 bar.
</P>
<P>
18. A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 17, wherein before step (a) any residual solvent is removed from the article.
</P>
<P>
19. A method as claimed in claim 5, wherein the polyimide with hydroxyl side groups is a porous film.
</P>
<P>
20. A product produced by the method of any one of claims 1 to 19.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1948556A4;WO2007046772A1;US2009047478A1;TWI321266B;JP2009512576A;JP4898820B2;AU2005337438A1;AU2005337438B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
