<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
IMPROVED CARBON DIOXIDE NANOSENSOR, AND RESPIRATORY CO2 MONITORS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1941270A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHANG DANIEL M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHANG YING-LAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GABRIEL JEAN-CHRISTOPHE P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
JOSHI VIKRAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MICKELSON WILLIAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NIEMANN JOSEPH [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PASSMORE JOHN LOREN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STAR ALEXANDER [US]
</Name>
<Name>
VALCKE CHRISTIAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHANG, DANIEL M
</Name>
<Name>
CHANG, YING-LAN
</Name>
<Name>
GABRIEL, JEAN-CHRISTOPHE P
</Name>
<Name>
JOSHI, VIKRAM
</Name>
<Name>
MICKELSON, WILLIAM
</Name>
<Name>
NIEMANN, JOSEPH
</Name>
<Name>
PASSMORE, JOHN LOREN
</Name>
<Name>
STAR, ALEXANDER
</Name>
<Name>
VALCKE, CHRISTIAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NANOMIX INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NANOMIX, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1941270
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060851621
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-07-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US28079
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050700944P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-07-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050730905P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060773138P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-13
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060390493
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060437275
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C12M3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/12
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/414
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/00D2D4C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An electronic system and method for detecting analytes, such as carbon dioxide, is provided, using an improved nanostructure sensor (CO2 sensor). The CO2 sensor may comprise a substrate and a nanostructure, such as a one or more carbon nanotubes disposed over the substrate (e.g., as a network). One or more conductive elements may electrically communicate with the nanostructure. A counter or gate electrode may be positioned adjacent the nanostructure. A functionalization material reactive with carbon dioxide may be included, either disposed in contact with the nanostructure or isolated by a dielectric. The sensor may be connected to a circuit responsive to changes in CO2 concentration in the environment. Embodiments are described of medical sensing systems including one or more CO2 sensors. One embodiment comprises a breath sampling cannula which is connected to a sensor unit.;  In an alternative, the cannula permits supplemental oxygen to be administered, while recovering and measuring analytes in breath samples. The cannula may connect to a portable processor-display unit for monitoring one or more analytes, such as CO2. Another embodiment includes a cannula configured for the monitoring of sleep disorders, such as apnea, comprising one or more sensors disposed adjacent a breath sampling channel, optionally including flow rate or other sensors. The sensors may be connected by wired or wireless links for to a processor/input/display unit. Any of the embodiments may include filters, selectively permeable membranes, absorbents, and the like to precondition the breath sample, may be configured to include complementary chemistry measurements.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A nanostructure sensor for sensing carbon dioxide, comprising: a substrate; a first nanostructure disposed adjacent the substrate; one or more conducting elements in electrical communication with the first nanostructure; and at least one recognition material operatively associated with the first nanostructure, the at least one recognition material configured for interacting with carbon dioxide.
</P>
<P>
2. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 1, wherein the recognition material is in direct contact with the nanostructure.
</P>
<P>
3. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 1, wherein the recognition material is in isolated from the nanostructure by a dielectric layer.
</P>
<P>
4. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 3, wherein the dielectric layer is less than about 500 nm thick.
</P>
<P>
5. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 4, wherein the dielectric layer is between about 50 nm and 1 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 5, wherein the dielectric layer is between about 30 nm and 5 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 3, wherein the dielectric layer is deposited by atomic layer deposition (ALD).
</P>
<P>
8. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 7, further including at least a second layer deposited by ALD having material properties distinct from the dielectric layer.
</P>
<P>
9. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 8, wherein the second layer includes a recognition material configured for interacting with carbon dioxide.
</P>
<P>
10. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 1, wherein the recognition material further comprises an aqueous solution capable of reacting with carbon dioxide.
</P>
<P>
11. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 10, wherein the recognition material comprises an accelerator configured to catalyze the conversion of aqueous carbon dioxide to carbonic acid.
</P>
<P>
12. A nanostructure sensor as in claim 11, wherein the accelerator comprises carbonic anhydrase.
</P>
<P>
13 A breath analyzer system comprising: a breath sampling cannula including one or more lumens configured to by mounted adjacent at least one of a patient&apos;s nostril and mouth, the lumen having an opening arranged to gather an exhaled breath sample upon patient exhalation; one or more nanostructure sensor comprised as in Claim 1, the sensor in communication with the lumen of the breath sampling cannula, so as to contact at least a portion of the exhaled breath sample; the sensor have a sensitivity carbon dioxide (CO2) in human exhaled breath so at to produce a sensor signal in response to the breath species; a processing unit in communication with the sensor so as to receive the sensor signal, the processor unit configured to use the signal to determine a measurement of one of:
</P>
<P>
(i) the concentration of CO2 in the sample; and
</P>
<P>
(ii) the amount of CO2 in the sample, and an output device in communication with the processing unit and configured to output at least the measurement to a user, so as to provide information related to a human medical state.
</P>
<P>
14. A breath analyzer comprising: one or more first sensors comprised as in Claim 1 having a sensitivity for carbon dioxide; at least one second sensor having a sensitivity for at least one second non-carbon- dioxide species found in human exhaled breath, and wherein the concentration of carbon dioxide and the second species in human exhaled breath has a correlation with a human medical state; a breath sampler configured to sample at least the exhaled breath of a patient, and in communication with the first and second sensors; a processor system in communication with the first and second sensors and configured to measure the concentration of carbon dioxide and the second species, and to the measurements to a user, so as to provide information related to the human medical state.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1941270A4;WO2008039165A2;WO2008039165A3
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
