<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Manufacturing method of magnetic core -  ceramic shell nanocrystals
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1942508A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KIM YOUNG KEUN [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
LIU HONG LING [CN]
</Name>
<Name>
WU JUN HUA [CN]
</Name>
<Name>
MIN JI HYUN [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM YOU SONG [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, YOUNG KEUN
</Name>
<Name>
LIU, HONG LING
</Name>
<Name>
WU, JUN HUA
</Name>
<Name>
MIN, JI HYUN
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, YOU SONG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KOREA UNIVERSITY FOUNDATION [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KOREA UNIVERSITY FOUNDATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1942508
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080150055
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20070000997
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-04
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G49/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00E10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Provided are magnetic core - ceramic shell (e.g., magnetite (Fe 3 O 4 ) core - calcium phosphate (Ca 3 (PO 4 ) 2 ) shell) nanocrystals with high crystallization degree, uniform size, and high chemical stability and a method for synthesizing the same. A core-shell structure is synthesized in a process of forming magnetite seeds corresponding to cores by the reduction of magnetite precursors and then, sequentially, coating the magnetite with Ca 3 (PO 4 ) 2 by the reduction of Ca 3 (PO 4 ) 2 precursors.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for manufacturing bifunctional magnetic core - ceramic shell nanocrystals in a sequential process, characterized in that the method comprises:
</P>
<P>
mixing magnetic core material precursors with a reducing agent for the core material precursors;
</P>
<P>
mixing the resultant with a solvent for the magnetic core material precursors and the reducing agent and forming a first mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the first mixture solution to a first temperature and maintaining the first mixture solution for a first time;
</P>
<P>
cooling the first mixture solution to room temperature and forming magnetic core materials;
</P>
<P>
mixing the magnetic core materials with ceramic shell material precursors and a reducing agent for the ceramic shell material precursors and forming a second mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the second mixture solution to a second temperature and maintaining the second mixture solution for a second time; and
</P>
<P>
cooling the second mixture solution to room temperature and coating the magnetic core materials with the ceramic shell materials.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, characterized by further comprising: precipitating the bifunctional nanocrystals by the addition of ethanol and performing separation using a centrifugal separator.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, characterized in that the forming of the first mixture solution further comprises adding a surfactant.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, characterized in that the forming of the second mixture solution does not further comprise adding a surfactant.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1, characterized in that the core is magnetite (Fe3O4) and the shell is calcium phosphate (Ca3(PO4)2).
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1, characterized by further comprising: after maintaining the first mixture solution at the first temperature for a predetermined time,
</P>
<P>
heating the first mixture solution to a third temperature higher than the first temperature and maintaining the first mixture solution for a third time.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1, characterized by further comprising: after maintaining the second mixture solution at the second temperature for a predetermined time,
</P>
<P>
heating the second mixture solution to a fourth temperature higher than the second temperature and maintaining the second mixture solution for a fourth time.
</P>
<P>
8. A method for manufacturing bifunctional magnetite-calcium phosphate (Ca3(PO4)2) core-shell nanocrystals in a sequential process, characterized in that the method comprises:
</P>
<P>
mixing magnetite precursors, Fe&amp;lt;III&amp;gt; (acac)3, with a reducing agent for the magnetite precursors;
</P>
<P>
mixing the resultant with dioctyl ether, a solvent, and forming a first mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the first mixture solution to 300 deg. C and maintaining the first mixture solution for 1 to 2 hours;
</P>
<P>
cooling the first mixture solution to room temperature and forming magnetite cores;
</P>
<P>
mixing the magnetite cores with calcium acetate, ammonium phosphate, and reducing agents thereof and forming a second mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the second mixture solution to 80 deg. C and maintaining the second mixture solution for 30 minutes; and
</P>
<P>
cooling the second mixture solution to room temperature and coating the magnetite cores with the calcium phosphate (Ca3(PO4)2) shells.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 8, characterized by further comprising: precipitating the bifunctional nanocrystals by the addition of ethanol and performing separation using a centrifugal separator.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 8, characterized in that the forming of the first mixture solution further comprises: adding tri-block copolymer (Poly(Ethylene Oxide) - Poly(Propylene Oxide) - Poly(Ethylene Oxide): PEO-PPO-PEO) as a surfactant.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 8, characterized in that the forming of the second mixture solution does not further comprise: adding a surfactant.
</P>
<P>
12. Bifunctional magnetic core - ceramic shell nanocrystals manufactured in a sequential process, characterized in that the process comprises:
</P>
<P>
mixing magnetic core material precursors with a reducing agent for the core material precursors;
</P>
<P>
mixing the resultant with a solvent for the magnetic core material precursors and the reducing agent and forming a first mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the first mixture solution to a first temperature and maintaining the first mixture solution for a first time;
</P>
<P>
cooling the first mixture solution to room temperature and forming magnetic core materials;
</P>
<P>
mixing the magnetic core materials with ceramic shell material precursors and a reducing agent for the ceramic shell material precursors;
</P>
<P>
mixing the resultant with a solvent for the ceramic shell material precursors and the reducing agent and forming a second mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the second mixture solution to a second temperature and maintaining the second mixture solution for a second time; and
</P>
<P>
cooling the second mixture solution to room temperature and coating the magnetic core materials with ceramic shell materials.
</P>
<P>
13. Bifunctional magnetite-calcium phosphate (Ca3(PO4)2) core-shell nanocrystals manufactured in a sequential process, characterized in that the process comprises:
</P>
<P>
mixing magnetite precursors, Fe&amp;lt;III&amp;gt; (acac)3, with a reducing agent for the magnetite precursors;
</P>
<P>
mixing the resultant with dioctyl ether, a solvent, and forming a first mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the first mixture solution to 60 deg. C to 80 deg. C and maintaining the first mixture solution for 1 to 2 hours;
</P>
<P>
cooling the first mixture solution to room temperature and forming magnetite cores;
</P>
<P>
mixing the magnetite cores with calcium acetate, ammonium phosphate, and reducing agents thereof and forming a second mixture solution;
</P>
<P>
heating the second mixture solution to 80 deg. C and maintaining the second mixture solution for 30 minutes; and
</P>
<P>
cooling the second mixture solution to room temperature and coating the magnetite cores with the calcium phosphate (Ca3(PO4)2) shells.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1942508B1;US2008210899A1;KR100791731B1;JP2008162884A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
