<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
TITANIUM DIOXIDE FINISHING PROCESS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1954767A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DIEMER RUSSELL BERTRUM JR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
EATON ALAN ROGER [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SUBRAMANIAN NARAYANAN SANKARA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TAYLOR STEPHEN WILLIAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SCHURR GEORGE A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZIMMERMAN DAVID A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DIEMER, RUSSELL, BERTRUM, JR
</Name>
<Name>
EATON, ALAN, ROGER
</Name>
<Name>
SUBRAMANIAN, NARAYANAN, SANKARA
</Name>
<Name>
TAYLOR, STEPHEN, WILLIAM
</Name>
<Name>
SCHURR, GEORGE, A
</Name>
<Name>
ZIMMERMAN, DAVID, A
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E.I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1954767
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060827118
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US42389
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050263702
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/07
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/07
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/07B
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
This disclosure relates to process for producing titanium dioxide (TiO2) pigments, comprising the following steps: a) oxidizing a mixture of titanium tetrahalide and a rutile forming agent, such as aluminum halide, present in the vapor phase and in the presence of a nucleant to form a gaseous suspension comprising titanium dioxide particles;  b) passing the gaseous suspension to a cooling conduit;  c) introducing scouring material into the cooling conduit;  wherein the particles of the scouring material have a diameter in the range of about 0.25 mm to about 12.7 mm;  d) separating the vapor phase to form a powder comprising the titanium dioxide particles and the scouring material; ;  and e) simultaneously subjecting the powder to substantially uniform heating at a temperature of about 300 DEG  C. to about 600 DEG  C. and reducing the size of the titanium dioxide particles and the particles of the scouring material in the powder to a mean particle size of about 50 nm to about 1000 nm, whereby the titanium dioxide pigment has a chloride content of less than about 500 ppm. The so treated powder may have a residual free chlorine content of less than about 1 ppm.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for producing titanium dioxide pigment, comprising the following steps:
</P>
<P>
a) vapor-phase oxidizing a mixture of titanium tetrahalide and a rutile forming agent in the presence of a nucleant to form a gaseous suspension comprising titanium dioxide particles;
</P>
<P>
b) passing the gaseous suspension to a cooling conduit;
</P>
<P>
c) introducing scouring material particles into the cooling conduit, wherein the particles of the scouring material have a diameter in the range of about 0.25 mm to about 12.7 mm and forming a cooled product having a solid and a vapor phase;
</P>
<P>
d) separating the vapor phase from the cooled product to form a powder comprising the titanium dioxide particles and the scouring material; and
</P>
<P>
e) subjecting the powder to substantially uniform heating at a temperature of about 300[deg.] C. to about 600[deg.] C. while size reducing at least the titanium dioxide particles of the powder to form titanium dioxide particles having a mean particle size of about 50 nm to about 1000 nm.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 wherein the temperature is of about 300[deg.] C. to about 450[deg.] C. and is accomplished in a fluid energy mill.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 2 wherein the fluid energy mill comprises a heated fluid selected from the group consisting of steam, air, argon, helium, nitrogen and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 3 wherein the heated fluid is steam.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 2 wherein the fluid energy mill is a micronizer and the heating at a temperature of about 300[deg.] C. to about 600[deg.] C. is accomplished by way of a heated fluid selected from the group consisting of steam, air, argon, helium, nitrogen and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 1 wherein at least one of (a) the titanium tetrahalide is titanium tetrachloride, (b) the rutile-forming agent is aluminum chloride and (c) the nucleant is selected from the group consisting of potassium chloride, cesium chloride or and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 6 wherein the powder comprises chlorides and the chloride content of the size-reduced powder is less than about 500 ppm.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 5 wherein the powder is heated at a temperature of about 300[deg.] C. to about 450[deg.] C.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 5 wherein the powder is heated at a temperature of about 350[deg.] C. to about 425[deg.] C.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 1 wherein the titanium dioxide particles and the scouring material particles are reduced to a particle size of about 100 nm to about 250 nm.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 7 wherein the chloride content of the titanium dioxide particles is reduced to less than about 350 ppm.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 7 wherein the chloride content of the titanium dioxide particles is reduced to less than about 230 ppm.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 1 wherein the scouring material is selected from the group consisting of calcined titanium dioxide and compressed titanium dioxide, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
14-17. (canceled)
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1954767A4;US2007095253A1;US7247200B2;WO2007053584A1;US2008105165A1;JP2009513483A;CA2626047A1;AU2006308877A1;AU2006308877B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
