<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Nanomagnet array and method of forming the same
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1988555A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TEICHERT CHRISTIAN [AT]
</Name>
<Name>
HOFER CHRISTIAN [AT]
</Name>
<Name>
DE MIGUEL JUAN JOSE [ES]
</Name>
<Name>
NINO MIGUEL ANGEL [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
MIKUSZEIT NIKOLAI [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
JIMENEZ ERIKA [ES]
</Name>
<Name>
CAMARERO JULIO [ES]
</Name>
<Name>
MIRANDA RODOLFO [ES]
</Name>
<Name>
ARVANITIS DIMITRI [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
GRIDNEVA LIDIA [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
PERSSON ANDREAS [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
BOBEK THOMAS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KURZ HEINRICH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
TEICHERT, CHRISTIAN
</Name>
<Name>
HOFER, CHRISTIAN
</Name>
<Name>
DE MIGUEL, JUAN JOSE
</Name>
<Name>
NINO, MIGUEL ANGEL
</Name>
<Name>
MIKUSZEIT, NIKOLAI
</Name>
<Name>
JIMENEZ, ERIKA
</Name>
<Name>
CAMARERO, JULIO
</Name>
<Name>
MIRANDA, RODOLFO
</Name>
<Name>
ARVANITIS, DIMITRI
</Name>
<Name>
GRIDNEVA, LIDIA
</Name>
<Name>
PERSSON, ANDREAS
</Name>
<Name>
BOBEK, THOMAS
</Name>
<Name>
KURZ, HEINRICH
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MONTANUNIVERSITAET LEOBEN [AT]
</Name>
<Name>
RWTH AACHEN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIV AACHEN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY MADRID [ES]
</Name>
<Name>
MONTANUNIVERSITAET LEOBEN
</Name>
<Name>
RWTH AACHEN
</Name>
<Name>
UNIVERSITY AACHEN
</Name>
<Name>
AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY MADRID
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1988555
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070008974
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070008974
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G11C11/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00E12
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32L2P
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/22M
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for forming a nanomagnet array is provided, wherein the method comprises forming an array of nanoobjects on the substrate, forming a first layer on the nanoobjects in such a way that magnetic nanodots are formed on the nanoobjects, wherein the magnetic nanodots are substantially magnetically decoupled.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for forming a nanomagnet array, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
forming an array of nanoobjects on a substrate; and
</P>
<P>
forming a first layer on the nanoobjects in such a way that magnetic nanodots are formed on the nanoobjects, wherein the magnetic nanodots are magnetically decoupled.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the forming of the array of nanoobjects is done by using a self-organizing process.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 1 or 2, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
forming an intermediate layer onto the substrate before depositing the first layer.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the intermediate layer comprises a non-magnetic metal.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 4,
</P>
<P>
wherein the non-magnetic metal has a high polarizability and/or spin-orbit coupling.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 4,
</P>
<P>
wherein the non-magnetic metal of the intermediate layer has a different atomic distance than a material of the first layer.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to any one of the claims 1 to 6,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first layer comprises a ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any one of the claims 1 to 7,
</P>
<P>
wherein the forming of the first layer is done by using a grazing incidence deposition process.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to claim 8,
</P>
<P>
wherein the grazing incidence deposition is performed under an incidence angle in such a way that the first layer comprises different regions having different thicknesses.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to claim 9,
</P>
<P>
wherein one of the different thicknesses is above a predetermined thickness threshold.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to any one of the claims 1 to 7, further comprising
</P>
<P>
forming an additional layer,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first layer comprises a ferromagnetic material, and
</P>
<P>
wherein the additional layer comprises an antiferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
12. A nanomagnet array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate having a plurality of nanoobjects formed on one surface of the substrate; and
</P>
<P>
a first layer formed on the nanoobjects;wherein the first layer is formed in such a way that an array of magnetic nanodots are formed on the plurality of nanoobjects in such a way that the magnetic nanodots are magnetically decoupled from each other.
</P>
<P>
13. The nanomagnet array according to claim 12,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first layer comprises a ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
14. The nanomagnet array according to the claim 12 or 13, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
an intermediate layer, which is arranged between the substrate and the first layer.
</P>
<P>
15. The nanomagnet array according to claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the intermediate layer comprises a non-magnetic material.
</P>
<P>
16. The nanomagnet array according to any one of claims 12 to 15,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first layer has a first thickness on a top-surface of the plurality of nanoobjects and a second thickness on side-faces of the plurality of nanoobjects.
</P>
<P>
17. The nanomagnet array according to any one of the claims 12 to 16, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
a top layer, which is formed on the first layer.
</P>
<P>
18. The nanomagnet array according to claim 17,
</P>
<P>
wherein the top layer is formed of a non-magnetic material.
</P>
<P>
19. A Magneto-resistive Random Access Memory comprising:
</P>
<P>
a nanomagnet array according to any one of the claims 12 to 18.
</P>
<P>
20. The Magneto-resistive Random Access Memory according to claim 19, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of wordlines; and
</P>
<P>
a plurality of bitlines,wherein the plurality of nanodots is connected to the plurality of wordlines and the bitlines.
</P>
</Claims>
</BiblioData>
