<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CONDUCTIVE MEMBER CONTAINING FIBER NANOCARBON AND CONTACT DEVICE USING SUCH CONDUCTIVE MEMBER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1981035A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YAMAMOTO TAKAHISA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKADA SHIGEKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA KOICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TAKAMI HIROSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
WATANABE YOICHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAMOTO, TAKAHISA
</Name>
<Name>
OKADA, SHIGEKI
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA, KOICHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUBIANTORO
</Name>
<Name>
TAKAMI, HIROSHI
</Name>
<Name>
WATANABE, YOICHIRO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KOJIMA PRESS KOGYO KK [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ASAHI RUBBER INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI BUSSAN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KOJIMA PRESS INDUSTRY CO., LTD
</Name>
<Name>
ASAHI RUBBER INC
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI &amp; CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1981035
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060823556
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-01
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP324077
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050347808
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/12
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01Q1/32
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/12
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01Q1/32
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A conductive member composed of a conductive resin transmits a signal by being conductively connected with a body to be connected. The conductive resin includes fiber nanocarbon in the resin.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A conductive member comprising a conductive resin, for transmitting electric signals by being conductively connected to an object to be connected, wherein said conductive resin comprises a fibrous nanocarbon in a resin that is a base material.
</P>
<P>
2. The conductive member according to claim 1, wherein the aspect ratio of the fibrous nanocarbon is between 10 and 20000.
</P>
<P>
3. The conductive member according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the fibrous nanocarbon is contained at 4-40 wt% of the total weight of the conductive resin.
</P>
<P>
4. The conductive member according to any one of claims 1-3, wherein the fibrous nanocarbon is a carbon nanotube, a carbon nanofiber or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The conductive member according to claim 4, wherein the carbon nanotube is a multiwalled carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
6. The conductive member according to claim 5, wherein the maximum diameter of the cross sections orthogonal to the longitudinal direction of the multiwalled carbon nanotube is 15-150 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. The conductive member according to claim 5 or 6, wherein ID/IG of the multiwalled carbon nanotube measured by Raman spectroscopic analysis is 0.1 or less.
</P>
<P>
8. The conductive member according to any one of claims 5-7, wherein the conductive member is composed of a conductive resin comprising a three-dimensional network-form carbon fibrous structure in a resin that is a base material, said carbon fibrous structure being composed of multiwalled carbon nanotubes that extend from granular parts as origins of growth during a growth process and that are connected to each other, and wherein cross sections orthogonal to the longitudinal direction of said multiwalled carbon nanotubes have polygonal shapes.
</P>
<P>
9. The conductive member according to claim 4, wherein the carbon nanofiber is a carbon nanofiber manufactured by gas phase process.
</P>
<P>
10. The conductive member according to any one of claims 1-9, wherein the resin that is a base material is an elastomer.
</P>
<P>
11. A contact device comprising the conductive member according to any one of claims 1-10.
</P>
<P>
12. A contact device comprising the conductive member according to any one of claims 1-10, a base, and an elastic member mounted on said base, wherein said conductive member is biased by said elastic member so that it is conductively connected to an object to be connected.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1981035A4;US2009169876A1;WO2007063984A1;CN101322197A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
