<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING FINE CARBON FIBER AGGLOMERATE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1980656A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TSUKADA TAKAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN JIAYI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA, TAKAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
SHAN, JIAYI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MITSUI BUSSAN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUI &amp; CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1980656
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070707621
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-01-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP51390
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-29
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060021873
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09D201/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is a method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates having a median diameter of not more than 30 [mu]m, which comprises a pulverization step where a composition which includes (a) fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates having a median diameter of not less than 30 [mu]m and (b) a dispersion medium undergoes acceleration in order to form a turbulent flow and/or collision flow, thereby shearing force and/or impacting force exert on the (a) component included in the composition and thus the (a) component is pulverized, wherein the value of [I D /I G of fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates after pulverization of the (a) component] / [I D /I G of fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregate before pulverization of the (a) component] (wherein the I D /I G is calculated from measurement values determined by Raman spectroscopic analysis using 514 nm light of the argon laser);  is in the range of 0.7 to 1.5. According to this method, it is possible to obtain fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates which possess a good electrical conductivity and repress agglomeration.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates having a circle-equivalent median diameter (hereinafter, it is expressed simply as &quot;median diameter&quot;.) of not more than 30 m, which comprises a pulverization step where a composition which comprises (a) fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates having a median diameter of not less than 30 m and (b) a dispersion medium (liquid at 25 deg. C) for the aggregates undergoes acceleration in order to forma turbulent flow and/or collision flow, thereby shearing force and/or impacting force exert on the (a) component included in the composition and thus the (a) component is pulverized, wherein the value of [ID/IG of fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates after pulverization of the (a) component] / [ID/IG of fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates before pulverization of the (a) component] (wherein the ID/IG is calculated from measurement values determined by Raman spectroscopic analysis using 514 nm light of the argon laser) is in the range of 0.7 to 1.5.
</P>
<P>
2. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to Claim 1, wherein the method for exerting the shearing force and/or impacting force is a method which comprises penetrating the composition which comprises the (a) component and the (b) component through a gap between a rotating rotor and a fixed stator, and thereby exerting the shearing force and/or impacting force on the composition which comprises the (a) component and the (b) component.
</P>
<P>
3. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to Claim 1, wherein the method for exerting the shearing force and/or impacting force is a method where flows, both of which are of the composition which comprises the (a) component and the (b) component, are made to collide with each other oppositely.
</P>
<P>
4. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 3, wherein the (b) component is an alcohol having a carbon number of 1 - 5.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 4, wherein the (a) component is aggregates of carbon fibrous structures, each of carbon fibrous structures comprising a three dimensional network of carbon fibers each having an outside diameter of 15 - 100 nm, wherein the carbon fibrous structure further comprises a granular part with which the carbon fibers are tied together in the state that the concerned carbon fibers are externally elongated therefrom, and wherein the granular part is produced in a growth process of the carbon fibers.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 5, wherein the (a) component has a bulk density of 0.0001 - 0.05g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
7. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 6, wherein the (a) component has ID/IG ratio determined by Raman spectroscopy of not more than 0.2.
</P>
<P>
8. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 7, wherein the (a) component has a oxidation temperature in air of not less than 750 deg. C.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 8, wherein the diameter of the granular part at a bonding site of carbon fibers in the carbon fibrous structure which constitutes the (a) component is larger than the outside diameter of the carbon fibers.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1- 9, wherein the (a) component is produced using as carbon sources at least two carbon compounds which have mutually different decomposition temperatures.
</P>
<P>
11. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 10, wherein the (a) component comprises fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates which are obtained by heating a mixture gas of catalyst and hydrocarbon at a temperature in the range of 800 deg. C-1300 deg. C, and which are in the state before undergoing annealing at a temperature in the range of 2400 deg. C - 3000 deg. C, and the aggregates having a median diameter of not less tan 30 m.
</P>
<P>
12. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 10, wherein the (a) component comprises fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates which are obtained by heating a mixture gas of catalyst and hydrocarbon at a temperature in the range of 800 deg. C-1300 deg. C, and the aggregates further undergoing annealing at a temperature in the range of 2400 deg. C- 3000 deg. C, and the aggregates having a median diameter of not less tan 30 m.
</P>
<P>
13. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 10, wherein the (a) component comprises fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates which are obtained by heating a mixture gas of catalyst and hydrocarbon at a temperature in the range of 800 deg. C - 1300 deg. C in order to synthesis fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates, annealing the synthesized fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates at a temperature in the range of 2400 deg. C - 3000 deg. C, and then subjecting the annealed fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates to air milling, and the aggregates having a median diameter of not less tan 30 m.
</P>
<P>
14. The method for manufacturing fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates according to one of Claims 1 - 13, wherein the (a) component further comprises a dispersing agent.
</P>
<P>
15. Coating material which comprises fine carbon fibers&apos; aggregates obtained by the manufacturing method as claimed in one of Claims 1-14, and an organic binder.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1980656A4;US2009023853A1;WO2007088810A1;JP2007204857A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
