<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
MODIFIED COLORANTS AND INKJET INK COMPOSITIONS COMPRISING MODIFIED COLORANTS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1951821A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GU FENG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BELMONT JAMES A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PALUMBO PAUL S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CORDEN BARRY B [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YU YUAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HALIM ERVINA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BURNS ELIZABETH G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GU, FENG
</Name>
<Name>
BELMONT, JAMES, A
</Name>
<Name>
PALUMBO, PAUL, S
</Name>
<Name>
CORDEN, BARRY, B
</Name>
<Name>
YU, YUAN
</Name>
<Name>
HALIM, ERVINA
</Name>
<Name>
BURNS, ELIZABETH, G
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CABOT CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CABOT CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1951821
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060827102
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US42348
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050731721P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060815305P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060815327P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060815326P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09B67/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/44
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/00P4
</Class>
<Class>
C09B67/00B
</Class>
<Class>
C09B67/00B2
</Class>
<Class>
C09B67/00B4F
</Class>
<Class>
C09B67/00B4F6
</Class>
<Class>
C09B67/00M1
</Class>
<Class>
C09B67/00P10B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/10
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/32
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/322
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/324
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/00P
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12D2B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a modified colorant comprising a colorant having attached at least one organic group. Various embodiments of the organic group are disclosed. For each of these embodiments, preferably the organic group has a defined calcium index value. Also disclosed are various uses for these modified colorants, including inkjet ink compositions.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A modified colorant comprising a colorant having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of 1,2,3-benzene tricarboxylic acid.
</P>
<P>
2. The modified colorant of claim 1, wherein the colorant is a pigment.
</P>
<P>
3. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. The modified colorant of claim 3, wherein the organic group comprises at least one geminal bisphosphonic acid group, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The modified colorant of claim 4, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CQ(PO3H2)2 or salts thereof, wherein Q is H, R, OR, SR, or NR2 wherein R, which can be the same or different, is H, a C1-C18 alkyl group, a C1-C18 acyl group, an aralkyl group, an alkaryl group, or an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
6. The modified colorant of claim 5, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -(CH2)n-CQ(PO3H2)2 or salts thereof, wherein n is 1 to 9.
</P>
<P>
7. The modified colorant of claim 6, wherein n is 1 to 3.
</P>
<P>
8. The modified colorant of claim 5, wherein the organic group comprises a group having the formula -X-(CH2)n-CQ(PO3H2)2 or salt thereof, wherein X, which is attached to the pigment, is an arylene, heteroarylene, alkylene, alkarylene, or aralkylene group, and wherein n is 0 to 9.
</P>
<P>
9. The modified colorant of claim 8, wherein X is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
10. The modified colorant of claim 5, wherein the organic group comprises a group having the formula -X-Sp-(CH2)n-CQ(PO3H2)2 or salt thereof, wherein X, which is attached to the pigment, is an arylene, heteroarylene, alkylene, alkarylene, or aralkylene group and Sp is a spacer group, and wherein n is 0 to 9.
</P>
<P>
11. The modified colorant of claim 10, wherein Sp is -CO2-, -O2C-, -O-, -NR&apos;&apos;-, -NR&apos;&apos;CO-, -CONR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2NR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2CH2CH2NR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2CH2CH2O-, or -SO2CH2CH2S-, wherein R&apos;&apos; is H or a C1-C6 alkyl group.
</P>
<P>
12. The modified colorant of claim 10, wherein X is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
13. The modified colorant of claim 3, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -N-[(CH2)m(PO3H2)]2 or salts thereof, wherein m, which can be the same or different, is 1 to 3.
</P>
<P>
14. The modified colorant of claim 13, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -(CH2)n-N-[(CH2)m(PO3H2)]2 or salts thereof, wherein n is 1 to 9.
</P>
<P>
15. The modified colorant of claim 13, wherein the organic group comprises a group having the formula -X-(CH2)n-N-[(CH2)m(PO3H2)]2 or salts thereof, wherein X, which is attached to the pigment, is an arylene, heteroarylene, alkylene, alkarylene, or aralkylene group, and wherein n is 0 to 9.
</P>
<P>
16. The modified colorant of claim 13, wherein the organic group comprises a group having the formula -X-Sp-(CH2)n-N-[(CH2)m(PO3H2)]2 or salts thereof, wherein X, which is attached to the pigment, is an arylene, heteroarylene, alkylene, alkarylene, or aralkylene group and Sp is a spacer group, and wherein n is 0 to 9.
</P>
<P>
17. The modified colorant of claim 16, wherein Sp is -CO2-, -O2C-, -O-, -NR&apos;&apos;-, -NR&apos;&apos;CO-, -CONR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2NR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2CH2CH2NR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2CH2CH2O-, or -SO2CH2CH2S-, wherein R&apos;&apos; is H or a C1-C6 alkyl group.
</P>
<P>
18. The modified colorant of claim 3, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CR-C(PO3H2)2 or salts thereof, wherein R is H, a C1-C6 alkyl group, or an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
19. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The modified colorant of claim 19, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxy pyridonyl group or at least one hydroxy quinolonyl group.
</P>
<P>
21. The modified colorant of claim 20, wherein the organic group comprises a 1-hydroxy-2-pyridonyl group.
</P>
<P>
22. The modified colorant of claim 20, wherein the organic group comprises a 1-hydroxy-2-quinolonyl group.
</P>
<P>
23. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises at least one heterocyclic group having at least one OH group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
24. The modified colorant of claim 23, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxy pyridinyl group or at least one hydroxy quinolinyl group.
</P>
<P>
25. The modified colorant of claim 24, wherein the organic group comprises a 2-hydroxy-pyridinyl group.
</P>
<P>
26. The modified colorant of claim 24, wherein the organic group comprises an 8-hydroxy-quinolinyl group or a 2-hydroxy-quinolinyl group
</P>
<P>
27. The modified colorant of claim 23, wherein the heterocyclic group has at least two OH groups.
</P>
<P>
28. The modified colorant of claim 27, wherein the organic group is a 2,3-dihydroxy-pyridinyl group or a 3,4-dihydroxy-pyridinyl group.
</P>
<P>
29. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises at least one phosphonic acid group or a salt thereof and at least one second ionic, ionizable, or basic group vicinal or geminal to the phosphonic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
30. The modified colorant of claim 29, wherein the second ionic, ionizable, or basic group is a carboxylic acid group, a sulfonic acid group, an hydroxyl group, or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
31. The modified colorant of claim 29, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CQ(PO3H2)(CO2H) or salts thereof, wherein Q is H, R, OR, SR, or NR2 wherein R, which can be the same or different, is H, a C1-C18 alkyl group, a C1-C18 acyl group, an aralkyl group, an alkaryl group, or an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
32. The modified colorant of claim 29, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CR(PO3H2)(OH) or salts thereof, wherein R is H or a C1-C6 alkyl group.
</P>
<P>
33. The modified colorant of claim 29, wherein the organic group comprises a group having the formula -X-(PO3H2)(OH) or salts thereof, wherein X is an arylene or heteroarylene group and wherein the PO3H2 and OH group, or salts thereof, are ortho to each other.
</P>
<P>
34. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises a heteroaryl group having at least one carboxylic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
35. The modified colorant of claim 34, wherein the heteroaryl group has at least two carboxylic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
36. The modified colorant of claim 35, wherein the organic group is a 2,6-pyridinyl-dicarboxylic acid group or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
37. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises an aryl group having at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
38. The modified colorant of claim 37, wherein the organic group is a nitrosophenolic group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
39. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the organic group comprises an azoarene group having at least two OH groups, at least two NH2 groups, or at least one OH group and at least one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
40. The modified colorant of claim 39, wherein the organic group is a group having the structure -(HO)C6H3-N-N-C6H3Z(OH), wherein Z is a chloro or nitro group.
</P>
<P>
41. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the pigment further has attached at least one second organic group different from the organic group.
</P>
<P>
42. The modified colorant of claim 41, wherein the second organic group comprises at least one ionic group, at least one ionizable group, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
43. The modified colorant of claim 41, wherein the second organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of phenylphosphonic acid.
</P>
<P>
44. The modified colorant of claim 41, wherein the second organic group is a polymeric group.
</P>
<P>
45. The modified colorant of claim 44, wherein the polymeric group comprises a polymer having an acid number less than or equal to 200.
</P>
<P>
46. The modified colorant of claim 44, wherein the polymeric group comprises a polymer having a Tg less than 100.
</P>
<P>
47. The modified colorant of claim 44, wherein the polymeric group is present in an amount of from 0.1 to 50% by weight of the colorant.
</P>
<P>
48. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the pigment comprises a blue pigment, a black pigment, a brown pigment, a cyan pigment, a green pigment, a white pigment, a violet pigment, a magenta pigment, a red pigment, a yellow pigment, or mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
49. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the pigment is Pigment Blue 15, Pigment Red 122, Pigment Violet 19, Pigment Yellow 74, Pigment Yellow 155, Pigment Yellow 128, Pigment Yellow 218, Pigment Yellow 220, or Pigment Yellow 221.
</P>
<P>
50. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
51. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
52. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CQ(PO3H2)(CO2H) or salts thereof, wherein Q is H, R, OR, SR, or NR2 wherein R, which can be the same or different, is H, a C1-C18 alkyl group, a C1-C18 acyl group, an aralkyl group, an alkaryl group, or an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
53. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the organic group comprises a heteroaryl group having at least two carboxylic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
54. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the organic group comprises an aryl group having at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
55. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the organic group comprises an azoarene group having at least two OH groups, at least two NH2 groups, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
56. The modified colorant of claim 49, wherein the pigment further has attached at least one second organic group different from the organic group.
</P>
<P>
57. The modified colorant of claim 56, wherein the second organic group comprises at least one ionic group, at least one ionizable group, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
58. The modified colorant of claim 56, wherein the second organic group is a polymeric group.
</P>
<P>
59. The modified colorant of claim 2, wherein the pigment is carbon black.
</P>
<P>
60. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
61. The modified colorant of claim 60, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CQ(PO3H2)2 or salts thereof, wherein Q is H, R, OR, SR, or NR2 wherein R, which can be the same or different, is H, a C1-C18 alkyl group, a C1-C18 acyl group, an aralkyl group, an alkaryl group, or an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
62. The modified colorant of claim 60, wherein the organic group comprises a group having the formula -X-Sp-(CH2)n-CQ(PO3H2)2 or salt thereof, wherein X, which is attached to the pigment, is an arylene, heteroarylene, alkylene, alkarylene, or aralkylene group and Sp is a spacer group, and wherein n is 0 to 9.
</P>
<P>
63. The modified colorant of claim 62, wherein Sp is -CO2-, -O2C-, -O-, -NR&apos;&apos;-, -NR&apos;&apos;CO-, -CONR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2NR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2CH2CH2NR&apos;&apos;-, -SO2CH2CH2O-, or -SO2CH2CH2S-, wherein R&apos;&apos; is H or a C1-C6 alkyl group.
</P>
<P>
64. The modified colorant of claim 60, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -N-[(CH2)m(PO3H2)]2 or salts thereof, wherein m is 1 to 3.
</P>
<P>
65. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
66. The modified colorant of claim 65, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxy pyridonyl group or at least one hydroxy quinolonyl group.
</P>
<P>
67. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the organic group comprises at least one group having the formula -CQ(PO3H2)(CO2H) or salts thereof, wherein Q is H, R, OR, SR, or NR2 wherein R, which can be the same or different, is H, a C1-C18 alkyl group, a C1-C18 acyl group, an aralkyl group, an alkaryl group, or an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
68. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the organic group comprises a heteroaryl group having at least two carboxylic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
69. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the organic group comprises an aryl group having at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
70. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the organic group comprises an azoarene group having at least two OH groups, at least two NH2 groups, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
71. The modified colorant of claim 59, wherein the colorant further has attached at least one second organic group different from the organic group.
</P>
<P>
72. The modified colorant of claim 71, wherein the second organic group comprises at least one ionic group, at least one ionizable group, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
73. The modified colorant of claim 71, wherein the second organic group is a polymeric group.
</P>
<P>
74. The modified colorant of claim 1, wherein the colorant is a dye.
</P>
<P>
75. The modified colorant of claim 74, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
76. The modified colorant of claim 74, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
77. A modified colorant comprising a pigment having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group comprises
</P>
<P>
i) at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof,
</P>
<P>
ii) at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof,
</P>
<P>
iii) at least one phosphonic acid group or salt thereof and at least one second ionic, ionizable, or basic group, or
</P>
<P>
iv) an aryl group having at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
78. The modified colorant of claim 77, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
79. The modified colorant of claim 77, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
80. The modified colorant of claim 77, wherein the organic group comprises at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
81. A modified colorant comprising a pigment having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group comprises
</P>
<P>
i) at least one heterocyclic group having at least one OH group or salt thereof,
</P>
<P>
ii) at least one heteroaryl group having at least one carboxylic acid group or salts thereof, or
</P>
<P>
iii) an azoarene group has at least one OH group, at least one NH2 group, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
82. The modified colorant of claim 81, wherein the organic group comprises an azoarene group having at least two OH groups, at least two NH2 groups, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
83. A modified colorant comprising a pigment having attached at least one organic group and at least one second organic group, wherein the organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of phenylphosphonic acid and wherein the second organic group is a polymeric group.
</P>
<P>
84. The modified colorant of claim 83, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
85. The modified colorant of claim 83, wherein the organic group comprises at least one aryl polyacid group.
</P>
<P>
86. The modified colorant of claim 83, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
87. The modified colorant of claim 83, wherein the organic group comprises an azoarene group having at least two OH groups, at least two NH2 groups, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
88. An inkjet ink composition comprising a) a liquid vehicle and b) a modified colorant comprising a colorant having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of 1,2,3-benzene tricarboxylic acid.
</P>
<P>
89. The inkjet ink composition of claim 88, wherein the colorant is a pigment.
</P>
<P>
90. The inkjet ink composition of claim 89, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
91. The inkjet ink composition of claim 88, further comprising a second modified pigment comprising a pigment having attached at least one second organic group different from the organic group.
</P>
<P>
92. The inkjet ink composition of claim 91, wherein the second organic group comprises at least one ionic group, at least one ionizable group, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
93. The inkjet ink composition of claim 91, wherein the second organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of phenylphosphonic acid.
</P>
<P>
94. The inkjet ink composition of claim 88, further comprising a second modified pigment comprising a pigment having attached or adsorbed at least one polymer.
</P>
<P>
95. The inkjet ink composition of claim 94, wherein the second modified pigment is a polymer coated pigment.
</P>
<P>
96. The inkjet ink composition of claim 94, wherein the second modified pigment is a pigment having attached at least one polymeric group, wherein the polymeric group comprises the polymer.
</P>
<P>
97. The inkjet ink composition of claim 88, wherein the vehicle is an aqueous vehicle.
</P>
<P>
98. An inkjet ink composition comprising a) a liquid vehicle and b) a modified colorant comprising a pigment having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group comprises:
</P>
<P>
i) at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof,
</P>
<P>
ii) at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof,
</P>
<P>
iii) at least one phosphonic acid group or salt thereof and at least one second ionic, ionizable, or basic group, or
</P>
<P>
iv) an aryl group having at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
99. The inkjet ink composition of claim 98, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
100. The inkjet ink composition of claim 98, wherein the organic group comprises at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
101. The inkjet ink composition of claim 98, wherein the organic group comprises an aryl group having at least one nitroso group and at least one OH group or a salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
102. The inkjet ink composition of claim 98, further comprising a second modified pigment comprising a pigment having attached at least one second organic group different from the organic group.
</P>
<P>
103. The inkjet ink composition of claim 102, wherein the second organic group comprises at least one ionic group, at least one ionizable group, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
104. The inkjet ink composition of claim 102, wherein the second organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of phenylphosphonic acid.
</P>
<P>
105. The inkjet ink composition of claim 102, further comprising a second modified pigment comprising a pigment having attached or adsorbed at least one polymer.
</P>
<P>
106. The inkjet ink composition of claim 105, wherein the second modified pigment is a polymer coated pigment.
</P>
<P>
107. The inkjet ink composition of claim 105, wherein the second modified pigment is a pigment having attached at least one polymeric group, wherein the polymeric group comprises the polymer.
</P>
<P>
108. An inkjet ink composition comprising a) a liquid vehicle and b) a modified colorant comprising a pigment having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group comprises:
</P>
<P>
i) at least one heterocyclic group having at least one OH group or salt thereof,
</P>
<P>
ii) a heteroaryl group having at least one carboxylic acid groups or salts thereof, or
</P>
<P>
iii) an azoarene group has at least one OH group, at least one NH2 group, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
109. The inkjet ink composition of claim 108, wherein the organic group comprises an azoarene group having at least two OH groups, at least two NH2 groups, or one OH group and one NH2 group and has the formula Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; -N-N-Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , wherein Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; , which can be the same or different, are an arylene group or an aryl group and at least one of Ar&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt; or Ar&amp;lt;2 &amp;gt; is an arylene group.
</P>
<P>
110. An inkjet ink composition comprising a) a liquid vehicle and b) a modified colorant comprising a dye having attached at least one organic group, wherein the organic group comprises:
</P>
<P>
i) at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof, or
</P>
<P>
ii) at least one hydroxamic acid group or salt thereof.
</P>
<P>
111. An inkjet ink composition comprising a) a liquid vehicle and b) a modified pigment comprising a colorant having attached at least one organic group and at least one second organic group, wherein the organic group has a calcium index value greater than a calcium index value of phenylphosphonic acid and wherein the second organic group is a polymeric group.
</P>
<P>
112. The inkjet ink composition of claim 111, wherein the organic group comprises at least two phosphonic acid groups, partial esters thereof, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
113. The inkjet ink composition of claim 111, wherein the organic group comprises an aryl polyacid group having at least three carboxylic acids.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007100024A1;WO2007053564A2;WO2007053564A3;WO2007053563A2;WO2007053563A3;US2007100023A1;KR20080065686A;KR20080079249A;JP2009515007A;JP2009513802A;EP2431427A1;EP2431426A1;EP2431425A1;EP1951819A2;EP1951819B1;BRPI0618109A2;BRPI0618100A2;AU2006308952A1;AU2006308951A1;AT464355T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
