<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Thermoplastic resin composition, polycarbonate resin composition, and molded article thereo
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1944337A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NODERA AKIO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NODERA, AKIO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
IDEMITSU KOSAN CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
IDEMITSU KOSAN CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1944337
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080152892
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-01-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060126479
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-01-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030734619
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-01-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20020021023
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-01-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20020021024
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-01-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20020350850
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-12-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08K3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/49
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/523
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/49
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/523
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a thermoplastic resin composition containing 100 parts by mass of a mixture of a thermoplastic resin (A) and carbon nanotubes (B), the mixture being composed of the component (A) in an amount of 20 to 99.95 mass% and the component (B) in an amount of 0.05 to 20 mass%;  a flame retardant (C) in an amount of 0.05 to 30 parts by mass;  and a polyfluoroolefin resin in an amount of 0 to 2 parts by mass. The flame retardant is preferably a phosphorus compound, and the thermoplastic resin preferably contains, as a component, an aromatic polycarbonate-polyorganosiloxane copolymer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A polycarbonate resin composition comprising 100 parts by mass of a mixture of
</P>
<P>
an aromatic polycarbonate-polyorganosiloxane copolymer (A1) having an end group represented by formula (1):
</P>
<P>
wherein R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; represents an alkyl group having 1 to 35 of carbon atoms and a is an integer from 0 to 5,
</P>
<P>
an aromatic polycarbonate resin (A2) having an end group represented by formula (2)
</P>
<P>
wherein R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; represents an alkyl group having 1 to 35 of carbon atoms and b is an integer of 0 to 5, and
</P>
<P>
carbon nanotubes (B), the mixture being composed of the component (A1) in an amount of 0.1 to 99.9 mass%, the component (A2) in an amount of 0 to 99.8 mass%, and the component (B) in an amount of 0.1 to 30 mass%; and a polytetrafluoroethylene resin (E) in an amount of 0 to 2 parts by mass.
</P>
<P>
2. The polycarbonate resin composition as described in claim 1, wherein the carbon nanotubes contain amorphous carbon particles in an amount of 20 mass% or less and have a diameter of 0.5 to 120 nm and a length of 500 nm or more.
</P>
<P>
3. The polycarbonate resin composition as described in claim 1 or 2, wherein the carbon nanotubes have open ends.
</P>
<P>
4. The polycarbonate resin composition as described in any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the phosphorus-containing compound is a phosphite ester.
</P>
<P>
5. A polycarbonate resin composition as described in any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the aromatic polycarbonate-polyorganosiloxane copolymer has a polyorganosiloxane moiety which is a polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) skeleton.
</P>
<P>
6. A polycarbonate resin composition as described in claim 5, which contains polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) in an amount of 0.1 to 10 mass %.
</P>
<P>
7. A polycarbonate resin composition as described in any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein the aromatic polycarbonate resin (A2) has an alkyl group having 10 to 35 of carbon atoms at an end of the molecule.
</P>
<P>
8. A molded product of a thermoplastic resin composition as recited in any one of claims 1 to 7.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1944337A3;EP1944337B1;EP1471114A1;EP1471114A4;EP1471114B1;US2008176978A1;US8044127B2;US2006089434A1;US7307120B2;WO03064536A1;EP1801164A1;EP1801164B1;DE60315132T2;AT368080T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
