<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
COMPOSITION FOR USE IN THE FORMATION OF HARDCOAT LAYER AND OPTICAL LENS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1947155A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MURAI SACHIO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ITO HIDEKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MIYANO YOSHIFUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA HIROKAZU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MURAI, SACHIO
</Name>
<Name>
ITO, HIDEKI
</Name>
<Name>
MIYANO, YOSHIFUMI
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA, HIROKAZU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CATALYSTS &amp; CHEM IND CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
CATALYSTS &amp; CHEMICALS INDUSTRIES CO., LTD
</Name>
<Name>
JGC CATALYSTS AND CHEMICALS LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1947155
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060811873
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-17
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP320618
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050303322
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/12
</Class>
<Class>
C09D183/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09D183/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12
</Class>
<Class>
C09J7/04
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/10
</Class>
<Class>
G02C7/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00H
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00H2
</Class>
<Class>
C09D183/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12D2
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N1
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N2
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/10B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The hard coat layer-forming composition of this invention includes (A) composite oxide fine particles with a mean particle diameter of 1 to 200 nm, containing titanium, tin and optionally silicon, and with a rutile-type crystal structure, (B) an organosilicon compound represented by the formula R 1 a R 2 b Si(OR 3 ) 4-(a+b) and/or a hydrolyzate thereof, and (C) a cyanamide derivative compound. A hard coat layer formed from the composition not only is excellent in transparency, scratch resistance, adhesion property, weathering resistance, impact resistance, etc. but also can enjoy no coloration or little coloration, particularly in bluing or yellowing, upon exposure to or irradiation with ultraviolet rays, even if an antireflection film is provided.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A hard coat layer-forming composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
(A) composite oxide fine particles with a mean particle diameter of 1 to 200 nm, containing titanium, tin and optionally silicon, and with a rutile-type crystal structure,
</P>
<P>
(B) an organosilicon compound represented by the following formula (I) and/or a hydrolyzate thereof,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; aR&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; bSi(OR&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; )4-(a+b) (I)
</P>
<P>
wherein R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an organic group having 8 or less carbon atoms containing a vinyl group, an organic group having 8 or less carbon atoms containing an epoxy group, an organic group having 8 or less carbon atoms containing a methacryloxy group, an organic group having 1 to 5 carbon atoms containing a mercapto group, or an organic group having 1 to 5 carbon atoms containing an amino group,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 3 carbon atoms, a cycloalkyl group having 3 carbon atoms or a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 3 carbon atoms, or an allyl group,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 4 carbon atoms or a cycloalkyl group having 3 to 4 carbon atoms,
</P>
<P>
a is 0 or 1, and b is 0, 1 or 2,and
</P>
<P>
(C) a cyanamide derivative compound.
</P>
<P>
2. The hard coat layer-forming composition as claimed in claim 1, wherein the composite oxide fine particles (A) are those coated with a composite oxide containing silicon and zirconium and/or aluminum.
</P>
<P>
3. The hard coat layer-forming composition as claimed in claim 1 or 2, wherein the cyanamide derivative compound is one or more compounds selected from the group consisting of guanidine, a guanidine organic acid, a guanidine inorganic acid salt, an alkylguanidine, aminoguanidine and dicyandiamide.
</P>
<P>
4. The hard coat layer-forming composition as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 3, further comprising an uncrosslinked epoxy compound.
</P>
<P>
5. The hard coat layer-forming composition as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 4, further comprising, as a curing agent, one or more compounds selected from the group consisting of an organic carboxylic acid and an acetylacetone metal chelate compound.
</P>
<P>
6. An optical lens comprising a plastic lens base material and a hard coat layer provided on the plastic lens base material, wherein the hard coat layer is formed from a hard coat layer-forming composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
(A) composite oxide fine particles with a mean particle diameter of 1 to 200 nm, containing titanium, tin and optionally silicon, and with a rutile-type crystal structure,
</P>
<P>
(B) an organosilicon compound represented by the following formula (I) and/or a hydrolyzate thereof,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; aR&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; bSi (OR&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; )4-(a+b) (I)
</P>
<P>
wherein R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an organic group having 8 or less carbon atoms containing a vinyl group, an organic group having 8 or less carbon atoms containing an epoxy group, an organic group having 8 or less carbon atoms containing a methacryloxy group, an organic group having 1 to 5 carbon atoms containing a mercapto group, or an organic group having 1 to 5 carbon atoms containing an amino group,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 3 carbon atoms, a cycloalkyl group having 3 carbon atoms or a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 3 carbon atoms, or an allyl group,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 4 carbon atoms or a cycloalkyl group having 3 to 4 carbon atoms,
</P>
<P>
a is 0 or 1, and b is 0, 1 or 2,and
</P>
<P>
(C) a cyanamide derivative compound.
</P>
<P>
7. The optical lens as claimed in claim 6, wherein the hard coat layer has a refractive index of not less than 1.52.
</P>
<P>
8. The optical lens as claimed in claim 6 or 7, wherein an antireflection film is formed on an upper side surface of the hard coat layer.
</P>
<P>
9. The optical lens as claimed in any one of claims 6 to 8, wherein a primer layer is formed between the plastic lens base material and the hard coat layer.
</P>
<P>
10. The optical lens as claimed in claim 9, wherein the primer layer is formed from a coating composition containing a mixture of a polyurethane resin or a polyester resin, and metal oxide fine particles, or a composite polymer obtained by reacting them.
</P>
<P>
11. The optical lens as claimed in claim 10, wherein the metal oxide fine particles are composite oxide fine particles with a mean particle diameter of 1 to 200 nm, containing titanium, tin and optionally silicon, and with a rutile-type crystal structure.
</P>
<P>
12. A cured coating film obtained by curing a coating film comprising the hard coat layer-forming composition of any one of claims 1 to 5.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1947155A4;US2010058955A1;US7978409B2;KR20080052688A;WO2007046357A1;CN101292005A;CN101292005B;AU2006305319A1;AU2006305319B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
