<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOPARTICLE AND METHODS THEREFOR
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1960308A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GAO ZHIQIANG [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
GAO, ZHIQIANG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AGENCY SCIENCE TECH &amp; RES [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
AGENCY FOR SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY AND RESEARCH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1960308
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060813147
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006SG00368
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050740676P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543K2B
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58H4
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
There is provided an electroactive nanoparticle, which may be used as a label in electrochemical detection assays. The nanoparticle comprises a transition metal oxide and a capping agent, the capping agent comprising a ligand group and a functional group. The capping agent is coordinated to a transition metal centre in the transition metal oxide via the ligand group. Also provided are methods relating to preparation of the nanoparticle and detection of an analyte molecule in a sample using electrochemical methods.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A nanoparticle comprising a transition metal oxide and a capping agent, the capping agent comprising a ligand group and a functional group, the capping agent coordinated to a transition metal centre in the transition metal oxide via the ligand group.
</P>
<P>
2. The nanoparticle of claim 1 wherein the transition metal oxide is a platinum group metal oxide.
</P>
<P>
3. The nanoparticle of claim 1 or claim 2 wherein the transition metal oxide is OsO2.
</P>
<P>
4. The nanoparticle of any one of claims 1 to 3 wherein the functional group is a primary amino group.
</P>
<P>
5. The nanoparticle of any one of claims 1 to 4 wherein the ligand group is an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
6. The nanoparticle of claim 5 wherein the capping agent is isoniazid.
</P>
<P>
7. The nanoparticle of any one of claims 1 to 6 having a diameter of from about 5 to about 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
8. The nanoparticle of claim 7 having a diameter of from about 20 to about 30 nm.
</P>
<P>
9. A method of preparing a nanoparticle comprising:
</P>
<P>
adding a capping agent to a transitional metal oxide precipitate, the capping agent comprising a ligand group and a functional group, the capping agent coordinating with a transition metal centre in the transition metal oxide precipitate via the ligand group.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9 wherein the transition metal oxide is a platinum group metal oxide.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9 or claim 10 wherein the transition metal precipitate is formed by adding a hydroxide base to a solution of a transition metal salt.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 11 wherein the transition metal salt comprises one or more alkaline earth metals, one or more halides or an ammonium ion.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of any one of claims 9 to 12 wherein the transition metal oxide is OsO2.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 11 wherein the osmium salt is K2OsCl6.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of any one of claims 11 to 14 wherein the solution comprises 20/80 ratio of water/ethanol.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of any one of claims 11 to 15 wherein the hydroxide base is sodium hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of any one of claims 9 to 16 wherein the functional group is a primary amino group.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of any one of claims 9 to 17 wherein the ligand group is an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 17 or claim 18 wherein the capping agent is isoniazid.
</P>
<P>
20. A method of detecting an analyte molecule in a sample, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
labelling the analyte molecule with a nanoparticle to form a nanoparticle/analyte molecule complex, the nanoparticle comprising a transition metal oxide and a capping agent, the capping agent comprising a ligand group and a functional group, the capping agent coordinated to a transition metal centre in the transition metal oxide via the ligand group, the capping agent reacting with the analyte molecule through the functional amino group; contacting the sample with a working electrode, the working electrode having a surface with a capture molecule disposed thereon to capture the analyte molecule from the sample;
</P>
<P>
contacting the captured analyte molecule that forms the nanoparticle-analyte molecule complex with a redox substrate, under conditions that allow for oxidation or reduction of the redox substrate; and
</P>
<P>
detecting current flow at the working electrode.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 20 wherein the labelling occurs prior to contacting the sample with the working electrode.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 20 wherein the labelling occurs after contacting the sample with the working electrode.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of any one of claim 20 to 22 wherein the transition metal oxide is a platinum group metal oxide.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of any one of claims 20 to 23 wherein the transition metal oxide is OsO2.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of any one of claims 20 to 24 wherein the functional group is a primary amino group.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of any one of claims 20 to 25 wherein the ligand group is an aryl group.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 25 or claim 26 wherein the capping agent is isoniazid.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of any one of claims 20 to 27 further comprising rinsing the working electrode prior to contacting the redox substrate with the captured analyte molecule.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of any one of claims 20 to 28 wherein the sample comprises a biological sample, a tissue culture, a tissue culture supernatant, a prepared biochemical sample, a field sample, a cell lysate or a fraction of a cell lysate.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 29 wherein the biological sample comprises a biological fluid and the prepared biochemical sample comprises a prepped nucleic acid sample or a prepped protein sample.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 30 wherein the sample comprises a prepped RNA sample.
</P>
<P>
32. The method of any one of claims 20 to 31 wherein the analyte molecule comprises a protein, a peptide, DNA, mRNA, microRNA or a small molecule.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 20 wherein the analyte molecule is a microRNA.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of any one of claims 20 to 33 wherein the capture molecule comprises a protein, a peptide, DNA, RNA, an oligonucleotide, a ligand, a receptor, an antibody or a small molecule.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of claim 34 wherein the capture molecule comprises an oligonucleotide having a sequence complementary to the sequence of a microRNA.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of any one of claims 20 to 35 wherein the redox substrate is hydrazine or ascorbic acid.
</P>
<P>
37. The method of any one of claims 20 to 36 wherein the working electrode comprises carbon paste, carbon fiber, graphite, glassy carbon, gold, silver, copper, platinum, palladium, a metal oxide or a conductive polymer.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of claim 37 wherein the metal oxide is indium tin oxide and the conductive polymer is poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) (PEDOT) or polyaniline.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of any one of claims 20 to 38 wherein the analyte molecule is labelled directly with the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of any one of claims 20 to 38 wherein a labelling molecule is used to label the analyte molecule indirectly with the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
41. The method of claim 40 wherein the labelling molecule comprises a protein, a peptide, a ligand, an antibody, a nucleic acid binding protein or protein domain or an oligonucleotide.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007064301A1;US2009305247A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
