<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Surfaces physically transformable by environmental changes
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1948555A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
AIZENBERG JOANNA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KRUPEKIN THOMAS NIKITA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SYDORENKO OLEKSANDER [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TAYLOR JOSEPH ASHLEY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AIZENBERG, JOANNA
</Name>
<Name>
KRUPEKIN, THOMAS NIKITA
</Name>
<Name>
SYDORENKO, OLEKSANDER
</Name>
<Name>
TAYLOR, JOSEPH, ASHLEY
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LUCENT TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LUCENT TECHNOLOGIES INC
</Name>
<Name>
ALCATEL LUCENT
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1948555
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060815382
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US37335
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050239973
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-09-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B81B1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B81B3/00S10
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An apparatus includes a substrate having a top surface, a substantially regular array of raised structures located over the top surface, and a layer located on the top surface between the structures. Distal surfaces of the structures are farther from the top surface than remaining portions of the structures. The layer is able to contract such that the distal surfaces of the structures protrude through the layer. The layer is able to swell such that the distal surfaces of the structures are closer to the top surface of the substrate than one surface of the layer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An apparatus, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate having a top surface;
</P>
<P>
a substantially regular array of raised structures located over the top surface, distal surfaces of the structures being farther from the top surface than remaining portions of the structures; and
</P>
<P>
a layer being located over the top surface and being between the structures, the layer being able to contract such that the distal surfaces of the structures protrude through the layer, the layer being able to swell such that the distal surfaces of the structures are closer to the top surface of the substrate than one surface of the layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the layer comprises a hydrogel.
</P>
<P>
3. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the layer is capable of performing the swelling and the contracting responsive to humidity changes.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the one surface of the layer is chemically functionalized with antibodies, nucleic acid, or protein.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the one surface of the layer is chemically functionalized with molecules that change a wettability of the layer.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 2, wherein the one surface of the layer is coated with a fluorinated polymer.
</P>
<P>
7. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the structures comprise one of posts, on-edge planes, and closed cells.
</P>
<P>
8. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the structures have a linear feature dimension lateral to the surface, the dimension being smaller than about 4 microns.
</P>
<P>
9. The apparatus of claim 1, further comprising an anchoring layer bonded to the substrate and the layer.
</P>
<P>
10. The apparatus of claim 9, wherein distal portions of the structures intersect an imaginary plane such that the distal portions occupy less than 10% of the portion of the plane between the structures.
</P>
<P>
11. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the layer is capable of performing the swelling and the contracting responsive to one of temperature changes, pH changes, dissolved ion concentration changes, and illumination level changes.
</P>
<P>
12-20. (canceled)
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1948555B1;US2007077396A1;US8084116B2;US2012036846A1;WO2007041080A1;JP2009509783A;AT531668T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
