<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
TECHNIQUE FOR SEPARATING A MOLD FROM SOLIDIFIED IMPRINTING MATERIAL
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1954472A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GANAPATHISUBRAMANIAN MAHADEVAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI BYUNG-JIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MILLER MICHAEL N [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STACEY NICHOLAS A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WATTS MICHAEL P C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GANAPATHISUBRAMANIAN, MAHADEVAN
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI, BYUNG-JIN
</Name>
<Name>
MILLER, MICHAEL, N
</Name>
<Name>
STACEY, NICHOLAS, A
</Name>
<Name>
WATTS, MICHAEL, P., C
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1954472
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060804074
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US37109
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050292568
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050303777
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C43/00
</Class>
<Class>
B29C59/02
</Class>
<Class>
B29C69/00
</Class>
<Class>
B41F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B41F19/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F1/92
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B29C33/44B2
</Class>
<Class>
B29C43/00B
</Class>
<Class>
B29C43/02B
</Class>
<Class>
B29C43/50
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a method for separating a mold (136) from solidified imprinting material that includes creating deformation in the template (214) in which the mold is included. The deformation (P2) is sufficient to create a returning force that is greater than the adhesion force between the solidified imprinting material and the mold. For example, the deformation may result from a pressure differential created by a pump system (546) between the mold and a side of the template disposed opposite to the mold. In this manner, the distortion may be undulations in the template of sufficient magnitude to contact a substrate upon which the solidified imprinting material is disposed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for separating a mold, included in a template, from solidified imprinting material disposed on a substrate, said method comprising: creating deformation in said template proximate to said mold, sufficient to create a returning force that is greater than an adhesion force between said solidified imprinting material and said mold.
</P>
<P>
2. The method as recited in claim 1 wherein said template includes a first side, disposed opposite to said mold, with creating further including inducing a pressure differential between said first side and said mold.
</P>
<P>
3. The method as recited in claim 1 wherein creating further includes generating an undulation in said mold of sufficient magnitude to contact said substrate.
</P>
<P>
4. The method as recited in claim 1 wherein said mold includes a perimeter and further including separating regions of said mold, from said solidified imprinting material, disposed concentrically with respect to said perimeter.
</P>
<P>
5. The method as recited in claim 1 wherein said mold includes a perimeter and further including sequentially separating a plurality of regions of said mold, from said solidified imprinting material, disposed concentrically with respect to said perimeter.
</P>
<P>
6. The method as recited in claim 1 further including separating regions of said mold, from said solidified imprinting material, that are radially symmetrically disposed about an axis passing through a center of said mold.
</P>
<P>
7. The method as recited in claim 1 further including sequentially separating a plurality of regions of said mold, from said solidified imprinting material, that are radially symmetrically disposed about an axis passing through a center of said mold.
</P>
<P>
8. The method as recited in claim 1 further including separating regions of said mold, from said solidified imprinting material, by rotating said mold about an axis that extends transversely to a normal of a surface of said mold.
</P>
<P>
9. The method as recited in claim 1 wherein generating further includes forming a surface of said template surrounding mold to have a constant radius of curvature.
</P>
<P>
10. A method for spreading a conformable material between a substrate and a template having a mold, said method comprising: positioning said mold to be in superimposition with said substrate defining a volume therebetween; charging a first sub-portion of said volume with said conformable material through capillary action between said conformable material and one of said mold and said substrate; and filling a second sub-portion of said volume by creating a deformation in said mold.
</P>
<P>
11. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein said template includes a first side, disposed opposite to said mold, with filling further including creating a pressure differential between said first side and said mold.
</P>
<P>
12. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein said mold includes a central portion and filling further includes contacting conformable material with said central portion and subsequently contacting the remaining portions of said mold with said conformable material.
</P>
<P>
13. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein said mold includes a neutral axis and charging further includes bowing said neutral axis before contacting said conformable material.
</P>
<P>
14. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein positioning further including centering said mold with respect to said substrate.
</P>
<P>
15. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein said mold has an area associated therewith that is greater than an area of said substrate.
</P>
<P>
16. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein said template includes a first side, disposed opposite to said mold, with charging further includes varying a distance between said mold and said substrate, while maintaining a substantially equal pressure on said first side and said mold.
</P>
<P>
17. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein charging occurs before filling.
</P>
<P>
18. The method as recited in claim 10 wherein said first and second sub-portions have an aggregate volume associated therewith that is less than said volume.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1954472A4;WO2007064386A1;US2007126150A1;US7906058B2;TWI310730B;KR20080071151A;JP2009517882A;EP2413189A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
