<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CARBON NANOTUBES FUNCTIONALIZED WITH FULLERENES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1948562A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KAUPPINEN ESKO [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
BROWN DAVID P [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
NASIBULIN ALBERT G [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
JIANG HUA [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
KAUPPINEN, ESKO
</Name>
<Name>
BROWN, DAVID P
</Name>
<Name>
NASIBULIN, ALBERT G
</Name>
<Name>
JIANG, HUA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CANATU OY [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
CANATU OY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1948562
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060764432
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-06-15
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006FI00206
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-15
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
FI20050001171
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01B
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B2
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D6
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to covalently bonded fullerene-functionalized carbon nanotubes (CBFFCNTs), a method and an apparatus for their production and to their end products. CBFFCNTs are carbon nanotubes with one or more fullerenes or fullerene based molecules covalently bonded to the nanotube surface. They are obtained by bringing one or more catalyst particles, carbon sources and reagents together in a reactor.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube, characteri sed in that the carbon nanotube comprises one or more fullerenes and/or fullerene based molecules covalently bonded to the carbon nanotube .
</P>
<P>
2. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to claim 1, charact e ri s ed in that one or more fullerenes and/or fullerene based molecules are covalently bonded to the outer surface and/or to the inner surface of the carbon nanotube .
</P>
<P>
3. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to any of claims 1 - 2 , characteri s ed in that the fullerene and/or fullerene based molecule comprises 20 - 1000 atoms.
</P>
<P>
4. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to any of claims 1 - 3 , cha ract e ri s ed in that the fullerene and/or fullerene based molecule are/is covalently bonded via one or more bridging groups and/or are/is directly covalently bonded.
</P>
<P>
5. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to claim 4, characteri s ed in that the bridging group comprises oxygen, hydrogen, nitrogen, sulphur, an amino, a thiol, an ether, an ester, a carboxylic group and/or a carbon-containing group .
</P>
<P>
6. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to claim 4, chara ct e ri s ed in that the fullerene and/or fullerene based molecule are/is directly covalently bonded through one or more carbon bonds .
</P>
<P>
7. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to any of claims 1 - 6, chara ct er i s ed in that said carbon nanotube comprises a single, a double or a multiple walled carbon nanotube or a composite carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
8. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to any of claims 1 - 7, cha ract e ri s ed in that said carbon nanotube is formulated in a solid, liquid and/or gas dispersion, a solid structure, a powder, a paste, a colloidal suspension and/or is deposited on a surface and/or is synthesized on a surface.
</P>
<P>
9. Fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube according to any of claims 1 - 8 , cha racte r i s ed in that it is bonded through one or more fullerenes and/or fullerene based molecules to one or more carbon nanotubes and/or fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
10. A method for producing one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes according to any of claims 1 - 9, chara ct e ri s ed in that the method comprises: bringing one or more catalyst particles, carbon sources and/or reagents into contact with each other and heating in a reactor to produce one or more carbon nanotubes comprising one or more fullerenes and/or fullerene based molecules covalently bonded to the one or more carbon nanotubes .
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to claim 10, characteri s ed in that the carbon source is selected from a group, which consists of methane, ethane, propane, ethylene, acetylene, benzene, toluene, xylene, trimethylbenzene, methanol, ethanol, octanol , tiophene and carbon monoxide. 12. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
11, characteri s ed in that the reagent is an etching agent .
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
12, charact e r i s ed in that the reagent is selected from a group, which consists of hydrogen, nitrogen, water, carbon dioxide, nitrous oxide, nitrogen dioxide, oxygen, ozone, carbon monoxide, octanol , thiophene and hydride .
</P>
<P>
14. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
13, cha racte ri s e d in that the catalyst particle comprises a metal, preferably a transition metal and/or a combination of metals and/or transition metals.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
14, cha racteris e d in that the catalyst particle comprises iron, cobalt, nickel, chromium, molybdenum and/or palladium.
</P>
<P>
16 A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
15, cha ract e r i s ed in that the catalyst .particle is produced using a chemical precursor and/or by heating a metal or metal containing substance.
</P>
<P>
17. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
16, cha ract e ri s ed in that the amount of fullerene and/or fullerene based molecules produced on the carbon nanotube is adjusted by adjusting the amount of one or more reagents used, by adjusting the heating temperature and/or by adjusting the residence time .
</P>
<P>
18. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
17, charact e r i s ed in that the heating is performed at a temperature of 250 - 2500 [deg.]C, preferably
</P>
<P>
600 - 1000 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
19. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
18, chara ct e r i s ed in that the method further comprises the following step: introducing one or more additional reagents.
</P>
<P>
20. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
19, cha ract eri s ed in that the method further comprises the following step: introducing one or more additives to produce a fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube composite material .
</P>
<P>
21. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
20, c h a r a c t e r i s e d in that the method further comprises the following step: collecting the produced one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes and/or the fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube composite material in a solid, liquid and/or gas dispersion, a solid structure, a powder, a paste, a colloidal suspension and/or as a film and/or surface deposition. 22. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
21, c h a r a ct e r i s e d in that the method further comprises the following step: depositing a dispersion of produced fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes and/or fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube composite material onto a surface and/or into a matrix and/or a layered structure and/or a device .
</P>
<P>
23. A method according to any of claims 10 -
</P>
<P>
22, ch a r a c t e r i s e d in that the fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes are produced in a gas phase as an aerosol and/or on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
24. An apparatus for producing one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes according to any of claims 1 - 9, ch a r a ct e r i s e d in that the apparatus comprises a reactor for heating one or more catalyst particles, carbon sources and/or reagents to produce one or more carbon nanotubes comprising one or more fullerenes and/or fullerene based molecules covalently bonded to the one or more carbon nanotubes .
</P>
<P>
25. An apparatus according to claim 24, c ha r a c t e r i s e d in that the apparatus further comprises one or more of the following: means for producing catalyst particles; means for introducing one or more catalyst particles; means for introducing one or more catalyst particle precursors; means for introducing one or more carbon sources; means for introducing one or more carbon source precursors; means for introducing one or more reagents; means for introducing one or more reagent precursors ; means for introducing one or more additional reagents; means for introducing one or more additives; means for collecting the produced one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes and/or fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube composite material ; means for depositing a dispersion of produced fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes and/or fullerene functionalized carbon nanotube composite material ; means for supplying energy to said means for producing catalyst particles and/or to the reactor.
</P>
<P>
26. An apparatus according to any of claims 24 - 25, charact er i s ed in that the means for producing catalyst particles comprises a hot wire generator.
</P>
<P>
27. A functional material, charact er i s ed in that it is made using one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes according to any of claims 1 - 9.
</P>
<P>
28. A thick or thin film, a line, a wire or a layered or three dimensional structure, characteri sed in that it is made using one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes according to any of claims 1 - 9 or a functional material according to claim 27.
</P>
<P>
29. A device, cha ract e ri s ed in that it is made by using one or more fullerene functionalized carbon nanotubes according to any of claims 1 - 9 and/or a functional material according to claim 27 and/or a thick or thin film, a line, a wire or a layered or three dimensional structure according to claim 28.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1948562B1;WO2007057501A1;US2009226704A1;SI1948562T1;RU2008121393A;RU2437832C2;KR20080082646A;JP2009515804A;FI120195B1;ES2351845T3;DK1948562T3;CN101370734A;CA2630166A1;AU2006314401A1;AT474812T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
