<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR FORMING MOLECULAR SEQUENCES ON SURFACES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1996947A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GULARI ERDOGAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ROUILLARD JEAN-MARIE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GAO XIAOLIAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHOU XIAOCHUAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GULARI, ERDOGAN
</Name>
<Name>
ROUILLARD, JEAN-MARIE
</Name>
<Name>
GAO, XIAOLIAN
</Name>
<Name>
ZHOU, XIAOCHUAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV MICHIGAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIV HOUSTON [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN
</Name>
<Name>
UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1996947
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070759251
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US64791
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060785938P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070690368
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-23
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C07B61/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K14/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/551
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J19/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C40B50/18
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for forming molecular sequences includes derivatizing an unconfined substrate surface with at least one linker containing a protected reactive group. The substrate is contacted with a solution containing a photogenerated reagent precursor and a buffer and/or a neutralizer. A photogenerated reagent is generated in at least a portion of the solution. The photogenerated reagent is configured to initiate the formation of at least one active region on the substrate surface. A monomer is coupled to the active region.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for forming a molecular sequence, comprising:
</P>
<P>
derivatizing an unconfined substrate surface with at least one linker containing a protected reactive group;
</P>
<P>
contacting the substrate with a solution containing a photogenerated reagent precursor and at least one of a buffer or a neutralizer;
</P>
<P>
generating a photogenerated reagent in at least a portion of the solution, the photogenerated reagent configured to initiate the formation of at least one active region on the substrate surface; and
</P>
<P>
coupling a monomer to the at least one active region.
</P>
<P>
2. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the photogenerated reagent precursor is selected from a photoacid generating molecule and a photobase generating molecule.
</P>
<P>
3. The method as defined in claim 2 wherein the photogenerated reagent is selected from an acid and a base.
</P>
<P>
4. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein generating the photogenerated reagent is accomplished via selectively exposing at least one region of the substrate to electromagnetic radiation.
</P>
<P>
5. The method as defined in claim 4 wherein the photogenerated reagent is substantially confined to the at least one exposed region via the at least one of the buffer or neutralizer.
</P>
<P>
6. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the photogenerated reagent diffuses to a surface of the substrate where it catalyzes deprotection of the protected reactive group, thereby exposing a reactive group and forming the at least one active region.
</P>
<P>
7. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein prior to coupling the monomer to the at least one active region, the method further comprises removing the solution from the substrate.
</P>
<P>
8. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the monomer has two ends, one of the two ends being unprotected and an other of the two ends having a protected reactive group attached thereto.
</P>
<P>
9. The method as defined in claim 8 wherein the contacting, the generating, and the coupling steps are repeated to form a predetermined sequence.
</P>
<P>
10. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the solution further comprises at least one of a sensitizer, a stabilizer, a viscosity additive, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the photogenerated reagent is an acid, and wherein the buffer or neutralizer is selected from pyridine, lutidine, piperidine, primary amines, secondary amines, tertiary amines, derivatives thereof, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the photogenerated reagent is a base, and wherein the buffer or neutralizer is selected from benzillic acid, aluminum chloride, iron (III) chloride, boron trifluoride, ytterbium (III) triflate, butyric acid, propionic acid, phenol, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the monomer has two unprotected ends.
</P>
<P>
14. The method as defined in claim 1 wherein the monomer is in a solution containing at least one activator.
</P>
<P>
15. The method as defined in claim 14 wherein the at least one activator is selected from tetrazole; 4,5,dicyanoimidazole (DCI); pyridiniumtrifluoroacetate; 5-ethlythiotetrazole; (3,5-dintrophenyl)-1H-tetrazole; trimethylchlorosilane; activator 42 (5-(bis-3,5-trifluormethylphenyl)1-H-tetrazole; derivatives thereof, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. A molecular sequence formed by the method of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
17. An apparatus, comprising:
</P>
<P>
an unconfined substrate surface; and
</P>
<P>
a molecular sequence coupled to the unconfined substrate surface.
</P>
<P>
18. The apparatus as defined in claim 17 wherein the molecular sequence includes a first monomer coupled to the unconfined substrate surface via a reactive group of a linker.
</P>
<P>
19. The apparatus as defined in claim 18 wherein the reactive group initially contains a protection group that is removed via a photogenerated reagent.
</P>
<P>
20. The apparatus as defined in claim 17 wherein the molecular sequence is formed of a plurality of monomers coupled together.
</P>
<P>
21. The apparatus as defined in claim 20 wherein each of the plurality of monomers is selected from nucleotides, locked nucleic acid monomers, amino acids, monosaccharides, disaccharides, and combinations thereof.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007224616A1;WO2008118167A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
