<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR THE PREPARATION OF AQUEOUS DISPERSIONS OF TIO2 IN THE FORM OF NANOPARTICLES, AND DISPERSIONS OBTAINABLE WITH THIS METHOD
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1996515A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BALDI GIOVANNI [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
BITOSSI MARCO [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
BARZANTI ANDREA [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
BALDI, GIOVANNI
</Name>
<Name>
BITOSSI, MARCO
</Name>
<Name>
BARZANTI, ANDREA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
COLOROBBIA ITALIANA SPA [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
COLOROBBIA ITALIA S.P.A
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1996515
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070726249
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-01-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP50826
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-29
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
IT2006FI00030
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J35/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C03C17/25
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J35/00D6
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C03C17/245C
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D8
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to a method for the preparation of aqueous dispersions of TiO2 in the crystalline form anatase, as well as the dispersions obtained with said method, useful for the preparation of photocatalytic coatings for surfaces, and for the photocatalytic decontamination of gases and liquids.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Method for the preparation of nanoparticle dispersions of TiO2 in anatase form, wherein a titanium alkoxide is made to react under heat in water in the presence of mineral acids and a non-ionic surfactant, the solution thus obtained is possibly reduced to a small volume if necessary.
</P>
<P>
2. Method according to claim 1 , wherein said Titanium alkoxide is chosen from a group composed of titanium methoxide, ethoxide, normal-propoxide, iso- propoxide, normal-butoxide, and isobutoxide.
</P>
<P>
3. Method according to claim 2, wherein said Titanium alkoxide is Titanium iso- propoxide.
</P>
<P>
4. Method according to claims 1 - 3 wherein said mineral acid is a halogen acid
</P>
<P>
5. Method according to claim 4 wherein said halogen acid is HCI.
</P>
<P>
6. Method according to claims 1 - 5 wherein said non-ionic surfactants possess the polar function of an ether or ester type. 7. Method according to claim 6 wherein said non-ionic surfactant is Triton X-100 (TX-100).
</P>
<P>
8. Method according to claims 1 - 7 wherein the titanium alkoxide/ halogen acid molar ratio is between 0.005 and 15.
</P>
<P>
9. Method according to claim 8 wherein the titanium alkoxide/ halogen acid molar ratio is between 5 and 6.
</P>
<P>
10. Method according to claims 1 - 9 wherein the reaction temperature is between 15[deg.]C and 95 [deg.]C, and the reaction times are between 12 and 72 hours.
</P>
<P>
11. Method according to claim 10 wherein the reaction temperature is between 45 [deg.]C and 55 [deg.]C, and the reaction time is 24 hours. 12. Method according to claims 1 - 1 1 wherein a metal salt Ag, or Cu or Ce, is added to the solution containing the titanium alkoxide, the mineral acid, and the surfactant.
</P>
<P>
13. Nanoparticle dispersions of TiO2 in anatase form in water, obtainable using the method as defined in claims 1 -1 1. 14. Nanoparticle dispersions of TiO2 in water, wherein the Ti is doped with a metal selected from the series of transition metals obtainable using the method according to claim 12.
</P>
<P>
15. Dispersions according to claim 14 wherein said transition metal is selected from the group composed of : Ag, Cu and Ce.
</P>
<P>
16. Use of nanoparticle dispersions of TiO2 according to claims 13 - 15, for the preparation of photocatalytic coatings on surfaces that require said treatment. 17. Use according to claim 16, wherein said surfaces are selected among the surfaces of textile fabric, metal, ceramic and enamelled products.
</P>
<P>
18. Use of nanoparticle dispersions of TiO2 according to claims 13 - 15, for photocatalytic decontamination of gases and liquids.
</P>
<P>
19. Use of nanoparticle dispersions of TiO2 according to claims 13 - 15, for the preparation of cosmetics with a protective action for the human skin against sun rays.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1996515B1;WO2007088151A1;ZA200806991A;US2008317959A1;RU2008135345A;RU2431604C2;PT1996515E;NZ570356A;KR20080094675A;JP2009525246A;ITFI20060030A1;ES2357369T3;DK1996515T3;CN101378993A;CA2640938A1;BRPI0707256A2;AU2007211536A1;AT490220T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
