<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYMERIC COMPOSITIONS CONTAINING NANOTUBES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1937763A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BHATT SANDEEP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PONCELET JEAN-MICHEL [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
TAORMINA VINCENZO [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
BHATT, SANDEEP
</Name>
<Name>
PONCELET, JEAN-MICHEL
</Name>
<Name>
TAORMINA, VINCENZO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CABOT CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CABOT CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1937763
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060851673
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-08-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US30609
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050706469P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-08-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
H01B3/44B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A polymeric composition containing at least one polymer and carbon nanotubes is described. The polymeric composition can have carbon nanotubes that are multi-wall carbon nanotubes and/or single-wall carbon nanotubes. The compositions can also contain carbon black. Also described are various articles made from the polymeric compositions including cables and other articles
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A polymeric composition comprising at least one polymer and carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
2. The polymeric composition of claim 1, wherein the carbon nanotubes are multi- wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
3. The polymeric composition of claim 1, wherein the carbon nanotubes are single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
4. The polymeric composition of claim 1, wherein the carbon nanotubes are purified carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
5. The polymeric composition of claim 1, further comprising carbon black.
</P>
<P>
6. The polymeric composition of claim 1, wherein the polymer comprises an ethylene containing polymer.
</P>
<P>
7. The polymeric composition of claim 6, wherein the ethylene containing polymer is an ethylene ethyl acrylate copolymer.
</P>
<P>
8. The polymeric composition of claim 6, wherein the ethylene containing polymer comprises an ethylene ethyl acrylate copolymer, an ethylene vinyl acetate copolymer, an ethylene propylene rubber, an ethylene propylenediene monomer, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. An article of manufacture formed, at least in part, from a composition comprising: an ethylene containing polymer, carbon nanotubes, and a crosslinking agent, and wherein the article is a cable.
</P>
<P>
10. The article of manufacture of claim 9, wherein: the ethylene containing polymer is present in an amount of from about 70% to about 99.95%, by weight, based on the total weight of the composition, the carbon nanotubes are present in an amount of from about 0.05% to about 60%, by weight, based on the total weight of the composition, the crosslinking agent is present in an amount of from about 1% to about 10%, by weight, based on the total weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
11. The article of manufacture of claim 9, wherein the ethylene containing polymer is an ethylene ethyl aery late copolymer.
</P>
<P>
12. The article of manufacture of claim 9, wherein the ethylene containing polymer is an ethylene ethyl acrylate copolymer, an ethylene vinyl acetate copolymer, an ethylene propylene rubber, an ethylene propylenediene monomer, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. The article of manufacture of claim 9, wherein the composition is a semiconductive composition, and the article of manufacture is an electric cable comprising: a metal conductor core; a semiconductive shield; an insulation layer; an outer semiconductive layer; and wherein the composition is utilized in at least one of the semiconductive shield or the outer semiconductive layer.
</P>
<P>
14. The article of manufacture of claim 13, wherein the composition is directly bonded to the insulation layer and the insulation layer comprises an ethylene homopolymer or copolymer.
</P>
<P>
15. A method of electrostatic painting an article comprising coating at least a portion of said article by electrostatic painting, wherein said article comprises the polymeric composition of claim 1, wherein said polymer is a conductive polymer.
</P>
<P>
16. The polymeric composition of claim 5, wherein said carbon black has one or more of following characteristics:
</P>
<P>
CDBP (dibutyl adsorption value of the crushed carbon black): 30 to 700 cc per 100 grams of carbon black.
</P>
<P>
Iodine number: 15 to 1,500 mg/g.
</P>
<P>
Primary particle size: 7 to 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
BET surface area: 12 to 1,800 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g
</P>
<P>
DBP: 30 to 1,000 cc per 100 grams of carbon black.
</P>
<P>
17. An article comprising the polymeric composition of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
18. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is an automotive article.
</P>
<P>
19. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is an internal trim, a dashboard, a panel, a bumper fascia, a mirror, a seat fiber, a switch, a housing.
</P>
<P>
20. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is a finger trap safety system.
</P>
<P>
21. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is a pipe, profile, tube, tape, film, membrane, jacketing, components thereof, or fittings thereof
</P>
<P>
22. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is a pressure pipe.
</P>
<P>
23. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is a fuel line.
</P>
<P>
24. The article of claim 17, wherein said article is an extruded article.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008041965A2;WO2008041965A3;US2010078194A1;RU2008109016A;RU2389739C2;KR20080053924A;JP2009521535A;CN101283027A;CA2620452A1;BRPI0614329A2;AU2006347615A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
