<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METAL-BASE NANOWIRE TRANSISTOR
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1952444A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
AGARWAL PRABHAT [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
HURKX GODEFRIDUS A M [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
AGARWAL, PRABHAT
</Name>
<Name>
HURKX, GODEFRIDUS, A., M
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONINKL PHILIPS ELECTRONICS NV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V
</Name>
<Name>
NXP B.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1952444
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060821239
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-10-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006IB53995
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-29
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20050110934
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-11-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060821239
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L29/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/76
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/76C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A metal-base transistor is suggested. The transistor comprises a first and a second electrode (2, 6) and base electrode (6) to control current flow between the first and second electrode. The first electrode (2) is made from a semiconduction material. The base electrode (3) is a metal layer deposited on top of the semiconducting material forming the first electrode. According the invention the second electrode is formed by a semiconducting nanowire (6) being in electrical contact with the base electrode (3).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. Transistor comprising a first, a second electrode (2, 6), and base electrode (3) to control current flow between the first and second electrode, wherein the first electrode (2) is made from a semiconducting material, wherein the base electrode is a metal layer deposited on top of the semiconducting material forming the first electrode, characterized in that the second electrode is formed by a semiconducting nanowire (6) being in electrical contact with the base electrode (3).
</P>
<P>
2. Transistor according to claim 1 characterized in that the nanowire (6) is growing on the base electrode (3).
</P>
<P>
3. Transistor according to claim 1 characterized in that the base electrode (3) is made from a transition metal suicide.
</P>
<P>
4. A transistor according to claim 3 that the transition metal is selected from the group of cobalt and nickel.
</P>
<P>
5. Transistor according to claim 1 characterized in that the nanowire (6) is made from silicon and/or germanium.
</P>
<P>
6. Transistor according to claim 5 characterized in that the nanowire is composed of a semiconductor heterostructure.
</P>
<P>
7. Transistor according to claim 6 characterized in that the composition of the nanowire (6) heterostructure changes in radial direction of the nanowire (6).
</P>
<P>
8. Transistor according to claim 6 characterized in that the composition of the nanowire heterostructure changes in axial direction of the nanowire (6).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1952444B1;WO2007057802A1;US2008237574A1;US7709923B2;KR20080074988A;KR101106913B1;JP2009516385A;CN101310389A;CN101310389B;AT518250T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
