<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PARTICULATE METAL OXIDE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1963438A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KESSELL LORNA MARGARET [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
TOOLEY IAN ROBERT [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
KESSELL, LORNA, MARGARET
</Name>
<Name>
TOOLEY, IAN, ROBERT
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CRODA INT PLC [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
CRODA INTERNATIONAL PLC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1963438
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060820611
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006GB04842
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20050026328
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-23
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09C1/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q17/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053D
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/04B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D4B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D8
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36P
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A particulate metal oxide having a median volume particle diameter in the range from 24 to 42 nm, a photogreying index in the range from 0.05 to 3 and/or and a yellowing index of less than 6. The dispersion can be used in a sunscreen product which is transparent, exhibits effective UV protection, reduced photoactivity, and reduced yellowing in combination with organic UV absorbers.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A particulate metal oxide having a median volume particle diameter in the range from 24 to 42 nm and a photogreying index in the range from 0.05 to 3.
</P>
<P>
2. A metal oxide according to claim 1 wherein the metal oxide particles have a photogreying index in the range from 0.2 to 2.
</P>
<P>
3. A metal oxide according to either one of claims 1 and 2 wherein the metal oxide particles have a yellowing index of less than 6.
</P>
<P>
4. A metal oxide according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the metal oxide particles have a yellowing index in the range from 0.5 to 5.
</P>
<P>
5. A metal oxide according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the metal oxide particles have an extinction coefficient at 524 nm in the range from 0.4 to 1.5 l/g/cm.
</P>
<P>
6. A metal oxide according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the metal oxide particles have an extinction coefficient at 360 nm in the range from 2 to 14 l/g/cm.
</P>
<P>
7. A metal oxide according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the metal oxide particles have an extinction coefficient at 308 nm in the range from 38 to 52 l/g/cm.
</P>
<P>
8. A metal oxide according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the metal oxide particles have at least one of (i) an extinction coefficient at 524 nm in the range from 0.7 to 1.3 l/g/cm, (ii) an extinction coefficient at 450 nm in the range from 1.2 to 1.8 l/g/cm, (iii) an extinction coefficient at 360 nm in the range from 4 to 8 l/g/cm, (iv) an extinction coefficient at 308 nm in the range from 42 to 48 l/g/cm, (v) a maximum extinction coefficient in the range from 61 to 69 l/g/cm, and/or (vi) a [lambda](max) in the range from 271 to 279 nm.
</P>
<P>
9. A particulate metal oxide having a median volume particle diameter in the range from 24 to 42 nm and a yellowing index of less than 6.
</P>
<P>
10. A metal oxide according to claim 9 wherein the metal oxide particles have a yellowing index in the range from 0.5 to 5.
</P>
<P>
11. A metal oxide according to either one of claims 9 and 10 wherein the metal oxide particles have a photogreying index of less than 5.
</P>
<P>
12. A dispersion comprising metal oxide particles according to any one of the preceding claims.
</P>
<P>
13. A dispersion comprising metal oxide particles having an extinction coefficient at 524 nm in the range from 0.4 to 1.5 l/g/cm, a photogreying index in the range from 0.05 to 3, and a yellowing index of less than 6.
</P>
<P>
14. A sunscreen product comprising metal oxide particles and/or dispersion according to any one of the preceding claims.
</P>
<P>
15. The use of metal oxide particles having a median volume particle diameter in the range from 24 to 42 nm and a photogreying index in the range from 0.05 to 3 to produce a sunscreen having reduced photoactivity.
</P>
<P>
16. The use of a dispersion comprising particles of metal oxide having a median volume particle diameter in the range from 24 to 42 nm and a yellowing index of less than 6, in the manufacture of a transparent sunscreen comprising an organic UV absorber.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007072008A2;WO2007072008A3;US2009098206A1;KR20080080563A;JP2009520675A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
