<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PASSIVATING LAYER FOR PHOTOVOLTAIC CELLS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP1974391A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LEE KWANGHEE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HEEGER ALAN J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LEE, KWANGHEE
</Name>
<Name>
HEEGER, ALAN J
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV CALIFORNIA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP1974391
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070717250
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-01-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US60124
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060756604P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-01-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060872401P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L27/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/10
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/10P
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/42H
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/44P
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/50G
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/50K
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E10/50
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An electronic device which comprises a first electrode, a second electrode, an active polymer layer between the first and the second electrodes, and a passivating layer adapted to enhance the lifetime of the electronic device. The passivating layer comprises a substantially amorphous titanium oxide having the formula of TiOx where x represents a number from 1 to 1.96.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. An electronic device comprising a first electrode, a second electrode, an active polymer layer between the first and the second electrodes, and a passivating layer adapted to enhance lifetime of the electronic device, wherein the passivating layer comprises a substantially amorphous titanium oxide having the formula of TiOx where x represents a number from 1 to 1.96.
</P>
<P>
2. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein in the formula of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.1 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
3. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein in the formula of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.2 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
4. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein the titanium oxide layer has a thickness ranging from 5 to 500 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
5. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein the titanium oxide layer has a thickness ranging from 5 to 100 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
6. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein the titanium oxide layer has a thickness ranging from 10 to 40 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
7. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein the titanium oxide layer is positioned adjacent to the active polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
8. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein the titanium oxide layer is positioned between the active polymer layer and one of the first and the second electrodes.
</P>
<P>
9. The electronic device of Claim 1 wherein the titanium oxide layer is a boundary layer of the electronic device.
</P>
<P>
10. The electronic device of Claim 1 which is a polymer diode.
</P>
<P>
11. The electronic device of Claim 1 which is a polymer light-emitting diode.
</P>
<P>
12. The electronic device of Claim 1 which is a photodiode.
</P>
<P>
13. The electronic device of Claim 1 which is a photodetector.
</P>
<P>
14. A light-emitting diode comprising an electron-injecting electrode, a hole- injecting electrode, a luminescent polymer layer between the electron-injecting electrode and the hole-injecting electrode, and a layer of substantially amorphous titanium oxide having the formula of TiOx where x represents a number from 1 to 1.96.
</P>
<P>
15. The light-emitting diode of Claim 14 wherein in the formula Of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.1 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
16. The light-emitting diode of Claim 14 wherein in the formula Of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.2 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
17. The light-emitting diode of Claim 14 wherein the layer of titanium oxide has a thickness ranging from 10 to 40 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
18. The light-emitting diode of Claim 14 wherein the layer of titanium oxide has a thickness of about 20 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
19. The light-emitting diode of Claim 14 wherein the layer of titanium oxide is positioned between the luminescent polymer layer and the electron injecting electrode.
</P>
<P>
20. The light-emitting diode of Claim 19 wherein the electron-injecting electrode comprises a metal electrode, the hole-injecting electrode comprises an indium-tin oxide and a hole injection layer of poly(3,4-ethylenedioxylenethiophene)-polystyrene sulfonic acid (ITO/P EDOT: PSS) bilayer electrode, the luminescent polymer layer comprises a luminescent semiconducting polymer of poly(2-methoxy, 5-(2&apos;-ethyl-hexyloxy)-1 A- phenylenevinylene) (MEH-PPV), and the layer of titanium oxide has a thickness of about 20 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
21. A field-effect transistor comprising a gate electrode, a gate dielectric, a source electrode, a drain electrode, a semiconducting polymer layer, and a layer of substantially amorphous titanium oxide having the formula Of TiOxwhere x represents a number from 1 to 1.96.
</P>
<P>
22. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein the titanium oxide layer is atop the semiconducting polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
23. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein the titanium oxide layer is a boundary layer of the field-effect transistor.
</P>
<P>
24. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein in the formula Of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.1 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
25. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein in the formula of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.2 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
26. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein the titanium oxide layer has a thickness ranging from 5 to 500 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
27. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein the titanium oxide layer has a thickness ranging from 5 to 100 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
28. The field-effect transistor of Claim 21 wherein the titanium oxide layer has a thickness ranging from 10 to 40 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
29. A photodetector comprising an electron-collecting electrode, a hole- collecting electrode, a photoactive, charge-separating layer comprising a semiconducting polymer blended with a suitable acceptor between the electron- collecting and the hole-collecting electrode, and a layer of substantially amorphous titanium oxide having a formula Of TiOx where x represents a number from 1 to 1.96.
</P>
<P>
30. The photodetector of Claim 29 wherein in the formula of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.1 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
31. The photodetector of Claim 29 wherein in the formula of TiOx, x represents a number from 1.2 to 1.9.
</P>
<P>
32. The photodetector of Claim 29 wherein the layer of titanium oxide has a thickness ranging from 10 to 40 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
33. The photodetector of Claim 29 wherein the layer of titanium oxide is positioned between the photoactive polymer layer and the electron-collecting electrode.
</P>
<P>
34. The photodetector of Claim 33 wherein the electron-collecting electrode comprises a metal electrode, the hole-collecting electrode comprises an indium-tin oxide and poly(3,4-ethylenedioxylenethiophene)~polystyrene sulfonic acid (ITO/PEDOT:PSS) bilayer electrode, and the photoactive polymer layer comprises poly(3-hexylthiophene) and [6,6,]-phenyl-C6i-butyric acid methyl ester (P3HT:PCBM).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1974391A4;WO2007079498A2;WO2007079498A3;WO2007079500A2;WO2007079500A9;WO2007079500A3;US2012025174A1;US2007221926A1;JP2009522818A;JP2009536445A;EP1974386A2;EP1974386A4
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
