<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
REACTION SYSTEM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2073933A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MASTERS ANTHONY FREDERICK [AU]
</Name>
<Name>
FOIS ALESSANDRO [AU]
</Name>
<Name>
MASCHMEYER THOMAS [AU]
</Name>
<Name>
MASTERS, ANTHONY, FREDERICK
</Name>
<Name>
FOIS, ALESSANDRO
</Name>
<Name>
MASCHMEYER, THOMAS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV SYDNEY [AU]
</Name>
<Name>
THE UNIVERSITY OF SYDNEY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2073933
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070784848
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007AU01212
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060840009P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J13/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01J33/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12P41/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12P7/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/40
</Class>
<Class>
B01J29/70B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J33/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02C4
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02C6B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12P41/00C2
</Class>
<Class>
C12P7/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention provides a reaction system comprising: a first reaction promoter capable of converting a first substrate into a first substance;  and a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second reaction promoter encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second reaction promoter being capable of converting a second substrate into a second substance. The second substrate is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second reaction promoter and the second substance is capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant. In the reaction system, either (a) the first substance is, or is capable of being converted into, the second substrate and, in operation, the conversion of the second substrate by the second reaction promoter occurs to a greater extent than the conversion of the first substrate by the second reaction promoter and the conversion of the second substance by the first reaction promoter is low, or (b) the second substance is, or is capable of being converted into, the first substrate and, in operation, the conversion of the first substrate by the first reaction promoter occurs to a greater extent than the conversion of the second substrate by the first reaction promoter and the conversion of the first substance in the microcapsules is low.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
The claims which define the invention are as follows:
</P>
<P>
1. A reaction system comprising:
</P>
<P>
- a first reaction promoter capable of converting a first substrate into a first substance; and s - a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second reaction promoter encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second reaction promoter being capable of converting a second substrate into a second substance, wherein the second substrate is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second reaction promoter and the second substance is o capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant; whereby either (a) the first substance is, or is capable of being converted into, the second substrate and, in operation, the conversion of the second substrate by the second reaction promoter occurs to a greater extent than the conversion of the first substrate by the second reaction promoter and the conversion of the second substance by the first reaction s promoter is low, or (b) the second substance is, or is capable of being converted into, the first substrate and, in operation, the conversion of the first substrate by the first reaction promoter occurs to a greater extent than the conversion of the second substrate by the first reaction promoter and the conversion of the first substance in the microcapsules is low.
</P>
<P>
2. The reaction system of claim 1 wherein, in case (a), the first reaction promoter 0 is capable of interconverting the first substrate and the second substrate, and in case (b), the second reaction promoter is capable of interconverting the first substrate and the second substrate.
</P>
<P>
3. The reaction system of claim 1 or claim 2 wherein the first and second reaction promoters are catalysts. 5 4. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 3 comprising one or more further reaction promoters which are capable of converting the second substance (in case a) or converting the first substance (in case b).
</P>
<P>
5. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 4 wherein the first substance (case b) or the second substance (case a) passes slowly through the encapsulant or is 0 incapable of passing therethrough.
</P>
<P>
6. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 5 additionally comprising a separator for separating a product from the first reaction promoter and from the microcapsules.
</P>
<P>
7. The reaction system of claim 6 also comprising a purifier for purifying the separated product.
</P>
<P>
8. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 7 wherein the first reaction promoter is a selective reaction promoter. 9. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 8 wherein the microcapsules are capable of converting the second substrate to the second substance selectively.
</P>
<P>
10. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 9 wherein the encapsulant comprises a polymer.
</P>
<P>
11. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 10 wherein the encapsulant comprises at least one positively charged polymeric layer and at least one negatively charged polymeric layer.
</P>
<P>
12. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 11 wherein the first and second reaction promoters are capable of interacting so as to deactivate one or both thereof, but in the reaction system of the present invention are at least partially prevented from doing so due to encapsulation of the second reaction promoter.
</P>
<P>
13. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 12 wherein first reaction promoter and the microcapsules are distributed within a reaction medium.
</P>
<P>
14. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 13 wherein the microcapsules have a mean diameter of between about 0.2 and about 10 microns. 15. The reaction system of any one of claims 1 to 14 wherein the microcapsules comprise an energy absorber for absorbing energy in order to promote the reaction promoted by the second reaction promoter.
</P>
<P>
16. A method for conducting a reaction comprising:
</P>
<P>
- providing a reaction system comprising (i) a first reaction promoter capable of converting a first substrate into a first substance; and (ii) a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second reaction promoter encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second reaction promoter being capable of converting a second substrate into a second substance, wherein the second substrate is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second reaction promoter and the second substance is capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant; and
</P>
<P>
- adding either the first substrate or the second substrate or both the first substrate and the second substrate to the reaction system; whereby either (a) the first substance is, or is capable of being converted into, the second substrate, such that the first substrate is converted either directly or indirectly to the second substrate and the second substrate is converted to the second substance, or (b) the second substance is, or is capable of being converted into, the first substrate, such that the second substrate is converted either directly or indirectly to the first substrate and the first substrate is converted to the first substance.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 whereby in case (a) the first reaction promoter interconverts the first and second substrates and in case (b) the second reaction promoter interconverts the first and second substrates. 18. The method of claim 16 or claim 17 wherein first substrate and the second substrate are added together to the reaction system.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of any one of claims 16 to 18 comprising separating a product from the reaction system.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of any one of claims 16 to 19 comprising heating the reaction system and/or irradiating the reaction system with radiation of a wavelength capable of being absorbed by a component of the reaction system, by the first or second substrate or by more than one of these.
</P>
<P>
21. A reaction system for Dynamic Kinetic Resolution of a racemic alcohol comprising: - a first catalyst capable of esterifying a first optical isomer of the alcohol to form a first optical isomer of an ester of the alcohol at a rate greater than it esterifies a second optical isomer of the alcohol; and
</P>
<P>
- a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second catalyst encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second catalyst being capable of racemising the second optical isomer of the alcohol, wherein the second optical isomer of the alcohol is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second catalyst and the first optical isomer of the alcohol is capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant; whereby the rate of racemisation of the first optical isomer of the ester of the alcohol in the microcapsules is low.
</P>
<P>
22. A method for Dynamic Kinetic Resolution of a racemic alcohol comprising:
</P>
<P>
- providing a reaction system comprising (i&apos;&quot;) a first catalyst capable of esterifying a first optical isomer of the alcohol to form a first optical isomer of an ester of the alcohol at a rate greater than it esterifies a second optical isomer of the alcohol; and (U&quot;&apos;) a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second catalyst encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second catalyst being capable of racemising the second optical isomer of the alcohol, wherein the second optical isomer of the alcohol is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second catalyst and the first optical isomer of the alcohol is capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant; whereby the rate of racemisation of the first optical isomer of the ester of the alcohol in the microcapsules is low; and
</P>
<P>
- adding the racemic alcohol to the reaction system; whereby the first optical isomer of the alcohol is converted to the first optical isomer of the ester and the second optical isomer is racemised to form a mixture of the first and second optical isomers of the alcohol.
</P>
<P>
23. A product produced by the method of any one of claims 16 to 22.
</P>
<P>
24. A reaction system comprising: - a first reaction promoter capable of converting a first substrate into a first substance; and
</P>
<P>
- a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second reaction promoter encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second reaction promoter being capable of converting a second substrate into a second substance, wherein the second substrate is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second reaction promoter and the second substance is capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant; whereby the first and second reaction promoters are capable of interacting so as to deactivate one or both thereof, but in the reaction system are at least partially prevented from doing so due to encapsulation of the second reaction promoter.
</P>
<P>
25. The reaction system of claim 24 whereby either (a) the first substance is the second substrate, or (b) the second substance is the first substrate.
</P>
<P>
26. A method for conducting a reaction comprising:
</P>
<P>
- providing a reaction system comprising (i) a first reaction promoter capable of converting a first substrate into a first substance; and (ii) a plurality of microcapsules, each of said microcapsules comprising a second reaction promoter encapsulated within an encapsulant, said second reaction promoter being capable of converting a second substrate into a second substance, wherein the second substrate is capable of passing through the encapsulant to contact the second reaction promoter and the second substance is capable of passing out of the microcapsules through the encapsulant; and - adding either the first substrate or the second substrate or both the first substrate and the second substrate to the reaction system; whereby either (a) the first substance is the second substrate, or (b) the second substance is the first substrate, and whereby the first and second reaction promoters are capable of interacting so as to deactivate one or both thereof, but in the reaction system are at least partially prevented from doing so due to encapsulation of the second reaction promoter. 27. A product produced by the method of claim 26.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008022394A1;ZA200901142A;US2010081849A1;JP2010501490A;CN101563160A;AU2007288122A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
