<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Composite material coatings
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2014728A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ASGARI SOHEIL [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
ASGARI, SOHEIL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CINV AG [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
CINVENTION AG
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2014728
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080166025
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2005-12-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20050850369
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050643842P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-01-13
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08K9/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/44
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N1
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12S
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a process of producing composite materials by a sol/gel-process, comprising carbon nanoparticles and organic polymer material. The invention further relates to composite materials, which are manufactured with the use of said sol/gel technology.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A composite material coating comprising
</P>
<P>
a) at least one sol/gel network formed of a sol/gel forming component;
</P>
<P>
b) at least one carbon nanoparticle which was chemically modified by functionalization with suitable linker groups which are capable to react with said sol/gel forming component; and
</P>
<P>
c) organic polymer material,wherein the carbon-based nano-particle is covalently connected with said at least one sol/gel forming component in said sol/gel network.
</P>
<P>
2. The composite material coating of claim 1 obtainable by a process comprising the following steps:
</P>
<P>
a) forming a sol/gel by reacting at least one sol/gel forming component with at least one carbon nanoparticle which was chemically modified by functionalization with suitable linker groups which are capable to react with the sol/gel forming component, wherein the carbon-based nano-particle within the sol/gel is covalently connected with said at least one sol/gel forming component;
</P>
<P>
b) adding organic polymer material to the formed sol/gel,
</P>
<P>
c) converting the resulting mixture into a solid composite material.
</P>
<P>
3. The composite material coating according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the carbon nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of fullerene molecules, in particular C36 - C60 -, C70 -, C76-, C80-, C 86-, C112- fullerenes or any mixtures thereof; nano-tubes, in particular MWNT, SWNT, DWNT; random-oriented nano-tubes, as well as fullerene onions or metallo-fullerenes, carbon fibres, soot particles or graphite particles; as well as combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. The composite material coating according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the linker groups are selected from the group consisting of primary, secondary or tertiary amino groups, straight chain or branched, substituted or unsubstituted alkyl-, alkenyl-, alkynyl-, cycloalkyl-, cycloalkenyl-, cycloalkynyl-, aryl-, alkylaryl-, arylalkyl-, alkenylaryl-, arylalkenyl-, alkynylaryl-, arylalkynyl-groups; alkyl-metal alkoxides, halogen, aromatic or aliphatic alcohol groups, pyrrolidinegroups, phthalocyaninegroups, carboxyl, carboxylate, esters, and ethers.
</P>
<P>
5. The composite material coating according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the nanoparticles are functionalized by reaction with one of 3-aminopropyltrimethoxysilane, 3-aminopropyl-triethoxysilane, 6-amino-1-hexanol, 2-(2-aminoethoxy)ethanol, cyclohexylamine, butyric acid choleterylester (PCBCR), 1-(3-methoxycarbonyl)-propyl)-1-phenylester, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The composite material coating according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the nanoparticles have an average particle size before chemical modification of 0.5 nm to 500 nm, preferably 0.5 nm - 100 nm, more preferably from 0.7 nm to 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. The composite material coating according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the at least one sol/gel forming component is selected from the group consisting of alkoxides, metal alkoxides, metal oxides, metal acetates, metal nitrates, metal halides, as well as combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The composite material coating according to claim 7, wherein the sol/gel forming component is selected from the group consisting of silicon alkoxides, oligomeric forms of silicon alkoxides; alkylalkoxysilanes; aryltrialkoxysilanes and phenyltributoxysilane; phenyl-tri-(3-glycidyloxy)-silane-oxide (TGPSO), aminoalkylsilanes; 3-glycidyloxypropyltrimethoxysilane, 3-glycidyloxypropyltriethoxy-silane, bisphenol-A-glycidylsilanes; (meth)acrylsilanes, phenylsilanes, oligomeric or polymeric silanes, epoxysilanes; fluoroalkylsilanes as well as any mixtures of the foregoing.
</P>
<P>
9. The composite material coating according to claim 7, wherein the sol/gel forming component is selected from metal halides and is reacted with oxygen-functionalized carbon nanoparticles selected from alkoxide-, ether-, ester-, alcohol- or acetate-functionalized carbon nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
10. The composite material coating according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the organic polymer material is selected from homo- or copolymers of aliphatic or aromatic polyolefins like polyethylene, polypropylene, polybutene, polyisobutene, polypentene; polybutadiene; polycarbonate; polynorbornylene, polyalkyne, polydimethylsiloxane, polyethyleneterephthalate, nylons, polyvinylics like polyvinylchloride or polyvinylalcohol; poly(meth)acrylic acid, polyacrylonitrile, polyamide, polyester, polyurethane, polystyrene, polytetrafluoroethylene, waxes, paraffin waxes, Fischer-Tropsch-waxes; paracyclophane, alkyd resin, fluorinated rubber, epoxy resin, acrylic resin, phenolic resin, amine resin, tar, tar-like materials, tar pitch, bitumen, starch, cellulose, shellac, organic materials of renewable raw materials, mixtures, copolymers and combinations of any of the foregoing.
</P>
<P>
11. The composite material coating according to any one of the claims 2 to 10, wherein the conversion of the mixture of sol/gel and organic polymer material into a solid composite material is obtained by drying.
</P>
<P>
12. The composite material coating according to any one of the previous claims, additionally comprising at least one crosslinking agent, the crosslinking agent being selected from the group consisting of isocyanates, silanes, (meth)acrylates, or mixtures of any of the foregoing.
</P>
<P>
13. The composite material coating according to any one of the previous claims, additionally comprising at least one filler, the filler being selected from the group consisting of components which do not react with the other components of the sol/gel.
</P>
<P>
14. The composite material coating according to claim 13, wherein the filler is a polymer encapsulated carbon nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
15. The composite material coating according to any one of claims 12 or 13, wherein the filler is at least partially removed from the resulting solid composite material.
</P>
<P>
16. The composite material coating according to any one of the previous claims, wherein the coating is applied in liquid, pulpy or pasty form, preferably by painting, furnishing, phase-inversion, dispersing atomizing or melt coating, extruding, slip casting, dipping or as a hotmelt.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2006155376A1;US7780875B2;SI1836239T1;PT1836239E;MX2007008425A;KR20070101312A;JP2008527119A;HK1114400A1;ES2317344T3;WO2006074809A2;WO2006074809A3;EP2014708A1;EP1836239A2;EP1836239B1;EA200701505A1;EA011516B1;DK1836239T3;CN101098916A;CA2591942A1;BRPI0519754A2;AU2005324915A1;AT412691T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
