<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Use of superparamagnetic crystals to catalyse polymerisation of epoxide monomers
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2051075A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FONNUM GEIR [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
MODAHL GRETE IRENE [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
STENE TORKEL [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLTEBERG ASTRID EVENROD [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
FINNE ERLING SIGURD [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
WENG ELLEN [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
FONNUM, GEIR
</Name>
<Name>
MODAHL, GRETE IRENE
</Name>
<Name>
STENE, TORKEL
</Name>
<Name>
MOLTEBERG, ASTRID, EVENROD
</Name>
<Name>
FINNE, ERLING, SIGURD
</Name>
<Name>
WENG, ELLEN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
INVITROGEN DYNAL AS [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
INVITROGEN DYNAL AS
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2051075
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090151402
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-12-11
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030780374
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-12-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20020028914
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-12-11
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K47/48
</Class>
<Class>
C08F4/60
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543D4D
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N4
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N6
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a use of superparamagnetic crystals to catalyse the polymerisation of coating monomers which comprise at least one epoxide.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Use of superparamagnetic crystals to catalyse the polymerisation of coating monomers which comprise at least one epoxide.
</P>
<P>
2. The use of claim 1, wherein the epoxide is selected from: epichlorohydrin, epibromohydrin, isopropylglycidyl ether, butyl glycidyl ether, allylglycidyl ether, 1,4-butanediol diglycidyl ether (1,4-bis (2,3-epoxypropoxy) butane), neopentylglycol diglycidyl ether, ethylene glycol diglycidyl ether, glycerol diglycidyl ether, glycidol, and glycidyl methacrylate, ethyl hexyl glycidylether, methyl glycidylether, glycerol propoxylate triglycidylether, poly(propylene glycol) diclycidylether, 1,3 butanediol diglycidylether, tert-butyl glycidylether, 1,4 cyclohexanedimethanol diglycidyl ether, diethylene glycol diglycidyl ether, dodecyl glycidylether, O-(2,3 epoxypropyl) -O&apos;-methylpolyethylene glycol glydidylether, glycidyl tetrafluoroethyl ether, 1,6 hexanediol diglycidylether, octyl glycidylether, decyl glycidylether, poly(epichlorohydrin-co-ethylene oxide-co-allyl glycidylether), polyethylene glycol diglycidyl ether, trimethylolethane triglycidylether, trimethylolpropane, triglycidylether, tert-butyldimethylsilyl glycidylether, 1,2-epoxybutane, 1,2-epoxypentane, 1,2-epoxy-5-hexene, 1,2-epoxy-hexane, 1,2-epoxy-7-octene, 1,2-epoxyoctane, 1,2,7,8-diepoxyoctane, 1,2-epoxy-9-decene, 1,2-epoxydecane, 1,2-epoxydodecane, and 1,2-epoxytetradecane.
</P>
<P>
3. The use of claim 1, wherein the coating monomers comprise at least two epoxides.
</P>
<P>
4. The use of claim 3, wherein the epoxides are selected from epichlorohydrin, epibromohydrin, isopropylglycidyl ether, butyl glycidyl ether, allylglycidyl ether, 1,4-butanediol diglycidyl ether (1,4-bis (2,3-epoxypropoxy) butane), ethylhexylglycidylether, methyl glycidylether neopentylglycol diglycidyl ether, ethylene glycol diglycidyl ether, glycerol diglycidyl ether, glycidol, and glycidyl methacrylate.
</P>
<P>
5. The use of any preceding claim wherein the superparamagnetic crystals are magnetic iron oxides.
</P>
<P>
6. The use of claim 5 wherein the magnetic iron oxide is magnetite or maghemite.
</P>
<P>
7. The use of any of claims 1 to 4 wherein the superparamagnetic crystals are mixed metal oxides.
</P>
<P>
8. Superparamagnetic crystals in combination with an epoxy coating obtainable by polymerisation of at least one epoxide monomer or at least two epoxide monomers as defined in any of claims 1 to 4.
</P>
<P>
9. The combination of claim 8 wherein the superparamagnetic crystals are defined in any of claims 5 to 7.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2051075B1;WO2004053490A1;US2006131542A1;US2010087327A1;JP2006511935A;EP1573325A1;EP1573325B1;CN101382546A;CN1732386A;CN100414297C;CA2507625A1;AU2003288454A1;AT519111T;AT427491T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
