<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SINGLE-WALLED CARBON NANOTUBE, CARBON FIBER AGGREGATE CONTAINING THE SINGLE- WALLED CARBON NANOTUBE, AND METHOD FOR PRODUCTION OF THE SINGLE- WALLED CARBON NANOTUBE OR THE CARBON FIBER AGGREGATE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2025643A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SAITO TAKESHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHSHIMA SATOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YUMURA MOTOO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SAITO, TAKESHI
</Name>
<Name>
OHSHIMA, SATOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
YUMURA, MOTOO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NAT INST OF ADVANCED IND SCIEN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ADVANCED INDUSTRIAL SCIENCEAND TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2025643
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070742300
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-04-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP58865
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060119774
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D02G3/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B2
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
It relates to high purity single-walled carbon nanotubes having controlled diameter, useful as industrial materials, including high-strength carbon wire rods, particularly uniform single-walled carbon nanotubes having diameter fallen in a range of from 1.0 to 2.0 nm, and a method for producing the same efficiently, in large amount and inexpensively. The single-walled carbon nanotube obtained is characterized in that its diameter is fallen in a range of from 1.0 to 2.0 nm, and an intensity ratio IG/ID between G-band and D-band in a Raman spectrum is 200 or more. Furthermore, those single-walled carbon nanotubes are synthesized by a gas-phase flow CVD method that uses a saturated aliphatic hydrocarbon which is liquid at ordinary temperature as a first carbon source and an unsaturated aliphatic hydrocarbon which is gas at ordinary temperature as a second carbon source.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A single-walled carbon nanotube, wherein its diameter is in a range of from 1.0 to 2.0 nm and an intensity ratio IG/ID between G-band and D-band in a Raman spectrum is 200 or more.
</P>
<P>
2. A carbon fiber aggregate, wherein the content of the single-walled carbon nanotube as claimed in claim 1 is 90 at. % or more of the whole.
</P>
<P>
3. A method for producing single-walled carbon nanotubes or carbon fiber aggregates containing the same from by a gas-phase flow CVD method using, at least, two kinds of carbon sources, wherein a saturated aliphatic hydrocarbon which is liquid at ordinary temperature is used as a first carbon source, and an unsaturated aliphatic hydrocarbon which is gas at ordinary temperature is used as a second carbon source.
</P>
<P>
4. The method for producing single-walled carbon nanotubes as claimed in claim 3, wherein the first carbon source is a non-cyclic saturated aliphatic hydrocarbon represented by the general formula cnH2n+2 (n=6 to 17) or a cyclic saturated aliphatic hydrocarbon.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for producing carbon fiber aggregates containing single-walled carbon nanotubes as claimed in claim 4, wherein the cyclic saturated aliphatic hydrocarbon is decalin.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing a carbon fiber aggregate containing single-walled carbon nanotubes as claimed in claim 3, wherein the second carbon source is ethylene or acetylene.
</P>
<P>
7. A carbon fiber aggregate containing single-walled carbon nanotubes having diameter in a range of from 1.0 to 2.0 nm obtained by the production method as claimed in any one of claims 3 to 6.
</P>
<P>
8. The carbon fiber aggregate containing single-walled carbon nanotubes as claimed in claim 7, wherein the shape is a ribbon shape or a sheet shape.
</P>
<P>
9. A high-strength carbon wire rod obtained by spinning the carbon fiber aggregate containing the single-walled carbon nanotube as claimed in claim 8.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009186223A1;TW200804179A;KR20080113242A;WO2007125923A1;CN101437755A;CN101437755B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
