<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FLUIDIZED BED SYSTEMS AND METHODS INCLUDING SECONDARY GAS FLOW
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2094382A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
PFEFFER ROBERT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
QUEVEDO JOSE A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FLESCH JUERGEN [TH]
</Name>
<Name>
PFEFFER, ROBERT
</Name>
<Name>
QUEVEDO, JOSE A
</Name>
<Name>
FLESCH, JUERGEN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NEW JERSEY TECH INST [US]
</Name>
<Name>
EVONIK DEGUSSA GMBH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
NEW JERSEY INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
<Name>
EVONIK DEGUSSA GMBH
</Name>
<Name>
ORION ENGINEERED CARBONS GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2094382
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070868716
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US84284
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060858072P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01F13/02
</Class>
<Class>
B01J8/18
</Class>
<Class>
B01J8/24
</Class>
<Class>
B01J8/32
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01F13/02
</Class>
<Class>
B01F13/02J
</Class>
<Class>
B01F3/18
</Class>
<Class>
B01J8/18G
</Class>
<Class>
B01J8/18L
</Class>
<Class>
B01J8/32
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Methods and systems for enhancing fluidization of nanoparticle and/or nanoagglomerates and for mixing nanoparticle/nanoagglomerate systems at the nanoscale are provided. A fluidization chamber is provided with a fluidizing medium (e.g., a fluidizing gas) directed in a first fluidizing direction, e.g., upward into and through a bed containing a volume of nanoparticles and/or nanopowders. A second source of air/gas flow is provided with respect to the fluidization chamber, the secondary air/gas flow generally being oppositely (or substantially oppositely) directed relative to the fluidizing medium.;  Turbulence created by the secondary gas flow, e.g., a jet from a micro-jet nozzle, is advantageously effective to aerate the agglomerates and the shear generated by the jet is advantageously effective to break apart nanoagglomerates and/or reduce the tendency for nanoagglomerates to form or reform. A downwardly directed source of secondary gas flow located near the main gas distributor leads to full fluidization of the entire amount of powder in the column. In addition, the oppositely directed fluid flow facilitates powder circulation within the fluidization chamber, thereby enhancing fluidization and mixing/blending results.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A system for fluidizing nanopowders or nanoagglomerates, comprising: a. a fluidization chamber; b. a source of a fluidizing medium communicating with the fluidization chamber, the fluidizing medium being directed in a first direction relative to the fluidization chamber; c. at least one micro-jet nozzle for delivering a secondary gas flow to the fluidization chamber; wherein the secondary gas flow is effective to enhance fluidization performance of nanopowders or nanoagglomerates.
</P>
<P>
2. The system according to claim 1, wherein the fluidization chamber is a column.
</P>
<P>
3. The system according to claim 1, wherein the fluidization chamber includes at least one deflector.
</P>
<P>
4. The system according to claim 3, wherein the at least one deflector includes one or more sieve trays.
</P>
<P>
5. The system according to claim 1, wherein the fluidizing medium is upwardly directed relative to the fluidization chamber through a porous gas distributor.
</P>
<P>
6. The system according to claim 1, wherein the at least one micro-jet nozzle has a diameter of between about 100 [mu]m and 500 [mu]m. 7. The system according to claim 1, wherein the gas delivered to the at least one micro-jet nozzle is subject to an upstream pressure of about 1 psi to about 500 psi. 8. The system according to claim 1, wherein between approximately 1 to 50% of gas flow to the fluidization chamber is directed to the at least one micro-jet nozzle.
</P>
<P>
9. The system according to claim 1, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet nozzle exits the at least one micro-jet nozzle at a velocity in the range from 100 m/s to about 5000 m/s and flow velocity of the fluidizing medium is up to 0.1 m/s.
</P>
<P>
10. The system according to claim 1, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet nozzle is effective to reduce bulk density of the nanopowders or nanoagglomerates.
</P>
<P>
11. The system according to claim 1, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet nozzle is effective to increase bed height within the fluidization chamber by at least a factor of two (2) relative to conventional fluidization performance.
</P>
<P>
12. The system according to claim 1, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet nozzle is effective to increase the bed height by up to ten (10) times relative to conventional fluidization performance.
</P>
<P>
13. The system according to claim 1, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet may be discontinued after fluidization is achieved without substantial loss of bed expansion. 14. The system according to claim 1, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet is effective to modify behavior of a nanopowder or nanoagglomerate volume from an agglomerate bubbling fluidization (ABF) behavior to an agglomerate particulate fluidization (APF) behavior.
</P>
<P>
15. The system according to claim 1, wherein a plurality of micro-jet nozzles are positioned in and downwardly directed relative to the fluidization chamber.
</P>
<P>
16. A method for fluidizing nanopowders or nanoagglomerates, comprising: a. introducing nanopowders or nanoagglomerates into a fluidization chamber; b. delivering a fluidizing medium to the fluidization chamber, the fluidizing medium being directed in an upward direction relative to the fluidization chamber; c. delivering a secondary gas flow to the fluidization chamber, the secondary gas flow being introduced to the fluidization chamber by at least one micro-jet nozzle; wherein the fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are effective to fluidize the nanopowders or nanoagglomerates to a predetermined level.
</P>
<P>
17. The method according to claim 16, wherein the fluidizing medium is introduced through a porous distributor.
</P>
<P>
18. The method according to claim 16, wherein the at least one micro-jet nozzle has a diameter of between about 100 [mu]m and 500 [mu]m. 19. The method according to claim 16, wherein the gas flow through the at least one micro- jet nozzle is subject to an upstream pressure of about 1 psi to about 500 psi.
</P>
<P>
20. The method according to claim 16, wherein between approximately 1 to 50% of gas flow to the fluidization chamber is directed to the at least one micro-jet nozzle.
</P>
<P>
21. The method according to claim 16, wherein gas flow through the at least one micro-jet nozzle exits the at least one micro-jet nozzle at a velocity in the range from 100 m/s to about 5000 m/s and flow velocity of the fluidizing medium is up to 0.1 m/s.
</P>
<P>
22. The method according to claim 16, wherein the predetermined level constitutes an increased bed height within the fluidization chamber by at least a factor of two (2) relative to conventional fluidization performance. 23. The method according to claim 16, wherein the predetermined level constitutes a bed height that is up to ten (10) times greater as compared to conventional fluidization performance.
</P>
<P>
24. The method according to claim 16, further comprising discontinuing gas flow through the at least one micro -jet after fluidization to the predetermined level is achieved without substantial loss of bed expansion.
</P>
<P>
25. A fluidization method, comprising: a. introducing at least one of nanopowders and nanoagglomerates into a fluidization chamber; b. delivering a fluidizing medium to the fluidization chamber, the fluidizing medium being directed in a first direction relative to the fluidization chamber; c. delivering a secondary gas flow to the fluidization chamber; whereby the secondary gas flow is fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are effective to fluidize the nanopowders or nanoagglomerates to a predetermined level. 26. The fluidization method according to claim 26, wherein the fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are substantially co-current.
</P>
<P>
27. The fluidization method according to claim 26, wherein the fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are substantially counter-current.
</P>
<P>
28. The fluidization method according to claim 26, wherein the predetermined fluidization level represents a bed expansion that is at least two (2) times greater than a bed expansion level achieved in the absence of the secondary gas flow.
</P>
<P>
29. A system for mixing and blending nanopowders or nanoagglomerates, comprising: a. a fluidization chamber; b. a source of a fluidizing medium communicating with the fluidization chamber, the fluidizing medium being directed in a first direction relative to the fluidization chamber; c. at least one micro-jet nozzle for delivering a secondary gas flow to the fluidization chamber; whereby the fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are effective to substantially uniformly mix the first and the second nanopowders or nanoagglomerates at the nanoscale.
</P>
<P>
30. A method for mixing or blending nanopowders or nanoagglomerates at nanoscale, comprising: a. introducing at least a first nanopowder or nanoagglomerate and a second nanopowder or nanoagglomerate into a fluidization chamber; b. delivering a fluidizing medium to the fluidization chamber, the fluidizing medium being directed in a first direction relative to the fluidization chamber; c. delivering a secondary gas flow to the fluidization chamber; whereby the fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are effective to substantially uniformly mix the first and the second nanopowders or nanoagglomerates at the nanoscale.
</P>
<P>
31. The method according to claim 30, wherein the secondary gas flow is delivered through at least one micro-jet nozzle.
</P>
<P>
32. The method according to claim 30, wherein the fluidizing medium and the secondary gas flow are substantially counter-current.
</P>
<P>
33. The mixing method according to claim 30, wherein the first nanopowder or nanoagglomerate and the second nanopowder or nanoagglomerate define different material species.
</P>
<P>
34. The mixing method according to claim 30, wherein the first nanopowder or nanoagglomerate and the second nanopowder or nanoagglomerate define define the same material species that are characterized by different properties.
</P>
<P>
35. The mixing method according to claim 34, wherein the different properties relate to at least one of particle size and surface properties.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2094382B1;WO2008061015A2;WO2008061015A3;US2012140588A1;US2008179433A1;US8118243B2;CN101605598A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
