<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
TUNABLE WAVELENGTH LIGHT EMITTING DIODE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2074666A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SOH CHEW BENG [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
CHUA SOO JIN [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
HARTONO HARYONO [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
SOH, CHEW BENG
</Name>
<Name>
CHUA, SOO JIN
</Name>
<Name>
HARTONO, HARYONO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AGENCY SCIENCE TECH &amp; RES [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
AGENCY FOR SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY AND RESEARCH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2074666
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060784275
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-09-08
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006SG00263
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/205
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4B1B1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1B1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3C
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/08
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A light emitting diode and a method of fabricating a light emitting diode. the diode comprises a first set of multiple quantum wells (MQWs), each of the MQWs of the first set comprising a wetting layer providing nucleation sites for quantum dots (QDs) or QD-like structures in a well layer of said each MQW;  and a second set of MQWs, each of the MQWs of the second set formed so as to exhibit a photoluminescence (PL) peak wavelength shifted compared to the MQWs of the first set.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A light emitting diode comprising: a first set of multiple quantum wells (MQWs), each of the MQWs of the first set comprising a wetting layer providing nucleation sites for quantum dots (QDs) or QD-like structures in a well layer of said each MQW; and a second set of MQWs, each of the MQWs of the second set formed so as to exhibit a photoluminescence (PL) peak wavelength shifted compared to the MQWs of the first set.
</P>
<P>
2. The light emitting diode as claimed in claim 1, wherein the QDs or QD-like structures comprise In atoms.
</P>
<P>
3. The light emitting diode as claimed in claims 1 or 2, wherein the first set of MQWs comprises about 3 to 5 MQWs.
</P>
<P>
4. The light emitting diode as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the second set of MQWs comprises about 2 to 5 MQWs. 5. The light emitting diode as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein each of the MQWs of the second set comprises a Ga-based barrier layer and an Ga-based well layer formed on the Ga-based barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
6. The light emitting diode as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein each of the MQWs of the first set comprises a Ga-based barrier layer, an InGa-based wetting layer formed on the Ga-based barrier layer, and a Ga-based well layer formed on the InGa-wetting layer.
</P>
<P>
7. The light emitting diode as claimed in claim 6, wherein the first set of MQWs are formed on an n-type doped Ga-based layer, the second set of MQWs is formed on the first set of MQWs, a Ga-based capped layer is formed on the second set of MQWs, and a p-type doped Ga-based layer is formed on the Ga-based capped layer.
</P>
<P>
8. The light emitting diode as claimed in claim 7, further comprising electrical contacts for contacting the n-type doped Ga-based layer and the p-type doped Ga-based layer respectively. 9. The light emitting diode as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the first and second sets of MQWs are supported on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
10. The light emitting diode as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein the MQWs comprise one material system of a group consisting of InGa/Ga, InGa/AIGa, Ga/AIGa and InGa/AllnGa.
</P>
<P>
11. The light emitting diode as claimed in claim 10, wherein the MQWs comprise the nitride or phosphide of the material system.
</P>
<P>
12. The light emitting diode as claimed in any one of the preceding claims, wherein a combined PL spectrum of the diode covers a tunable wavelength range of about 400-800nm.
</P>
<P>
13. A method of fabricating a light emitting diode, the method comprising the steps of: forming a first set of multiple quantum wells (MQWs), each of the MQWs of the first set comprising a wetting layer providing nucleation sites for quantum dots (QDs) or QD-like structures in a well layer of said each MQW; and forming a second set of MQWs, each of the MQWs of the second set formed so as to exhibit a photoluminescence (PL) peak wavelength shifted compared to the MQWs of the first set.
</P>
<P>
14. The method as claimed in claim 13, wherein the QDs or QD-like structures comprise In atoms.
</P>
<P>
15. The method as claimed in claims 13 or 14, wherein the first set of MQWs comprises about 3 to 5 MQWs.
</P>
<P>
16. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 15, wherein the second set of MQWs comprises about 2 to 5 MQWs. 17. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 16, wherein each of the MQWs of the second set comprises a Ga-based barrier layer and an InGa-based well layer formed on the Ga-based barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
18. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 17, wherein each of the MQWs of the first set comprises a Ga-based barrier layer, an InGa-based wetting layer formed on the Ga-based barrier layer, and a Ga-based well layer formed on the InGa-wetting layer.
</P>
<P>
19. The method as claimed in claim 18, wherein the first set of MQWs are formed on an n-type doped Ga-based layer, the second set of MQWs is formed on the first set of MQWs, a Ga-based capped layer is formed on the second set of MQWs, and a p-type doped Ga-based layer is formed on the Ga-based capped layer.
</P>
<P>
20. The method as claimed in claim 19, further comprising forming electrical contacts for contacting the n-type doped Ga-based layer and the p-type doped Ga-based layer respectively.
</P>
<P>
21. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 20, wherein the first and second sets of MQWs are supported on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
22. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 21 , wherein the first set of MQWs is formed at a lower temperature than the second set of MQWs. 23. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 22, wherein the first set of MQWs is formed with a higher In precursor flow than the second set of MQWs.
</P>
<P>
24. The method as claimed in any one of claims 13 to 23, wherein the MQWs comprise one material system of a group consisting of InGa/Ga, InGa/AIGa, Ga/AIGa and InGa/AllnGa.
</P>
<P>
25. The method as claimed in claim 24, wherein the MQWs comprise the nitride or phosphide of the material system.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2074666A4;WO2008030183A1;US2010025653A1;TW200824153A;JP2010503228A;CN101589478A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
