<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METAL NANOPARTICLE DISPERSION AND PROCESS FOR PRODUCING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2050792A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MATSUKI KOICHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
LEE SEUNGTAEG [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
JIN REN-HUA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MATSUKI, KOICHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
LEE, SEUNGTAEG
</Name>
<Name>
JIN, REN-HUA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DAINIPPON INK &amp; CHEMICALS [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
DIC CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2050792
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060782532
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-08-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP315716
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08G73/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/08
</Class>
<Class>
C08L79/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08G73/02L
</Class>
<Class>
C08L79/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A metal nanoparticle dispersion comprising: a dispersion of a polymer compound (X), which comprises a polyalkyleneimine chain (a), a hydrophilic segment (b) and a hydrophobic segment (c), and metal nanoparticles (Y).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A metal nanoparticle dispersion comprising: a dispersion of a polymer compound (X), which comprises a polyalkyleneimine chain (a), a hydrophilic segment (b) and a hydrophobic segment (c), and metal nanoparticles (Y).
</P>
<P>
2. The metal nanoparticle dispersion according to claim 1, wherein the polyalkyleneimine chain (a) is a polyethyleneimine chain.
</P>
<P>
3. The metal nanoparticle dispersion according to claim 1, wherein the hydrophilic segment (b) is a polyoxyalkylene chain.
</P>
<P>
4. The metal nanoparticle dispersion according to claim 1, wherein the hydrophobic segment (c) is a residue of at least one compound selected from the group consisting of polystyrenes, poly(meth)acrylic acid esters, epoxy resins, polyurethanes, polycarbonates and polyacylalkyleneimines having a hydrophobic substituent.
</P>
<P>
5. The metal nanoparticle dispersion according to claim 1, wherein the metal nanoparticles (Y) are at least one type of metal selected from the group consisting of silver, gold and platinum.
</P>
<P>
6. The metal nanoparticle dispersion according to any of claims 1 to 5, wherein the metal nanoparticles (Y) have a particle diameter of 1 to 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. A production process of a metal nanoparticle dispersion comprising:
</P>
<P>
forming a dispersion of a polymer compound, which comprises a polyalkyleneimine chain, a hydrophilic segment and a
</P>
<P>
hydrophobic segment, in a solvent; and
</P>
<P>
adding a metal salt or metal ion solution to the dispersion to reduce metal ions and obtain metal nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
8. The production process of a metal nanoparticle dispersion according to claim 7, wherein a reducing agent is used when reducing the metal ions.
</P>
<P>
9. The metal nanoparticle dispersion according to claim 1, wherein one or more of the metal nanoparticles (Y) are coordinated in the dispersion of the polymer compound (X).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009198009A1;KR20090014186A;KR100987973B1;WO2008018123A1;CN101506307A;CN101506307B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
