<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Detecting, localizing, and targeting internal sites in vivo using optical contrast agents
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2048504A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BENARON DAVID A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BENARON, DAVID A
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SPECTROS CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SPECTROS CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2048504
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090001013
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2000-03-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20000918467
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2000-03-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19990305855
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-05-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61B5/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/574
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61B5/00P12B
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/00P5
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/1455
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/41J2
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/41J8
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/43M2
</Class>
<Class>
A61B5/68D1B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/574C14
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/574C4
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A targeted optical contrast agent comprising an optical contrast moiety selected from the list of contrast agents consisting of isosulfan blue, methyl red, or other light absorbing contrast agents, indocyanine green, porphyrins, or other fluorophores, biologically responsive dyes, colored or fluorescent proteins and other gene products, quantum dots and other spectroscopically distinct physical constructs, and contrast-filled micelles;  and,a localizing moiety that achieves a targeting action selected from the list consisting of an antibody, antibody fragment, receptor or translocator binding site or substance, or a microbubble or liposomal structure in which the surrounding structure is targeted using surface structures.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A targeted optical contrast agent comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) an optical contrast moiety selected from the list of contrast agents consisting of isosulfan blue, methyl red, or other light absorbing contrast agents, indocyanine green, porphyrins, or other fluorophores, biologically responsive dyes, colored or fluorescent proteins and other gene products, quantum dots and other spectroscopically distinct physical constructs, and contrast-filled micelles; and,
</P>
<P>
(b) a localizing moiety that achieves a targeting action selected from the list consisting of an antibody, antibody fragment, receptor or translocator binding site or substance, or a microbubble or liposomal structure in which the surrounding structure is targeted using surface structures.
</P>
<P>
2. The targeted optical contrast agent of claim 1 wherein the agent targets sites selected from the list of target sites consisting of CEA, MUCI and other mucins, mammaglobin, HER-2/neu, EGF-R, ER, PR, PSMA, PSA, and CEA.
</P>
<P>
3. The targeted optical contrast agent of claim 1 or 2 which is suitable for
</P>
<P>
(a) measuring a target site within a living subject during surgery selected so as to provide measurable contrast for said target site in vivo after administration to the subject,
</P>
<P>
(b) providing a source of contrast for externally or internally measuring a target tissue within an opaque portion of the body of a living subject, after administration to the subject and allowance of time sufficient to have achieved distribution and localization within the body or
</P>
<P>
(c) use in measuring a target site within a living subject during surgery selected so as to provide measurable contrast for said target site in vivo after administration to the subject.
</P>
<P>
4. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of the preceding claims wherein the optical contrast agent is fluorescent.
</P>
<P>
5. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of the preceding claims, wherein contrast agent is selected to have spectral features occurring between 800 nm and 2 microns.
</P>
<P>
6. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the agent is used to identify tissue types in the body selected from the list of tissue types consisting of cancer, nerve, artery, vein, lymph node, and muscle.
</P>
<P>
7. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the agent comprises an antibody or molecule against the PSMA receptor of prostate and a fluorescent dye.
</P>
<P>
8. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the agent comprises an antibody, protein, or other molecule against the PSMA receptor of prostate for labeling at least prostate cancer, and a fluorescent dye.
</P>
<P>
9. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of the preceding claims wherein the agent comprises a localizing moiety that achieves a targeting action by binding to an antigen present on all cells of a class of tissues.
</P>
<P>
10. The targeted optical contrast agent of any one of claims 1 to 8 wherein the agent comprises a localizing moiety that achieves a targeting action by binding to an antigen or receptor expressed or over-expressed in cancer as compared to normal tissue.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO0068665A1;US6246901B1;US6167297A;JP2009133876A;JP2002543859A;EP1196763A1;EP1196763B1;EP1196763B2;AU3926900A;AT422048T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
