<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Rare earth permanent magnetic alloy and producing method thereof
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2043111A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YAMAMOTO HIROSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TAYU TETSUROU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHMURA MASASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OTANI KEIZOU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YABUMI TAKAO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HASHINO HAYATO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMAMOTO, HIROSHI
</Name>
<Name>
TAYU, TETSUROU
</Name>
<Name>
OHMURA, MASASHI
</Name>
<Name>
OTANI, KEIZOU
</Name>
<Name>
YABUMI, TAKAO
</Name>
<Name>
HASHINO, HAYATO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NISSAN MOTOR [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MEIJI UNIVERSITY LEGAL PERSON [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NISSAN MOTOR CO., LTD
</Name>
<Name>
MEIJI UNIVERSITY LEGAL PERSON
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2043111
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080015866
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-09-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070234793
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20080066884
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01F1/057
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F9/00M4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C22C1/04R
</Class>
<Class>
C22C33/02F
</Class>
<Class>
C22C38/00E
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/057C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A rare earth permanent magnet alloy with a high coercive force is disclosed. The rare earth permanent magnet alloy comprises: a rare earth-iron-boron type magnetic phase (R 2 Fe 14 B type magnetic phase) constituting a parent phase;  and a defect structure. The parent phase contains the defect structure. Displacement of magnetic domain wall of the R 2 Fe 14 B type magnetic phase is prevented by the defect structure, thereby improving coercive force.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy comprising:
</P>
<P>
a rare earth-iron-boron type magnetic phase (R2Fe14B type magnetic phase) constituting a parent phase; and
</P>
<P>
a defect structure,
</P>
<P>
wherein the parent phase contains the defect structure, and the defect structure includes a part comprising the R2Fe14B type magnetic phase as a main component and that magnetic property is modulated from magnetic property of the parent phase.
</P>
<P>
2. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 1, wherein the part is formed by element concentration.
</P>
<P>
3. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 1, wherein the part is formed by lattice strain resulting from element concentration.
</P>
<P>
4. A rare earth permanent magnet according to claim 1, wherein the defect structure includes impurity.
</P>
<P>
5. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 4, wherein the impurity induces lattice strain of the R2Fe14B phase comprising the defect structure.
</P>
<P>
6. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 1, wherein the defect structure includes precipitated phase originated from supersaturated solid solution.
</P>
<P>
7. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 1, wherein the R is a rare earth element including Yttrium (Y).
</P>
<P>
8. A rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 1, wherein the magnetic phase includes at least one or more kind of additive element in addition to R, Fe, and B.
</P>
<P>
9. A producing method of a rare earth permanent magnet alloy comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
generating a defect structure included in a rare earth-iron-boron type magnetic phase (R2Fe14B type magnetic phase) constituting a parent phase and comprising the R2Fe14B type magnetic phase as a main component,
</P>
<P>
wherein the defect structure is generated to include a part that magnetic property is modulated from magnetic property of the parent phase by performing one or more aging process.
</P>
<P>
10. A producing method of a rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 9, wherein at least one amorphization process and a crystallization process of the parent phase after the amorphization process are performed as the aging process.
</P>
<P>
11. A producing method of a rare earth permanent magnet alloy according to claim 9, wherein the defect structure is generated by the crystallization process.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009081071A1;JP2009242936A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
