<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Process for producing carbon fibrils and reaction apparatus for performing this process
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2025781A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MANDEVILLE W HARRY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TRUESDALE LARRY K [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TENNENT HOWARD G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MANDEVILLE, W. HARRY
</Name>
<Name>
TRUESDALE, LARRY K
</Name>
<Name>
TENNENT, HOWARD G
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HYPERION CATALYSIS INT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HYPERION CATALYSIS INTERNATIONAL, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2025781
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080015827
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
1989-12-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP19990114233
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1989-12-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP19900901950
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1989-12-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19880285817
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1988-12-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J23/745
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/76
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/86
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/88
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/889
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127B2
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127D4
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127F
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127L
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a a continuous process for producing carbon fibrils by decomposing a source of carbon at elevated temperatures in contact with a multivalent metal and recovering the fibrils formed thereby comprising the steps of introducing catalyst particles having a size of up to 400 [mu]m (microns) and comprising at least one multivalent transition metal on a particulate substrate into a reactor heated to a temperature of 500 DEG C to 1500 DEG C, and recovering the fibrils formed thereby wherein said metal is present on said substrate as a multiplicity of discontinuous catalytic sites which, at least during fibril formation, have a size of 3,5 to 70 nm (35 to 700 AA) which size is measured by measuring the size of the transition metal particles recovered along with produced fibrils. This invention also relates to a reaction apparatus to be used for carrying out said process.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A continuous process for producing carbon fibrils by decomposing a source of carbon at elevated temperatures in contact with a multivalent metal and recovering the fibrils formed thereby comprising the steps of introducing catalyst particles having a size of up to 400 [micro]m (microns) and comprising at least one multivalent transition metal on a particulate substrate into a reactor heated to a temperature of 500[deg.]C to 1500[deg.]C, and recovering the fibrils formed thereby wherein said metal is present on said substrate as a multiplicity of discontinuous catalytic sites which, at least during fibril formation, have a size of 3,5 to 70 nm (35 to 700 A) which size is measured by measuring the size of the transition metal particles recovered along with produced fibrils.
</P>
<P>
2. The process claimed in claim 1 wherein said transition metal comprises iron with a catalyst site size of about 6 to 30 mm (60 to 300 A).
</P>
<P>
3. The process claimed in claim 1 wherein said carbon source is a mixture of hydrocarbons.
</P>
<P>
4. The process claimed in claim 1 wherein said carbon source is at least one member selected from the group consisting of methane, ethane, propane, butane, benzene, butene, isobutene, cyclohexane, ethylene, propylene, acetylene, toluene, xylene, cumene, ethyl benzene, naphthalene, phenanthrene, anthracene, formaldehyde, acetaldehyde, acetone, methanol, ethanol and carbon monoxide.
</P>
<P>
5. The process as claimed in claim 1 carried out in an ebulliating bed wherein said catalyst/substrate has a particle size of about 50 to 300 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
6. The process as claimed in claim 1 carried out in a transport bed wherein said catalyst/substrate has a particle size of less than about 1 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
7. The process as claimed in claim 1 including cofeeding said catalyst/substrate and said source of carbon downflow through a reaction zone.
</P>
<P>
8. The process claimed in claim 10 including cofeeding said catalyst/substrate upflow through a reaction zone.
</P>
<P>
9. The process claimed in claim 1 including cofeeding a non-hydrocarbonaceous gas with said carbon contributing feed.
</P>
<P>
10. The process claimed in claim 1 including adding said catalyst particles to said process over the course of said fibril forming reaction.
</P>
<P>
11. A continuos process for the production of carbon fibrils in a fluid reaction zone comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) introducing a suitable gaseous fibril precursor into a lower part of a vertical fluid bed reactor.
</P>
<P>
(b) reacting said precursor in said fluid bed in the presence of finely divided particles of a catalyst for converting said precursor to fibrils without the coproduction of a thermal carbon overcoat under fibril-forming reaction conditions; and
</P>
<P>
(c) removing fibrils from said vertical reactor.
</P>
<P>
12. The process according to claim 11, wherein said fibril-forming reaction-conditions include a temperature from about 500 to 1500[deg.]C, preferably a temperature from about 600 to 900[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
13. The process according to claim 11, wherein said finely divided particles of a catalyst comprise at least one metal selected from the group consisting of transition metals, lanthanides and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The process according to claim 13, wherein said transition metals are selected from the group consisting of iron, cobalt, nickel, platinum, palladium, vanadium, chromium or mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
15. A reaction apparatus for the continuous production of carbon fibrils from a gaseous fibril precursor without the coproduction of a thermal carbon overcoat comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) a vertical reaction zone containing fluidizable, finely divided particles of a catalyst for converting said precursor to carbon fibrils;
</P>
<P>
(b) a port for introducing said gaseous precursor into a lower part of said vertical reaction zone;
</P>
<P>
(c) means for causing said gaseous precursor to flow upwardly in said reaction zone and fluidize said finely divided particles of catalyst;
</P>
<P>
(d) means for maintaining fibril-forming reaction conditions within said vertical reaction zone; and
</P>
<P>
(e) a port for removing fibrils from said vertical reaction zone.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO9007023A1;ZA8909615A;KR0137224B1;JPH04504445A;JP11256430A;IL92717A;EP0969127A2;EP0969127A3;EP0451208A1;EP0451208A4;EP0451208B1;DE68929243T2;BR8907845A;AU4947390A;AU642401B2;AT191018T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
