<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
MAGNETIC SENSOR DEVICE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2041593A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KAHLMAN JOSEPHUS ARNOLDUS HENR [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
PRINS MENNO WILLEM JOSE [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
NIEUWENHUIS JEROEN HANS [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KAHLMAN, JOSEPHUS ARNOLDUS HENRICUS MARIA
</Name>
<Name>
PRINS, MENNO WILLEM JOSE
</Name>
<Name>
NIEUWENHUIS, JEROEN HANS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONINKL PHILIPS ELECTRONICS NV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2041593
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070789854
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-07-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IB52558
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060116957
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070789854
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/74B
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543D4B
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09B
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12M
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a magnetic sensor device comprising means (11, 14) for increasing a binding possibility of magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) e.g. magnetic particles, onto the binding sites by applying a moving magnetic field. The present invention furthermore provides a biochip (40) comprising at least one such magnetic sensor and a method for detecting and/or quantifying target moieties in a sample fluid by using such a magnetic sensor.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. A magnetic sensor device for detecting and/or quantifying target moieties in a sample fluid, the magnetic sensor device comprising:
</P>
<P>
- a first sensor chip (16, 16a) having a top surface and binding sites,
</P>
<P>
- means for attracting magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) towards and onto the top surface of the sensor chip (16, 16a), - at least one sensor element (12) for sensing the presence of magnetic or magnetizable objects (15), and
</P>
<P>
- means (11, 14) for increasing a binding possibility of the magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) onto the binding sites by inducing a moving magnetic field.
</P>
<P>
2. Magnetic sensor device according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sensor element (12) is integrated in the first sensor chip (16, 16a).
</P>
<P>
3. Magnetic sensor device according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the means for increasing a binding possibility of magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) onto the binding sites comprises a plurality of concentric current lines (11) adapted for generating a moving magnetic field.
</P>
<P>
4. Magnetic sensor device according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the means for increasing a binding possibility of magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) onto the binding sites comprises a plurality of parallel current wires (14) adapted for generating a moving magnetic field.
</P>
<P>
5. Magnetic sensor device according to claim 4, wherein the plurality of parallel current wires (17) are positioned so as to form a closed circular configuration.
</P>
<P>
6. Magnetic sensor device according to claim 1 or 2, furthermore comprising at least one container (22) for storing magnetic or magnetizable objects (15).
</P>
<P>
7. A biochip (40) comprising at least one magnetic sensor device according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
8. A method for detecting and/or quantifying target moieties in a sample fluid, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
- providing the sample fluid to a magnetic sensor device,
</P>
<P>
- attracting magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) to a sensor chip surface of the magnetic sensor device, the sensor chip surface having binding sites, and
</P>
<P>
- applying a moving magnetic field for increasing a binding possibility of magnetic or magnetizable objects (15) onto the binding sites.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to claim 8, wherein applying a moving magnetic field may be performed by sequentially actuating a plurality of concentric current lines
</P>
<P>
(11).
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to claim 8, wherein applying a moving magnetic field may be performed by sequentially actuating a plurality of parallel current wires (14).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008007291A2;WO2008007291A3;US2009206832A1;JP2009543088A;CN101490576A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
