<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
DEVICE AND METHOD FOR OPTICAL LOCALIZED PLASMON SENSING
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2092308A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RUBINSTEIN ISRAEL [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
VASKEVICH ALEXANDER [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
RUACH-NIR IRIT [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
BENDIKOV TATYANA [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
RUBINSTEIN, ISRAEL
</Name>
<Name>
VASKEVICH, ALEXANDER
</Name>
<Name>
RUACH-NIR, IRIT
</Name>
<Name>
BENDIKOV, TATYANA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
YEDA RES &amp; DEV [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
YEDA RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT COMPANY LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2092308
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070827475
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IL01505
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060872797P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N21/55
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/55B2N
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A device is presented comprising a multi-layer structure with a plurality of metal islands on the surface of a solid transparent substrate. The islands are coated by an ultrathin sol-gel derived silica film via self-assembled monolayer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
I. A device comprising a multi-layer structure with a plurality of metal islands on the surface of a solid transparent substrate, whereon said islands are coated by an ultrathin sol-gel derived silica film via self-assembled monolayer. 2. A device according to Claim 1, wherein said self-assembled monolayer is of a compound having the general formula (I)
</P>
<P>
Z-R-SiOxZ2(OH)3-, (I)
</P>
<P>
Z being a binding moiety that can chemically associate with, attach to, or chemically sorb onto the metal, and R is a linker moiety, 3. A device according to Claim 2, wherein Z is a sulfur containing moiety.
</P>
<P>
4. A device according to any one of Claims 1 to 3, wherein R is an aliphatic or aromatic moiety optionally substituted by a carboxy, carbonyl, amino, hydroxy or thio group.
</P>
<P>
5. A device according to any one of Claims 1 to 4, wherein said silica layer has a thickness of 0.5-20 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. A device according to any one of Claim 1 to 5, wherein said noble metal is gold. &quot;
</P>
<P>
7. A device according to any one of Claims 1 to 6, having inherent stable optical properties and essentially unaffected following exposure to -aqueous or organic solvents, washing and drying.
</P>
<P>
8. A device according to Claim 7, wherein said optical properties are localized surface plasmon absorption.
</P>
<P>
9. A device according to Claim 7 or 8, wherein changes in optical properties are essentially a consequence of binding or release of an analyte to/from a surface of the silica layer.
</P>
<P>
10. A device according to Claim 9, wherein said surface comprises analyte binding sites.
</P>
<P>
II. A sensing device for sensing an analyte in a medium, the device comprising a device according to Claim 9 or 10.
</P>
<P>
12. A device according to Claim 1, configured and operable as a transmission localized surface plasmon resonance (T-LSPR) recognition interface in which changes in the SP band are attributed exclusively to binding/release of analytes to/from the interface, enabling sensing applications. 13. A device according to Claim 12, configured and operable as a sensor based on T-LSPR mode and the optical response of said sensor is sensitive to changes in the effective dielectric constant of the immediate environment. 14. A device according to Claim 12, wherein said sensor is configured and operable as an optical transducer for chemical and/or biological sensing, 15. A device according to Claim 14, wherein said biological sensing comprises label-free recognition of biological molecules using selective antibody-antigen interactions.
</P>
<P>
16. A device according to Claim 14, wherein said sensor is an immunosensor configured and operable to selectivity differentiating between specific and nonspecific interactions.
</P>
<P>
17. A device according to Claim 12, wherein said silica layer is thin enough to afford high T-LSPR sensitivity, while the hydroxyl groups on its surface enable chemical modification for binding of receptor molecules.
</P>
<P>
18. A process for manufacturing a sensing device, the process comprising: (a) providing a solid transparent substrate with a plurality of metal islands on its surface;
</P>
<P>
(b) coating the islands with a monolayer of a compound having the general structure
</P>
<P>
Z-R-SiOxZ2(OH)3-X Z being a binding moiety that can chemically associate with, attach to, or chemically sorb onto the noble metal and R is a linker moiety; and
</P>
<P>
(c) immersing the monolayer-coated substrate in a medium comprising a silica-based sol-gel precursor and providing conditions for a sol-gel reaction to yield a silica film over said monolayer. 19. A process according to Claim 18, wherein the noble metal is gold.
</P>
<P>
20. A process according to Claim 18 or 19, wherein the silica film has a thickness of 0.5-20 nm.
</P>
<P>
21. A process according to Claim 18, wherein the coating is performed at temperature in the range of about 40&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to about 100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C. 22. A process according to any one of Claims 18 to 21, wherein the sol-gel precursor is sodium silicate.
</P>
<P>
23. A process according to any one of Claims 18 to 22, wherein said plurality of metal islands is formed on the surface of the substrate by an evaporation procedure. 24. A process for improving stability of surface optical properties of solid substrate carrying islands of a noble metal on its surface, the process comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) coating the islands with a monolayer of a compound having the general structure
</P>
<P>
Z-R-SiOxZ2(OH)3-X Z being a binding moiety that can chemically associate with, attach to, or chemically sorb onto the noble metal and R is a linker moiety; and
</P>
<P>
(b) immersing the monolayer-coated substrate in a medium comprising a silica-based sol-gel precursor and providing conditions for a sol-gel reaction to yield a silica film over said monolayer. 25. A process according to Claim 24, maintaining a high sensitivity of the surface plasmon absorbance to analyte binding.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008068758A1;US2009257062A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
