<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SEMICONDUCTOR DEVICE HAVING A SEMICONDUCTOR- ON-INSULATOR CONFIGURATION AND A SUPERLATTICE AND ASSOCIATED METHODS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2016621A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KREPS SCOTT A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RAO KALIPATNAM VIVEK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KREPS, SCOTT, A
</Name>
<Name>
RAO, KALIPATNAM, VIVEK
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MEARS TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MEARS TECHNOLOGIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2016621
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070761837
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US68159
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060381835
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060381850
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L21/84
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/12
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/10
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/786
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/786S
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A semiconductor device may include an SOI substrate, an insulating layer adjacent the substrate, and a semiconductor layer adjacent a face of the insulating layer opposite the substrate. The device may further include source and drain regions on the semiconductor layer, a superlattice adjacent the semiconductor layer and extending between the source and drain regions to define a channel, and a gate overlying the superlattice. The superlattice may include a plurality of stacked groups of layers, with each group of layers including a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion and an energy band-modifying layer thereon. The energy band-modifying layer may include at least one non-semiconductor monolayer constrained within a crystal lattice of adjacent base semiconductor portions. The superlattice may contain Germanium.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
THAT WHICH IS CLAIMED SS:
</P>
<P>
1. A semiconductor device comprising: a substrate; an insulating layer adjacent said substrate; a semiconductor layer adjacent a face of said insulating layer opposite said substrate; source and drain regions on said semiconductor layer; a superlattice adjacent said semiconductor layer and extending between said source and drain regions to define a channel; and a gate overlying said superiattice; said superlattice comprising a plurality of stacked groups of layers with each group of layers comprising a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion and an energy band-modifying layer thereon; said energy band-modifying layer comprising at least one non- semiconductor monolayer constrained within a crystal lattice of adjacent base semiconductor portions.
</P>
<P>
2. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 further comprising a contact layer on at least one of said source and drain regions.
</P>
<P>
3. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein said substrate comprises silicon, and wherein said insulating layer comprises silicon oxide,
</P>
<P>
4. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein said superlattice has a common energy band structure therein.
</P>
<P>
5. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein said superlattice has a higher charge carrier mobility than would otherwise be present without said energy band-modifying layer.
</P>
<P>
6. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein each base semiconductor portion comprises silicon.
</P>
<P>
7. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein each base semiconductor portion comprises germanium.
</P>
<P>
8. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein each energy band-modifying layer comprises oxygen.
</P>
<P>
9. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein each energy band-modifying layer is a single monolayer thick.
</P>
<P>
10. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein each base semiconductor portion is less than eight monolayers thick.
</P>
<P>
11. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein said superlattice further has a substantially direct energy bandgap.
</P>
<P>
12. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein said superiattice further comprises a base semiconductor cap layer on an uppermost group of layers.
</P>
<P>
13. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein a!! of said base semiconductor portions are a same number of monolayers thick.
</P>
<P>
14. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein at least some of said base semiconductor portions are a different number of monolayers thick.
</P>
<P>
15. The semiconductor device of Claim 1 wherein each energy band-modifying layer comprises a non-semiconductor selected from the group consisting of oxygen, nitrogen, fluorine, and carbon-oxygen.
</P>
<P>
16.A method for making a semiconductor device comprising: forming an insulating layer adjacent a substrate; forming a superiattice adjacent a semiconductor layer, and positioning the semiconductor layer adjacent a face of the insulating layer opposite the substrate; forming a gate overlying the superiattice; and forming source and drain regions on the semiconductor layer so that the superiattice extends therebetween to define a channel; the superiattice comprising a plurality of stacked groups of layers with each group of layers comprising a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion and an energy band-modifying layer thereon; the energy band-modifying layer comprising at least one non- semiconductor monolayer constrained within a crystal lattice of adjacent base semiconductor portions.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of Claim 16 further comprising forming a contact layer on at least one of the source and drain regions.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of Claim 16 wherein the substrate comprises silicon, and wherein the insulating layer comprises silicon oxide.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of Claim 16 wherein the superlattice has a common energy band structure therein.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of Claim 16 wherein the superlattice has a higher charge carrier mobility than wou!d otherwise be present without the energy band-modifying iayer.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of Claim 16 wherein each base semiconductor portion comprises silicon.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of Claim 16 wherein each base semiconductor portion comprises germanium.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of Claim 16 wherein each energy band- modifying iayer comprises oxygen.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of Claim 16 wherein each energy band- modifying layer is a single monolayer thick.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of Claim 16 wherein each base semiconductor portion is less than eight monolayers thick.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of Claim 16 wherein the superlattice further has a substantially direct energy bandgap.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of Claim 16 wherein the superlattice further comprises a base semiconductor cap layer on an uppermost group of layers.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of Claim 16 wherein all of the base semiconductor portions are a same number of monolayers thick.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of Claim 16 wherein at least some of the base semiconductor portions are a different number of monolayers thick.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of Claim 16 wherein each energy band- modifying layer comprises a non-semiconductor selected from the group consisting of oxygen, nitrogen, fluorine, and carbon-oxygen.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007131119A1;TW200807708A;JP2009536464A;CA2650489A1;AU2007247955A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
