<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Use of surface- modified nanoparticles for oil recovery
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2045439A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BARAN JIMMIE R JR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CABRERA OSWALDO J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BARAN, JIMMIE R., JR
</Name>
<Name>
CABRERA, OSWALDO J
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2045439
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080169030
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-05-12
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030726813
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-05-12
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20020383205P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-05-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09C1/30
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/32
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/38
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/518
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/536
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/58
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/70
</Class>
<Class>
E21B43/22
</Class>
<Class>
E21B43/25
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/30D12
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/38
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/518
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/536
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/58
</Class>
<Class>
C09K8/70B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a method of removing debris from a well using a drilling fluid comprising the steps of: injecting under pressure a foamed drilling fluid into the well;  contacting the debris with the foamed drilling fluid;  and directing the debris and foamed drilling fluid out of the well, wherein the drilling fluid comprises a foam composition comprising solvent, foaming agent, and surface-modified nanoparticles disposed in said solvent.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of removing debris from a well using a drilling fluid comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
injecting under pressure a foamed drilling fluid into the well;
</P>
<P>
contacting the debris with the foamed drilling fluid; and
</P>
<P>
directing the debris and foamed drilling fluid out of the well,wherein the drilling fluid comprises a foam composition comprising solvent, foaming agent, and surface-modified nanoparticles disposed in said solvent.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein the foam composition further comprises a surfactant.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein the surface-modified particles are present in an amount of from 0.01 to 70 wt.%.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles have a particle diameter of less than about 100 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of silica, titania, alumina, zirconia, vanadia, ceria, iron oxide, antimony oxide, tin oxide, aluminum/silica, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles comprise surface groups selected from the group consisting of hydrophobic groups, hydrophilic groups, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles comprise surface groups derived from an agent selected from the group consisting of silane, organic acid, organic base, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1, wherein the solvent is selected from the group consisting of water, acids, alcohols, ketones, aldehydes, amines, ethers, hydrocarbons, petroleum oils, halocarbons, monomers, oligomers, polymers, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1, wherein the foaming agent is selected from the group consisting of liquid, gas, and solid foaming agents, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1, wherein the foaming agent comprises a gas selected from the group consisting of air, nitrogen, oxygen, carbon dioxide, helium, argon, nitrous oxide, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 1, wherein the solvent comprises water.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1, wherein the solvent comprises non-aqueous fluids.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2045439B1;US2003220204A1;US7033975B2;WO03100214A1;JP2005526887A;EP1509676A1;EP1509676B1;AU2003229032A1;AT421564T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
