<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SYSTEMS AND METHODS FOR CELL MEASUREMENT UTILIZING ULTRASHORT T2* RELAXOMETRY
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2004242A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LIU WEI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DAHNKE HANNES [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SCHAEFFTER TOBIAS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LIU, WEI
</Name>
<Name>
DAHNKE, HANNES
</Name>
<Name>
SCHAEFFTER, TOBIAS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONINKL PHILIPS ELECTRONICS NV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
PHILIPS INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V
</Name>
<Name>
PHILIPS INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY &amp; STANDARDS GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2004242
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070735226
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IB51013
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060788473P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61B5/055
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/54
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K49/18R2N2R
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18W
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present disclosure is directed to a new technique for MR measurement of ultrashort T2 &amp;lt;*&amp;gt;
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for measuring labeled cells, comprising:
</P>
<P>
labeling cells ex vivo with a contrasting agent; monitoring migration, proliferation and/or homing of said labeled cells with magnetic resonance (MR) imaging; measuring T2 relaxometry having a T2 decay curve by acquiring a series of spin echo images comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) inducing a first spin echo signal generating a first spin echo image;
</P>
<P>
(b) inducing multiple spin echo signals generating a series of additional spin echo images from suitable echo shifts towards said T2 decay; and
</P>
<P>
(c) deriving T2 maps using exponential fitting.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1, wherein said contrasting agent is superparamagnetic iron oxide (SPIO).
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1, wherein T2 is ultrashort.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to claim 3, wherein T2 varies from application-to-application, and in certain applications is less than or equal to 2 milliseconds.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to claim 1, wherein said first spin echo signal and said second spin echo signal are formed by a first radio frequency (RF) pulse followed by a second RF pulse respectively.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to claim 5, wherein said first RF pulse is a 90 degree RF pulse followed by a 180 degree RF pulse.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to claim 1, wherein a T2 decay curve is defined by the relationship:
</P>
<P>
M,,e -t/T2
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to claim 1, wherein said T2 decay curve is defined by the relationship: Msse &amp;lt;TE/T2&amp;gt; e &amp;lt;(t&apos;TE)/T2*&amp;gt; .
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to claim 1, wherein said suitable echo shift is done by steps below 1 or 2 milliseconds.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to claim 1, wherein said T2 maps are combined and displayed as an overall T2 map.
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the labeled cells are measured in connection with cell trafficking or cell therapy.
</P>
<P>
12. A system for measuring labeled cells according to any of the preceding claims.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007113721A2;WO2007113721A3;US2009111140A1;TW200806327A;RU2008143199A;RU2434645C2;JP2009531705A;CN101460199A;CN101460199B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
