<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Reinforced and conductive resin compositions comprising polyolefins and poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid)
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2028218A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DEBRAS GUY [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
LUIJKX ROMAIN [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
DEBRAS, GUY
</Name>
<Name>
LUIJKX, ROMAIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOTAL PETROCHEMICALS RES FELUY [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
TOTAL PETROCHEMICALS RESEARCH FELUY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2028218
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070114921
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070114921
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08J3/22
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01B3/44
</Class>
<Class>
C08L67/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/22L
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/10
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01B3/44B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A resin composition comprising a polyolefin, carbon nanotubes and poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid). The invention also covers a process for preparing a resin composition comprising a polyolefin, carbon nanotubes and poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) by (i) blending a poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) with carbon nanotubes to form a composite (ii) blending the composite with a polyolefin. The use of poly(hydroxy carboxylic acids) as a compatibiliser to blend carbon nanotubes into polyolefins is also claimed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for preparing a carbon nanotube-containing masterbatch by melt blending a poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) with carbon nanotubes to form a composite.
</P>
<P>
2. The process according to claim 1 wherein the poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) is polylactic acid.
</P>
<P>
3. A process for preparing a resin composition comprising a polyolefin, carbon nanotubes and poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) by
</P>
<P>
i. blending a poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) with carbon nanotubes to form a composite
</P>
<P>
ii. blending the composite with a polyolefin.
</P>
<P>
4. The process according to claim 3 wherein the polyolefin was prepared with a single-site catalyst, preferably with a metallocene catalyst.
</P>
<P>
5. The process according to claim 3 or claim 4 wherein the poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) is polylactic acid.
</P>
<P>
6. The process according to any one of claims 3 to 5 wherein the poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) is melt blended with carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
7. A resin composition comprising a polyolefin, carbon nanotubes and poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid).
</P>
<P>
8. The resin composition according to claim 6 wherein the polyolefin was prepared with a single-site catalyst, preferably with a metallocene catalyst.
</P>
<P>
9. The resin composition according to claim 6 or claim 7 wherein the poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) is polylactic acid.
</P>
<P>
10. The resin composition according to any one claims 6 to 8 wherein the composition comprises at most 10% by weight of carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
11. The resin composition according to any one claims 6 to 9 wherein the polyolefin is selected from polypropylene and polyethylene homo- and copolymers.
</P>
<P>
12. Use of the resin composition according to any one claims 6 to 10 in injection, extrusion or stretch blow moulded or thermoformed articles, films, foams or fibres.
</P>
<P>
13. Use of poly(hydroxy carboxylic acid) as a compatibiliser to blend carbon nanotubes into polyolefins.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2011184115A1;KR20100044232A;JP2010536973A;WO2009027357A1;EP2181142A1;CN101784588A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
