<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Process for the production of polyester nanocomposites
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2006323A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MOLITOR MICHAEL JOSEPH [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WEIBERG MARK GARY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WETZEL MARK DAVID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WILLIAMSON DAVID T [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLITOR, MICHAEL JOSEPH
</Name>
<Name>
WEIBERG, MARK GARY
</Name>
<Name>
WETZEL, MARK DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
WILLIAMSON, DAVID T
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E.I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2006323
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080010437
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070767035
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-22
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/34
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08G63/80
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/20H
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08L67/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for dispersing sepiolite-type clay particles in a polyester matrix by melt-compounding a mixture of: sepiolite-type clay, at least one linear polyester oligomer, and at least one polyester polymer to produce a nanocomposite composition;  and, optionally, subjecting said nanocomposite composition to solid state polymerization to increase polyester molecular weight. Further described is a method for preparing a polyester nanocomposite composition from a masterbatch, comprising melt-compounding a mixture of: sepiolite-type clay, at least one polyester oligomer, and at least one polyester polymer to produce a nanocomposite composition containing a greater concentration of sepiolite-type clay than is desired in the final resin composition;  optionally, subjecting said nanocomposite composition to solid state polymerization to increase the polyester molecular weight;  and further melt compounding said nanocomposite composition with polyester polymer and, optionally, additional ingredients.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for dispersing particles of sepiolite-type clay in a polyester matrix comprising melt-mixing a mixture of ingredients:
</P>
<P>
a. sepiolite-type clay,
</P>
<P>
b. at least one linear polyester oligomer, and
</P>
<P>
c. at least one polyester polymerto produce a nanocomposite composition; and, optionally, subjecting said nanocomposite composition to solid state polymerization to increase polyester molecular weight.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 wherein the ratio of the at least one linear polyester oligomer to the at least one polyester polymer is from about 1:99 to about 99:1 by weight.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 wherein the amount of sepiolite-type clay is from about 0.1 to about 35 wt% based on the weight of the sepiolite-type clay plus the at least one linear polyester oligomer and at least one polyester polymer.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1 wherein the at least one linear polyester oligomer and/or the at least one polyester polymer is branched or unbranched, a homopolymer or copolymer, or a polymeric blend comprising at least one such homopolymer or copolymer.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 wherein the at least one linear polyester oligomer and/or the at least one polyester polymer is selected from the group consisting of the following:
</P>
<P>
a. polyesters produced from reaction mixtures containing one or more diols and one or more hydrocarbyl diacids or esters of such diacids, wherein the diols are selected from the group consisting of ethylene glycol, 1,3-propylene glycol, 1,2-propylene glycol, 2,2-diethyl-1,3-propane diol, 2,2-dimethyl-1,3-propane diol, 2-ethyl-2-butyl-1,3-propane diol, 2-ethyl-2-isobutyl-1,3-propane diol, 1,3-butane diol, 1,4-butane diol, 1,5-pentane diol, 1,6-hexane diol, 2,2,4-trimethyl-1,6-hexane diol, 1,2-cyclohexane dimethanol, 1,3-cyclohexane dimethanol, 1,4-cyclohexane dimethanol, 2,2,4,4-tetramethyl-1,3-cyclobutane diol, isosorbide, naphthalene glycols, biphenols, diethylene glycol, triethylene glycol, resorcinol, hydroquinone, t-butyl-hydroquinone, polytetramethylene ether glycol and other longer chain diols and polyols which are the reaction products of diols or polyols with alkylene oxides, and alkyl-substituted and chloro-substituted versions of said diols; and the diacids are selected form the group consisting of terephthalic acid, isophthalic acid, naphthalene dicarboxylic acids, cyclohexane dicarboxylic acids, succinic acid, glutaric acid, adipic acid, sebacic acid, 1,12-dodecane dioic acid, fumaric acid, maleic acid, and alkyl-substituted and chloro-substituted versions of said diacids;
</P>
<P>
b. polyesters produced from reaction mixtures containing one or more polymerizable polyester monomers selected from the group consisting of hydroxybenzoic acids, hydroxynaphthoic acids, lactic acid, bis(2-hydroxyethyl) terephthalate, bis(4-hydroxybutyl) terephthalate, bis(2-hydroxyethyl)naphthalenedioate, bis(2-hydroxyethyl)isophthalate, bis[2-(2-hydroxyethoxy)ethyl]terephthalate, bis[2-(2-hydroxyethoxy)ethyl]isophthalate, bis[(4-hydroxymethylcyclohexyl)methyl]terephthalate, and bis[(4-hydroxymethylcyclohexyl)methyl]isophthalate, mono(2-hydroxyethyl)terephthalate, bis(2-hydroxyethyl)sulfoisophthalate, lactide, and alkyl-substituted and chloro-substituted versions of said polymerizable polyester monomers; and
</P>
<P>
c. polyesters produced directly from reaction mixtures containing macrocyclic polyester oligomers selected from the group consisting of macrocyclic polyester oligomers of: 1,4-butylene terephthalate,1,3-propylene terephthalate, 1,4-cyclohexylenedimethylene terephthalate, ethylene terephthalate, 1,2-ethylene 2,6-naphthalenedicarboxylate, the cyclic ester dimer of terephthalic acid and diethylene glycol, macrocyclic co-oligoesters comprising two or more of the above structural repeat units, and alkyl-substituted and chloro-substituted versions of said macrocyclic polyester oligomers.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 5 wherein the at least one linear polyester oligomer and/or the at least one polyester polymer is selected from the group consisting of the following: poly(ethylene terephthalate), poly(1,3-propylene terephthalate), poly(1,4-butylene terephthalate, a thermoplastic elastomeric polyester having poly(1,4-butylene terephthalate) and poly(tetramethylene ether)glycol blocks, poly(1,4-cylohexyldimethylene terephthalate), and polylactic acid.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1 wherein the sepiolite-type clay is unmodified.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1 wherein the sepiolite-type clay is rheological grade.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1 wherein the melt-mixing is carried out using at least one twin-screw extruder.
</P>
<P>
10. The The method of claim 9 wherein some or all of the output of one twin-screw extruder is re-fed one or more times through the same extruder.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9 wherein the at least one linear polyester oligomer and/or the at least one polyester polymer is fed as a melt.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 9 wherein the sepiolite-type clay is fed as a slurry in an additional ingredient.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 9 further comprising staged feeding.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13 wherein the sepiolite-type clay and the at least one linear polyester oligomer are fed as a dry blend and the at least one polyester polymer is fed as a separate component.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 13 wherein at least one polyester polymer is fed into a first feed port and the sepiolite-type clay and the at least one linear polyester oligomer are fed either as a blend into a second feed port or separately into second and third feed ports downstream.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 13 wherein the at least one linear polyester oligomer and the at least one polyester polymer are fed into a first feed port of the extruder, and the sepiolite-type clay is fed into a second port downstream.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 9 further comprising split feeding at least one ingredient.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 17 comprising split feeding the sepiolite-type clay.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 9 further comprising the step of feeding the output of the extruder, or co-feeding said output with an additional polymer stream, into an additional forming device to form a shaped article.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19 wherein the additional forming device is an extruder.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 19 wherein the shaped article is selected from the group consisting of monofilament, multifilament yarn, film, sheet, tubing, and pellets.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 1 further comprising addition of at least one ingredient selected from the group consisting of antioxidants, toughening agents, pigments, solid particulate filler exclusive of the sepiolite-type clay, plasticizers, epoxy compounds and resins, hydrolysis stabilizers, lubricants, mold release, flame retardants, other polymers, adhesion promoters, thermal stabilizers, UV absorbers, UV stabilizers, processing aids, waxes, color stabilizers, pigments, nucleants, dyes, delusterants, antiblocks, antistats, brighteners, silicon nitride, metal ion sequestrants, anti-staining agents, silicone oil, surfactants, soil repellants, viscosity modifiers, and zirconium acid.
</P>
<P>
23. A method for preparing a polyester nanocomposite composition from a masterbatch, comprising melt-compounding a mixture of: sepiolite-type clay, at least one polyester oligomer, and at least one polyester polymer to produce a nanocomposite composition containing a greater concentration of sepiolite-type clay than is desired in the final resin composition; optionally, subjecting said nanocomposite composition to solid state polymerization to increase the polyester molecular weight; and further melt compounding said nanocomposite composition with polyester polymer and, optionally, additional ingredients.
</P>
<P>
24. A shaped article comprising the polyester nanocomposite composition produced by the method of claim 1 or claim 23, wherein the article is formed using at least one method selected from the group consisting of injection molding, (co)extrusion, blow molding, thermoforming, solution casting, lamination, and film blowing.
</P>
<P>
25. The shaped article of claim 23 wherein said shaped article is selected from the group consisting of:
</P>
<P>
a. appearance parts selected from the group consisting of automotive body panels, fenders, fascia, hoods, tank flaps and other exterior parts; interior automotive panels; automotive lighting fixtures; appliance handles, control panels, chassises (cases), washing machine tubs and exterior parts, interior or exterior refrigerator panels, and dishwasher front or interior panels; power tool housings; electronic cabinets and housings; exterior and interior panels for vehicles; decorative interior panels for buildings; office and home furniture; telephones and other telephone equipment;
</P>
<P>
b. non-appearance parts selected from the group consisting of electrical connectors, covers for switchboxes or fuses, radiator grille supports, headlamp mountings, printed circuit boards, plugs, switches, keyboard components, small electric motor components, distributor caps, bobbins, coil-formers, rotors, windshield wiper arms, headlight mountings, other fittings, conveyor-belt links, hydraulic hosing, rail car couplers, release binders, auto vacuum control tubing, door lock bumpers, railroad car shock absorbers, headphones; specialty fibers, films, and sheets; jacketing, automotive shock absorbers, diaphragms for railroad cars, corrugated plastic tubing, railroad draft gear, auto electric window drive tapes, CVJ boots, recreational footware, conductive rubbers, wire coatings, energy management devices, telephone handset cords, compression spring pads, wire clamps, gun holsters, drive belts, run-flat tire inserts, and medical films;
</P>
<P>
c. packaging selected from the group consisting of packaging film, liners, shrink bags, shrink wrap, frozen food trays, other trays, tray/container assemblies, replaceable and nonreplaceable caps, lids, drink bottle necks, cans, boxes, bottles, jars, bags, cosmetics packages, and closed-ended tubes; and
</P>
<P>
d. monofilaments, multifilament yarn, fishing lines, toothbrush bristles, paintbrush bristles, industrial belts and paper machine clothing comprising woven fabrics produced from monofilaments, tire cords, composites, belts, textiles, reinforced rubber, and high strength industrial fabrics.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2006323B1;US2008315453A1;KR20080112980A;JP2009001796A;CA2634793A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
