<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METAL OXIDE PARTICLES CARRYING CARBON NANOTUBES AND GRANULAR CARBON NANOTUBES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2065341A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GOTO TOSHIKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANI MASATO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
GOTO, TOSHIKI
</Name>
<Name>
TANI, MASATO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
OTSUKA CHEMICAL CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OTSUKA CHEMICAL CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2065341
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070807613
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP68249
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060257656
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-22
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J23/88
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01B33/24
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/28
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/883
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B2
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00F2
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00F4
</Class>
<Class>
C01G53/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention provides novel metal oxide particles on which carbon nanotubes are supported. Needle- or flake-like crystalline metal oxide particles characterized in that carbon nanotubes grown parallel to each other in the direction nearly perpendicular to the surface of each particle are supported on the surfaces of the particles and that the carbon nanotubes supported on the particles are 1 to 500[mu]m in length in the direction nearly perpendicular to the surface of each particle.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes, wherein an acicular or tabular crystalline metal oxide particle carries carbon nanotubes on the surface, the nanotubes being grown in parallel with one another in an approximately perpendicular direction to the surface.
</P>
<P>
2. The metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes according to claim 1, wherein the carried carbon nanotubes have a length in the range from 1 [micro]m to 500 [micro]m in the approximately vertical direction relative to the surface of the metal oxide particle.
</P>
<P>
3. The metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the metal oxide particle is a particle of alkali earth metal silicate, alkali earth metal titanate, or alkali titanate.
</P>
<P>
4. The metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the metal oxide particle is a particle of Wollastonite.
</P>
<P>
5. A method for manufacturing the metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes described in any one of claims 1 - 4, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
contacting a solution containing a metal ion to be a catalyst for generating carbon nanotubes to an acicular or tabular crystalline metal oxide particle to adhere the catalyst to the surface of the metal oxide particle, and contacting hydrocarbon and/or carbon monoxide to the metal oxide particle to which the catalyst has been adhered while heating the particle to 500[deg.]C to 1000[deg.]C to generate and grow carbon nanotubes on the surface of the metal oxide particle.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for manufacturing the metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes according to claim 5, wherein the metal oxide particle is heated by the combustion of a gas containing hydrocarbon and oxygen, and the particle is contacted with hydrocarbon and/or carbon monoxide at the same time to generate and grow carbon nanotubes on the surface of the metal oxide particle.
</P>
<P>
7. The method for manufacturing the metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes according to claim 5 or 6, wherein the solution containing the metal ion to be a catalyst for generating carbon nanotubes comprises at least one element selected from Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, In, Sn, Al and Pt, and Mo element, wherein the at least one element selected from Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, In, Sn, Al and Pt is contained in a range from 0.1 to 1000 mol relative to 1 mol of Mo element.
</P>
<P>
8. A resin composition comprising the metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes described in any one of claims 1 - 4.
</P>
<P>
9. A granular carbon nanotube produced by granulating the metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes described in any one of claims 1 - 4 using no binder.
</P>
<P>
10. A method for manufacturing the granular carbon nanotubes described in claim 9 comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
preparing a water-containing cake of the metal oxide particle carrying carbon nanotubes described in any one of claims 1 - 4,
</P>
<P>
segmentalizing the water-containing cake while applying shear force to produce a granular material, and
</P>
<P>
drying the granular material.
</P>
<P>
11. A resin composition comprising the granular carbon nanotubes described in claim 9.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2065341A4;US2010004372A1;TW200819393A;KR20090064546A;WO2008035730A1;CN101516774A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
