<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Polymer carbon nanotube composites
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2062853A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LUCAS PATRICE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
SCHIERHOLZ KAI [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
BOUTEVIN BERNARD [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
GANACHAU FRANCOIS [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
LUCAS, PATRICE
</Name>
<Name>
SCHIERHOLZ, KAI
</Name>
<Name>
BOUTEVIN, BERNARD
</Name>
<Name>
GANACHAU, FRANCOIS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NANOLEDGE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
CENTRE NAT RECH SCIENT [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
ECOLE NALE SUP ARTES METIERS [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
NANOLEDGE
</Name>
<Name>
CENTRE NATIONAL DE LA RECHERCHE SCIENTIFIQUE
</Name>
<Name>
ECOLE NATIONALE SUPERIEURE DE CHIMIE DE MONTPELLIER
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2062853
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070301580
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070301580
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-23
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D6
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for forming polymer carbon nanotube composites, the method comprising: contacting carbon nanotubes with ozone to functionalize the sideways of the carbon nanotubes with at least one oxygen moiety;  and reacting the functionalized carbon nanotubes with at least one monomer or at least one polymer or copolymer to attach polymer chains to the sidewalls of the carbon nanotubes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for forming polymer carbon nanotube composites, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
contacting carbon nanotubes with ozone to functionalize the sidewalls of the carbon nanotubes with at least one oxygen moiety; and
</P>
<P>
reacting the functionalized carbon nanotubes with at least one monomer or at least one polymer or copolymer to attach polymer chains to the sidewalls of the carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1, wherein the at least one oxygen moiety is selected from the group consisting of primary ozonides, secondary ozonides, peroxides, hydroperoxides, alcohol groups and carboxylic acid groups.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the carbon nanotubes are dispersed in an aprotic solvent, the carbon nanotube dispersion being contacted with the ozone at about -78[deg.]C to about 150[deg.]C, preferably at about -45[deg.]C to about 150[deg.]C, and more preferably at about -45[deg.]C to about 30[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the carbon nanotubes are dispersed in a protic solvent, the carbon nanotube dispersion being contacted with the ozone at about -78[deg.]C to about 100[deg.]C, and preferably at or about -45[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the carbon nanotubes are contacted with the ozone in a gas phase at a temperature range of about -78[deg.]C to about 200[deg.]C, and preferably at about room temperature.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to any one of claims I to 5, wherein the at least one oxygen moiety of the carbon nanotubes are reacted to form a macromer carbon nanotube before being reacted with the at least one monomer to attach polymer chains to the sidewalls of the carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the at least one oxygen moiety of the carbon nanotubes are reacted with the at least one monomer, the method further comprising applying an activating energy or an activating chemical to the functionalized carbon nanotube and the at least one monomer.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the at least one polymer or copolymer is an isocyanate containing polymer or copolymer.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to claim 8, wherein the isocyanate containing copolymer is prepared by mixing 3-isopropenyl-[alpha],[alpha]-dimethyl benzylisocyanate, styrene and an initiator.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to claim 9, wherein the functionalized carbon nanotubes are contacted with the isocyanate containing copolymer for about 48 hours at about room temperature to attach polymer chains to the carbon nanotubes.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2011046316A1;JP2011505313A;EP2227501A1;CN101970550A;WO2009065225A1;CA2706390A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
