<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FORMATION OF ORGANIC NANOSTRUCTURE ARRAY
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2089418A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GAZIT EHUD [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
RECHES MEITAL [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
GAZIT, EHUD
</Name>
<Name>
RECHES, MEITAL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV RAMOT [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
RAMOT AT TEL-AVIV UNIVERSITY LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2089418
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070827468
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IL01495
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060872499P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-04
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K5/06
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B81C1/00C2A
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K17/14
</Class>
<Class>
C07K5/06A2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanostructure array is disclosed. The nanostructure array comprises a plurality of elongated organic nanostructures arranged generally perpendicularly to a plane.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A nanostructure array, comprising a substrate and a plurality of elongated organic nanostructures arranged generally perpendicularly on said substrate.
</P>
<P>
2. A nanostructure array, comprising a planar arrangement of a plurality of elongated organic nanostructures aligned generally parallel to each other.
</P>
<P>
3. A method of fabricating a nanostructure array, comprising dispensing on a substrate organic monomers dissolved in an organic volatile solvent, and evaporating said solvent while generating conditions for self assembling of said organic monomers such as to form a plurality of elongated organic nanostructures arranged generally perpendicularly on said substrate.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 3, wherein said organic volatile solvent is selected so as to allow dispersion of said organic monomers in said solvent prior to said evaporation.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 3, wherein said organic monomers are peptide monomers dissolved in said organic volatile solvent at a concentration of at least 10 mg/ml
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 3, wherein said organic monomers are electrically charged.
</P>
<P>
7. A method of fabricating a nanostructure array, comprising: incubating organic monomers and nanoparticles being responsive to a force field under conditions for self assembling of said organic monomers to elongated organic nanostructures and self coating of said elongated organic nanostructures by said nanoparticles; and applying a force field to said elongated organic nanostructures such as to align said elongated organic nanostructures generally parallel to each other.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 7, wherein said nanoparticles are magnetic nanoparticles and said force field is a magnetic field.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 7, wherein said nanoparticles are electrically charged nanoparticles and said force field is an electric field.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 3 or 7, wherein said organic monomers comprise peptide monomers.
</P>
<P>
11. The nanostructure array or method of claim 1, 2 or 10, wherein said organic nanostructures are multi-walled nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
12. The nanostructure array or method of claim 1, 2 or 10, wherein said organic nanostructures are peptide nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
13. The nanostructure array or method of claim 1, 2 or 12, wherein each of said peptide nanostructures comprises a plurality of peptides.
</P>
<P>
14. The nanostructure array or method of claim 13, wherein each peptide in said plurality of peptides comprises from 2 to 15 amino acid residues.
</P>
<P>
15. The nanostructure array or method of claim 13, wherein each of said peptides in said plurality of peptides comprises at least one aromatic amino acid residue.
</P>
<P>
16. The nanostructure array or method of claim 13, wherein at least one peptide in said plurality of peptides is an end-capping modified peptide.
</P>
<P>
17. The nanostructure array or method of claim 15, wherein at least one peptide in said plurality of peptides consists essentially of aromatic amino acid residues.
</P>
<P>
18. The nanostructure array or method of claim 13, wherein at least one peptide in said plurality of peptides is a dipeptide.
</P>
<P>
19. The nanostructure array or method of claim 18, wherein each peptide in said plurality of peptides is a phenylalanine-phenylalanine dipeptide.
</P>
<P>
20. The nanostructure array or method of any of claims 12-19, wherein at least one of said peptide nanostructures is coated by at least one layer of nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
21. The nanostructure array or method of claim 20, wherein said nanoparticles are magnetic nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
22. The nanostructure array or method of claim 20, wherein said nanoparticles are electrically charged.
</P>
<P>
23. The nanostructure array of any of claims 12-19, wherein at least one peptide nanostructure comprises a functional group attached thereto.
</P>
<P>
24. The nanostructure array of any of claims 1-19, wherein said organic nanostructures are electrically charged.
</P>
<P>
25. A field effect transistor, comprising the nanostructure array of any of claims 1- 24.
</P>
<P>
26. A conductive layer, comprising the nanostructure array of claim 2.
</P>
<P>
27. A sensor comprising the nanostructure array of any of claims 1-24.
</P>
<P>
28. A medical lead comprising the nanostructure array of any of claims 1-24.
</P>
<P>
29. A stimulating electrode comprising the nanostructure array of any of claims 1- 24.
</P>
<P>
30. A device for transferring thermal energy, comprising the nanostructure array of any of claims J -24.
</P>
<P>
31. An analyte collecting device, comprising the nanostructure array of any of claims 1-24.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008068752A2;WO2008068752A3;US2012021954A1;JP2010512015A;CN101652382A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
