<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PUMP PROBE MEASURING DEVICE, AND SCANNING PROBE MICROSCOPE APPARATUS USING THE DEVICE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2090880A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SHIGEKAWA HIDEMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TAKEUCHI OSAMU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIGEKAWA, HIDEMI
</Name>
<Name>
TAKEUCHI, OSAMU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
JAPAN SCIENCE &amp; TECH AGENCY [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
JAPAN SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY AGENCY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2090880
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070832710
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP72988
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060322662
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01B7/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/01
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/27
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/39
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/10
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q30/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A pump probe measuring device (1) includes an ultrashort optical pulse laser generator (11) for generating a first ultrashort optical pulse train, which becomes a pump light, and a second ultrashort optical pulse train, which becomes a probe light, a delay time adjusting unit (15) for adjusting a delay time between ultrashort optical pulse trains, a first pulse picker and a second pulse picker (13, 14) for accepting each of the first and the second ultrashort optical pulse trains and allowing only one pulse to be transmitted at an arbitrary repetition periodicity, thus reducing the effective repetition frequency of the optical pulses, a delay time modulation unit (10) for periodically changing a position through which pulses are transmitted by the first and the second pulse pickers (13, 14), an irradiation optical system (16) for applying pump light and probe light to a sample (19), a measuring unit (20) for detecting probe signals from a sample (19), and a lock-in amplifier (18).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A pump probe measuring device comprising:
</P>
<P>
an ultrashort optical pulse laser generator for generating a first ultrashort optical pulse train, which becomes a pump light, and a second ultrashort optical pulse train, which becomes a probe light;
</P>
<P>
a delay time adjusting unit for adjusting a delay time of said first and second ultrashort optical pulse trains;
</P>
<P>
a first pulse picker and a second pulse picker for reducing effective repetition frequency of optical pulses by accepting each of said first and second ultrashort optical pulse trains and transmitting only one pulse at an arbitrary repetition frequency;
</P>
<P>
a delay time modulating unit for periodically changing a position through which optical pulses are transmitted by said first and second pulse pickers;
</P>
<P>
a measuring unit for detecting probe signals from a sample equipped with an irradiation optical system for applying said pump light and said probe light to said sample; and
</P>
<P>
a lock-in detecting unit for performing a phase-sensitive detection of probe signals from said sample at a modulation frequency of said delay time modulation unit, wherein
</P>
<P>
the first or the second pulse picker changes the position through which optical pulses are transmitted, thus changing the delay time between the optical pulse that is transmitted through said second pulse picker or the optical pulse that is transmitted through said first pulse picker.
</P>
<P>
2. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1, wherein each pulse picker comprises a Pockels cell and a light polarizer, and it transmits or blocks arbitrary optical pulses.
</P>
<P>
3. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1 or 2, wherein said delay time modulation unit comprises: a photosensor for detecting optical pulses generated by said ultrashort optical pulse laser generator; a counting means for counting pulse signals from said photosensor; a delaying means to be connected to said counting means; and a driving means for said pulse pickers.
</P>
<P>
4. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1, wherein said ultrashort optical pulse laser generator includes a laser source comprising a titanium sapphire laser.
</P>
<P>
5. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1, wherein an optical system employing an optical path length adjustment mechanism using movable mirrors is provided with said delay time adjusting unit.
</P>
<P>
6. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1 or 4, wherein said ultrashort optical pulse laser generator comprises: an ultrashort optical pulse laser source; and an optical device for dividing the ultrashort optical pulses generated by said ultrashort optical pulse laser source to form the pump light and the probe light.
</P>
<P>
7. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1, wherein said ultrashort optical pulse laser generator comprising two ultrashort optical pulse laser sources and the ultrashort optical pulses generated by each ultrashort optical pulse laser source are transmitted into the corresponding pulse pickers as the pump light and the probe light, respectively.
</P>
<P>
8. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 6 or 7, wherein a cavity dumper is provided with said ultrashort optical pulse laser source.
</P>
<P>
9. The pump probe measuring device as set forth in claim 1, wherein an optical system for applying the pump light and the probe light to the surface of the sample and an optical system for measuring the intensity of said reflected probe light is provided with said measuring unit, and said intensity of the reflected probe light is output as probe signals.
</P>
<P>
10. A scanning probe microscope apparatus comprising a pump probe measuring device as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein a scanning tunneling microscope for measuring local physical properties at the position where pump light and probe light are applied is provided with said measuring unit, and the probe signals obtained by said scanning tunneling microscope are output.
</P>
<P>
11. Various measuring devices including a pump probe measuring device as set forth in any one of claims 1 to 9 as one of their components.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010088787A1;US7961379B2;KR20090082934A;WO2008066090A1;JP2008139028A;CN101595379A;CN101595379B;CA2670948A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
