<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOMATERIAL POLYMER COMPOSITIONS AND USES THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2057212A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ROZHIN OLEKSIY [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
FERRARI ANDREA [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
MILNE WILLIAM IRELAND [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
ROZHIN, OLEKSIY
</Name>
<Name>
FERRARI, ANDREA
</Name>
<Name>
MILNE, WILLIAM, IRELAND
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CAMBRIDGE ENTPR LTD [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
CAMBRIDGE ENTERPRISE LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2057212
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070789313
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007GB03226
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060513489
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
<Class>
C08L83/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/12
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention is directed to compositions (&quot;Nanomaterial Polymer Compositions&quot;) comprising a silicone polymer and a nanomaterial, including but not limited to, a single or multi-walled nanotube, a nanowire, a nanodot, a quantum dot, a nanorod, a nanocrystal, a nanotetrapod, a nanotripod, a nanobipod, a nanoparticle, a nanosaw, a nanospring, a nanoribbon, a branched nanomaterial, or any combination thereof. The Nanomaterial Polymer Compositions are useful for optical and sensing devices including but not limited to noise suppression, passive Q-switching, mode-locking, waveform shaping, optical switching, optical signal regeneration, phase conjugation or filter devices, dispersion compensation, wavelength conversion, a soliton stabilization, microcavity applications, interferometers;  optical, magneto-optical or electro-optical modulation;  and biochemical sensors and photodetectors. The Nanomaterial Polymer Compositions are also useful in soft lithography processes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS ;
</P>
<P>
1. A composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) one or more nanomaterials; and (b) a silicone polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition of claim 1, wherein the silicone polymer is selected from the group consisting of polydimethylsiloxane, polydimethyl-methylphenylsiloxane, polymethyl-phenylsiloxane, polyphenyl-T resin, polyfluorosilicones, tetramethyltetra-phenyltrisiloxane, silanes and any mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition of claim 1, wherein the polymer comprises polydimethylsiloxane.
</P>
<P>
4. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 3 , wherein the nanomaterial is selected from a group consisting of Au, Ag, Pt, Pd, Ni, Co, Ti, Mo, W, Mn, Ir, Cr, Fe, C, Si, Ge, B, Sn, SiGe, SiC, SiSn, GeC, BN, InP, InN, InAs, InSb, GaN, GaP,
</P>
<P>
GaAs, GaSb, AlN, AlP, AlAs, AlSb, CdO, CdS, CdSe, CdTe, ZnO, ZnS, ZnSe, ZnTe, MgO, MgS, MgSe, MgTe, HgO, HgS, HgSe, HgTe, PbO, PbS, PbSe, PbTe, GeS, GeSe, GeTe, SnS, SnSe, SnTe, InO, SnO, GeO, WO, TiO, FeO, MnO, CoO, NiO, CrO, VO, CuSn, CuF, CuCl, CuBr, CuI, AgF, AgCl, AgBr, AgI, CaCN2, BeSiN2, ZnGeP2, CdSnAs2, ZnSnSb2, CuGeP3, CuSi2P3, Si3N4, Ge3N4, Al2O3, Al2CO, Inx0y, Snx0y, SiOx, GeOx, Wx0y, TixOy, Fex0y, Mnx0y, Cox0y, Nix0y, Crx0y, Vx0y, MSiO4, any alloys thereof, and any combination thereof, wherein x is an integer ranging from 1 to 5, y is an integer ranging from 1 to 5, and M is selected from a group consisting of Zn, Cr, Fe, Mn, Co, Ni, V, and Ti.
</P>
<P>
5. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the nanomaterial is selected from a group consisting of at least one nanotube, nanowire, nanodot, quantum dot, nanorod, nanocrystal, nanotetrapod, nanotripod, nanobipod, nanoparticle, nanospring, nanoribbon, and branched nanomaterial .
</P>
<P>
6. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the nanomaterial comprises at least one nanotube.
</P>
<P>
7. The composition of claim 6, wherein the nanotubes have a diameter of from about 0.01 nm to about 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
8. The composition of claim 7, wherein the nanotubes have a diameter between 0.5 nm and 1.5 nm.
</P>
<P>
9. The composition of claim 6, wherein the nanotubes comprise at least one single-walled carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
10. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 9 , wherein the nanomaterial is present in an amount of from about 0.0001 % to about 50 % by total weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
11. The composition of claim 10, wherein the nanomaterial is present in an amount of from about 0.01 % to about 20% by total weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
12. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein the composition is in the form of a thin film or a liquid.
</P>
<P>
13. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the nanomaterials are arranged in the polymer in a random array.
</P>
<P>
14. The composition of claim 13, wherein the nanomaterials are nanotubes and the polymer is polydimethylsiloxane .
</P>
<P>
15. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the nanomaterial is arranged in the polymer in an ordered array.
</P>
<P>
16. The composition of claim 15, wherein the nanomaterials are nanotubes and the polymer is polydimethylsiloxane.
</P>
<P>
17. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the one or more nanomaterials each have a diameter of from about 1 nm to about 500 run and a length of from about 10 run to about 2 mm.
</P>
<P>
18. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the nanomaterials comprise nanomaterials purified from impurities .
</P>
<P>
19. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the nanomaterials comprise chemically or physically functionalized nanomaterials.
</P>
<P>
20. A device comprising: the composition of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
21. The device of claim 20, wherein the device is a nonlinear optical device or a sensor device.
</P>
<P>
22. The device of claim 21, wherein the composition is in the form of a thin film.
</P>
<P>
23. The device of claim 22, wherein the composition is applied to a substrate using spin coating.
</P>
<P>
24. The device of claim 22, wherein the thin film is affixed to a substrate.
</P>
<P>
25. The device of claim 24, wherein the substrate is quartz, glass, or a mirror.
</P>
<P>
26. The device of claim 21, wherein the composition is in the form of a liquid.
</P>
<P>
27. The device of claim 20, wherein the device is a lens, a prism, a polarization plate, a fiber end, a fiber surface, a waveguide facet, a waveguide surface, a portion of a laser, or a surface of a laser.
</P>
<P>
28. The device of claim 20, wherein the nanomaterial further comprises a dopant.
</P>
<P>
29. The device of claim 27, wherein the dopant is a p-type dopant .
</P>
<P>
30. The device of claim 27, wherein the dopant is an n-type dopant .
</P>
<P>
31. The device of claim 20, wherein the device is integrated into a photonic circuit.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008025962A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
