<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SCANNING ION CONDUCTANCE MICROSCOPY FOR THE INVESTIGATION OF LIVING CELLS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2047231A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KORCHEV YURI EVGENIEVICH [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
LAB MAX JOSEPH [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
SANCHEZ-HERRERA DANIEL PAULO [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
KORCHEV, YURI, EVGENIEVICH
</Name>
<Name>
LAB, MAX, JOSEPH
</Name>
<Name>
SANCHEZ-HERRERA, DANIEL, PAULO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
IONSCOPE LTD [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
IONSCOPE LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2047231
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070766408
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-01
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007GB02924
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20060015277
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01Q30/20
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/44
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q30/20
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/44
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for interrogating a surface using scanning probe microscopy comprises bringing a scanning probe into proximity with the surface and controlling the position of the probe relative to the surface to maintain a constant distance, characterised in that pressure is applied to the surface by a regulated flow of liquid through the probe, with subsequent monitoring of the position of the probe, wherein movement of the probe indicates a consequent movement of the surface.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method for interrogating a surface using scanning probe microscopy, comprising bringing a scanning probe into proximity with the surface and controlling the position of the probe relative to the surface to maintain a constant distance, characterised in that pressure is applied to the surface by a regulated flow of liquid through the probe, with subsequent monitoring of the position of the probe, wherein movement of the probe indicates a consequent movement of the surface.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1 , wherein positive pressure is applied to the surface.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1 , wherein negative pressure is applied to the surface.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to any preceding claim wherein the probe is a micropipette or nanopipette.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to any preceding claim, wherein the surface to be interrogated is a cellular or subcellular structure.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to any of claims 1 to 4, wherein the surface is that of a liquid.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to claim 6, wherein the liquid is an emulsion.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any of claims 1 to 4, wherein the surface is of a non- biological structure.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to any preceding claim, wherein the scanning probe microscopy is scanning ion-conductance microscopy.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to any preceding claim, for monitoring electrical or mechanical changes in or at the surface.
</P>
<P>
11. A method for inducing an electrophysiological or chemical change in a cell, comprising bringing a scanning probe into proximity with the cell surface and applying a defined pressure to the surface by means of a regulated flow of liquid through the probe, and monitoring the cell for changes in electrophysiological or chemical signals.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to claim 11 , wherein the electrophysiological or chemical signal is associated with an ion channel present on a cell.
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to claim 11 or claim 12, wherein scanning ion conductance microscopy is used to bring the probe into proximity with the cell.
</P>
<P>
14. An apparatus for interrogating a surface, comprising a scanning probe microscope, and a means for applying pressure to the surface by a regulated flow of liquid through the probe.
</P>
<P>
15. An apparatus according to claim 14, wherein the scanning probe microscope is a scanning ion-conductance microscope.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008015428A1;US2009260114A1;US8006316B2;KR20090063208A;JP2009545736A;JP4912465B2;CN101517393A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
