<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Enzyme electrode and enzyme sensor
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2012121A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SHIMOMURA TAKESHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUMIYA TOURU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MASUDA YUICHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ONO MASATOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMOMURA, TAKESHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUMIYA, TOURU
</Name>
<Name>
MASUDA, YUICHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
ONO, MASATOSHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
FUNAI EAA TECH RES INST INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUNAI ELECTRIC CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUNAI ELECTRIC ADVANCED APPLIED TECHNOLOGY RESEARCH INSTITUTE INC
</Name>
<Name>
FUNAI ELECTRIC CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2012121
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080011804
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070176200
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-04
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N33/50
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/00B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is an enzyme electrode comprising: an electrode;  a carbon nanotube layer including a plurality of carbon nanotubes extending directly from the electrode and/or a metallic catalyst immobilized on the electrode;  and an enzyme immobilized in the carbon nanotube layer by being sandwiched between the carbon nanotubes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An enzyme electrode comprising:
</P>
<P>
an electrode;
</P>
<P>
a carbon nanotube layer including a plurality of carbon nanotubes extending directly from the electrode and/or a metallic catalyst immobilized on the electrode; and
</P>
<P>
an enzyme immobilized in the carbon nanotube layer by being sandwiched between the carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
2. The enzyme electrode according to claim 1, further comprising an outflow preventing section to prevent the enzyme immobilized in the carbon nanotube layer from outflowing.
</P>
<P>
3. The enzyme electrode according to claim 2, wherein the outflow preventing section is a predetermined layer to cover the carbon nanotube layer.
</P>
<P>
4. The enzyme electrode according to claim 2 or 3, wherein the outflow preventing section is a predetermined cross-linking agent introduced in the carbon nanotube layer.
</P>
<P>
5. The enzyme electrode according to any one of the claims 2-4, wherein the outflow preventing section is a carboxyl group introduced in an end of the carbon nanotubes, the carboxyl group reacting with an amine group of the enzyme to form an amide bond.
</P>
<P>
6. The enzyme electrode according to any one of the claims 1-5, wherein an electron carrier to accelerate delivery of electrons between the enzyme and the electrode or the carbon nanotubes, and/or a coenzyme to catalyze expression of activity of the enzyme, are introduced in the carbon nanotube layer.
</P>
<P>
7. The enzyme electrode according to any one of the claims 1-6, further comprising a hydrophobic insulating section provided around the electrode.
</P>
<P>
8. An enzyme electrode comprising:
</P>
<P>
an electrode;
</P>
<P>
a carbon nanotube layer including a plurality of carbon nanotubes extending directly from the electrode and/or a metallic catalyst immobilized on the electrode;
</P>
<P>
an enzyme immobilized in the carbon nanotube layer by being sandwiched between the carbon nanotubes;
</P>
<P>
an outflow preventing section to prevent the enzyme immobilized in the carbon nanotube layer from outflowing;
</P>
<P>
an electron carrier to accelerate delivery of electrons between the enzyme and the electrode or the carbon nanotubes, and/or a coenzyme to catalyze expression of activity of the enzyme, the electron carrier and/or the coenzyme being introduced in the carbon nanotube layer; and
</P>
<P>
a hydrophobic insulating section provided around the electrode.
</P>
<P>
9. An enzyme sensor to detect a target substance by an electrochemical measurement method, comprising the enzyme electrode according to any one of the claims 1-8.
</P>
<P>
10. The enzyme sensor according to claim 9, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate; and
</P>
<P>
an analysis section provided on a top surface of the substrate, wherein
</P>
<P>
the enzyme electrode is disposed inside the analysis section on the top surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
11. The enzyme sensor according to claim 10, further comprising a hydrophobic insulation film provided around the analysis section on the top surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
12. The enzyme sensor according to claim 10 or 11, wherein an upper surface of the analysis section includes an opening portion, and
</P>
<P>
the enzyme sensor further comprises a predetermined film to cover the opening portion, to suppress transmission of a liquid, and to transmit a gas molecule.
</P>
<P>
13. An enzyme sensor to detect a target substance by an electrochemical measurement method, comprising:
</P>
<P>
the enzyme electrode according to any one of the claims 1-8;
</P>
<P>
a substrate;
</P>
<P>
an analysis section provided on a top surface of the substrate, the analysis section including an opening portion on an upper surface of the analysis section;
</P>
<P>
a hydrophobic insulation film provided around the analysis section on the top surface of the substrate; and
</P>
<P>
a predetermined film to cover the opening portion, to suppress transmission of a liquid, and to transmit a gas molecule, wherein
</P>
<P>
the enzyme electrode is disposed inside the analysis section on the top surface of the substrate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009008248A1;KR20090004674A;JP2009014485A;CN101339155A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
