<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SPINTRONIC DEVICES WITH CONSTRAINED SPINTRONIC DOPANT AND ASSOCIATED METHODS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2002481A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HUANG XIANGYANG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HALILOV SAMED [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YIPTONG JEAN AUGUSTIN CHAN SOW [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DUKOVSKI ILIJA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HYTHA MAREK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MEARS ROBERT J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HUANG, XIANGYANG
</Name>
<Name>
HALILOV, SAMED
</Name>
<Name>
YIPTONG, JEAN AUGUSTIN CHAN SOW FOOK
</Name>
<Name>
DUKOVSKI, ILIJA
</Name>
<Name>
HYTHA, MAREK
</Name>
<Name>
MEARS, ROBERT J
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MEARS TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MEARS TECHNOLOGIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2002481
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070753441
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-19
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US06814
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-19
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060783598P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070687430
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070687422
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L29/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/66
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/40D
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32F
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N6
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/15B2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/15D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/66S
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A spintronic device may include at least one superlattice and at least one electrical contact coupled thereto, with the at least one superlattice including a plurality of groups of layers. Each group of layers may include a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion having a crystal lattice, at least one non-semiconductor monolayer constrained within the crystal lattice of adjacent base semiconductor portions, and a spintronic dopant. The spintronic dopant may be constrained within the crystal lattice of the base semiconductor portion by the at least one non-semiconductor monolayer. In some embodiments, the repeating structure of a superlattice may not be needed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
THAT WHICH IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A spintronic device comprising: at least one superlattice; and at least one electrical contact coupled to said at least one superlattice; said at least one superlattice comprising a plurality of groups of layers with each group of layers comprising a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion having a crystal lattice, at least one non-semiconductor monolayer constrained within the crystal lattice of adjacent base semiconductor portions, and a spintronic dopant constrained within the crystal lattice of the base semiconductor portion by said at least one non-semiconductor monolayer.
</P>
<P>
2. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said spintronic dopant comprises at least one spintronic dopant monolayer adjacent said at least one non- semiconductor monolayer.
</P>
<P>
3. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said spintronic dopant comprises a transition metal.
</P>
<P>
4. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said spintronic dopant comprises Manganese.
</P>
<P>
5. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said at least one transition metal comprises at least one of Manganese, Iron, and Chromium.
</P>
<P>
6. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said spintronic dopant comprises a rare earth.
</P>
<P>
7. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said rare earth comprises a rare earth lanthanide.
</P>
<P>
8. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said non-semiconductor comprises Oxygen.
</P>
<P>
9. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said non-semiconductor comprises at least one of Oxygen, Nitrogen, Fluorine, Carbon-Oxygen, and Sulphur.
</P>
<P>
10. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said semiconductor comprises Silicon.
</P>
<P>
11. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said semiconductor comprises a semiconductor selected from the group comprising Group IV semiconductors, Group III-V semiconductors, and Group II-VI semiconductors.
</P>
<P>
12. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said at least one superlattice comprises a pair of superlattices; and further comprising: a substrate carrying said pair of superlattices in spaced apart relation to define a source and a drain; a channel between said source and drain; and a gate adjacent said channel so that said spintronic device defines a spintronic field effect transistor.
</P>
<P>
13. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said at least one superlattice comprises a pair of superlattices; and further comprising: a substrate carrying said pair of superlattices in spaced apart relation; and a spacer between said pair of superlattices so that said spintronic device defines a spintronic valve.
</P>
<P>
14. The spintronic device according to Claim 1 wherein said at least one superlattice exhibits a Curie temperature of at least as high as room temperature. T/US2007/006814
</P>
<P>
15. A spintronic device comprising: a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion having a crystal lattice;
</P>
<P>
_ at least one non-semiconductor monolayer constrained within the crystal lattice; a spintronic dopant constrained within the crystal lattice of the base semiconductor portion by said at least one non-semiconductor monolayer; and an electrical contact coupled to said base semiconductor portion.
</P>
<P>
16. The spintronic device according to Claim 15 wherein said spintronic dopant comprises at least one spintronic dopant monolayer adjacent said at least one non- semiconductor monolayer.
</P>
<P>
17. The spintronic device according to Claim 15 wherein said spintronic dopant comprises at least one of a transition metal and a rare earth.
</P>
<P>
18. The spintronic device according to Claim 15 wherein said non-semiconductor comprises at least one of Oxygen, Nitrogen, Fluorine, Carbon-Oxygen, and Sulphur.
</P>
<P>
19. The spintronic device according to Claim 15 wherein said semiconductor comprises a semiconductor selected from the group comprising Group IV semiconductors, Group III-V semiconductors, and Group- II-VI semiconductors.
</P>
<P>
20. The spintronic device according to Claim 15 further comprising a substrate carrying said base semiconductor portion.
</P>
<P>
21. The spintronic device according to Claim 15 wherein said base semiconductor portion exhibits a Curie temperature of at least as high as room temperature.
</P>
<P>
22. A method for making a spintronic device comprising: forming at least one superlattice; and forming at least one electrical contact coupled to the at least one superlattice; the at least one superlattice comprising a plurality of groups of layers with each group of layers comprising a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion having a crystal lattice, at least one non-semiconductor monolayer constrained within the crystal lattice of adjacent base semiconductor portions, and a spintronic dopant constrained within the crystal lattice of the base semiconductor portion by the at least one non-semiconductor monolayer.
</P>
<P>
23. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the spintronic dopant comprises at least one spintronic dopant monolayer adjacent the at least one non-semiconductor monolayer.
</P>
<P>
24. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the spintronic dopant comprises a transition metal.
</P>
<P>
25. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the spintronic dopant comprises Manganese.
</P>
<P>
26. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the at least one transition metal comprises at least one of Manganese, Iron, and Chromium.
</P>
<P>
27. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the spintronic dopant comprises a rare earth.
</P>
<P>
28. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the rare earth comprises a rare earth lanthanide.
</P>
<P>
29. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the non-semiconductor comprises Oxygen.
</P>
<P>
30. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the non-semiconductor comprises at least one of Oxygen, Nitrogen, Fluorine, Carbon-Oxygen, and Sulphur.
</P>
<P>
31. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the semiconductor comprises Silicon.
</P>
<P>
32. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the semiconductor comprises a semiconductor selected from the group comprising Group IV semiconductors, Group III-V semiconductors, and Group II-VI semiconductors.
</P>
<P>
33. The method according to Claim 22 wherein forming the at least one superlattice comprises forming a pair of superlattices; and further comprising: providing a substrate carrying the pair of superlattices in spaced apart relation to define a source and a drain; forming a channel between the source and drain; and forming a gate adjacent the channel so that the spintronic device defines a spintronic field effect transistor.
</P>
<P>
34. The method according to Claim 22 wherein forming the at least one superlattice comprises forming a pair of superlattices; and further comprising: providing a substrate carrying the pair of superlattices in spaced apart relation; and forming a spacer between the pair of superlattices so that the spintronic device defines a spintronic valve.
</P>
<P>
35. The method according to Claim 22 wherein the at least one superlattice exhibits a Curie temperature of at least as high as room temperature.
</P>
<P>
36. A method for making spintronic device comprising: forming a plurality of stacked base semiconductor monolayers defining a base semiconductor portion having a crystal lattice; forming at least one non-semiconductor monolayer constrained within the crystal lattice; providing a spintronic dopant constrained within the crystal lattice of the base semiconductor portion by the at least one non-semiconductor monolayer; and forming an electrical contact coupled to the base semiconductor portion.
</P>
<P>
37. The method according to Claim 36 wherein the spintronic dopant comprises at least one spintronic dopant . monolayer adjacent the at least one non-semiconductor monolayer.
</P>
<P>
38. The method according to Claim 36 wherein the spintronic dopant comprises at least one of a transition metal and a rare earth.
</P>
<P>
39. The method according to Claim 36 wherein the non-semiconductor comprises at least one of Oxygen, Nitrogen, Fluorine, Carbon-Oxygen, and Sulphur.
</P>
<P>
40. The method according to Claim 36 wherein the semiconductor comprises a semiconductor selected from the group comprising Group IV semiconductors, Group III-V semiconductors, and Group II-VI semiconductors.
</P>
<P>
41. The method according to Claim 36 further comprising providing a substrate carrying the base semiconductor portion.
</P>
<P>
42. The method according to Claim 36 wherein the base semiconductor portion exhibits a Curie temperature of at .least as high as room temperature.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007109231A1;JP2009530827A;CA2646325A1;AU2007227418A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
