<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SEMICONDUCTOR NANOPARTICLE AND METHOD FOR PRODUCING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2062855A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GOAN KAZUYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKADA HISATAKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FURUSAWA NAOKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
GOAN, KAZUYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
OKADA, HISATAKE
</Name>
<Name>
FURUSAWA, NAOKO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONICA MINOLTA MED &amp; GRAPHIC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KONICA MINOLTA MEDICAL &amp; GRAPHIC, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2062855
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070806723
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP67280
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060250713
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-15
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J19/00
</Class>
<Class>
B03B5/28
</Class>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B33/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09K11/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B33/02
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is a method to produce a semiconductor nanoparticle which is excellent in monodispersibility and productivity. This method is characterized in that two or more kinds of semiconductor nanoparticles having different average particle diameters are dispersed in a solvent and mixed together, and then subjected to size classification.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of producing a semiconductor nanoparticle comprising the subsequent steps of:
</P>
<P>
mixing two or more kinds of semiconductor nanoparticles each kind having an average particle diameter different from each other while each kind of the semiconductor nanoparticle is dispersed in a solvent; and
</P>
<P>
carrying out size classification of the semiconductor nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein the method includes the step of:
</P>
<P>
separating the semiconductor nanoparticles dispersed in the solvent via centrifugation.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the method includes the step of:
</P>
<P>
separating the semiconductor nanoparticles dispersed in the solvent via centrifugation after a dispersion liquid is concentrated.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 3, wherein the method includes the step of:
</P>
<P>
separating the semiconductor nanoparticles dispersed in the solvent via centrifugation after the dispersion liquid is concentrated by vacuum drying.
</P>
<P>
5. The semiconductor nanoparticle produced by the method of any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the semiconductor nanoparticle has a core/shell structure.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009263659A1;WO2008032619A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
