<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PREPARING MIXED METAL OXIDE POWDERS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2027071A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KATUSIC STIPAN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
ZIMMERMANN GUIDO [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KRAEMER MICHAEL [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MIESS HORST [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
STAAB EDWIN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KATUSIC, STIPAN
</Name>
<Name>
ZIMMERMANN, GUIDO
</Name>
<Name>
KRAEMER, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
MIESS, HORST
</Name>
<Name>
STAAB, EDWIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
EVONIK DEGUSSA GMBH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
EVONIK DEGUSSA GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2027071
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070729221
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-16
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP54773
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
DE200610027335
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-13
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/27
</Class>
<Class>
B01J21/04
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/06
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/03
</Class>
<Class>
C01G99/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/11
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/19
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/27
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q19/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/00B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/06
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02G
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/20
</Class>
<Class>
C01B13/24
</Class>
<Class>
C01F17/00F
</Class>
<Class>
C01G45/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/03
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Process for preparing mixed metal oxide powders Abstract Process for preparing a mixed metal oxide powder, in which oxidizable starting materials are evaporated in an evaporation zone of a reactor and oxidized in the vaporous state in an oxidation zone of this reactor, the reaction mixture is cooled after the reaction and the pulverulent solids are removed from gaseous substances, wherein at least one pulverulent metal, together with one or more combustion gases, is fed to the evaporation zone, the metal is evaporated completely in the evaporation zone under nonoxidizing conditions, an oxygen-containing gas and at least one metal compound are fed, separately or together, in the oxidation zone to the mixture flowing out of the evaporation zone, the oxygen content of the oxygen-containing gas being at least sufficient to oxidize the metal, the metal compound and the combustion gas completely.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims :
</P>
<P>
1. Process for preparing a mixed metal oxide powder, in which - oxidizable starting materials are evaporated in an evaporation zone of a reactor and oxidized in the vaporous state in an oxidation zone of this reactor, the reaction mixture is cooled after the reaction and the pulverulent solids are removed from gaseous substances, characterized in that at least one pulverulent metal, together with one or more combustion gases, is fed to the evaporation zone, the metal is evaporated completely in the evaporation zone under nonoxidizing conditions, an oxygen-containing gas and at least one metal compound are fed, separately or together, in the oxidation zone to the mixture flowing out of the evaporation zone, the oxygen content of the oxygen-containing gas being at least sufficient to oxidize the metal, the metal compound and the combustion gas completely.
</P>
<P>
2. Process according to Claim 1, characterized in that the temperatures needed for the evaporation and oxidation are provided by a flame which is formed by igniting a combustion gas with an oxygenous gas, where 0.5 &amp;lt;= lambda &amp;lt;= 1 in the evaporation zone and 1 &amp;lt; lambda &amp;lt; 10 in the oxidation zone.
</P>
<P>
3. Process according to Claims 1 and 2, characterized in that the pressure in the reactor is 200 mbar to
</P>
<P>
1100 mbar.
</P>
<P>
4. Process according to Claims 1 to 3, characterized in that the pulverulent metal introduced into the evaporation zone is selected from the group comprising Ag, Al, As, Ba, Bi, Ca, Cd, Cu, Ga, Hg, In, Li, K, Mg, Mn, Na, Pb, Sb, Sn, Sr, Se, Te, Tl or Zn .
</P>
<P>
5. Process according to Claims 1 to 4, characterized in that the solid starting materials have a particle size of less than 1000 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
6. Process according to Claims 1 to 5, characterized in that the metal compound is introduced into the oxidation zone in dissolved, dispersed or vapour form.
</P>
<P>
7. Process according to Claims 1 to 6, characterized in that the metal compound used is a chloride, a nitrate, a sulphate, a carbonate, a C1-C12- alkoxide, a Ci-Ci2-carboxylate, an acetylacetonate and/or a carbonyl, with Ag, Al, As, Au, B, Ba, Be, Bi, Ca, Cd, Ce, Co, Cr, Cs, Cu, Er, Eu, Fe, Ga, Gd, Ge, Hf, In, K, La, Li, Mg, Mn, Mo, Na, Nb, Nd, Ni, P, Pb, Pd, Pm, Pr, Pt, Rb, Ru, Sb, Sc, Sm, Sn, Sr, Ta, Tb, Ti, Tl, Tm, V, W, Y, Yb, Zn or Zr as the metal component.
</P>
<P>
8. Process according to Claims 1 to 7, characterized in that the proportion of metal component from metal compound is not more than 25% by weight, based on the sum of metal and metal component from metal compound.
</P>
<P>
9. Process according to Claims 1 to 8, characterized in that the pulverulent metal introduced into the evaporation zone is zinc, the solution of the metal compound introduced into the oxidation zone is a solution of a C2-Cs-carboxylate or Ci-C4-alkoxide of aluminium, cerium or manganese as the metal component in Ci-C4-alcohols and/or C2-C8- carboxylic acids, the proportion of zinc being at least 90% by weight, based on the sum of zinc and metal component from metal compound, lambda is 0.8 to 0.95 in the evaporation zone, lambda is 1.3 to 7 in the oxidation zone.
</P>
<P>
10. Use of the metal oxide powder or mixed metal oxide powder prepared by the process according to Claims 1 to 9 as a filler, as a carrier material, as a catalytically active substance, as a ceramic raw material, as a cosmetic and pharmaceutical raw material.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007144243A1;US2009202427A1;JP2009539753A;DE102006027335A1;CN101466641A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
