<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
RADIATION GENERATING DEVICE, LITHOGRAPHIC APPARATUS, DEVICE MANUFACTURING METHOD AND DEVICE MANUFACTURED THEREBY
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2014141A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
IVANOV VLADIMIR VITALEVITCH [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
BANINE VADIM YEVGENYEVICH [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KRIVTSUN VLADIMIR MIHAILOVITCH [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
IVANOV, VLADIMIR VITALEVITCH
</Name>
<Name>
BANINE, VADIM YEVGENYEVICH
</Name>
<Name>
KRIVTSUN, VLADIMIR MIHAILOVITCH
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ASML NETHERLANDS BV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
ASML NETHERLANDS B.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2014141
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070747411
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-04-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007NL50187
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060417211
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-04
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H05G2/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/70B6
</Class>
<Class>
H05G2/00P2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An apparatus for producing radiation by an electrically operated discharge has a first electrode (generated by nozzle 21a), a second electrode, and a capacitor bank (24). The electrodes are configured at a distance from each other which allows plasma ignition. The capacitor bank is electrically connected at a first terminal (A) to the first electrode and at a second terminal (B) to the second electrode, and configured to store a discharge energy. The electrodes and the capacitor bank form an electric circuit. At least the first electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a first feeding line (45). The apparatus further has a charger (51) and a first high inductance unit (50). The charger is connected to at least one of the terminals. The first high inductance unit is provided upstream the first terminal in the first feeding line for electrically decoupling the electric circuit.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. An apparatus for producing radiation by an electrically operated discharge, comprising: a first electrode and a second electrode, the first and second electrode being configured at a distance from each other which allows ignition of a plasma in a gaseous medium between the first and second electrode; a capacitor bank electrically connected at a first terminal to the first electrode and at a second terminal to the second electrode, the capacitor bank configured to store a discharge energy needed for the ignition of the plasma, the first electrode, second electrode and capacitor bank forming an electric circuit, wherein at least the first electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a first feeding line, the apparatus further comprising a charger connected to the first terminal and/or the second terminal configured to charge the capacitor bank in a time varying manner; and a first high inductance unit provided upstream of the first terminal in the first feeding line for electrically decoupling the electric circuit.
</P>
<P>
2. An apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the radiation is EUV radiation.
</P>
<P>
3. An apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the charger is a pulsed charger.
</P>
<P>
4. An apparatus according to claim 1, further comprising: a laser beam configured to form the gaseous medium by providing a laser beam configured to partially evaporate the electrically conducting fluid.
</P>
<P>
5. An apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the first high inductance unit comprises a first coil-shaped portion of the first feeding line.
</P>
<P>
6. An apparatus according to claim 5, wherein the first coil-shaped portion is provided with a first saturated core.
</P>
<P>
7. An apparatus according to claim 6, wherein the first saturated core includes a ferromagnetic material of a group comprising a nanocrystal alloy.
</P>
<P>
8. An apparatus according to claim 7, wherein the nanocrystal alloy is METGLAS or a ferrite.
</P>
<P>
9. An apparatus according to claim 6, wherein the first high inductance unit is configured to provide an inductance of O.01-10 mH.
</P>
<P>
10. An apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the first feeding line comprises a first nozzle configured to provide the first electrode in the form of a jet of a material.
</P>
<P>
11. An apparatus according to claim 10, wherein the material includes a group of elements comprising tin, indium, gallium and/or lithium.
</P>
<P>
12. An apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the first electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a first feeding line and the second electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a second feeding line, the first feeding line comprising a first nozzle downstream the first terminal configured to provide the first electrode in the form of a first jet of a material, and the second feeding line comprising a second nozzle downstream the second terminal configured to provide the second electrode in the form of a second jet of the material, wherein the apparatus further comprises a second high inductance unit upstream the second terminal in the second feeding line for electrically decoupling the electric circuit.
</P>
<P>
13. An apparatus according to claim 12, wherein the first high inductance unit comprises a first coil-shaped portion of the first feeding line and the second high inductance unit comprises a second coil-shaped portion of the second feeding line.
</P>
<P>
14. An apparatus according to claim 13, wherein the first coil-shaped portion is provided with a first saturated core and the second coil-shaped portion is provided with a second saturated core.
</P>
<P>
15. An apparatus according to claim 14, wherein at least one of the first saturated core and the second saturated core includes a ferromagnetic material of a group comprising a nanocrystal alloy.
</P>
<P>
16. An apparatus according to claim 15, wherein the nanocyrstal alloy is METGLAS or a ferrite.
</P>
<P>
17. An apparatus according to claim 15, wherein at least one of the first high inductance unit and the second high inductance unit is configured to provide an inductance of 0.01-10 mH.
</P>
<P>
18. An apparatus according to claim 12, wherein the material includes a group of elements comprising tin, indium, gallium and/or lithium.
</P>
<P>
19. An apparatus according to claim 10, further comprising: a reservoir configured to collect the jet of the material at a position at which the jet has disintegrated in droplets.
</P>
<P>
20. An apparatus according to claim 10, wherein the apparatus further comprises a reservoir configured to collect the jet of the material and a feedback system configured to feedback the material collected in the reservoir towards the first feeding line, the feedback system comprising a melt chamber connected to the reservoir configured to melt the material collected to form a melt of the certain material; a filter connected to the first feeding line configured to filter contamination from the melt of the material; and a pump configured to pump the melt from the melt chamber towards the filter.
</P>
<P>
21. An apparatus according to claim 20, wherein the reservoir comprises a first collecting unit configured to collect the material of the jet corresponding to the first electrode, the apparatus further being provided with a third high inductance unit in a first feedback line between the reservoir and the feedback system.
</P>
<P>
22. An apparatus according to claim 21, wherein the third high inductance unit comprises a third coil-shaped portion in the first feedback line.
</P>
<P>
23. An apparatus according to claim 22, wherein the third coil-shaped portion is provided with a third saturated core.
</P>
<P>
24. An apparatus according to claim 23, wherein the third saturated core includes a ferromagnetic material of a group comprising a nanocrystal alloy.
</P>
<P>
25. An apparatus according to claim 24, wherein the nanocrystal allow is METGLAS or a ferrite.
</P>
<P>
26. An apparatus according to claim 23, wherein the third high inductance unit is configured to provide an inductance of O.01-10 mH.
</P>
<P>
27. An apparatus according to claim 12, further comprising: a first reservoir configured to collect the first jet of the certain material; a second reservoir configured to collect the second jet of the certain material; and a feedback system connected to the first reservoir via a first feedback line and to the second reservoir via a second feedback line, the feedback system being configured to feedback the certain material collected in the first and second reservoir towards the first feeding line and/or the second feeding line, the feedback system comprising melt chamber connected to the first and second reservoir configured to melt the material as respectively collected to form a melt of the certain material; a filter connected to the first feeding line and/or the second feeding line configured to filter contamination from the melt of the material; and a pump configured to pump the melt from the melt chamber towards the filter, wherein the apparatus is further provided with a third high inductance unit downstream the first reservoir in the first feedback line and a fourth high inductance unit downstream the second reservoir in the second feedback line.
</P>
<P>
28. An apparatus according to claim 27, wherein the third high inductance unit comprises a third coil-shaped portion in the first feedback line, and the fourth high inductance unit comprises a fourth coil-shaped portion in the second feedback line.
</P>
<P>
29. An apparatus according to claim 28, wherein the third coil-shaped portion is provided with a third saturated core, and the fourth coil-shaped portion is provided with a fourth saturated core.
</P>
<P>
30. An apparatus according to claim 29, wherein at least one of the third saturated core and the fourth saturated core includes a ferromagnetic material of a group comprising a nanocrystal alloy.
</P>
<P>
31. An apparatus according to claim 30, wherein the nanocrystal alloy is METGLAS or a ferrite.
</P>
<P>
32. An apparatus according to claim 29, wherein at least one of the third high inductance unit and the fourth high inductance unit is configured to provide an inductance of 0.01-10 mH.
</P>
<P>
33. A lithographic apparatus, comprising: an illumination system configured to condition a radiation beam; a support configured to support a patterning device, the patterning device being configured to impart the radiation beam with a pattern in its cross-section to form a patterned radiation beam; a substrate table configured to hold a substrate; and a projection system configured to project the patterned radiation beam onto a target portion of the substrate, wherein the illumination system comprises an apparatus for producing radiation by an electrically operated discharge, the apparatus comprising a first electrode and a second electrode, the first and second electrode being configured at a distance from each other which allows ignition of a plasma in a gaseous medium between the first and second electrode; a capacitor bank electrically connected at a first terminal to the first electrode and at a second terminal to the second electrode, the capacitor bank configured to store a discharge energy needed for the ignition of the plasma, the first electrode, second electrode and capacitor bank forming an electric circuit, wherein at least the first electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a first feeding line, the apparatus further comprising a charger connected to the first terminal and/or the second terminal configured to charge the capacitor bank in a time varying manner; and a first high inductance unit provided upstream of the first terminal in the first feeding line configured to electrically decouple the electric circuit.
</P>
<P>
34. An apparatus for producing radiation by an electrically operated discharge comprising: a first electrode and a second electrode, the first and second electrode being configured at a distance from each other which allows ignition of a plasma in a gaseous medium between the first and second electrode; a capacitor bank electrically connected at a first terminal to the first electrode and at a second terminal to the second electrode, the capacitor bank configured to store a discharge energy needed for the ignition of the plasma, the first electrode, second electrode and capacitor bank forming an electric circuit, wherein the first electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a first feeding line, and the second electrode is formed by electrically conducting fluid supplied via a second feeding line, the first feeding line comprising a first nozzle configured to provide the first electrode in the form of a first jet of a material and the second feeding line comprising a second nozzle configured to provide the second electrode in the form of a second jet of a material, the apparatus further comprising: a charger configured to charge the capacitor bank in a time varying manner; a first high inductance unit provided upstream the first terminal in the first feeding line, the first high inductance unit comprising a first coil-shaped portion of the first feeding line; a second high inductance unit provided upstream the second terminal in the second feeding line, the second high inductance unit comprising a second coil-shaped portion of the second feeding line.
</P>
<P>
35. An apparatus according to claim 34, wherein the radiation is EUV radiation.
</P>
<P>
36. An apparatus according to claim 34, wherein the charger is a pulsed charger.
</P>
<P>
37. An apparatus according to claim 34, wherein the first coil-shaped portion and/or the second coil-shaped portion is provided with a saturated core.
</P>
<P>
38. An apparatus according to claim 37, wherein the saturated core includes a ferromagnetic material from a group comprising a nanocrystal alloy.
</P>
<P>
39. An apparatus according to claim 38, wherein th nanocrystal alloy is METGLAS or a ferrite.
</P>
<P>
40. An apparatus according to claim 37, wherein the first high inductance unit and/or second high inductance unit is configured to provide an inductance of 0.01-10 mH.
</P>
<P>
41. A device manufacturing method, comprising: providing radiation from a radiation source configured to produce radiation by an electrically operated discharge, the radiation source comprising a first electrode and a second electrode, the first and second electrode being configured at a distance from each other which allows ignition of a plasma in a gaseous medium between the first and second electrode; a capacitor bank electrically connected at a first terminal to the first electrode and at a second terminal to the second electrode, the capacitor bank configured to store a discharge energy needed for the ignition of the plasma, the first electrode, second electrode and capacitor bank forming an electric circuit, wherein at least the first electrode is formed by an electrically conducting fluid supplied via a first feeding line, the apparatus further comprising a charger connected to the first terminal and/or the second terminal configured to charge the capacitor bank in a time varying manner; and a first high inductance unit provided upstream of the first terminal in the first feeding line for electrically decoupling the electric circuit; conditioning a beam of radiation from the radiation; patterning the beam of radiation; and projecting the patterned beam of radiation onto a target portion of a substrate.
</P>
<P>
42. A device manufactured by the method of claim 41.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2014141B1;WO2007129891A1;US2008067453A1;US7557366B2;TW200807165A;KR20090006166A;KR101023797B1;JP2009535839A;CN101438631A;CN101438631B;AT547924T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
