<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
OPTICAL NANOMATERIAL COMPOSITIONS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2057211A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ROZHIN OLEKSIY [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
FERRARI ANDREA [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
MILNE WILLIAM IRELAND [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
ROZHIN, OLEKSIY
</Name>
<Name>
FERRARI, ANDREA
</Name>
<Name>
MILNE, WILLIAM IRELAND
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CAMBRIDGE ENTPR LTD [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
CAMBRIDGE ENTERPRISE LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2057211
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070804056
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007GB03239
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060513484
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09J11/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09J9/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C09J11/04
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides compositions (&quot;Optical Nanomaterial Compositions&quot;) comprising one or more nanomaterials and an optical coupling gel or an optical adhesive. The invention also provides methods for using the Optical Nanomaterial Compositions as an index-matching gel, an optical adhesive or an optical film, all of which are suitable for optical and sensing devices applications, including but not limited to noise suppression, passive Q-switching, mode-locking, waveform shaping, optical switching, optical signal regeneration, phase conjugation, in filter devices, dispersion compensation, wavelength conversion, soliton stabilization, microcavity applications, in interferometers (such as the Gires-Tournois interferometer), optical, magneto-optical or electro-optical modulation, biochemical sensors and photodetectors.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS :
</P>
<P>
1. A composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) one or more nanomaterials; and (b) an optical coupling gel or an optical adhesive.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition of claim 1, wherein the composition comprises the optical coupling gel.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition of claim 1, wherein the composition comprises the optical adhesive.
</P>
<P>
4. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the nanomaterial is randomly oriented in the optical material.
</P>
<P>
5. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the nanomaterial is in a regularly oriented array in the optical material .
</P>
<P>
6. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the one or more nanomaterials have at least one dimension in the size ranging from about 0.1 nm to about 500 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. The composition of claim 6, wherein the one or more nanomaterials have at least one dimension in the size ranging from about 0.5 nm to about 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
8. The composition of claim 6, wherein the nanomaterials have lengths of from about 0.01 [mu]m to about 10 mm.
</P>
<P>
9. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein the one or more nanomaterials comprise nanomaterials purified from impurities .
</P>
<P>
10. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein the nanomaterials comprise chemically or physically functionalized nanomaterials.
</P>
<P>
11. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein the nanomaterial is selected from a group consisting of Au, Ag, Pt, Pd, Ni, Co, Ti, Mo, W, Mn, Ir, Cr, Fe, C, Si, Ge, B, Sn, SiGe, SiC, SiSn, GeC, BN, InP, InN, InAs, InSb, GaN, GaP, GaAs, GaSb, AlN, AlP, AlAs, AlSb, CdO, CdS, CdSe, CdTe, ZnO, ZnS, ZnSe, ZnTe, MgO, MgS, MgSe, MgTe, HgO, HgS, HgSe, HgTe, PbO, PbS, PbSe, PbTe, GeS, GeSe, GeTe, SnS, SnSe, SnTe, InO, SnO, GeO, WO, TiO, FeO, MnO, CoO, NiO, CrO, VO, CuSn, CuF, CuCl, CuBr, CuI, AgF, AgCl, AgBr, AgI, CaCN2, BeSiN2, ZnGeP2, CdSnAs2, ZnSnSb2, CuGeP3, CuSi2P3, Si3N4, Ge3N4, Al2O3, Al2CO, Inx0y, SnxOy, SiOx, GeOx, Wx0y, TixOy, Fex0y, Mnx0y, Cox0y, NixOy, CrxOy, Vx0y, MSiO4, any alloys thereof, and any combinations thereof, wherein x is an integer ranging from 1 to 5, y is an integer ranging from 1 to 5, and M is selected from Zn, Cr, Fe, Mn, Co, Ni, V, and Ti.
</P>
<P>
12. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein the one or more nanomaterials is selected from a group consisting of at least one nanotube, nanowire, nanodot, quantum dot, nanorod, nanocrystal, nanotetrapod, nanotripod, nanobipod, nanoparticle, nanosaw, nanospring, nanoribbon, and branched nanomaterial.
</P>
<P>
13. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the nanomaterial comprises at least one nanotube .
</P>
<P>
14. The composition of claim 13, wherein the at least one nanotube comprises at least one single-walled carbon nanotube .
</P>
<P>
15. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 14, further comprising an additional type of nanomaterial.
</P>
<P>
16. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 15, wherein the concentration of nanomaterial in the composition is from about 0.0001 % to about 50 % by total weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
17. The composition of any one of claims 1 to 15, wherein the concentration of nanomaterial in the composition is from about 0.01 % to about 20 % by total weight of the composition .
</P>
<P>
18. A device comprising the composition of any one of claims 1 to 17.
</P>
<P>
19. The device of claim 18, wherein the device is an optical device or a sensor device.
</P>
<P>
20. The device of claim 19, wherein the device is a nonlinear optical device.
</P>
<P>
21. The device of any one of claims 18 to 20, wherein the composition is in the form of a film.
</P>
<P>
22. The device of claim 21, further comprising a quartz, a glass, or a mirror substrate.
</P>
<P>
23. The device of any one of claims 18 to 22, wherein the device is a lens, a prism, a polarization plate, a fiber end, a fiber surface, a waveguide facet, a waveguide surface, or a laser material surface.
</P>
<P>
24. The device of any one of claims 18 to 20, wherein the composition is in the form of a liquid.
</P>
<P>
25. An index-matching gel comprising the composition of any one of claims 1 to 17.
</P>
<P>
26. An optical adhesive comprising the composition of any one of claims 1 to 17.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008025966A1;US2011163280A1;US2010002324A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
