<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ORGANIZED CARBON AND NON- CARBON ASSEMBLY AND METHODS OF MAKING
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2024282A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GRIGORIAN LEONID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
COLBERN STEVEN G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOSER ALEX E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GUMP ROBERT L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NIEBAUER DANIEL A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BRAHIM SEAN IMTIAZ [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GRIGORIAN, LEONID
</Name>
<Name>
COLBERN, STEVEN G
</Name>
<Name>
MOSER, ALEX E
</Name>
<Name>
GUMP, ROBERT L
</Name>
<Name>
NIEBAUER, DANIEL A
</Name>
<Name>
BRAHIM, SEAN IMTIAZ
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
YAZAKI CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAZAKI CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2024282
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070761494
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-04-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US67672
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060796399P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060808096P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060842281P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060842543P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-06
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060874876P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D10
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B6
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
This invention relates generally to organized assemblies of carbon and non-carbon compounds and methods of making such organized structures. In preferred embodiments, the organized structures of the instant invention take the form of nanorods or their aggregate forms. More preferably, a nanorod is made up of a carbon nanotube filled, coated, or both filled and coated by a non-carbon material. This invention is further drawn to the separation of single-wall carbon nanotubes. In particular, it relates to the separation of semiconducting single-wall carbon nanotubes from conducting (or metallic) single-wall carbon nanotubes. It also relates to the separation of single-wall carbon nanotubes according to their chirality and/or diameter.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED:
</P>
<P>
] . An organized carbon and non-carbon assembly comprising a carbon nanotube filled with a titanium compound and substantially free of titanium carbide. 2. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1, wherein the titanium compound has a formula of TiHwBxNyOz, where w varies in the range of 0 to 2, x varies in the range of 0 to 2, y varies in the range of 0 to 1, and z varies in the range of O to 2.
</P>
<P>
3. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1, wherein the titanium compound fills at least about 0,10 weight percent of the organized assembly,
</P>
<P>
4. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1, wherein the titanium compound flils at least about 1.00 weight percent of the organized assembly.
</P>
<P>
5. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1 , wherein the titanium compound fills at least about 4.00 weight percent of the organized assembly. 6. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1, wherein the amount of titanium carbide is less than about I O volume percent of the core volume of the carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
7. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1, wherein the amount of titanium carbide is less than about 1 volume percent of the core volume of the carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
8. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly of claim 1, wherein the amount of titanium carbide is less than about 0.1 volume percent of the core volume of the carbon nanotube core.
</P>
<P>
9. A method for preparing an organized carbon and non-carbon assembly comprising the steps of: reacting a carbon nanotube precursor with a halogenated precursor to form a halogenated intermediate wherein the halogenated precursor comprises a halogenated compound and a halogen, and removing the halogen from the halogenated intermediate to obtain an organized carbon and non-carbon assembly.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9, wherein the halogenated compound comprises titanium iodide.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The method of claim 9, wherein the halogen comprises iodine.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of ciaim 9, wherein the halogen comprises bromine. 13. The method of claim 9, wherein the step of reacting a carbon nanotube precursor and a halogenated precursor is carried out at or above the temperature where the halogenated precursor forms a liquid.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 9, wherein the step of removing the halogen from the halogenated intermediate is carried out in a gas mixture comprising hydrogen. 15. The method of claim 9, wherein the step of removing the halogen from the halogenated intermediate is carried out below atmospheric pressure.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 9, where the method further comprises the step of selecting the carbon nanotube precursor or the halogenated precursor such that the inner diameters of carbon nanotubes are larger than the diameter of the halogenated compound. 17. The method of claim 9, wherein the method further comprises washing the organized carbon and non-carbon assembly with a solvent.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 9, wherein the method further comprises the step of selecting the carbon nanotube precursor or the halogenated precursor such that the inner diameters of carbon nanotubes are smaller than the diameter of the halogenated compound. 19. The organized assembly of the carbon and non-carbon material prepared by the method of claim 9.
</P>
<P>
20. A method for growing an organized assembly carbon and the non-carbon comprising the steps of: selecting a substrate, depositing a metal-layer on the substrate, and growing the organized assembly of the carbon and the non-carbon material on the metal-layer in an environment containing an alcohol.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 20, wherein the substrate comprises silicon.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 20, wherein the substrate comprises glass.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 20, wherein the metal-layer comprises titanium nitride.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 20, wherein the alcohol comprises ethanol.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 20, wherein the environment further comprises hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 20, wherein the method further comprises depositing a catalyst- layer on the metal-layer.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 26, wherein the catalyst-layer comprises iron.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 26, wherein the method further comprises heat treating the catalyst-layer in an environment comprising hydrogen but not any alcohol.
</P>
<P>
29. The organized carbon and non-carbon assembly as prepared by the method of claim 20.
</P>
<P>
30. A method for separating single-wall carbon nanotubes comprising the steps of: halogenating a starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes by incorporating the starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes with a halogen to form halogenated single-wail carbon nanotubes, dispersing said halogenaled single-wall carbon nanotubes in a medium to form dispersed single-wall carbon nanotubes, and centrifuging said dispersed single-wall carbon nanotubes to obtain a supernatant and a precipitate phase.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 30, wherein the halogen comprises iodine. 32. The method of claim 30, wherein the halogen comprises bromine.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 30, wherein the halogenation step further comprises soaking the starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes in the molten form of the halogen.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 30, wherein the halogenation step is carried out at a temperature equal to or higher than the melting point of the halogen. 35. The method of claim 30, wherein the method further comprises heat treating of the halogenated single-wall carbon nanotubes after the halogenation step.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of claim 30, wherein the dispersion step further comprises using an ionic or nonionic surfactant.
</P>
<P>
37. The method of claim 30, wherein the dispersion step further comprises high shear processing of the single wali carbon nanotubes,
</P>
<P>
38. The method of ciaim 30, wherein the medium is substantially water.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of ciaim 30, wherein the centrifugation step further comprises centrifuging at a centrifugal force higher than about 10,000 g.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of claim 30, wherein the method further comprises evaporation of the medium.
</P>
<P>
41. The method of claim 30, wherein the method further comprises treatment below atmospheric pressure. 42. The method of ciaim 30, wherein the method further comprises a sonication step.
</P>
<P>
43. The method of claim 30, wherein more than about 85% of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the supernatant have a diameter larger than a predetermined size.
</P>
<P>
44. The method of ciaim 30, wherein more than about 95% of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the supernatant have a diameter larger than a predetermined size. 45. The method of claim 30, wherein the enrichment of a population of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the supernatant is a factor of at least about 2.0 compared to the precipitate phase.
</P>
<P>
46. The method of claim 30, wherein the enrichment of a population of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the supernatant is a factor of at least about 3.0 compared to the precipitate phase.
</P>
<P>
47. The method of claim 30, wherein the enrichment of a population of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the supernatant is a factor of at least about 3.0 compared to the starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
48. The method of claim 30, wherein the enrichment of a population of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the supernatant is a factor of at least about 4.0 compared to the starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
49. The method of claim 30, wherein the enrichment of a population of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the precipitate phase is a factor of at least about 2.0 compared to the starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
50. The method of claim 30, wherein the enrichment of a population of the single-wall carbon nanotubes in the precipitate phase is a factor of at least about 3.0 compared to the starting form of single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
51. The method of claim 30, wherein the incorporation involves preferentially intercalating the cores of the single-wall carbon nanotubes by the halogen.
</P>
<P>
52. The supernatant phase as prepared by the method of claim 30.
</P>
<P>
53. The precipitate phase as prepared by the method of claim 30.
</P>
<P>
54. The enriched population of single wall carbon nanotubes as prepared by the method of claim 30.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007130869A2;WO2007130869A3;US2011183139A1;US2010117032A1;US7938987B2;JP2009535294A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
