<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
IMPROVEMENTS RELATING TO ELECTRO- OPTIC WINDOWS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2095160A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DUNLEAVY MICHAEL [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
HAQ SAJAD [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
DAVIES JOSEPH MAURICE [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
FINN HARRY JOHN [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
DUNLEAVY, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
HAQ, SAJAD
</Name>
<Name>
DAVIES, JOSEPH MAURICE
</Name>
<Name>
FINN, HARRY JOHN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BAE SYSTEMS PLC [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
BAE SYSTEMS PLC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2095160
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070824955
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007GB50746
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20060024804
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-13
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060256352
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-13
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070824955
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
F42B15/34
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/20
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An electro-optic window (1200) is made of a material substantially transparent to infra-red radiation and is treated to have reduced RF transmission characteristics by the provision of carbon nanotubes within the window or on at least one surface thereof.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. An electro-optic window made of a material substantially transparent to at least one of infra-red and visible radiation and treated to have reduced RF transmission characteristics by the provision of carbon nanotubes within the window or on at least one surface thereof.
</P>
<P>
2. An electro-optic window according to Claim 1 , wherein said carbon nanotubes are provided as a layer on one surface of the window.
</P>
<P>
3. An electro-optic window according to Claim 2, wherein said layer of carbon nanotubes has a mat structure.
</P>
<P>
4. An electro-optic window according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, wherein said layer includes an array of holes.
</P>
<P>
5. An electro-optic window according to Claim 4, wherein said holes are formed by laser drilling. 6. An electro-optic window according to Claim 1 , wherein said carbon nanotubes are incorporated into a film applied to a surface of said material transparent to infra-red and/or visible radiation, said film comprising a polymer material incorporating said carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
7. An electro-optic window according to Claim 1 , wherein said carbon nanotubes are incorporated into the material transparent to infra-red and/or visible radiation during formation of the window.
</P>
<P>
8. An electro-optic window according to any of the preceding Claims, wherein said material transparent to infra-red and/or visible radiation comprises a crystalline material.
</P>
<P>
9. An electro-optic window according to any of Claims 1 to 8, wherein said material substantially transparent to radiation comprises a glass material.
</P>
<P>
10. A method of making an electro-optic window which comprises providing a distribution of carbon nanotubes within the window or on at least one surface thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to Claim 10, which includes a step of providing a mat made of carbon nanotubes, and bonding said mat to the surface of the window.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to Claim 11 , wherein said mat is provided with an array of holes to increase the IR transmission characteristics thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to Claim 12, wherein said holes are formed by laser drilling.
</P>
<P>
14. A method according to Claim 10, wherein said distribution is provided by applying a dryable or curable liquid carrier containing a dispersion of carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to Claim 14, wherein said liquid carrier is applied by spraying, optionally through a mask.
</P>
<P>
16. A method according to Claim 14, wherein said liquid carrier is applied to said window using a spin-on process. 17. A method according to Claim 10, which comprises providing a window precursor material in particulate form and dispersing carbon nanotubes within said window precursor material to form a composite material.
</P>
<P>
18. A method according to Claim 17, wherein said window precursor material particles are substantially mono-disperse.
</P>
<P>
19. A method according to Claim 18, which includes the step of providing said particulate window material in colloidal form and dispersing carbon nanotubes in said colloid, and thereafter drying said colloid.
</P>
<P>
20. A method according to Claim 19, which includes applying elevated pressure and temperature to said dried colloid to form said window.
</P>
<P>
21. A method according to Claim 10, which includes the step of dispersing said nanotubes in a resin or polymer and thereafter applying said polymer to the surface of a window material.
</P>
<P>
22. A method according to Claim 17, wherein said carbon nanotubes are initially coated with said window material.
</P>
<P>
23. A method according to Claim 10, which includes the step of depositing nanotubes onto an electro-optic window by chemical vapour deposition.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008072010A1;US2010079842A1;US7948674B2;JP2010514149A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
