<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CHUCKING SYSTEM COMPRISING AN ARRAY OF FLUID CHAMBERS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2007566A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHERALA ANSHUMAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI BYUNG-JIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LAD PANKAJ B [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SHACKLETON STEVEN C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHERALA, ANSHUMAN
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI, BYUNG-JIN
</Name>
<Name>
LAD, PANKAJ, B
</Name>
<Name>
SHACKLETON, STEVEN, C
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2007566
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070754062
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US07487
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060788777P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L21/683
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/67S2V
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/683V
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention is directed towards a chucking system to hold a substrate, said system including, inter alia, a chuck body having first and second opposed sides, said first side including an array of fluid chambers arranged in rows and columns, said fluid chambers each comprising first and second spaced-apart recesses defining first and second spaced-apart support regions, with said first support region cincturing said second support region and said first and second recesses, and said second support region cincturing said second recess, with said substrate resting against said first and second support regions, with said first recess and a portion of said substrate in superimposition therewith defining a first chamber and said second recess and a portion of said substrate in superimposition therewith defining a second chamber,;  with each column of said first chambers and each row of said second chambers being in fluid communication with a differing source of fluid to control a flow of fluid in said array of fluid chambers.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A chucking system to hold a substrate, said system comprising: a chuck body having first and second opposed sides, said first side including a fluid chamber, said fluid chamber comprising first and second spaced-apart recesses, defining first and second spaced-apart support regions, with said first support region cincturing said second support region and said first and second recesses, and said second support region cincturing said second recess, with said substrate resting against said first and second support regions, with said first recess and a portion of said substrate in superimposition therewith defining a first chamber and said second recess and a portion of said substrate in superimposition therewith defining a second chamber; with said first chamber and said second chamber being in fluid communication with a differing source of fluid to control a flow of fluid in said fluid chambers.
</P>
<P>
2. The chucking system as recited in claim 1, further comprising: a pressure control system in fluid communication with said first and second chambers to control a pressure within said first and second chambers such that one of said first and second chambers has a positive pressure therein and the remaining chamber of said first and second chambers has a negative pressure therein, wherein for a given positive pressure within one of said first and second chambers and a negative pressure within the remaining chamber of said first and second chambers, a ratio of an area between said first and second recesses is such that said fluid chamber exerts a negative force upon a portion of said substrate in superimposition with said fluid chamber.
</P>
<P>
3. The chucking system as recited in claim 1 or 2 further including a plurality of fluid chambers.
</P>
<P>
4. The chucking system as recited in claim 1 , 2 or 3 further including a first and second throughways to place said first and second chambers, respectively, in fluid communication with said pressure control system.
</P>
<P>
5. The chucking system as recited in any of the preceding claims wherein said pressure control system comprises a plurality of sources of fluid.
</P>
<P>
6. The chucking system as recited in any of the preceding claims said system further including an array of fluid chambers arranged in rows and columns, with each column of said first chambers and each row of said second chambers are in fluid communication with a differing source of fluid of said plurality of sources of fluid to control a flow of fluid in said array of fluid chambers.
</P>
<P>
7. The chucking system as recited in claim 6 wherein each first chamber in a column of said fluid chambers is in fluid communication with a common fluid source.
</P>
<P>
8. The chucking system as recited in claim 6 wherein each second chamber in a row of said fluid chambers is in fluid communication with a common fluid source.
</P>
<P>
9. The chucking system as recited in claim 6 wherein each first chamber in a column of said fluid chambers is in fluid communication with a first common fluid source and wherein each second chamber in a row of said fluid chambers is in fluid communication with a second common fluid source differing from said first common fluid source.
</P>
<P>
10. The chucking system as recited in claim 6 wherein a fluid chamber of said array of fluid chambers is sealed from the remaining fluid chambers of said array of fluid chambers.
</P>
<P>
11. The chucking system as recited in claim 6 further including a plurality of throughways, with each column of said first chambers and each row of said second chambers being coupled to differing throughways to place said first and second chambers in fluid communication with said differing source of fluid.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2007566A4;WO2007126767A2;WO2007126767A3;TW200813619A;KR20090004910A;JP2011077529A;JP2009532899A;CN101415535A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
