<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POROUS TITANIUM OXIDE AND METHOD FOR PRODUCING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2067747A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WADA MASAYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIO SHOICHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
WADA, MASAYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
SHIO, SHOICHIRO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SHISEIDO CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHISEIDO COMPANY, LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2067747
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070807742
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP68410
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060263832
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q17/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q1/02
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q1/12
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D8
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a porous titanium oxide having improved ultraviolet protection ability, usability, and transparency in the visible region and a process for producing thereof. The porous titanium oxide powder according to the present invention can be obtained by adding an alkali to a titanium salt solution containing a polyalcohol and then thermally hydrolyzing the solution. In addition, it is possible that after the addition of the alkali, an acid is further added to the solution and then the thermal hydrolysis is conducted, or that after thermal hydrolysis, further heat treatment with an acid is conducted. A porous titanium oxide has a mean particle size of 0.01 to 1.0 [mu]m and a specific surface area of 50 m 2 /g or more.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for producing a porous titanium oxide comprising steps of:
</P>
<P>
adding an alkali to a titanium salt solution containing a polyalcohol; and
</P>
<P>
thermally hydrolyzing the solution.
</P>
<P>
2. The process according to claim 1, wherein after the alkali is added to the titanium salt solution, an acid is further added thereto and then the solution is thermally hydrolyzed.
</P>
<P>
3. The process according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the molar ratio of the amount of the alkali added with respect to that of the titanium salt is 0.1:1 to 1:1.
</P>
<P>
4. The process according to claim 2 or 3, wherein the molar ratio of the amount of the acid added with respect to that of the titanium salt is 0.1:1 to 1:1.
</P>
<P>
5. The process according to any of claims 1 to 4, wherein after the thermal hydrolysis, a heat treatment with an acid is further conducted.
</P>
<P>
6. The process according to any of claims 1 to 5, wherein the molar ratio of the amount of the polyalcohol to that of the titanium salt is 0.1: 1 to 5:1.
</P>
<P>
7. A porous titanium oxide, which is obtained by any of the processes according to claims 1 to 6, and has a mean particle size of 0.01 to 1.0 [micro]m and a specific surface area of 50 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g or more.
</P>
<P>
8. A cosmetic preparation, comprising the porous titanium oxide according to claim 7.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2067747A4;US2010009192A1;US8168145B2;KR20090064550A;WO2008038592A1;JP2008081366A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
