<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOWIRE ON NON- SINGLE CRYSTAL SUBSTRATE FOR OPTOELECTRONIC APPLICATIONS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2020034A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WANG SHIH-YUAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KOBAYASHI NOBUHIKO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WANG, SHIH-YUAN
</Name>
<Name>
KOBAYASHI, NOBUHIKO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HEWLETT PACKARD DEVELOPMENT CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HEWLETT-PACKARD DEVELOPMENT COMPANY, L.P
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2020034
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070874436
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US12273
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060439011
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-22
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L29/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0352
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0352B
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/08
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
One embodiment in accordance with the invention is an apparatus that can include a non-single crystal substrate and a nanowire grown from a surface of the non-single crystal substrate. Furthermore, the apparatus can also include an electrode coupled to the nanowire. It is noted that the nanowire can be electrically conductive and/or optically active.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. An apparatus comprising:
</P>
<P>
a non-single crystal substrate;
</P>
<P>
a nanowire grown from a surface of said non-single crystal substrate; and
</P>
<P>
an electrode coupled to said nanowire, wherein said nanowire is electrically conductive or optically active.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein said nanowire is for emitting electromagnetic wave.
</P>
<P>
3. The apparatus of claim 2, wherein a display device comprises said apparatus.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein said nanowire is for absorbing electromagnetic wave and generating a current.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein a solar cell comprises said apparatus.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein said non-single crystal substrate comprises polycrystalline silicon.
</P>
<P>
7. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein said non-single crystal substrate comprises amorphous silicon.
</P>
<P>
8. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein said non-single crystal substrate comprises microcrystalline silicon.
</P>
<P>
9. An apparatus comprising:
</P>
<P>
a non-single crystal substrate comprising:
</P>
<P>
a first protruding portion; and
</P>
<P>
a second protruding portion; and
</P>
<P>
a nanowire grown from said first protruding portion and coupled to said second protruding portion.
</P>
<P>
10. The apparatus of claim 9, wherein said nanowire is for emitting light.
</P>
<P>
11. The apparatus of claim 9, wherein said nanowire is for absorbing electromagnetic wave and generating a current.
</P>
<P>
12. The apparatus of claim 9, wherein said first protruding portion comprises a material selected from the group consisting of polycrystalline silicon, amorphous silicon, poly-crystal diamond and related carbon-based materials, and microcrystalline silicon.
</P>
<P>
13. The apparatus of claim 9, wherein said non-single crystal substrate comprises a material selected from the group consisting of glass, quartz, Mylar, steel, metal, plastic, and stainless steel.
</P>
<P>
14. The apparatus of claim 9, wherein said apparatus is incorporated with a device selected from the group consisting of a display and a solar cell.
</P>
<P>
15. A method for fabricating an apparatus, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
disposing a nanowire above a non-single crystal substrate; and
</P>
<P>
coupling an electrode to said nanowire for conducting current.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 15, wherein said nanowire is for emitting light.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 15, wherein said nanowire is for absorbing electromagnetic wave and generating a current.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 15, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
disposing an insulating material above said non-single crystal substrate.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 15, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
disposing a material above said non-single crystal substrate, said material selected from the group consisting of polycrystalline silicon, poly-crystal diamond and related carbon-based materials, amorphous silicon, and microcrystalline silicon,
</P>
<P>
wherein said nanowire is disposed above said material.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 15, wherein said nanowire comprises a material selected from the group consisting of a metal, a group III-V compound semiconductor material and related alloys, a group II-VI compound semiconductor material and related alloys, and a group IV semiconductor material and related alloys.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 15, wherein said apparatus is incorporated with a device selected from the group consisting of a display, a radiation detector, and a solar cell.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 15, wherein said disposing comprises disposing a plurality of nanowires above said non-single crystal substrate, wherein each of said plurality of nanowires has a random orientation.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007267625A1;US7741647B2;WO2008115191A2;WO2008115191A3;US2011023948A1;JP2009538533A;CN101553934A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
