<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ATOMIC FORCE MICROSCOPE TIP ARRAYS AND METHODS OF MANUFACTURING SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2013609A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RUBY BRIAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PATTERSON RANDEN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RUBY, BRIAN
</Name>
<Name>
PATTERSON, RANDEN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CARBON NANOPROBES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CARBON NANOPROBES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2013609
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060848402
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US49701
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050755495P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N23/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/38
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/42
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q70/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/38
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/42
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q70/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q70/12
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides methods and apparatus for forming an array of multiple nanotube tips that can be utilized with AFM technology. The multiprobe tips may be independently modified or specifically left unmodified. Software can generate a composite image of data collected from two or more of the independently modified and unmodified tips.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. An apparatus for biological interrogations, the apparatus comprising: an atomic force microscope chip; and an array of two or more nanostructure tips operatively attached to the atomic force microscope chip, wherein at least one carbon nanotube tip in the array is not chemically modified and one or more carbon nanotube tips in the array are chemically modified.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the nanostructure comprises a carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
3. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the modified nanostructure tip is modified with a predetermined ligand.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 3 additionally comprising a microwell for containing the ligand with which the nanostructure tip is modified.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 4 additionally comprising a laser element operative to track cantilever movement and a laser control operative to generate positional data.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 5 additionally comprising a microfluidic channel for conducting a fluid used to modify a nanostructure tip to a corresponding microwell.
</P>
<P>
7. The apparatus of claim 5 additionally comprising: a support substrate supporting an alignment apparatus for aligning the array of probes with corresponding microwells; and a stage supporting the substrate and operative to impart axis motion to the substrate.
</P>
<P>
8. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein at least two of the carbon nanotube tips are chemically modified , each modified nanostructure modified with a different chemical.
</P>
<P>
9. The apparatus of claim 8 wherein each nanostructure tip has a different purpose than the other carbon nanotube tips.
</P>
<P>
10. The apparatus of claim 2 wherein one or more probes are suitable for measuring one or more of ligand-receptor binding affinity and active site recognition of biological samples
</P>
<P>
11. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the nanostructure tips additionally comprise an insulating dielectric coating.
</P>
<P>
12. A device for selectively and simultaneously, chemically modifying an array of atomic force microscope tips, the device comprising: a microwell corresponding with each of the respective atomic microscope tips; a macrowell corresponding with each of the respective microwells and disparate fluids for modifying the respective atomic force microscope tips; and a microfluidic channel providing fluid communication between the macrowell and the microwell.
</P>
<P>
13. The device in claim 12, additionally comprising a dry microwell without fluid communication to a microchannel.
</P>
<P>
14. The device in claim 12, whereby chemicals can be combined in the macrowell and selectively delivered to a corresponding atomic microscope tip.
</P>
<P>
15. An apparatus for conducting biological testing, the apparatus comprising: an array of carbon nanostructure tips comprising an atomic force microscope probe array; microfluidic devices for selectively modifying the carbon nanostructure tips; an atomic force microscope operatively connected to the atomic force microscope probe; and an imaging device in communication with the atomic force microscope to receive data generated by the atomic force microscope based upon input received from the array of carbon nanostructure tips and provide a visual representation of the data.
</P>
<P>
16. The device of claim 15 additionally comprising a processor operative with executable software to generate one or both of: a predictive model and a bioinformatics model.
</P>
<P>
17. The device of claim 16 wherein the executable software is additionally operative to execute an implementation of the Gestalt algorithm.
</P>
<P>
18. The device of claim 16 wherein the executable software is additionally operative to execute one or more of: implement X-ray crystallography and process x-ray crystallographic data.
</P>
<P>
19. The device of claim 16 wherein the executable software is additionally operative to execute an implementation of one or more of: nuclear magnetic resonance and magnetic resonance imaging.
</P>
<P>
20. The device of claim 16 wherein the executable software is additionally operative to receive input from the atomic microscope probe array comprising: at least one unmodified probe tip; and at least one chemically modified probe tip, and create a composite image of the data collected from the at least one chemically modified probe tip and at least one unmodified probe tip.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007079269A2;WO2007079269A3;US2007261480A1;US7775088B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
