<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOPARTICLE COUPLED TO WAVEGUIDE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2022145A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SANTORI CHARLES [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SPILLANE SEAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BEAUSOLEIL RAYMOND [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FIORENTINO MARCO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SANTORI, CHARLES
</Name>
<Name>
SPILLANE, SEAN
</Name>
<Name>
BEAUSOLEIL, RAYMOND
</Name>
<Name>
FIORENTINO, MARCO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HEWLETT PACKARD DEVELOPMENT CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HEWLETT-PACKARD DEVELOPMENT COMPANY, L.P
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2022145
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070777226
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US12242
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060444222
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01S5/34
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/02N
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/42C2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanoparticle (110) is able to emit a single photons. A waveguide (150) is coupled to the nanoparticle (110) and able to receive the single photons. A backreflector (130) is optically coupled to the waveguide (150) and configured to reflect the single photons toward the waveguide (150).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A device comprising: a nanoparticle able to emit single photons; . a waveguide coupled to the nanoparticle and able to receive the single photons; and a backreflector optically coupled to the waveguide and configured to reflect the single photons toward the waveguide.
</P>
<P>
2. The device as set forth in claim 1 wherein the waveguide is a photonic crystal fiber.
</P>
<P>
3.. The device as set forth in claim 1 , wherein the backreflector is at least partially transparent at an excitation frequency for exciting the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
4. The .device as set forth in claim 4, further comprising: an optical fiber coupled to the waveguide, and able to direct a pulse through the waveguide toward the nanoparticle at the excitation frequency.
</P>
<P>
5. The device as set forth in claim 4, further comprising: a lens optically coupled to the backreflector, and able to direct a pulse through the backreflector toward the nanoparticle at the excitation frequency.
</P>
<P>
6. A method for suppressing leaky modes in photon transmission, comprising: coupling a nanoparticle to an end of a waveguide, and coupling a backreflector to the end of the waveguide behind the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 6 further comprising: exciting the nanoparticle to emit a single photon, reflecting the single photon toward a waveguide, and guiding the photon through the waveguide.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 7 wherein exciting the nanoparticle further comprises directing an optical pulse through the waveguide toward the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 7 wherein exciting the nanoparticle further comprises directing an optical pulse through the backreflector toward the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
10. A device comprising: quantum photon emitting means able to emit single photons; photon guiding means coupled to the emitting means and able to receive the single photons; and photon reflecting means optically coupled to the photon guiding means and configured to reflect the single photons toward the photon guiding means.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007142826A2;WO2007142826A3;US2009140275A1;US7546013B1;JP2009539140A;JP4871994B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
