<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CHEMICALLY-DIRECTED ELECTROSTATIC SELF- ASSEMBLY OF MATERIALS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2069062A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MCCARTY LOGAN S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WHITESIDES GEORGE M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WINKLEMAN ADAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MCCARTY, LOGAN, S
</Name>
<Name>
WHITESIDES, GEORGE, M
</Name>
<Name>
WINKLEMAN, ADAM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HARVARD COLLEGE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE PRESIDENT AND FELLOWS OF HARVARD COLLEGE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2069062
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070853761
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-10-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US80392
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060849970P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-06
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J2/00
</Class>
<Class>
B05D1/18
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B05D1/18C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A self-assembled article includes a surface comprising an chemical functionality having an immobilized charge;  and a plurality of particles assembled on the surface of the core, said particles having a surface comprising an immobilized chemical functionality of a charge opposite that of the core.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A method of self-assembling particles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a first set of microspheres having a first ionic functional group containing a first immobilized ion and a first mobile counterion;
</P>
<P>
providing a second set of microspheres having a second ionic functional group containing a second immobilized ion and a second mobile counterion, wherein the first immobilized ion has a charge opposite that of the second immobilized ion;
</P>
<P>
combining the first and second set of microspheres, wherein the oppositely- charged microspheres self-assemble under the influence of electrostatic forces.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein the first set of microspheres has a diameter greater than that of the second set of microspheres, and wherein a plurality of microspheres of the second set of microspheres assemble about a microsphere of the first set.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein the ionic functional group is located throughout the particle.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, wherein the ionic functional group is localized at a surface of the particle.
</P>
<P>
5. A method of particle self-assembly, comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a surface for self-assembly, said surface comprising a chemical functionality having an immobilized charge;
</P>
<P>
providing a plurality of first particles, the particles comprising an immobilized chemical functionality of a charge opposite that of the substrate; and
</P>
<P>
contacting the first charged particles with the substrate, wherein the first charged particles self-assemble on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 5, wherein the surface and the first particles are charged by contract electrification.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 5, wherein the fraction of chemical functionalities carrying a charge is in the range of about 1-25%.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 5, wherein the fraction of chemical functionalities carrying a charge is in the range of about 3-10%.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 5, wherein the surface is planar.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 5, wherein the substrate is in the form of a particle.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10, wherein the substrate particle is hollow.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 10, wherein the ratio of a diameter of the substrate particle and a diameter of an assembled particle is greater than or equal to 3: 1.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12, wherein the ratio is greater than 5: 1.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 12, wherein the ratio is greater than 10:1.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 5, wherein the particles assemble substantially into a monolayer.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 15, wherein an amount of particles is in excess of that needed to form a monolayer.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16, wherein the excess is greater than or equal to about 10- fold by weight.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 5, wherein the surface is selected from the group consisting of organic or inorganic polymers having a covalently bound ionic functional group.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 18, wherein the organic polymer comprises an ionomer.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 18, wherein the inorganic polymer comprises silica or glass.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 5, wherein the chemical functionality of the substrate is in the form of a preselected pattern.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 5, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
contacting the self-assembled article with a second charged particle, said second charged particle comprising an immobilized chemical functionality of a charge opposite that of the first charged particle, wherein the second charged particles self-assemble on the first charged particles.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 5, wherein the chemical functionality having an immobilized charge of the surface are located in regions of the surface in a selected pattern.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 5, further comprising linking the assembled beads to adjacent beads.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 24, wherein the linking is accomplished by annealing.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 24, wherein the linking is accomplished by covalent bonding.
</P>
<P>
27. A method of self-assembly, comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a surface for self-assembly, said surface comprising a first region comprising a chemical functionality having a negative immobilized charge and a second region comprising a chemical functionality having a positive immobilized charge that is opposite the first charge;
</P>
<P>
providing a plurality of first particles, the particles comprising an immobilized chemical functionality of a positive charge;
</P>
<P>
providing a plurality of second particles, the second particles comprising an immobilized chemical functionality of a negative charge; and
</P>
<P>
contacting the first and second charged particles with the substrate, wherein the first charged particles self-assemble on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
28. A self-assembled article comprising:
</P>
<P>
a surface comprising an chemical functionality having an immobilized charge; and
</P>
<P>
a plurality of particles assembled on the surface of the core, said particles having a surface comprising an immobilized chemical functionality of a charge opposite that of the core.
</P>
<P>
29. The article of claim 28, wherein the assembly of particles forms a monolayer.
</P>
<P>
30. The article of claim 28, wherein the assembly forms a pattern on the surface.
</P>
<P>
31. The article of claim 28, wherein the surface comprises a microsphere.
</P>
<P>
32. The article or claim 28, wherein the assembly of particles forms a pattern on the surface of the microsphere.
</P>
<P>
33. The article of claim 32, wherein the microsphere is hollow.
</P>
<P>
34. The article of claim 28, wherein the surface is selected from the group consisting of organic or inorganic polymers having a covalently bound ionic functional group.
</P>
<P>
35. The article of claim 28, wherein the particle is selected from the group consisting of organic or inorganic polymers having a covalently bound ionic functional group.
</P>
<P>
36. The article of claim 35, wherein the inorganic polymer comprises silica or glass.
</P>
<P>
37. The article of claim 28, wherein the chemical functionality of the surface and/or the particle is immobilized by a covalent bond.
</P>
<P>
38. The article of claim 37, wherein the chemical functionality is an anionic species.
</P>
<P>
39. The article of claim 37, wherein the chemical functionality is a cationic species.
</P>
<P>
40. An article comprising:
</P>
<P>
a core region of a first immobilized charge; a first self-assembled layer comprising particles of an immobilized charge opposite the core; and
</P>
<P>
a second self-assembled layer comprising particles of the first immobilized charge.
</P>
<P>
41. An article comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate comprising a region of immobilized positive charge and a region of immobilized negative charge;
</P>
<P>
a first set of negatively charged particles assembled over the region of positive charge and
</P>
<P>
a second set of positively charged particles assembled over the region of negative charge.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008045745A2;WO2008045745A3;US2008261006A1;JP2010505616A;CN101573175A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
