<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Nanoimprint Lithography System
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2016613A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RESNICK DOUBLAS J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MAISSL MARIO J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI BYUNG-JIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SREENIVASAN SIDIGATA V [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RESNICK, DOUBLAS, J
</Name>
<Name>
MAISSL, MARIO, J
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI, BYUNG-JIN
</Name>
<Name>
SREENIVASAN, SIDIGATA, V
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2016613
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070734513
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IB01202
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060799496P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-11
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/67
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/67S2M
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/67S2V
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanoimprint lithography template including, inter alia, a body having first and second opposed sides with a first surface disposed on the first side, the second side having a recess disposed therein, the body having first and second regions with the second region surrounding the first region and the recess in superimposition with the first region, with a portion of the first surface in superimposition with the first region being spaced-apart from the second side a first distance and a portion of the first surface in superimposition with the second region being spaced-apart from the second side a second distance, with the second distance being greater than the first distance;  and a mold disposed on the first side of the body in superimposition a portion of the first region.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A nanoimprint lithography template comprising: a body having first and second opposed sides with a first surface disposed on said first side, said second side having a recess disposed therein, said body having first and second regions with said second region surrounding said first region and said recess in superimposi- tion with said first region, with a portion of said first surface in superimposition with said first region being spaced-apart from said second side a first distance and a portion of said first surface in superimposition with said second region being spaced-apart from said second side a second distance, with said second distance being greater than said first distance; and a mold disposed on said first side of said body in superimposition with a portion of said first region.
</P>
<P>
2. The template as recited in claim 1 wherein said recess has a geometric shape selected from a group of geometric shapes consisting of square, rectangular, circular, and elliptical.
</P>
<P>
3. The template as recited in claim 1 wherein said recess comprises a nadir surface, with said portion of said first surface in superimposition with said first region being spaced-apart from said nadir surface a first distance.
</P>
<P>
4. The template as recited in claim 1 wherein said second distance has a magnitude of approximately 0.25 inches.
</P>
<P>
5. The template as recited in claim 1 wherein said first distance has a magnitude of approximately 700 microns.
</P>
<P>
6. The template as recited in claim 1 wherein said first distance has a magnitude in a range of 1 micron to 0.25 inches.
</P>
<P>
7. The template as recited in claim 1 wherein said mold comprises a plurality of protrusions and recessions.
</P>
<P>
8. A nanoimprint lithography template comprising: a body having first and second opposed sides with a first surface disposed on said first side being substantially planar, said body having first and second regions with said second region surrounding said first region, with a portion of said body in superimposition with said first region having a first thickness and a portion of said body in superimposition with said second region having a second thickness, with said second thickness being greater than said first thickness; and a mold disposed on said first side in superimposition with a portion of said first region.
</P>
<P>
9. The template as recited in claim 8 wherein said second side of said body has a recess disposed therein, with said recess being in superimposition with said first region of said body.
</P>
<P>
10. The template as recited in claim 9 wherein said recess has a geometric shape selected from a group of geometric shapes consisting of square, rectangular, circular, and elliptical.
</P>
<P>
11. The template as recited in claim 8 wherein said second thickness has a magnitude of approximately 0.25 inches.
</P>
<P>
12. The template as recited in claim 8 wherein said first distance has a magnitude of approximately 700 microns.
</P>
<P>
13. The template as recited in claim 8 wherein said first distance has a magnitude in a range of 1 micron to 0.25 inches.
</P>
<P>
14. The template as recited in claim 8 wherein said mold comprises a plurality of protrusions and recessions.
</P>
<P>
15. A nanoimprint lithography system comprising: a body having first and second opposed sides with a first surface disposed on said first side, said second side having a recess disposed therein, said body having first and second regions with said second region surrounding said first region and said recess in superimposition with said first region, with a portion of said first surface in superimposition with said first region being spaced-apart from said second side a first distance and a portion of said first sur-face in superimposition with said second region being spaced-apart from said second side a second distance, with said second distance being greater than said first distance, said body further having a mold disposed on said first side in superimposition with a portion of said first region; and an actuator coupled to said body to apply a force to said body to bow said first region of said body away from said second side of said body.
</P>
<P>
16. The system as recited in claim 15 further including a plurality of actuators.
</P>
<P>
17. The system as recited in claim 15 wherein said force of said actuator may vary dimensions of said body.
</P>
<P>
18. The system as recited in claim 15 wherein said recess has a geometric shape selected from a group of geometric shapes consisting of square, rectangular, circular, and elliptical.
</P>
<P>
19. The system as recited in claim 15 wherein said actuator is coupled to a periphery of said body.
</P>
<P>
20. The system as recited in claim 15 wherein said recess comprises a nadir surface spaced-apart from said first side and said body comprises a boundary surface defined between said nadir surface and said second side, with said actuator being coupled to said boundary surface.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2016613A4;WO2007132320A2;WO2007132320A3;US2011171340A1;US2010291257A1;US2008160129A1;TW200801819A;KR20090017469A;JP2009536591A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
