<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SOFT MEMS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2029300A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LIU CHANG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ENGEL JONATHAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RYU KEE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LIU, CHANG
</Name>
<Name>
ENGEL, JONATHAN
</Name>
<Name>
RYU, KEE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV ILLINOIS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2029300
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070852379
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-06-01
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US12987
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060810799P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B32B7/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01L3/5027A
</Class>
<Class>
B81C1/00G2S
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A microscale polymer-based apparatus comprises a substrate formed from a first polymer material and at least one active region integrated with the substrate. The at least one active region is patterned from a second polymer material that is modified to perform at least one function within the at least one active region.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A microscale polymer-based apparatus comprising: a substrate formed from a first polymer material; at least one active region integrated with said substrate, said at least one active region being patterned from a second polymer material; wherein the second polymer material is modified to perform at least one function within said at least one active region.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1 , wherein the second polymer material comprises a composite polymer material including the first polymer material and at least one additive.
</P>
<P>
3. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the first polymer material is substantially nonconductive, and the second polymer material is modified to be conductive.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 3, wherein said at least one active region is embedded within said substrate.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said at least one active region comprises at least one of an electrode, an embedded strain gauge, a conductive sensor, and a heater.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said substrate comprises a non-conductive sheet, and wherein said at least one active region comprises at least one embedded strain gauge.
</P>
<P>
7. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said substrate includes a microfluidic channel formed therein, and wherein said at least one active region comprises at least one conductive flow rate sensor.
</P>
<P>
8. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said substrate includes a microfluidic channel formed therein, and wherein said at least one active region comprises at least one resistive heater.
</P>
<P>
9. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said substrate includes a plurality of nonconductive layers, and wherein said at least one active region comprises a plurality of active regions, each of said plurality of nonconductive layers including a plurality of active regions.
</P>
<P>
10. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said substrate includes a plurality of nonconductive layers; wherein said at least one active region comprises a plurality of embedded electrodes, each of said plurality of nonconductive layers including a plurality of embedded electrodes; wherein the embedded electrodes are arranged orthogonally with respect to adjacent nonconductive layers to provide a capacitive array.
</P>
<P>
11. The apparatus of claim 4, wherein said at least one active region comprises a plurality of active regions embedded within said substrate such that each of the plurality of active regions are separated from one another by a portion of said substrate.
</P>
<P>
12. The apparatus of claim 3, further comprising: at least one electrical contact electrically coupled to said at least one active region.
</P>
<P>
13. The apparatus of claim 2, wherein the first polymer material comprises an elastomer, and wherein the second polymer material comprises an elastomer modified to become conductive.
</P>
<P>
14. The apparatus of claim 2, wherein the first polymer material comprises polydimethlysiloxane (PDMS), and wherein the second polymer material comprises PDMS modified to become conductive.
</P>
<P>
15. The apparatus of claim 14, wherein the second polymer material comprises PDMS combined with multiwall carbon nanotubes
</P>
<P>
(MWNT).
</P>
<P>
16. A method of forming a microscale polymer-based device, the method comprising: patterning a photoresist on a substrate to provide a photoresist mold; applying a modified polymer to the photoresist mold to form at least one modified polymer structure; removing said patterned photoresist; forming nonmodified polymer around the at least one modified polymer structure to provide a nonmodified polymer structure and capture the at least one modified polymer structure within the nonmodified polymer structure; and releasing the at least one modified polymer structure and the nonmodified polymer structure from the substrate.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 wherein the modified polymer comprises the nonmodified polymer and an additive to make the modified polymer conductive.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 17, wherein the nonmodif[iota]ed polymer comprises polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS), and wherein the modified polymer comprises PDMS combined with multiwall carbon nanorubes (MWNT).
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 16, wherein the at least one modified polymer structure comprises at least one of an electrode, a flow sensor, a heater, strain gauge, a capacitor plate, a chemical sensor, a biosensor, and a porous region.
</P>
<P>
20. An integrated, polymer-based structure comprising: a modified polymer-based means; a non-modified polymer-based means integrated with said modified polymer-based means, said modified polymer-based means being patterned in or on said non-modified polymer-based means to provide one or more active regions.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008030284A2;WO2008030284A3;US2010072565A1;KR20090051009A;JP2009539625A;CA2653557A1;AU2007293476A1;AU2007293476B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
