<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Vortex spin momentum transfer magnetotresistive device
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2056370A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DEAK JAMES G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DEAK, JAMES G
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NVE CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NVE CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2056370
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080168087
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-10-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070001496P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080229576
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-08-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L43/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N2
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/08
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A ferromagnetic thin-film based device that transitioned between alternative magnetic states thereof through having electrical currents established therethrough and has both a reference magnetization and a free layer magnetization provided therein by vortex magnetizations.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A ferromagnetic thin-film based device that is transitioned between alternative magnetic states thereof through having electrical currents established therethrough and has a reference magnetization provided therein by a vortex magnetization established in a thin-film, said device comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate, and
</P>
<P>
a device structure layer stack extending in a stack direction from said substrate on which it is supported, said stack having an outer surface curved at least in part about said stack direction with a lateral dimension between opposite curved side portions thereof, the stack comprising:
</P>
<P>
a nonmagnetic intermediate layer, said intermediate layer having two major surfaces each on an opposite side thereof,
</P>
<P>
a free layer of a ferromagnetic material on one of said major surfaces having a thickness sufficient to permit a vortex magnetization therein, and
</P>
<P>
a reference magnetization layer having therein a reference ferromagnetic material layer on that remaining one of said major surfaces with its magnetization being a vortex magnetization that is maintained so by a reference antiferromagnetic layer on said reference ferromagnetic material layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The device of claim 1 wherein said lateral dimension that is less than 500 nm.
</P>
<P>
3. The device of claim 2 wherein said lateral dimension that is less than 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
4. The device of any of claims 1 to 3 wherein said free layer has a thickness less than 20 nm.
</P>
<P>
5. The device of any of claims 1 to 4 wherein said free layer has a thickness exceeding 5 nm. 6. The device of any preceding claim wherein said free layer is of an iron and nickel alloy material.
</P>
<P>
7. The device of any preceding claim wherein said reference ferromagnetic material layer has a thickness exceeding 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
8. The device of any preceding claim wherein said reference ferromagnetic material layer is of an iron and nickel alloy material.
</P>
<P>
9. The device of any preceding claim wherein said reference antiferromagnetic layer has a thickness exceeding 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
10. The device of any preceding claim wherein said reference antiferromagnetic layer is of an iridium and manganese alloy material.
</P>
<P>
11. The device of any preceding claim wherein said intermediate layer is selected from an electrically conductive material and an electrically insulative material.
</P>
<P>
12. The device of any preceding claim wherein said outer surface of said device structure layer stack is a truncated cylindrical surface.
</P>
<P>
13. The device of any of claims 1 to 11 wherein said outer surface of said device structure layer stack is a truncated cylindrical surface portion insofar as it extends between two parallel lines also parallel to said stack direction with a remaining portion of said outer surface extending between said two parallel lines being a portion of a plane.
</P>
<P>
14. The device of any preceding claim wherein opposite ends of said device structure layer stack have electrodes thereon for electrically connecting said device to magnetic state setting and determination circuitry.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009117370A1;US7868404B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
