<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
DEVICE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2016632A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SONE TAKEYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KURIYAMA AKIRA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YANO KOJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ALBRECHT OTTO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TABATA MASAYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SONE, TAKEYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
KURIYAMA, AKIRA
</Name>
<Name>
YANO, KOJI
</Name>
<Name>
ALBRECHT, OTTO
</Name>
<Name>
TABATA, MASAYOSHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CANON KK [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
CANON KABUSHIKI KAISHA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2016632
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070828857
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP69116
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060261340
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060261341
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M2D2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A device is provided by use of a helical substituted polyacetylene. The device comprises a structure comprised of a helical substituted polyacetylene having a helical main chain, and a pair of electrodes for applying a voltage or electric current to the structure, wherein the molecule of the helical substituted polyacetylene has a length larger than the distance between the pair of the electrodes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A device comprising a structure comprised of a helical substituted polyacetylene having a helical main chain, and a pair of electrodes for applying a voltage or electric current to the structure, wherein the molecule of the helical substituted polyacetylene has a length larger than the distance between the pair of the electrodes. 2. The device according to claim 1, wherein the structure is comprised of a single molecule of the helical substituted polyacetylene.
</P>
<P>
3. The device according to claim 1, wherein the helical substituted polyacetylene has a non-conjugated functional group in the side chain.
</P>
<P>
4. The device according to claim 1, wherein the helical substituted polyacetylene has a polar substituent group in the side chain.
</P>
<P>
5. The device according to claim 1, wherein the device comprises a controlling electrode.
</P>
<P>
6. A device comprising a structure comprised of a helical substituted polyacetylene having a helical main chain, and a pair of electrodes for applying a voltage or electric current to the structure, wherein the helical substituted polyacetylene is oriented in the direction connecting the pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
7. The device according to claim 6, wherein the oriented helical substituted polyacetylene is placed to bridge the electrodes.
</P>
<P>
8 The device according to claim 6, wherein the oriented helical substituted polyacetylene has an absorption spectrum of a dichroism ratio of 0.1 or more.
</P>
<P>
9. The device according to claim 6, wherein the helical substituted polyacetylene has a substituted or unsubstituted aromatic or heterocyclic ring in the side chain. 10. The device according to claim 6, wherein films of the helical substituted polyacetylene are built up in layers on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
11. The device according to claim 6, wherein the oriented helical substituted polyacetylene is formed by transferring molecules developed on a water surface onto a substrate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2016632B1;WO2008047586A1;US2009179197A1;CN102157690A;AT449427T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
