<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING STABILISED METAL NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2021520A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BISHOP PETER TRENTON [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
BOARDMAN ALAN [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
BISHOP, PETER TRENTON
</Name>
<Name>
BOARDMAN, ALAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
JOHNSON MATTHEY PLC [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
JOHNSON MATTHEY PUBLIC LIMITED COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2021520
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070733702
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007GB50281
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20060010409
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F9/16
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
C07F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07F1/12
</Class>
<Class>
C22B11/00
</Class>
<Class>
C22B15/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J13/00
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C22B11/00
</Class>
<Class>
C22B5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process for making high metal content stabilised metal nanoparticles, comprises decomposing at least one metal acetylide in the presence of a first solvent under reducing conditions to yield a metal colloid solution and then recovering metal nanoparticles as a precipitate by either evaporating the first solvent or adding a second solvent to the first solvent. The metal colloid solution obtainable as an intermediate by such a process and the high metal content stabilised metal nanoparticles obtainable as the final product of such a process are also disclosed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A process for making high metal content stabilised metal nanoparticles, which process comprising decomposing at least one metal acetylide in the presence of a first solvent under reducing conditions to yield a metal colloid solution and then recovering metal nanoparticles as a precipitate by either:
</P>
<P>
(a) evaporating the first solvent; or
</P>
<P>
(b) adding a second solvent to the first solvent.
</P>
<P>
2. A process according to claim 1, wherein the at least one metal acetylide is decomposed by carrying out the reaction at a temperature of from 70 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 200 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
3. A process according to claim 1, wherein the at least one metal acetylide is decomposed using a chemical reductant or an electrochemical reductant.
</P>
<P>
4. A process according to claim 1, wherein the at least one metal acetylide is decomposed by exposure to electromagnetic radiation.
</P>
<P>
5. A process according to any preceding claim, wherein the at least one metal in the at least one metal acetylide is selected from the platinum group metals and the coinage metals.
</P>
<P>
6. A process according to claim 5, wherein the at least one metal is silver or gold and the process is carried out in air.
</P>
<P>
7. A process according to claim 5, wherein the at least one metal is copper and the process is carried out under an inert atmosphere.
</P>
<P>
8. A process according to any preceding claim, wherein the at least one metal acetylide is selected from the list consisting of 1-dodecyne, 1-decyne, 1-nonyne, 1- octyne, 3-methyl-octyn-3-ol, l-octyn-3-ol, 1-ethynyl cyclohexanol, 10-undecynoic acid, 1-ethynyl cyclohexyl acetate and dehydrolinalool.
</P>
<P>
9. A process according to any preceding claim, wherein the first solvent is selected from the list consisting of xylene, Shellsol, toluene, mesitylene, trie thy lamine, dioxane, cyclohexanone, 4-methyl-2-pentanone, cyclohexanol, dimethylacetamide, dimethylformamide and water.
</P>
<P>
10. A process according to any preceding claim, wherein the second solvent is selected from the list consisting of methanol, ethanol, iso-propanol, acetonitrile, acetone and hexane.
</P>
<P>
11. A metal colloid solution obtainable as an intermediate in a process according to any preceding claim.
</P>
<P>
12. A metal colloid solution according to claim 11, wherein the solution absorbs UV light in the wavelength range of from 510 to 540 nm, from 395 to 425 nm or from 555 to 585 nm.
</P>
<P>
13. A metal colloid solution according to claim 11 or 12, wherein the solution remains stable for a period of at least 3 months.
</P>
<P>
14. High metal content stabilised metal nanoparticles obtainable by a process according to any of claims 1 to 10.
</P>
<P>
15. High metal content stabilised metal nanoparticles according to claim 14, wherein the nanoparticles have a diameter of from 2 to 10 nm.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007138345A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
