<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CARBON NANOWALL WITH CONTROLLED STRUCTURE AND METHOD FOR CONTROLLING CARBON NANOWALL STRUCTURE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2048113A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HORI MASARU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HIRAMATSU MINEO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KANO HIROYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUGIYAMA TORU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HAMA YUICHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HORI, MASARU
</Name>
<Name>
HIRAMATSU, MINEO
</Name>
<Name>
KANO, HIROYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
SUGIYAMA, TORU
</Name>
<Name>
HAMA, YUICHIRO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOYOTA MOTOR CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TOYOTA JIDOSHA KABUSHIKI KAISHA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2048113
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070791720
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-07-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP65036
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060201927
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J21/18
</Class>
<Class>
B01J32/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/96
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J21/18C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B6
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/90S2
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/92S2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Provided is a method for controlling a carbon nanowall (CNW) structure having improved corrosion resistance against high potential by varying the spacing between the carbon nanowall (CNW) walls so that its surface area and crystallinity are controlled. Also provided is a carbon nanowall (CNW) with a high surface area and a carbon nanowall (CNW) with a high crystallinity, both of which have a controlled structure. According to the present invention, provided are: (1) a carbon nanowall, characterized by having a wall surface area of 50 cm 2 /cm 2 -substrate[mu]m or more;  (2) a carbon nanowall, characterized by having a crystallinity such that the D band half value width in the Raman spectrum measured with an irradiation laser wavelength of 514.5 nm is 85 cm -1 or less;  and (3) a carbon nanowall, characterized by having not only a wall surface area of 50 cm 2 /cm 2 -substrate[mu]m or more but also a crystallinity such that the D-band half value width in the Raman spectrum measured with an irradiation laser wavelength of 514.5 nm is 85 cm -1 or less.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A carbon nanowall, characterized by having a wall surface area of 50 cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;-substrate.[micro]m or more.
</P>
<P>
2. A carbon nanowall, characterized by having a crystallinity such that the D band half value width in the Raman spectrum measured with an irradiation laser wavelength of 514.5 nm is 85 cm&amp;lt;-1&amp;gt; or less.
</P>
<P>
3. A carbon nanowall, characterized by having not only a wall surface area of 50 cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;-substrate.[micro]m or more but also a crystallinity such that the D-band half value width in the Raman spectrum measured with an irradiation laser wavelength of 514.5 nm is 85 cm&amp;lt;-1&amp;gt; or less.
</P>
<P>
4. A method for controlling a carbon nanowall structure, characterized in that in a method for producing a carbon nanowall by forming in at least a part of a reaction chamber a plasma atmosphere in which a carbon source gas having at least carbon as a constituent element has been turned into plasma, injecting into the plasma atmosphere hydrogen radicals generated externally to the atmosphere from H2 gas, and forming a carbon nanowall on a surface of a substrate provided in the reaction chamber by reacting the plasma and the hydrogen radicals, a ratio between introduction rates of the H2 gas and the carbon source gas as a design factor controls the surface area and/or crystallinity of the produced carbon nanowall.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for controlling a carbon nanowall structure according to claim 4, characterized in that the ratio between the introduction rates of the H2 gas and the carbon source gas (H2 gas introduction rate (mol)/carbon source gas introduction rate (mol)) is 1 to 2.5.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for controlling a carbon nanowall structure according to claim 4 or 5, characterized by generating the hydrogen radicals from the H2 gas by irradiating one or more selected from microwaves, UHF waves, VHF waves, and RF waves on the H2 gas, and/or causing the H2 gas to come into contact with a heated catalyst metal.
</P>
<P>
7. The method for controlling a carbon nanowall structure according to any of claims 4 to 6, characterized in that the carbon source gas has at least carbon and hydrogen as constituent elements.
</P>
<P>
8. The method for controlling carbon nanowall structure according to any of claims 4 to 6, characterized in that the carbon source gas has at least carbon and fluorine as constituent elements.
</P>
<P>
9. A catalyst layer for a fuel cell, characterized in that a carrier for the catalyst layer is the carbon nanowall according to any of claims 1 to 3 and that a catalyst component and/or electrolyte component is supported/dispersed on the carrier for the catalyst layer composed of the carbon nanowall.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2048113A4;US2010009242A1;WO2008013309A1;JP2008024570A;CN101489926A;CA2654430A1;CA2654430C
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
