<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METAL NITRATE CONVERSION METHOD
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2061595A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SIETSMA JELLE RUDOLF ANNE [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
VAN DILLEN ADRIANUS JACOBUS [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
DE JONGH PETRA ELISABETH [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
DE JONG KRIJN PIETER [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
SIETSMA, JELLE RUDOLF ANNE
</Name>
<Name>
VAN DILLEN, ADRIANUS JACOBUS
</Name>
<Name>
DE JONGH, PETRA ELISABETH
</Name>
<Name>
DE JONG, KRIJN PIETER
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
JOHNSON MATTHEY PLC [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
JOHNSON MATTHEY PLC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2061595
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070789378
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007GB50492
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20060017529
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J23/755
</Class>
<Class>
B01J29/03
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/08
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/12
</Class>
<Class>
C01G53/04
</Class>
<Class>
C07C1/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/70
</Class>
<Class>
B01J29/03A2D
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/00D8D
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/08B6
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/16
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G1/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01G53/04
</Class>
<Class>
C07C209/48
</Class>
<Class>
C10G2/332
</Class>
<Class>
C10G45/06
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method is described for converting a supported metal nitrate into the corresponding supported metal oxide comprising heating the metal nitrate to effect its decomposition under a gas mixture that contains nitrous oxide and has an oxygen content of &amp;lt;5% by volume. The method provides very highly dispersed metal oxide on the support material. The metal oxide is useful as a catalyst or as a catalyst precursor.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims.
</P>
<P>
1. A method for converting a supported metal nitrate into the corresponding supported metal oxide comprising heating the metal nitrate to effect its decomposition under a gas mixture containing nitrous oxide and having an oxygen content of &amp;lt;5% by volume.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1 wherein the metal nitrate is impregnated onto a support material from a solution and dried to remove the solvent before heating the metal nitrate to convert it to the corresponding metal oxide.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 1 or claim 2 wherein the gas mixture consists of one or more inert gases and nitrous oxide.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to claim 3 wherein the inert gas is selected from nitrogen, helium or argon.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 4 wherein the nitrous oxide concentration in the gas mixture is in the range 0.001 to 15% by volume.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 5 wherein the supported metal nitrate is heated to a temperature in the range 100-1200&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 6 wherein the metal nitrate is a transition metal nitrate.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 7 wherein the metal nitrate is a nitrate of nickel, cobalt, copper, or iron.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 8 wherein the support is a metal, carbon, metal oxide, mixed metal oxide or solid polymer support.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 9 wherein the support is selected from alumina, metal-aluminate, silica, aluminosilicate, titania, zirconia or mixtures of these.
</P>
<P>
1 1. A method according to any one of claims 1 to 10 wherein the supported metal oxide is a reducible metal oxide, further comprising heating the supported metal oxide under a reducing gas stream to effect reduction of at least a part of the metal oxide.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to claim 11 wherein the reducing gas stream comprises carbon monoxide and/or hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to claim 11 or claim 12 wherein the supported metal oxide is nickel oxide, cobalt oxide, copper oxide or iron oxide and the reduction is performed with a hydrogen-containing gas.
</P>
<P>
14. A supported oxide obtainable by the method of any one of claims 1 to 10.
</P>
<P>
15. A supported reduced metal oxide obtainable by the method of claims 1 1-13.
</P>
<P>
16. Use of the supported oxide prepared according to the method of claims 1 to 10 as a catalyst, catalyst precursor or sorbent.
</P>
<P>
17. Use of the supported reduced metal oxide prepared according to the method of claims 1 1 to 13 as a catalyst or sorbent.
</P>
<P>
18. Use according to claim 17 wherein the reduced metal oxide is a hydrogenation catalyst or a Fischer-Tropsch catalyst.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2061595B1;WO2008029177A1;ZA200901370A;US2010099553A1;RU2009112600A;RU2437717C2;JP2010502556A;DK2061595T3;CN101511475A;AT473049T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
