<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
LARGE AREA INDUCED ASSEMBLY OF NANOSTRUCTURES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2054336A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
AIZENBERG JOANNA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KRUPENKIN THOMAS NIKITA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SYDORENKO OLEKSANDR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TAYLOR JOSEPH ASHLEY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AIZENBERG, JOANNA
</Name>
<Name>
KRUPENKIN, THOMAS, NIKITA
</Name>
<Name>
SYDORENKO, OLEKSANDR
</Name>
<Name>
TAYLOR, JOSEPH, ASHLEY
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LUCENT TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LUCENT TECHNOLOGIES INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2054336
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070872160
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-13
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US17923
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-13
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060822457P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-15
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070773534
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B81B3/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B81B3/00H10
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Provided is an apparatus. In one embodiment, this apparatus includes a substrate having a surface, and a plurality of nanostructures each having a first end and a second end, wherein the first end of each of the plurality of nanostructures is attached to the surface. At least a portion of the second ends of the plurality of nanostructures, in this embodiment, are bent toward one another to form two or more similarly configured clumps each including two or more nanostructures.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. An apparatus, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a substrate having a surface;
</P>
<P>
a plurality of nanostructures each having a first end and a second end, wherein the first end of each of the plurality of nanostructures is attached to the surface; and
</P>
<P>
wherein at least a portion of the second ends of the plurality of nanostructures are bent toward one another to form two or more similarly configured clumps, each of the two or more similarly configured clumps including two or more nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps are touching.
</P>
<P>
3. The apparatus of claim 2 wherein an adhesive fixes the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps together.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps do not touch.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the first ends of each of the plurality of nanostructures are located within a volume-tunable-material, the volume-tunable-material configured to bend the second ends of the plurality of nanostructures toward or away from one another.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 5 wherein the volume-tunable-material is a polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
7. The apparatus of claim 5 wherein the volume-tunable-material is a hydrogel layer.
</P>
<P>
8. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the two or more clumps each include only two nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
9. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the two or more clumps each include only four nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
10. A method for manufacturing, comprising:
</P>
<P>
forming a plurality of nanostructures over a substrate, each of the plurality of nanostructure having a first end attached to the substrate and a second end;
</P>
<P>
bringing together at least a portion of the second ends to form two or more similarly configured clumps, each of the two or more similarly configured clumps including two or more nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10 wherein bringing together includes bringing together using capillary forces between a droplet of liquid and the two or more nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 10 wherein bringing together includes causing the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps to touch one another.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12 further including applying an adhesive after bringing together, the adhesive configured to fix the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 10 wherein plastic deformation in the at least a portion of the second ends causes the at least a portion of the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps to remain at least partially bent toward one another after the bringing.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14 wherein the second ends remain bent toward one another but do not touch.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 10 further including forming a volume-tunable-material around the first ends of each of the plurality of nanostructures, and further wherein the volume-tunable-material is configured to bend the at least a portion of the second ends of nanostructures toward or away from one another by changing a volume thereof.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16 wherein the volume-tunable-material is a polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 16 wherein the volume-tunable-material is a hydrogel layer.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 10 wherein the two or more clumps each include only two nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 10 wherein the two or more clumps each include only four nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
21. A method of use, comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing an apparatus, the apparatus including;
</P>
<P>
a substrate having a surface;
</P>
<P>
a plurality of nanostructures each having a first end and a second end, wherein the first ends of each of the plurality of nanostructures are attached to the surface; and
</P>
<P>
a volume-tunable-material encompassing the first ends; and
</P>
<P>
exposing the volume-tunable-material to a stimulus, the stimulus changing a thickness of the volume-tunable-material and thereby bringing together at least a portion of the second ends to form two or more similarly configured clumps of two or more nanostructures or moving apart the second ends of two or more similarly configured clumps of two or more nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
22. The use of claim 21 wherein exposing the volume-tunable-material to the stimulus increases a thickness thereof, thus causing the second ends of the two or more similarly configured clumps to move apart and release an active particle.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008095977A1;US7764004B2;WO2008094213A2;WO2008094213A3;KR20090033896A;JP2010500931A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
