<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Magnetoresistive device
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2065886A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WUNDERLICH JOERG [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
PARK BYOUNG GUK [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
SHICK ALEXANDER [CZ]
</Name>
<Name>
JUNGWIRTH TOMAS [CZ]
</Name>
<Name>
MACA FRANTISEK [CZ]
</Name>
<Name>
WUNDERLICH, JOERG
</Name>
<Name>
PARK, BYOUNG GUK
</Name>
<Name>
SHICK, ALEXANDER
</Name>
<Name>
JUNGWIRTH, TOMAS
</Name>
<Name>
MACA, FRANTISEK
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HITACHI LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HITACHI LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2065886
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070121701
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070121701
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G11B5/39
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09B
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09R
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/39
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/155
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32L2P
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/08
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A magnetoresistive device comprises a ferromagnetic region (5), a non-ferromagnetic region (6), an insulating region (7) and a conductive region (8). The insulating region is arranged between the ferromagnetic region and the conductive region so as to provide a tunnel barrier. The non-ferromagnetic region separates the insulating region and the ferromagnetic region.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A magnetoresistive device comprising an insulating region arranged between a ferromagnetic region and a conductive region so as to provide a tunnel barrier and further comprising a non-ferromagnetic region which separates the insulating region and the ferromagnetic region.
</P>
<P>
2. A device according to claim 1, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region is configured such that the ferromagnetic region induces a magnetic moment in the non-ferromagnetic region.
</P>
<P>
3. A device according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises a metallic non-ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
4. A device according to claim 3, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises a transition metal or an alloy including a transition metal.
</P>
<P>
5. A device according to claim 4, wherein the transition metal or alloy comprises platinum.
</P>
<P>
6. A device according to claim 4 or 5, wherein the transition metal or alloy comprises palladium.
</P>
<P>
7. A device according to claim 4, 5 or 6, wherein the transition metal or alloy comprises iridium.
</P>
<P>
8. A device according to claim 1, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region is antiferromagnetic.
</P>
<P>
9. A device according to claim 8, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises a single layer.
</P>
<P>
10. A device according to claim 8 or 9, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises an antiferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
11. A device according to claim 8, 9 or 10, wherein the antiferromagnetic material comprises a rare earth element or an alloy including a rare earth element.
</P>
<P>
12. A device according to claim 11, wherein the antiferromagnetic material includes antiferromagnetic dysprosium.
</P>
<P>
13. A device according to claim 11 or 12, wherein the antiferromagnetic material includes antiferromagnetic erbium.
</P>
<P>
14. A device according to claim 11, 12 or 13, wherein the antiferromagnetic material includes gadolinium and europium, preferably GdEuS.
</P>
<P>
15. A device according to claims 8 to 14, wherein the antiferromagnetic material comprises a transition metal or an alloy including a transition metal.
</P>
<P>
16. A device according to claim 15, wherein the antiferromagnetic material includes platinum.
</P>
<P>
17. A device according to claim 15 or 16, wherein the antiferromagnetic material includes manganese.
</P>
<P>
18. A device according to claims 8 to 17, wherein the antiferromagnetic material comprises an antiferromagnetic oxide.
</P>
<P>
19. A device according to claims 18, wherein the antiferromagnetic material includes [alpha]-iron(III)oxide (Fe2O3).
</P>
<P>
20. A device according to any one of claims 9 to 19, wherein the layer has a thickness of one, two or three monolayers.
</P>
<P>
20. A device according to any one of claims 9 to 19, wherein the layer has a thickness of more than three monolayers.
</P>
<P>
22. A device according to claim 8, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises at least two layers.
</P>
<P>
23. A device according to claim 22, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises first and second layers.
</P>
<P>
24. A device according to claim 23, wherein the first layer comprises a first transition metal or an alloy including the first transition metal and the second layer comprises second, different transition metal or an alloy including the second transition metal.
</P>
<P>
25. A device according to claims 24, wherein the first layer comprises chromium.
</P>
<P>
26. A device according to claims 23 or 24, wherein the first layer comprises a ferromagnetic material and is configured such that the material behaves antiferromagnetically.
</P>
<P>
27. A device according to claim 26, wherein the first layer comprises manganese, iron and/or cobalt.
</P>
<P>
28. A device according to any one of claims 23 to 27, wherein the second layer comprises tungsten, palladium, platinum and/or iridium.
</P>
<P>
29. A device according to any one of claims 23 to 28, wherein the first layer has a thickness of one, two or three monolayers.
</P>
<P>
30. A device according to any one of claims 23 to 29, wherein the second layer has a thickness of one, two or three monolayers.
</P>
<P>
31. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region is ferrimagnetic.
</P>
<P>
32. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the ferromagnetic region comprises a metallic ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
33. A device according to claim 32, wherein the metallic ferromagnetic material comprises cobalt, nickel or iron or an alloy comprising cobalt, nickel and/or iron.
</P>
<P>
34. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the ferromagnetic region comprises at least two ferromagnetic regions separated by a non-ferromagnetic region.
</P>
<P>
35. A device according to claim 34, wherein the non-ferromagnetic region comprises a metallic non-ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
36. A device according to claim 35, wherein the metallic non-ferromagnetic material comprises platinum.
</P>
<P>
37. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the insulating region comprises an oxide.
</P>
<P>
38. A device according to claim 37, wherein the insulating region comprises aluminium oxide.
</P>
<P>
39. A device according to claim 37, wherein the insulating region comprises magnesium oxide.
</P>
<P>
40. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the insulating region has a thickness separating the conductive region and the non-ferromagnetic region of at least about 2 nm.
</P>
<P>
41. A device according to claim 40, wherein the thickness of the insulating region is no more than about 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
42. A device according to any one of claims 1 to 41, wherein the conductive region comprises a non-ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
43. A device according to claim 42, wherein the conductive region comprises a transition metal or an alloy including a transition metal.
</P>
<P>
44. A device according to claim 43, wherein the conductive region comprises platinum.
</P>
<P>
45. A device according to any one of claims 1 to 41, wherein the conductive region comprises a ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
46. A device according to any preceding claim, arranged as a multilayer stack including the ferromagnetic region, the non-ferromagnetic region, the insulating region and the conductive region.
</P>
<P>
47. A device according to any preceding claim, arranged as a pillar upstanding from a substrate.
</P>
<P>
48. A device according to claim 47, wherein the pillar has a width no more than about 10 [micro]m or width no more than about 1 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
49. A device according to claim 47 or 48, wherein the pillar has a width of the order of 10 nm or 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
50. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the conductive region includes a resonant tunnelling structure for filtering charge carriers.
</P>
<P>
51. A magnetic field sensor comprising a device according to any one of claims 1 to 50.
</P>
<P>
52. A read head for a hard disk drive comprising a device according to any one of claims 1 to 50.
</P>
<P>
53. A switching element comprising a device according to any one of claims 1 to 50.
</P>
<P>
54. A method of operating a magnetoresistive device according to any one of claims 1 to 50, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
applying a magnetic field to the magnetoresistive device; and
</P>
<P>
applying a bias between the ferromagnetic region and conductive region so as to determine a magnetoresistance.
</P>
<P>
55. A method of fabricating a magnetoresistive device, the method including:
</P>
<P>
forming a ferromagnetic region ;
</P>
<P>
forming a non-ferromagnetic region adjacent to the ferromagnetic region;
</P>
<P>
forming an insulating layer adjacent to the non-ferromagnetic region; and
</P>
<P>
forming a conductive region adjacent to the insulating region.
</P>
<P>
56. A method according to claim 55, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
etching the regions so as to form a pillar.
</P>
<P>
57. A method according to claim 55 or 56, comprising:
</P>
<P>
applying a magnetic field while depositing layers.
</P>
<P>
58. A method according to claim 55, 56 or 57, comprising:
</P>
<P>
applying stress while depositing layers.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009146232A1;US7939870B2;KR20090054907A;KR101105069B1;JP2009130371A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
