<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
REACTION METHOD, METAL OXIDE NANOPARTICLES OR CARBON CARRYING THE NANOPARTICLES, OBTAINED BY THE METHOD, ELECTRODES CONTAINING THE CARBON, AND ELECTROCHEMICAL DEVICES WITH THE ELECTRODES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2027916A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NAOI KATSUHIKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OGIHARA NOBUHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ISHIMOTO SHUICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAOI, KATSUHIKO
</Name>
<Name>
OGIHARA, NOBUHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
ISHIMOTO, SHUICHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
K &amp; W LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NIPPON CHEMICON [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
K &amp; W LIMITED
</Name>
<Name>
NIPPON CHEMI-CON CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2027916
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060833830
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006JP324027
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050356845
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-12-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J19/18
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01F7/16F4
</Class>
<Class>
B01F7/28B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J19/18B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J19/18M
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
H01G9/058
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/13
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/36K2
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/485
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/587
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/62
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E60/12B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention aims at: providing an accelerated reaction in a liquid-phase reaction;  forming, by way of the reaction, a metal oxide nanoparticle and carbon that carries the metal oxide nanoparticle in a highly dispersed state;  and providing an electrode containing the carbon and an electrochemical device using the electrode. In order to solve the above-mentioned problem, shear stress and centrifugal force are applied to the reactant in the rotating reactor so that an accelerated chemical reaction is attained in the course of the reaction. Further, the carbon carrying a metal oxide nanoparticle in a highly dispersed state comprises: a metal oxide nanoparticle produced by the accelerated chemical reaction, wherein shear stress and centrifugal force are applied to a reactant in a rotating reactor in the course of the reaction;  and carbon dispersed in the rotating reactor by applying shear stress and centrifugal force. An electrochemical device produced by using the carbon carrying the metal oxide nanoparticle as an electrode has high output and high capacity characteristics.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A reaction method for accelerating a chemical reaction, wherein shear stress and centrifugal force are applied to a reactant in a rotating reactor in the course of the chemical reaction.
</P>
<P>
2. A reaction method for accelerating a chemical reaction and for dispersing a product and carbon, wherein shear stress and centrifugal force are applied to a reactant and carbon in a rotating reactor in the course of the chemical reaction.
</P>
<P>
3. The reaction method according to claims 1 and 2 for accelerating the chemical reaction, wherein a thin film containing a reactant is produced in a rotating reactor and wherein shear stress and centrifugal force are applied to the thin film.
</P>
<P>
4. The reaction method according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the reactor comprises a pair of outer and inner concentric tubes, the inner tube having through-holes provided on the side thereof, and the outer tube having an end plate at an opening thereof,
</P>
<P>
wherein the reactant in the inner tube is caused, by centrifugal force generated from the rotation of the inner tube, to pass through the through-holes to the inside wall of the outer tube so that a thin film containing the reactant is produced on the inside wall of the outer tube, and
</P>
<P>
wherein shear stress and centrifugal force are applied to the thin film so that the chemical reaction is accelerated.
</P>
<P>
5. The reaction method according to claims 3 and 4, wherein the thin film is 5 mm or less in thickness.
</P>
<P>
6. The reaction method according to claims 4 and 5, wherein the centrifugal force to be applied to the reactant inside the inner tube of the reactor is 1500 N (kgms&amp;lt;-2&amp;gt;) or greater.
</P>
<P>
7. The reaction method according to claims 1 to 6, wherein the chemical reaction is a hydrolysis reaction and/or a condensation reaction of metallic salt.
</P>
<P>
8. A metal oxide nanoparticle formed in the reaction method according to claims 1 to 7.
</P>
<P>
9. A carbon that carries a metal oxide nanoparticle in a highly dispersed state, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a metal oxide nanoparticle produced by applying shear stress and centrifugal force to a reactant in a rotating reactor in the course of the chemical reaction; and a carbon dispersed by applying shear stress and centrifugal force in a rotating reactor.
</P>
<P>
10. A carbon that carries the metal oxide nanoparticle in a highly dispersed state according to claim 9 prepared by the reaction method according to claims 2 to 7.
</P>
<P>
11. An electrode that contains carbon carrying the metal oxide nanoparticle according to claims 9 and 10 in a highly dispersed state.
</P>
<P>
12. An electrochemical device using the electrode according to claim 11.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2027916A4;US2010025627A1;WO2007066581A1;WO2007066581A9;JP2007160151A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
