<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Dispersion of nanoparticles in organic solvents
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2048116A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BELT VAN DE ROELOF [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
CURRIE EDWIN [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
BELT, VAN DE, ROELOF
</Name>
<Name>
CURRIE, EDWIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CHEMIP B V [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
CHEMIP B.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2048116
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070118100
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-10-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070118100
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G19/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08F2/44
</Class>
<Class>
C08F292/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/22
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/5425
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/30
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/40
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/12
</Class>
<Class>
C09D1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D133/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09D151/10
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/03
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G19/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G25/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08F292/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08L51/10
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00K
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/30D12
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D12
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/12
</Class>
<Class>
C09D1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D151/10
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to a dispersion of nanoparticles in an organic solvent, comprising a) 5-75 wt% of nanoparticles having a mean average size between 1 and 100 nm. b) a solvent comprising a hydroxyl group and an ether group. c) a water content of less then 15wt%. d) a dispersant content of less then 0,1 wt%. The invention also relates to a method of making such a dispersion, by I. Making a mixture of an aqueous dispersion of particles having an average size between 1 and 100 nm, a solvent comprising a hydroxyl group and an ether group, which forms an azeotrope with water, and a grafting compound. II. Heating the mixture under stirring at a temperature between 20 and 150  DEG C. III. At least partially removing the solvent/water mixture. IV. Optionally adding more solvent. V. Repeating steps I and IV till the water content of the obtained dispersion is less then a desired value and the concentration solid is between 5 and 70 wt%.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Dispersion of nanoparticles in an organic solvent, comprising
</P>
<P>
a) 5-75 wt% of nanoparticles having a mean average size between 1 and 100 nm
</P>
<P>
b) A solvent comprising a hydroxyl group and an ether group
</P>
<P>
c) A water content of less then 15wt%
</P>
<P>
d) A dispersant content of less then 0,1 wt%.
</P>
<P>
2. The dispersion according to claim 1, wherein the amount of dispersant is less then 0,005 wt%.
</P>
<P>
3. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-2, wherein the solvent is chosen from the group consisting of 1-methoxy-2-propanol, 2-methoxy-1-propanol, 3-methoxy-1-butanol and 2-methoxy-ethanol.
</P>
<P>
4. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-3, wherein the nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of silica, alumina, zirconia, titanium oxide, zinc oxide, germanium oxide, indium oxide, tin oxide, indium- tin oxide (ITO), antimony oxide, antimony-tinoxide and cerium oxide.
</P>
<P>
5. the dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-4, wherein the nanoparticles comprise organic surface groups.
</P>
<P>
6. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-5, wherein the particles have been treated with grafting compounds having a hydrolysable silyl group.
</P>
<P>
7. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-6, wherein the particles have been treated with alkoxysilane compounds.
</P>
<P>
8. The dispersion according to claim 7, wherein the alkoxysilane is selected from the group consisting of methyltrimethoxysilane, methyltriethoxysilane, glycidoxypropyltrimethoxysilane, vinyltrimethoxysilane and methacryloxypropyltrimethoxysilane.
</P>
<P>
9. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 6-8, wherein the amount of grafting compounds added to the nanoparticles ranges between 2 and 40 wt% (relative to the weight of the nanoparticles).
</P>
<P>
10. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-9, wherein the composition comprises between 5 and 15 wt% ATO particles modified with 1 - 10 wt% 3-methacryloxypropyl trimethoxy silane (relative to particles).
</P>
<P>
11. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-9, wherein the composition comprises between 15 and 30 wt% ATO particles modified with 5-15 wt% 3-methacryloxypropyl trimethoxy silane (relative to particles).
</P>
<P>
12. The dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-9, wherein the composition comprises between 30 and 70 wt% ATO particles modified with 20-40 wt% 3-methacryloxypropyl trimethoxy silane (relative to particles).
</P>
<P>
13. Process for making the dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-12, comprising the steps of
</P>
<P>
I. Making a mixture of an aqueous dispersion of particles having an average size between 1 and 100 nm, a solvent comprising a hydroxyl group and an ether group, which forms an azeotrope with water, and a grafting compound
</P>
<P>
II. Heating the mixture under stirring at a temperature between 20 and 150 [deg.]C
</P>
<P>
III. At least partially removing the solvent/water mixture,
</P>
<P>
IV. Optionally adding more solvent comprising a solvent comprising a hydroxyl group and an ether group, which forms an azeotrope with water,
</P>
<P>
V. Repeating steps III and IV till the water content of the obtained dispersion is less then a desired value and the concentration solid is between 5 and 70 wt%.
</P>
<P>
14. Process according to claim 13, wherein the ratio of water to organic solvent in step I ranges between 0.1 and 10.
</P>
<P>
15. Process according to claim 13, wherein the ration of water to organic solvent in step I ranges between 0.3 and 4.
</P>
<P>
16. Coating composition comprising a dispersion according to anyone of claims 1-12.
</P>
<P>
17. The coating composition according to claim 16, wherein the composition comprises a curable component.
</P>
<P>
18. The coating composition according to claim 17, wherein the curable component is a UV curable component, and wherein the composition comprises a photoinitiator.
</P>
<P>
19. The coating composition according to claim 18, wherein the UV curable component is a compound having (meth)acrylate groups.
</P>
<P>
20. Use of the coating composition according to anyone of claims 16-19 for preparing a coating on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
21. Use according to claim 20, wherein the substrate is a triacetylcellulose film.
</P>
<P>
22. Coated film comprising a cured coating composition according to 17-19 on a substrate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010311859A1;KR20100089843A;JP2010540404A;WO2009047302A1;EP2203388A1;CN101896430A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
