<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Topologically structured polymer coating
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2014739A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SEIBERLE HUBERT [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
SCHADT MARTIN [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
IBN-ELHAJ MOHAMMED [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
BENECKE CARSTEN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
SCHMITT KLAUS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
SEIBERLE, HUBERT
</Name>
<Name>
SCHADT, MARTIN
</Name>
<Name>
IBN-ELHAJ, MOHAMMED
</Name>
<Name>
BENECKE, CARSTEN
</Name>
<Name>
SCHMITT, KLAUS
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ROLIC AG [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
ROLIC AG
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2014739
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080105038
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2000-10-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20000965716
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2000-10-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB19990024746
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-10-19
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB19990025458
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-10-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C41/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09K19/54
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/10
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/11
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/02
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/18
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/30
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/1334
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/1335
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/1337
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/139
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B29C41/00B
</Class>
<Class>
B29K995/00F19
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09K19/54A
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/18M
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/30R
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/1337T
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Sub-micron-structured (nanostructured) polymer film or coatings are made by coating a substrate with a mixture of materials. One of the materials is removed using a selective solvent, leaving pores or other nanostructure. The substrate may be grooved, providing a competing nanostructure. The coating may act as an antireflective coating, optical retarder, optical diffuser, or orientation layer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of making a replica of an isotropic or anisotropic topological polymer film or coating using an isotropic or anisotropic topological polymer film or coating comprising a material which has hollows and/or topological structure, wherein the material is crosslinked.
</P>
<P>
2. A method of making a replica of an isotropic or anisotropic topological structure, characterized in that the isotropic or anisotropic topological structure is a replica made according to Claim 1.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to any of the preceding Claims, wherein the replica is made of a material selected from the group: metals, pre-polymers, polymers, dielectrics.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to any of the preceding Claims, wherein the material for the replica is applied onto the isotropic or anisotropic topological structure, optionally further handled, preferably by heating, by exposition to heat or light, or by coating and then separated from the underlying structure.
</P>
<P>
5. Replica of an isotropic or anisotropic topological structure made according to any of the preceding Claims.
</P>
<P>
6. A method of creating a topologically structured polymer film or coating, in particular for use in a method according to one of the preceding claims, comprising mixing at least two materials, applying the mixture to a substrate and removing at least one of the materials, characterized in that at least one material is not cross-linkable and at least one other material is, that other material being cross-linked after application to the substrate.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to claim 6, characterized in that a solvent is used to remove the at least one material.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to Claim 6 or 7, wherein the cross-linkable material comprises molecules of a rod-like shape, and/or wherein the cross-linkable material is liquid crystalline and/or wherein the non-cross-linkable material is liquid crystalline preferably nematic liquid crystalline.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to any of Claims 6 - 8, wherein the cross-linkable material is maintained in an oriented state during crosslinking, wherein preferably the orientation is imposed by an underlying orientation layer, and wherein most preferably the underlying orientation layer is a photo-oriented layer such as an azo dye or linearly polymerized photopolymer.
</P>
<P>
10. A topologically structured polymer film or coating, in particular for use in a method according to any of the claims 1 to 5, which has been created by a method according to any of Claims 6-9.
</P>
<P>
11. A topologically structured polymer film or coating on a substrate in particular for use in a method according to any of the claims 1 to 5, comprising a material which has hollows and/or topological structure, characterized in that the material is crosslinked, wherein preferably the crosslinked material is a liquid crystal polymer.
</P>
<P>
12. An assembly comprising a layer of alignable molecules in contact with a replica according to Claim 5, the molecules being aligned thereby.
</P>
<P>
13. An antireflective surface comprising a replica according to Claim 5.
</P>
<P>
14. An optical display device comprising a replica according to Claim 5.
</P>
<P>
15. An element for protection against forgery and/or copying, comprising a replica according to Claim 5.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO0129148A1;US2007020404A1;US2009136687A1;JP2003512641A;JP4928038B2;EP1230319A1;EP1230319B1;CN1377399A;CN1220754C;AU7638600A;AT405623T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
