<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR MANUFACTURE OF SILVER- BASED PARTICLES AND ELECTRICAL CONTACT MATERIALS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2004551A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GOIA DAN V [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FRITZSCHE SEBASTIAN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KEMPF BERND [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BRAUMANN PETER [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
VANDEVELDE THIERRY CHARLES SIMON [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
GOIA, DAN, V
</Name>
<Name>
FRITZSCHE, SEBASTIAN
</Name>
<Name>
KEMPF, BERND
</Name>
<Name>
BRAUMANN, PETER
</Name>
<Name>
VANDEVELDE, THIERRY, CHARLES, SIMON
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UMICORE SA [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
UMICORE SA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2004551
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070723739
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP02795
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-29
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060394826
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G5/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01H1/021
</Class>
<Class>
H01H1/0233
</Class>
<Class>
H01H1/0237
</Class>
<Class>
H01H1/027
</Class>
<Class>
H01H11/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01R13/03
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B2
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G5/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01H1/021
</Class>
<Class>
H01H11/04C
</Class>
<Class>
H01R13/03
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention is directed to a process for manufacture of fine precious metal containing particles, specifically silver-based particles and silver-based contact materials via an intermediate silver(+l)-oxide species. The process comprises in a first step the formation of a thermally instable silver (+l)-oxide species by adding a base to an aqueous silver salt solution comprising an organic dispersing agent. Due to the presence of the organic dispersing agent, the resulting silver (+l)-oxide species is thermally instable, thus the species is decomposing to metallic silver at temperature lower than 1000 DEG C. The process optionally may comprise the addition of a powdered compound selected from the group of inorganic oxides, metals, and carbon-based compounds. Furthermore the process may contain additional separating and drying steps.;  The process is versatile, cost efficient and environmentally friendly and is used for the manufacture of silver-based particles and electrical contact materials. Silver nanoparticles made according to the process are characterized by a narrow particle size distribution. Electrical contact materials manufactured according to the process reveal improved contact welding properties.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed:
</P>
<P>
1. A thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species, wherein said species decomposes to metallic silver at temperatures lower than 100[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
2. The silver(+l)-oxide species according to claim 1, wherein said species comprises hydroxy- (OH), oxy- (O), hydrocarboxy- (HCO3) or carboxy- (CO3) groups and mixtures or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
3. The silver(+l)-oxide species according to claim 1 or 2, wherein said species further comprises precious metals species selected from the group consisting of gold (Au), platinum (Pt), rhodium (Rh), palladium (Pd) and mixtures or alloys thereof, up to an amount of 20 wt.-% based on the total weight of said species.
</P>
<P>
4. A process for manufacture of the thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species defined in any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein a base is reacted with a silver(+l) salt solution in the presence of an organic dispersing agent.
</P>
<P>
5. The process according to claim 4, further comprising the separation of the silver(+l)- oxide species after the reaction and an optional drying step.
</P>
<P>
6. The process according to claim 4 or 5, wherein the silver salt solution and the base are added simultaneously to a solution containing the organic dispersing agent.
</P>
<P>
7. The process according to claim 4, wherein the organic dispersing agent is a surface- active polar compound selected from the group consisting of anionic surfactants, cati- onic surfactants, non-ionic surfactants, ampholytic surfactants, polar organic solvents, protective colloids, stabilizing agents and mixtures and/or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The process according to claim 4, wherein the organic dispersing agent is a polar organic ketone solvent.
</P>
<P>
9. The process according to claim 4, wherein the organic dispersing agent is a polysac- charide.
</P>
<P>
10. The process according to claim 4, wherein the ratio of water/organic dispersing agent in the reaction mixture (prior to starting the process) is in the range of 100: 1 to 1 :6, preferably in the range of 50:1 to 1 :3.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The process according to claim 4, wherein silver nitrate, silver acetate, silver oxalate, silver citrate, silver sulfate, or silver thiosulfate and mixtures and combinations thereof are used as silver salts.
</P>
<P>
12. The process according to claim 4, wherein aqueous solutions of sodium hydroxide (NaOH), potassium hydroxide (KOH), lithium hydroxide (LiOH), sodium carbonate (Na2CO3), potassium carbonate (K2CO3) and mixtures or combinations thereof are used as base.
</P>
<P>
13. A process for manufacture of silver-based particles, comprising the steps of a) preparing a thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species in a reaction mixture according to the process of any one of claims 4 to 12, and b) heating the reaction mixture to a temperature lower than 100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, thereby decomposing said thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species to metallic silver.
</P>
<P>
14. The process according to claim 13, further comprising the step of separating the silver-based particles from the mixture and optionally the step of drying the particles.
</P>
<P>
15. The process according to claim 13 or 14, wherein step a) comprises the simultaneous addition of an silver salt solution and a base to a solution containing the organic dispersing agent to form the thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species.
</P>
<P>
16. The process according to claim 13, wherein the medium particle size (d50) of the silver-based particles is in the range of 1 to 1,000 nm, preferably in the range of 1 to 750 nm, and most preferably in the range of 1 to 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
17. The process according to claim 13, wherein the medium particle size (d50) of the silver-based particles is in the range of 10 to 30 nm.
</P>
<P>
18. A process for manufacture of a silver-based electrical contact material comprising the steps of: a) preparing a thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species according to the process of any one of claims 4 to 12 in the presence of a powdered compound to form a reaction mixture, and b) heating the reaction mixture to a temperature lower than 100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, thereby decomposing said thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species to metallic silver in the presence of said powdered compound.
</P>
<P>
19. The process according to claim 18, further comprising separating the silver-based contact material from the reaction mixture and optionally drying said contact material.
</P>
<P>
20. The process according to claim 18, wherein step a) comprises the simultaneous addition of a silver salt solution and a base to a solution containing the organic dispersing agent to form the thermally instable silver(+l)-oxide species in the presence of a powdered compound.
</P>
<P>
21. The process according to claim 18, wherein the powdered compound is selected from the group of inorganic oxides, metals, carbon-based compounds (including carbides), and mixtures and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
22. The process according to claim 18, wherein the powdered compound is an inorganic oxide such as SnO2, In2O3, Bi2O3, CuO, MoO3, WO3, ZnO, NbO3, TiO2, SiO2, ZrO2, HfO3, GeO2, a metal such as Ni, Co, W, a carbon-based compound such as WC, carbon black, graphite, carbon fibers or carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
23. The process according to claim 18, wherein the amount of the powdered compound is in the range of 1 to 80 wt.-%, preferably in the range of 5 to 50 wt.-%, based on the total weight of the silver-based contact material.
</P>
<P>
24. The process according to any one of claims 18 to 23, further comprising the separa- tion of the product from the reaction mixture after step b), the redispersing of the product in water and the addition of an additional powdered compound.
</P>
<P>
25. A silver-based electrical contact material made by the process according to any one of claims 18 to 24.
</P>
<P>
26. Silver-based particles made by the process of any one of claims 13 to 17.
</P>
<P>
27. Silver-based particles with a medium particle size (d50) in the range of 1 to 50 nm, wherein the maximum particle size (dlOO in nm) is given by the correlation: dlOO (nm) &amp;lt; 3 x d50 (nm) .
</P>
<P>
28. Silver-based particles with a medium particle size (d50) in the range of 1 to 50 nm, preferably in the range of 10 to 30 nm, wherein the dlO, d50 and d90 values (in nm) comply to the following correlation: [d9O - dlO ] / d5O &amp;lt; 1.3
</P>
<P>
29. Conductive ink comprising the silver-based particles according to claim 26.
</P>
<P>
30. Conductive ink comprising the silver-based particles according to claim 27.
</P>
<P>
31. Conductive ink comprising the silver-based particles according to claim 28.
</P>
<P>
32. Conductive silver ink according to any one of claims 29 to 31, wherein the ink is water-based.
</P>
<P>
33. Conductive silver ink according to any one of claims 29 to 31, wherein the ink is organic-based.
</P>
<P>
34. Conductive silver ink according to any one of claims 29 to 33, wherein the silver content is in the range of 5 to 50 wt.-%, preferably 10 to 30 wt.-% based on the total weight of the formulation.
</P>
<P>
35. Use of the silver-based particles according to claim 26 for antimicrobial applications.
</P>
<P>
36. Use of the silver-based particles according to claim 27 for antimicrobial applications.
</P>
<P>
37. Use of the silver-based particles according to claim 28 for antimicrobial applications.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007112926A2;WO2007112926A3;US2007234851A1;US7842274B2;TW200804194A;KR20080112318A;JP2009531540A;CN101415644A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
