<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CARBON NANOTUBE REINFORCED POLYMER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2013268A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KONING CORNELIS [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
GROSSIORD NADIA [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
MEULDIJK JAN [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
LOOS JOACHIM [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KONING, CORNELIS
</Name>
<Name>
GROSSIORD, NADIA
</Name>
<Name>
MEULDIJK, JAN
</Name>
<Name>
LOOS, JOACHIM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
STICHTING DUTCH POLYMER INST [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
STICHTING DUTCH POLYMER INSTITUTE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2013268
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070724085
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-04-06
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP03144
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-06
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060008273
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006EP10362
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070724085
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-06
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08J9/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08J9/00M2
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a (process for preparation of a) carbon nanotubes reinforced polymer, wherein the matrix polymer has both a low molecular weight fraction as well as a high molecular weight fraction, as a result of which the level of conductivity of the resulting composite can be controlled.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Process for the preparation of a carbon nanotube reinforced polymer by: a) contacting carbon nanotubes in an aqueous medium with a water-soluble component, being either a water-soluble first polymer or a water-soluble surfactant; b) mixing the resulting product from step a) with an aqueous latex of a second polymer; c) removing water from the so obtained mixture; d) heating the product from step c) to a temperature at which the second polymer flows; and e) solidifying the product of step d) into a desired form; wherein the second polymer has both a low molar mass fraction and a high molar mass fraction, the low molar mass fraction having a weight averaged molecular weight (Mw) of between 500 and 20,000 g/mol, the high molar mass fraction having an Mw of between 20,000 and 5,000,000 g/mol, and the low mass fraction is present in the second polymer in an amount greater than 5 wt. %.
</P>
<P>
2. Process according to claim 1 , wherein the second polymer is a composition of two miscible polymers, either based on different monomers or based on the same monomers, one polymer forming the low molar mass fraction, the other one forming the high molar mass fraction.
</P>
<P>
3. Process according to anyone of claims 1-2, wherein the second polymer is obtained by mixing a low Mw-polymer with a high Mw-polymer. 4. Process according to anyone of claims 1-2, wherein the second polymer is obtained by applying polymerization conditions, resulting in a broad molar mass distribution, comprising both a low Mw-polymer (with an Mw between 500 and 20,000 g/mol) and a high Mw-polymer (with an Mw between 20,000 and 5,000,000 g/mol. 5. Process according to anyone of claims 1-4, wherein the second polymer is a copolymer of styrene with either a (meth-)acrylate, maleic anhydride, a maleimide, a 2- or 4-vinylpyridine, acrylonitrile, or another vinyl or vinylidene type monomer. 6. Process according to anyone of claims 1-5, wherein the low molar mass fraction is present in the second polymer in an amount of at least 6.5 wt. %.
</P>
<P>
7. Process according to anyone of claims 1-6, wherein the low molar mass fraction is present in the second polymer in an amount of at most 40 wt. %.
</P>
<P>
8. Process according to anyone of claims 1-7, wherein single wall carbon nanotubes are used. 9. Carbon nanotubes reinforced polymer, obtained by a process according to anyone of claims 1-8.
</P>
<P>
10. Carbon nanotubes reinforced polymer according to claim 9, wherein the resistivity is less than 100 [Omega]&amp;lt;*&amp;gt;cm.
</P>
<P>
11. Carbon nanotubes reinforced polymer according to anyone of claims 9-10, wherein the ratio between the low molar mass part of the second polymer and the high molar mass part of the second polymer is between 0.065 and 0.67.
</P>
<P>
12. Carbon nanotubes reinforced polymer according to claim 11 wherein the ratio is between 0.10 and 0.25.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007121780A1;US2010069559A1;TW200804475A;KR20090034808A;JP2009534213A;CN101426838A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
