<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PHOTOVOLTAIC CELL WITH SILOLE- CONTAINING POLYMER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2082437A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GAUDIANA RUSSELL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KINGSBOROUGH RICHARD [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SHI XIAOBO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WALLER DAVID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHU ZHENGGUO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GAUDIANA, RUSSELL
</Name>
<Name>
KINGSBOROUGH, RICHARD
</Name>
<Name>
SHI, XIAOBO
</Name>
<Name>
WALLER, DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
ZHU, ZHENGGUO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONARKA TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KONARKA TECHNOLOGIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2082437
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070872313
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-10-01
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US80053
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060850963P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-11
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L27/30
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/068
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/44
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M16
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M2B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Photovoltaic cells with silole-containing polymers, as well as related systems, methods and components are disclosed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. An article, comprising: a first electrode; a second electrode; and a photoactive material disposed between the first and second electrodes, the photoactive material comprising a polymer including a first comonomer repeat unit and a second comonomer repeat unit different from the first comonomer repeat unit; wherein the first comonomer repeat unit comprises a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (1):
</P>
<P>
in which each of Ri, R2, R3, and R4, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R; R being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (I), a benzothiadiazole moiety, a thiadiazoloquinoxaline moiety, a cyclopentadithiophene moiety, a cyclopentadithiophene oxide moiety, a benzoisothiazole moiety, a benzothiazole moiety, a thiophene oxide moiety, a thienothiophene moiety, a thienothiophene oxide moiety, a dithienothiophene moiety, a dithienothiophene oxide moiety, a tetrahydroisoindole moiety, a fluorene moiety, a fluorenone moiety, a thiazole moiety, a selenophene moiety, a silole moiety, a thiazolothiazole moiety, a cyclopentadithiazole moiety, a naphthothiadiazole moiety, a thienopyrazine moiety, an oxazole moiety, an imidazole moiety, a pyrimidine moiety, a benzoxazole moiety, or a benzimidazole moiety; and the article is configured as a photovoltaic cell.
</P>
<P>
2. The article of claim 1, wherein each of Ri and R2, independently, is C1- C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
3. The article of claim 1, wherein each of Ri and R2 is hexyl.
</P>
<P>
4. The article of claim 1 , wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a benzothiadiazole moiety of formula (2), a thiadiazoloquinoxaline moiety of formula (3), a cyclopentadithiophene dioxide moiety of formula (4), a cyclopentadithiophene monoxide moiety of formula (5), a benzoisothiazole moiety of formula (6), a benzothiazole moiety of formula (7), a thiophene dioxide moiety of formula (8), a cyclopentadithiophene dioxide moiety of formula (9), a cyclopentadithiophene tetraoxide moiety of formula (10), a thienothiophene moiety of formula (11), a thienothiophene tetraoxide moiety of formula (12), a dithienothiophene moiety of formula (13), a dithienothiophene dioxide moiety of formula (14), a dithienothiophene tetraoxide moiety of formula (15), a tetrahydroisoindole moiety of formula (16), a thienothiophene dioxide moiety of formula (17), a dithienothiophene dioxide moiety of formula (18), a fluorene moiety of formula (19), a silole moiety of formula (20), a cyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (21), a fluorenone moiety of formula (22), a thiazole moiety of formula (23), a selenophene moiety of formula (24), a thiazolothiazole moiety of formula (25), a cyclopentadithiazole moiety of formula (26), a naphthothiadiazole moiety of formula (27), a thienopyrazine moiety of formula (28), an oxazole moiety of formula (29), an imidazole moiety of formula (30), a pyrimidine moiety of formula (31), a benzoxazole moiety of formula (32), or a benzimidazole moiety of formula (33):
</P>
<P>
wherein each of X and Y, independently, is CH2, O, or S; each of R5 and R6, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R, in which R is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or C 1-C20 heterocycloalkyl; and each OfR7 and Rg, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C2O cycloalkyl, or C3-C20heterocycloalkyl.
</P>
<P>
5. The article of claim 4, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a benzothiadiazole moiety of formula (2), in which each of R5 and R6 is H.
</P>
<P>
6. The article of claim 4, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiazole moiety of formula (23), in which R5 is hexyl.
</P>
<P>
7. The article of claim 1 , wherein the polymer further comprises a third comonomer repeat unit different from the first and second comonomer repeat units.
</P>
<P>
8. The article of claim 7, wherein the third comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety.
</P>
<P>
9. The article of claim 8, wherein the thiophene moiety is unsubstituted or substituted with hexyl.
</P>
<P>
10. An article, comprising: a first electrode; a second electrode; and a photoactive material disposed between the first and second electrodes, in which the photoactive material comprising a polymer including a first comonomer repeat unit and a second comonomer repeat unit different from the first comonomer repeat unit; wherein the first comonomer repeat unit comprises a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (1):
</P>
<P>
in which each of Ri, R2, R3, and R4, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R; R being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety substituted with Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR&apos;, C(O)R&apos;, C(O)OR&apos;, or SO2R&apos;; or a thiophene moiety fused with a 1,4-dioxane moiety; R&apos; being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; and the article is configured as a photovoltaic cell.
</P>
<P>
11. The article of claim 10, wherein each of Ri and R2, independently, is Ci-C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
12. The article of claim 11, wherein each of Ri and R2 is hexyl.
</P>
<P>
13. The article of claim 10, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety substituted with Ci-C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
14. The article of claim 13, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety substituted with hexyl.
</P>
<P>
15. An article, comprising : a first electrode; a second electrode; and a photoactive material disposed between the first and second electrodes, in which the photoactive material comprising a polymer including a first comonomer repeat unit and a second comonomer repeat unit different from the first comonomer repeat unit; wherein the first comonomer repeat unit comprises a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (1):
</P>
<P>
in which each of Ri, R2, R3, and R4, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R; R being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; the second comonomer repeat unit is not an unsubstituted thiophene moiety; and the article is configured as a photovoltaic cell.
</P>
<P>
16. A polymer, comprising : a first comonomer repeat unit comprising a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (1):
</P>
<P>
in which each of Ri, R2, R3, and R4, independently, is H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R; R being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; and a second comonomer repeat unit comprising a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (I), a benzothiadiazole moiety, a thiadiazoloquinoxaline moiety, a cyclopentadithiophene moiety, a cyclopentadithiophene oxide moiety, a benzoisothiazole moiety, a benzothiazole moiety, a thiophene oxide moiety, a thienothiophene moiety, a thienothiophene oxide moiety, a dithienothiophene moiety, a dithienothiophene oxide moiety, a tetrahydroisoindole moiety, a fluorene moiety, a fluorenone moiety, a thiazole moiety, a selenophene moiety, a silole moiety, a thiazolothiazole moiety, a cyclopentadithiazole moiety, a naphthothiadiazole moiety, a thienopyrazine moiety, an oxazole moiety, an imidazole moiety, a pyrimidine moiety, a benzoxazole moiety, or a benzimidazole moiety.
</P>
<P>
17. The polymer of claim 16, wherein each of Ri and R2, independently, is Ci-C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
18. The polymer of claim 16, wherein each of Ri and R2 is hexyl.
</P>
<P>
19. The polymer of claim 16, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a benzothiadiazole moiety of formula (2), a thiadiazoloquinoxaline moiety of formula (3), a cyclopentadithiophene dioxide moiety of formula (4), a cyclopentadithiophene monoxide moiety of formula (5), a benzoisothiazole moiety of formula (6), a benzothiazole moiety of formula (7), a thiophene dioxide moiety of formula (8), a cyclopentadithiophene dioxide moiety of formula (9), a cyclopentadithiophene tetraoxide moiety of formula (10), a thienothiophene moiety of formula (11), a thienothiophene tetraoxide moiety of formula (12), a dithienothiophene moiety of formula (13), a dithienothiophene dioxide moiety of formula (14), a dithienothiophene tetraoxide moiety of formula (15), a tetrahydroisoindole moiety of formula (16), a thienothiophene dioxide moiety of formula (17), a dithienothiophene dioxide moiety of formula (18), a fluorene moiety of formula (19), a silole moiety of formula (20), a cyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (21), a fluorenone moiety of formula (22), a thiazole moiety of formula (23), a selenophene moiety of formula (24), a thiazolothiazole moiety of formula (25), a cyclopentadithiazole moiety of formula (26), a naphthothiadiazole moiety of formula (27), a thienopyrazine moiety of formula (28), an oxazole moiety of formula (29), an imidazole moiety of formula (30), a pyrimidine moiety of formula (31), a benzoxazole moiety of formula (32), or a benzimidazole moiety of formula (33):
</P>
<P>
wherein each of X and Y, independently, is CH2, O, or S; each of R5 and R6, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R, in which R is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or C1-C20 heterocycloalkyl; and each OfR7 and Rs, independently, is H, Ci-C2O alkyl, Ci-C2O alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C2o cycloalkyl, or C3-C2o heterocycloalkyl.
</P>
<P>
20. The polymer of claim 19, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a benzothiadiazole moiety of formula (2), in which each of R5 and R6 is H.
</P>
<P>
21. The polymer of claim 19, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiazole moiety of formula (23), in which R5 is hexyl.
</P>
<P>
22. The polymer of claim 16, wherein the polymer further comprises a third comonomer repeat unit different from the first and second comonomer repeat units.
</P>
<P>
23. The polymer of claim 22, wherein the third comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety.
</P>
<P>
24. The polymer of claim 23, wherein the thiophene moiety is unsubstituted or substituted with hexyl.
</P>
<P>
25. A polymer, comprising: a first comonomer repeat unit comprising a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (1):
</P>
<P>
in which each of Ri, R2, R3, and R4, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R; R being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; and a second comonomer repeat unit comprising a thiophene moiety substituted with Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR&apos;, C(O)R&apos;, C(O)OR&apos;, or SO2R&apos;; or a thiophene moiety fused with a 1,4-dioxane moiety; R&apos; being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl.
</P>
<P>
26. The polymer of claim 25, wherein each of Ri and R2, independently, is Ci-C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
27. The polymer of claim 26, wherein each of Ri and R2 is hexyl.
</P>
<P>
28. The polymer of claim 25, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety substituted with C1-C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
29. The polymer of claim 28, wherein the second comonomer repeat unit comprises a thiophene moiety substituted with hexyl.
</P>
<P>
30. A polymer, comprising: a first comonomer repeat unit comprising a silacyclopentadithiophene moiety of formula (1):
</P>
<P>
in which each of Ri, R2, R3, and R4, independently, is H, C1-C20 alkyl, C1-C20 alkoxy, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, C1-C20 heterocycloalkyl, aryl, heteroaryl, halo, CN, OR, C(O)R, C(O)OR, or SO2R; R being H, Ci-C20 alkyl, Ci-C20 alkoxy, aryl, heteroaryl, C3-C20 cycloalkyl, or Ci-C20 heterocycloalkyl; and a second comonomer repeat unit that is not an unsubstituted thiophene moiety.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2082437A4;WO2008088595A2;WO2008088595A3;JP2010507233A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
