<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SURFACE-COATED ALUMINUM OXIDE NANOPARTICLE AND RESIN COMPOSITION THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2048189A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FUJITA NAOKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KAWA MANABU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SOMA MINORU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ODA TAKASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UNNO HARUO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MOROHOSHI KATSUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ITO TOMOHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KAI YASUAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MURAMATSU HIRONOBU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUJITA, NAOKO
</Name>
<Name>
KAWA, MANABU
</Name>
<Name>
SOMA, MINORU
</Name>
<Name>
ODA, TAKASHI
</Name>
<Name>
UNNO, HARUO
</Name>
<Name>
MOROHOSHI, KATSUMI
</Name>
<Name>
ITO, TOMOHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
KAI, YASUAKI
</Name>
<Name>
MURAMATSU, HIRONOBU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NISSAN MOTOR [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NISSAN MOTOR CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2048189
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070791670
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-07-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP64985
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060212261
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/06
</Class>
<Class>
C08L69/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/40
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/40F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles capable of being uniformly blended into polycarbonate resin in a good dispersed state while maintaining a molecular weight of the polycarbonate resin at a specific level or more. Surfaces of the surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles are coated with a dispersant and a silylation reagent.;  In a case where a monochromated Al-Ka ray is irradiated onto a sample surface by using an X-ray photoelectron spectroscope, when a surface element composition is calculated from an obtained photoelectron peak area, contents (atm%) of nitrogen atoms, thiol-derived sulfur atoms, and halogen atoms in the surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles are individually 2 or less, and when the surface element composition is calculated from obtained photoelectron peak areas of Al2p and Si2s, a concentration (mol%) of silicon atoms with respect to aluminum atoms is 0.05 to 30.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles of which surfaces are coated with a dispersant and a silylation reagent,
</P>
<P>
wherein contents (atm%) of nitrogen atoms, thiol-derived sulfur atoms, and halogen atoms in the surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles are individually 2 or less when a monochromated Al-Ka ray is irradiated onto a sample surface by using an X-ray photoelectron spectroscope, and a surface element composition is calculated from an obtained photoelectron peak area, and
</P>
<P>
a concentration (mol%) of silicon atoms with respect to aluminum atoms is 0.05 to 30 when the monochromated Al-Ka ray is irradiated onto the sample surface by using the X-ray photoelectron spectroscope, and the surface element composition is calculated from obtained photoelectron peak areas of Al2p and Si2s.
</P>
<P>
2. A surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the dispersant is one type or two or more types selected from the group consisting of organic sulfonic acid, organic phosphoric acid and derivatives of these.
</P>
<P>
3. A surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the dispersant comprises an organic acid with at least carbon number of 8 or more.
</P>
<P>
4. A surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein residues of the silylation reagent have alkyl groups and/or aryl groups.
</P>
<P>
5. Organic sol comprising a surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
6. A resin composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 1; and polycarbonate resin.
</P>
<P>
7. A resin composition comprising: surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles of which surfaces are coated with a dispersant and a silylation reagent; and polycarbonate resin, wherein haze measured by a method of JIS K7105 is 40% or less.
</P>
<P>
8. A resin composition according to claim 7, wherein a concentration (mol%) of silicon atoms derived from the silylation reagent with respect to aluminum atoms in the resin composition is 0.05 to 30.
</P>
<P>
9. A resin composition according to claim 7, wherein the dispersant comprises organic acid with at least carbon number of 8 or more.
</P>
<P>
10. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles, comprising: treating aluminum oxide nanoparticles with a silylation reagent,
</P>
<P>
wherein the silylation reagent is a monofunctional silylation reagent and/or a bifunctional silylation reagent, and atomic ratios of nitrogen atoms, sulfur atoms and halogen atoms with respect to silicon atoms in the silylation reagent are individually 0.05 or less.
</P>
<P>
11. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 10, wherein the silylation reagent is a silylation reagent represented by a following general formula (1) and/or a silylation reagent represented by a following general formula (2):
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;SiX (1)
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt;SiX&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;X&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; (2)
</P>
<P>
where, in the formulas (1) and (2), R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; to R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; represent alkyl groups or aryl groups independently of one another, and X, X&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and X&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; represent hydrogen atoms, hydrolytic substituents or hydroxyl groups independently of one another.
</P>
<P>
12. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 11, wherein X, X&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and X&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; are hydrogen atoms, acetoxy groups, alkoxy groups with a carbon number of 1 to 4, or hydroxyl groups independently of one another.
</P>
<P>
13. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 11, wherein the silylation reagent is represented by the general formula (1).
</P>
<P>
14. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 10, wherein an usage amount of the silylation reagent with respect to 1 weight part of the aluminum oxide nanoparticles is within a range of 0.001 to 50 weight parts.
</P>
<P>
15. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 10, wherein the treating the aluminum oxide nanoparticles with the silylation reagent is performed in a vapor phase.
</P>
<P>
16. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 10, further comprising: treating the aluminum oxide nanoparticles with a dispersant.
</P>
<P>
17. A production method of surface-coated aluminum oxide nanoparticles according to claim 10, wherein a dispersant comprises an organic acid with at least carbon number of 8 or more.
</P>
<P>
18. A production method of an organic sol, comprising: treating aluminum oxide nanoparticles with a silylation reagent, wherein the silylation reagent is a monofunctional silylation reagent and/or a bifunctional silylation reagent, and atomic ratios of nitrogen atoms, sulfur atoms and halogen atoms with respect to silicon atoms in the silylation reagent are individually 0.05 or less.
</P>
<P>
19. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 18, wherein the silylation reagent is a silylation reagent represented by a following general formula (1) and/or a silylation reagent represented by a following general formula (2):
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;SiX (1)
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt;SiX&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;X&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; (2)
</P>
<P>
where, in the formulas (1) and (2), R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; to R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; represent alkyl groups or aryl groups independently of one another, and X, X&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and X&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; represent hydrogen atoms, hydrolytic substituents or hydroxyl groups independently of one another.
</P>
<P>
20. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 19, wherein X, X&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and X&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; are hydrogen atoms, acetoxy groups, alkoxy groups with a carbon number of 1 to 4, or hydroxyl groups independently of one another.
</P>
<P>
21. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 19, wherein the silylation reagent is represented by the general formula (1).
</P>
<P>
22. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 18, wherein a usage amount of the silylation reagent with respect to 1 weight part of the aluminum oxide nanoparticles is within a range of 0.001 to 50 weight parts.
</P>
<P>
23. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 18, wherein the treating aluminum oxide nanoparticles with the silylation reagent is performed in a vapor phase.
</P>
<P>
24. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 18, further comprising: treating the aluminum oxide nanoparticles with a dispersant.
</P>
<P>
25. A production method of an organic sol according to claim 18, wherein the dispersant comprises an organic acid with at least carbon number of 8 or more.
</P>
<P>
26. A molded body comprising: a resin composition according to claim 6.
</P>
<P>
27. A molded body comprising: a resin composition according to claim 7.
</P>
<P>
28. A molded body of a polycarbonate resin composition containing aluminum oxide nanoparticles, wherein haze is 5% or less, and a modulus of elasticity in tension is 5 GPa or more.
</P>
<P>
29. A molded body of a polycarbonate resin composition containing aluminum oxide nanoparticles, wherein haze is 5% or less, and a coefficient of linear thermal expansion is 45 ppm/K or less.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2048189A4;US2009326097A1;WO2008016048A1;CN101501124A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
