<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR PRODUCING METAL NANOPOWDERS BY DECOMPOSITION OF METAL CARBONYL USING AN INDUCTION PLASMA TORCH
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2040867A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
PASERIN VLADIMIR [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
ADAMS RICHARD S [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
BOULOS MAHER I [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
JUREWICZ JERZY [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
GUO JIAYIN [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
PASERIN, VLADIMIR
</Name>
<Name>
ADAMS, RICHARD, S
</Name>
<Name>
BOULOS, MAHER, I
</Name>
<Name>
JUREWICZ, JERZY
</Name>
<Name>
GUO, JIAYIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CVRD INCO LTD [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
TEKNA PLASMA SYSTEMS INC [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
CVRD INCO LIMITED
</Name>
<Name>
TEKNA PLASMA SYSTEMS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2040867
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070719887
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007CA00970
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060444793
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F9/06
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/30
</Class>
<Class>
C01G1/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/30C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process for synthesizing metal nanopowders by introducing metal carbonyl into an induction plasma torch. By taking advantage of the much lower dissolution temperature of carbonyl as opposed to the high melting temperature of conventional metal powder feeds less torch power is required. Moreover, in contrast to current powder production techniques utilizing electrode based plasma torches, the induction plasma torch does not introduce contaminants into the nanopowder.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A process for producing metal nanopowders, the process comprising: a) providing metal carbonyl, b) introducing the metal carbonyl into an induction plasma torch, c) causing the metal carbonyl to decompose within the induction plasma torch and form nanopowder metal particles, d) quenching the nanopowder metal particles, and e) collecting the nanopowder particles.
</P>
<P>
2. The process according to claim 1 wherein the metal carbonyl is selected from at least one of the group consisting of nickel carbonyl, iron carbonyl, copper carbonyl, cobalt carbonyl, chromium carbonyl, molybdenum carbonyl, tungsten carbonyl, and ruthenium carbonyl.
</P>
<P>
3. The process according to claim 1 wherein the nanopowder particles are quenched in a reactor disposed downstream the plasma torch.
</P>
<P>
4. The process according to claim 1/wherein the metal carbonyl is mixed with a carrier gas.
</P>
<P>
5. The process according to claim 4 wherein the carrier gas is selected from at least one of the group consisting of helium, argon, nitrogen, hydrogen, and carbon monoxide. [alpha]rvq d[Lambda]x ^ c i \[theta] ^j
</P>
<P>
6. The process according to claim l/wherein a plasma gas is introduced
</P>
<P>
/ into the plasma torch.
</P>
<P>
7. The process according to claim 6 wherein the plasma gas is selected from at least one of the group consisting of helium, argon, nitrogen and hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
8. The process according to claim vwherein a sheath gas is selected from
</P>
<P>
A at least one the group consisting of helium, argon, nitrogen and hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
9. The process according to claim 8 wherein the sheath gas is selected from at least one the group consisting of helium, argon, nitrogen and hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
10. The process according to claim 1 wherein a quench gas is selected from at least one of the group consisting of argon, nitrogen, oxygen, ammonia and methane.
</P>
<P>
Ora l C -Al i 4&quot; i &amp;lt;o&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
</P>
<P>
11. The process according to claim r wherein the metal carbonyl is subjected to a temperature of about 3,000 - 11,000 K in the induction plasma torch.
</P>
<P>
12. The process according to claim 1 wherein the metal carbonyl resides in the induction plasma torch for about 0.001 - 10 seconds.
</P>
<P>
13. The process according to claim 1 wherein the nanopowder particles are filtered.
</P>
<P>
14. temperature of the
</P>
<P>
induction plasma torch is 11,000 K.
</P>
<P>
15. The process according to claim 1 where on the metal carbonyl is a gas.
</P>
<P>
16. The process ac :cccooorrrdddiiinnnggg tttooo ccclllaaaiiimmm 111 &apos; wwwhheerreeiinn tthh&amp;lt;e metal carbonyl is a liquid.
</P>
<P>
17. The process according to claim 1 &apos;wherein the metal nanopowders are at least substantially spherical.
</P>
<P>
18. The process according to claim 1 wherein the metal nanopowders have a typical mean particle diameter in the range of about 1 to 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
19. Metal nanopowders made by introducing metal carbonyl into an induction plasma torch, decomposing the metal carbonyl within the induction plasma torch and forming the metal nanopowders.
</P>
<P>
20. Metal nanopowders made according to claim 19 wherein the metal nanopowders are at least substantially spherical.
</P>
<P>
21. Metal nanopowders made according to claim 19 wherein the metal carbonyl is selected from at least one of the group consisting of a gas and a liquid.
</P>
<P>
Gx^ CVXJL \ 4o&amp;gt; 3 &amp;gt;;
</P>
<P>
22. Metal nanopowders made according to claim 19 wherein the metal
</P>
<P>
[Lambda] carbonyl is selected from at least one of the group consisting of nickel carbonyl, iron carbonyl, copper carbonyl, cobalt carbonyl, chromium carbonyl, molybdenum carbonyl, tungsten carbonyl, and ruthenium carbonyl.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2040867A4;WO2007137431A1;US2011277590A1;US2007277648A1;US7967891B2;RU2008152775A;KR20090078739A;JP2009538981A;DE07719887T1;CN101678461A;CA2654013A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
