<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Semiconductor laser device
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2048752A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
OCHIAI MASANAO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YUASA KOJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OCHIAI, MASANAO
</Name>
<Name>
YUASA, KOJI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NICHIA CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NICHIA CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2048752
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080172037
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-07-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060015927
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20050221338
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-07-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01S5/028
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/028
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A semiconductor laser device, which has a protective film at an end surface thereof, is adaptable to demands for higher outputs or shorter wavelengths. The semiconductor laser device according to the present invention includes a dielectric film (110) on at least one end surface of an optical resonator (300), in which the dielectric film includes a first dielectric layer (111) and a second dielectric layer (112) comprised of the same elements and disposed in sequence from the end surface side of the semiconductor, the first dielectric layer including a layer made of a single crystal material and the second dielectric layer including a layer made of an amorphous material.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A semiconductor laser device comprising:
</P>
<P>
an optical resonator; and
</P>
<P>
a dielectric film (110) on at least one end surface of the optical resonator,
</P>
<P>
wherein the dielectric film (110) comprises a first dielectric layer (111) and a second dielectric layer (112) that contain the same elements and are disposed in sequence from the end surface side of a semiconductor,
</P>
<P>
the first dielectric layer (111) is a reaction preventing layer that prevents a reaction between the semiconductor (200, 205, 210) and the dielectric film (110), and
</P>
<P>
the second dielectric layer (112) is a reflecting layer for a laser beam.
</P>
<P>
2. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first dielectric layer (111) includes a layer which comprises a single crystal material and the second dielectric layer (112), includes a layer made of an amorphous material.
</P>
<P>
3. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the first dielectric layer (111) has a lower refractive index than that of the second dielectric layer (112).
</P>
<P>
4. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the second dielectric layer (112) has a larger thickness than that of the first dielectric layer (111).
</P>
<P>
5. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein a reflectance of the dielectric film (110) is 25% or less.
</P>
<P>
6. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the dielectric film (110) has a reflectance of 20% or less when an oscillation wavelength of the semiconductor laser device is approximately 400 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first dielectric layer (111) and the second conductive layer (112) contain aluminum and oxygen as constituent elements.
</P>
<P>
8. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first dielectric layer (111) and the second dielectric layer (112) have approximately the same expansion coefficient.
</P>
<P>
9. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the outermost layer of the dielectric film (110) comprises a nitride.
</P>
<P>
10. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 1, wherein the device comprises:
</P>
<P>
an optical resonator; and
</P>
<P>
a dielectric film (110) on at least one end surface of the optical resonator, wherein
</P>
<P>
the dielectric film (110) comprises a first dielectric layer (111), a second dielectric layer (112), and a third dielectric layer disposed on the end surface side of a semiconductor in sequence from the end surface side of the semiconductor;
</P>
<P>
the first dielectric layer and the second dielectric layer are comprised of the same elements;
</P>
<P>
the third dielectric layer (310) contains an element different from the element in the first dielectric layer and the second dielectric layer;
</P>
<P>
the first dielectric layer (111) is a reaction preventing layer which prevents a reaction between the semiconductor and the dielectric film; and
</P>
<P>
the second dielectric layer (112) is a stress relaxation layer which reduces stress between the first dielectric layer (111) and the third dielectric layer.
</P>
<P>
11. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 10,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first dielectric layer (111) and the second dielectric layer (112) contain oxygen.
</P>
<P>
12. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 11,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first dielectric layer (111) has a higher oxygen content than that of the second dielectric layer.
</P>
<P>
13. The semiconductor laser device according to claim 10,
</P>
<P>
wherein the outermost layer of the dielectric layer is a nitride.
</P>
<P>
14. An optical pickup device comprising the semiconductor laser device according to any one of claims 1 to 13.
</P>
<P>
15. A device for optically reading information stored on a media by condensing a laser generated by a semiconductor laser device on the media and detecting the laser reflected on the media so as to read the information, wherein
</P>
<P>
the semiconductor laser device is the semiconductor laser device according to any one of claims 1 to 13.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2048752A3;EP2048752B1;EP1748524A1;EP1748524B1;US2007025231A1;US7738524B2;KR20070015062A;CN1929218A;CN100449888C;AT424052T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
