<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POWDERY TITANIUM OXIDE- ZINC OXIDE AGGREGATE, AND PROCESS FOR PRODUCTION THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2050719A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SHIO SHOICHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
WADA MASAYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUDA YUKIMITSU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAGARE YUKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIO, SHOICHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
WADA, MASAYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
SUDA, YUKIMITSU
</Name>
<Name>
NAGARE, YUKO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SHISEIDO CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHISEIDO COMPANY, LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2050719
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070790507
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-07-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP63686
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060187337
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/27
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q17/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/02A
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/27
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q17/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00H2
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a powder that can display excellent protection ability in both UV-A and UV-B regions. The titanium oxide-zinc oxide aggregate powder comprises an aggregate formed by the aggregation of porous titanium oxide particles and zinc oxide particles, and said porous titanium oxide particle is an aggregate of primary fine particles of titanium oxide. The production method of the titanium oxide-zinc oxide aggregate powder comprises the steps of: (a) hydrolyzing, with heating, an aqueous solution containing a titanium salt and an aliphatic alcohol;  (b) adding a water-soluble zinc salt to a suspension of a precipitate obtained by the hydrolysis with heating in step (a), and then neutralizing the suspension with an alkali;  and (c) calcining a precipitate obtained by the neutralization in step (b).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A titanium oxide-zinc oxide aggregate powder comprising an aggregate formed by the aggregation of porous titanium oxide particles and zinc oxide particles, and wherein said porous titanium oxide particle is an aggregate of primary fine particles of titanium oxide.
</P>
<P>
2. The powder according to claim 1, wherein the average particle size of the porous titanium oxide particles is 0.01 to 0.5 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
3. The powder according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the average particle size of the zinc oxide particles is 0.02 to 0.1 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
4. The powder according to any of claims 1 to 3, wherein the average particle size of the aggregate powder is 1 to 300 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
5. A production method of a titanium oxide-zinc oxide aggregate powder comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) hydrolyzing, with heating, an aqueous solution containing a titanium salt and an aliphatic alcohol;
</P>
<P>
(b) adding a water-soluble zinc salt to a suspension of a precipitate obtained by the hydrolysis with heating in step (a), and then neutralizing the suspension with an alkali; and
</P>
<P>
(c) calcining a precipitate obtained by the neutralization in step(b).
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 5, wherein a carboxylic acid is present in step (a) and/or step (b).
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to claim 5 or 6, wherein the precipitate obtained in step (a) is further heat-treated with an acid.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any of claims 5 to 7, wherein the aliphatic alcohol is a polyhydric alcohol.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to any of claims 6 or 8, wherein the carboxylic acid is acetic acid.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to any of claims 5 to 9, wherein the alkali is sodium carbonate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009258068A1;WO2008004694A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
