<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PIGMENT MIXTURES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2099715A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BUJARD PATRICE [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
BUGNON PHILIPPE [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
MAMAK MARC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STADLER URS LEO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BUJARD, PATRICE
</Name>
<Name>
BUGNON, PHILIPPE
</Name>
<Name>
MAMAK, MARC
</Name>
<Name>
STADLER, URS LEO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CIBA HOLDING INC [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
CIBA HOLDING INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2099715
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070857651
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-17
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP64017
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070879993P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070925392P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B21/06
</Class>
<Class>
C01B21/076
</Class>
<Class>
C01B21/082
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B21/076
</Class>
<Class>
C01B21/082B
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00F2
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00F20
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00F20D
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00H2
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/037
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12D2
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N1
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N2
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N3
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12S
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to novel pigment mixtures comprising at least two different particulate components A and B. The first component A comprises titanium suboxide(s), a titanium oxynitride or a titanium nitride species. Component B particle comprises inorganic, or organic pigments. The titanium suboxide particles display a bluish metallic luster, are new and form a further aspect of the present invention. When combined with particles from component B such as variously coated micas, for example, the bluish or bluish/black metallic color effect from component A leads to special color effects in the various mixtures.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A spherical particle, comprising at least a titanium suboxide, a titanium oxynitride or a titanium nitride a species or mixture of species thereof.
</P>
<P>
2. The particle of claim 1 , which further contains unreduced TiO2.
</P>
<P>
3. The particle of claims 1 , or 2, wherein the titanium suboxide species is defined as wholly or partially reduced TiO2 with an oxidation state of the titanium: from &amp;lt;4 to 2.
</P>
<P>
4. The particle of claims 1 to 3, wherein the particle size ranges from about 30 nm to about 30 [mu]m, preferably about 30 nm to about 10000 nm or most preferably 30 nm to about 5000 nm, especially about 30 nm to about 500 nm.
</P>
<P>
5. A process for producing particles, comprising at least a titanium suboxide, a titanium oxynitride or a titanium nitride a species or mixture of species thereof, wherein the process comprises treating TiO2 particles using a plasma torch.
</P>
<P>
6. A particle, especially a spherical, rod-like, flake or platelet-shaped particle, obtainable according to claim 5.
</P>
<P>
7. A pigment mixture comprising two different particulate components A and B, wherein component A is the particle of claim 1 , or 6, and component B particle is an organic, or inorganic pigment.
</P>
<P>
8. The pigment mixture of claim 7, wherein the component B is an effect pigment, especially a pearlescent pigment, a metal effect pigment, an interference pigment and/or a luster pigment.
</P>
<P>
9. The pigment mixture according to claim 8, wherein the pigment mixture has a bluish hue shift, wherein the hue difference (delta b) is expressed as a CIELAB quantity and is negative.
</P>
<P>
10. The pigment mixture according to claim 8, wherein the component B is a platelet-like particle and has a (multilayer) structure comprising at least:
</P>
<P>
wherein TRASUB is a semitransparent, or transparent substrate having a low index of refraction selected from the group consisting of natural, or synthetic mica, another layered silicate, glass, AI2O3, SiOz, SiO2, SiO2/SiOx/SiO2 (0.03 &amp;lt; x &amp;lt; 0.95), SiOi 40- 20/SiO070-099/SiOi 40-20, or Si/Si[theta]zwith 0.70 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 2.0, and STL is a semi-transparent layer selected from the group consisting of a semi- transparent metal layer of Cu, Ag, Cr, or Sn, or a semi-transparent silicon suboxide(s), titanium suboxide(s) or carbon layer.
</P>
<P>
1 1. A coating, varnish, a plastic, a paint, a printing ink, a masterbatch, a ceramic or glass, cosmetic or personal care product, comprising the particles of claims 1 , or 6, or the pigment mixture according to claims 7 to 10.
</P>
<P>
12. A method of forming a pigment mixture comprising the steps of: reducing TiO2 particles to form to form a Component A particle, and applying or coating said Component A particle onto a platelet-like Component B, which is different than Component A.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to claim 12, wherein Component A is spherical and Component B is platelet-like and the diameter ratio of Component A:Component B is at least 1 :2.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008083894A2;WO2008083894A3;US2012034178A1;US2010011992A1;JP2010515645A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
