<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOPARTICULATE ENCAPSULATION BARRIER STACK
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2082619A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RAMADAS SENTHIL KUMAR [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
CHUA SOO JIN [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
RAMADAS, SENTHIL KUMAR
</Name>
<Name>
CHUA, SOO JIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AGENCY SCIENCE TECH &amp; RES [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
AGENCY FOR SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY AND RESEARCH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2082619
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060813114
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-11-06
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006SG00334
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-06
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B32B27/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09K11/00
</Class>
<Class>
H05B33/04
</Class>
<Class>
H05B33/14
</Class>
<Class>
H05B33/20
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/52C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A barrier stack for encapsulating a moisture and/or oxygen sensitive electronic device is provided. The barrier stack comprises a multilayer film having at least one barrier layer having low moisture and/or oxygen permeability, and at least one sealing layer arranged to be in contact with a surface of the barrier layer, wherein the sealing material comprises reactive nanoparticles capable of interacting with moisture and/or oxygen, thereby retarding the permeation of moisture and/or oxygen through defects present in the barrier layer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. An encapsulation barrier stack capable of encapsulating a moisture and/or oxygen sensitive article, comprising: a multilayer film having at least one barrier layer having low moisture and/or oxygen permeability, and at least one sealing layer arranged to be in contact with a surface of the at least one barrier layer, thereby covering defects present in the barrier layer, wherein the at least one sealing layer comprises reactive nanoparticles capable of interacting with moisture and/or oxygen to retard the permeation of moisture and/or oxygen through the defects present in the barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The barrier stack of Claim 1 , wherein the at least one sealing layer conforms substantially to the shape of the defects present on the surface of the at least one barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
3. The barrier stack of Claim 1 or 2, wherein the sealing layer is formed by conformal deposition.
</P>
<P>
4. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 3, wherein the multilayer film comprises a plurality of sealing layers and barrier layers arranged in an alternating sequence.
</P>
<P>
5. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 4, wherein the reactive nanoparticles interact with moisture and/or oxygen through chemical reaction.
</P>
<P>
6. The barrier stack of Claim 5, wherein the nanoparticles comprise a material selected from the group consisting of metals and metal oxides.
</P>
<P>
7. The barrier stack of Claim 6, wherein the nanoparticles comprise a metal selected from the group consisting of Al, Ti, Mg, Ba and Ca.
</P>
<P>
8. The barrier stack of Claim 6 or 7, wherein the nanoparticles comprise a metal oxide selected from the group consisting of TiO2 , AbO3 , ZrO2, ZnO, BaO, SrO, CaO and MgO, VO2, CrO2, MoO2, and LiMn2O4.
</P>
<P>
9. The barrier stack of Claim 6 or 7, wherein the nanoparticles comprise a transparent conductive oxide selected from the group consisting of cadmium stannate (Cd2SnO4), cadmium indate (CdIn2O4), zinc stannate (Zn2SnO4 and ZnSnO3), and zinc indium oxide (Zn2In2O5).
</P>
<P>
10. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 9, wherein the reactive nanoparticles interact with moisture and/or oxygen through adsorption.
</P>
<P>
11. The barrier stack of Claim 10, wherein the nanoparticles comprise carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
12. The barrier stack of Claim 11 , wherein the carbon nanotubes have a multiwall conformation.
</P>
<P>
13. The barrier stack of Claim 11 or 12, wherein the amount of carbon nanotubes present is about 0.01% to about 10% of the total weight of nanoparticles present in the sealing layer.
</P>
<P>
14. The barrier stack of any of Claims 5 to 13, wherein the sealing layer comprises carbon nanotubes and metal oxide nanoparticles, the quantity of metal oxide nanoparticles present being between 500 to 15000 times
</P>
<P>
(by weight) the quantity of carbon nanotubes present.
</P>
<P>
15. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 14, further comprising inert nanoparticles capable of obstructing the permeation of moisture and/or oxygen through the defects present in the barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
16. The barrier stack of Claim 15, wherein the inert nanoparticles comprise a material selected from the group consisting of gold, copper, silver, platinum, silica, wollastonite, mullite, monmorillonite, silicate glass, fluorosilicate glass, fluoroborosilicate glass, aluminosilicate glass, calcium silicate glass, calcium aluminum silicate glass, calcium aluminum fluorosilicate glass, titanium carbide, zirconium carbide, zirconium nitride, silicon carbide, or silicon nitride, metal sulfides, and a mixture or combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
17. The barrier stack of Claim 1 to 16, wherein the size of the nanoparticles is smaller than the average diameter of defects present in the at least one barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
18. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 17, wherein when the oxygen and/or moisture sensitive article comprises an electroluminescent electronic component, the average size of the nanoparticles is less than one-half the characteristic wavelength of light produced by the electroluminescent electronic component.
</P>
<P>
19. The barrier stack of Claim 18, wherein the nanoparticles have a length of less than 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
20. The barrier stack of any of Claims 17 to 19, wherein the nanoparticles are rod-shaped, wherein said rod-shape has a diameter of between about 10 nm to 50 nm, a length of 50 to 400 nm, and an aspect ratio of 5 or more.
</P>
<P>
21. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 20, wherein the nanoparticles have at least two different shapes.
</P>
<P>
22. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 21 , wherein the nanoparticles have a surface area to weight ratio of between about 1 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g to about 200 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
23. The barrier stack of any of Claim 1 to 22, wherein the sealing layer further comprises a polymeric binder, wherein the nanoparticles are distributed within the polymeric binder.
</P>
<P>
24. The barrier stack of Claim 23, wherein the polymeric binder is derived from a monomer having at least one polymerisable group.
</P>
<P>
25. The barrier stack of Claim 24, wherein the polymeric binder comprises a material selected from the group consisting of polyacrylate, polyacrylamide, polyepoxide, parylene, polysiloxanes and polyurethane.
</P>
<P>
26. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 25, wherein the barrier layer comprises a material selected from indium tin oxide (ITO), TiAIN, SiO2, SiC, Si3N4, TiO2, HfO2, Y2O3, Ta2O5, and AI2O3.
</P>
<P>
27. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 27, further comprising a substrate for supporting the multilayer film.
</P>
<P>
28. The barrier stack of Claim 28, wherein the multilayer film is orientated such that the sealing layer is arranged on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
29. The barrier stack of Claims 28 or 29, wherein the substrate comprises a material selected from polyacetate, polypropylene, polyimide, cellophane, poly(1-trimethylsilyl-1-propyne, poly(4-methyl-2-pentyne), polyimide, polycarbonate, polyethylene, polyethersulfone, epoxy resins, polyethylene terepthalate, polystyrene, polyurethane, polyacrylate, and polydimethylphenylene oxide, styrene-divinylbenzene copolymers, polyvinylidene fluoride (PVDF), nylon, nitrocellulose, cellulose, glass, indium tin oxide, nano-clays, silicones, polydimethylsiloxanes, biscyclopentadienyl iron, and polyphosphazenes.
</P>
<P>
30. The barrier stack of any of Claims 28 to 30, wherein the substrate is flexible.
</P>
<P>
31. The barrier stack of any of Claims 28 to 30, wherein the substrate is rigid.
</P>
<P>
32. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 26, wherein the multilayer film comprises at least 3 or at least 5 barrier layers.
</P>
<P>
33. The barrier stack of any of Claims 32, wherein the multilayer film is arranged on one surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
34. The barrier stack of any of Claims 28 to 32, wherein each multilayer film is arranged on each opposing surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
35. The barrier stack of any of Claims 28 to 33, further comprising a planarising layer interposed between the substrate and the multilayer film.
</P>
<P>
36. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 34, further comprising a terminal layer for protecting the multilayer film.
</P>
<P>
37. The barrier stack of Claim 35, wherein the terminal layer comprises an acrylic film.
</P>
<P>
38. The barrier stack of Claim 36, wherein the acrylic film has distributed therein LiF and/or MgF2 particles.
</P>
<P>
39. The barrier stack of any of Claims 1 to 38, wherein the water vapour permeation rate of the encapsulation barrier stack is less than about 10&amp;lt;&quot;5&amp;gt; g/m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/day or 10&amp;lt;&quot;6&amp;gt; g/m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/day.
</P>
<P>
40. An electronic device comprising an active component that is sensitive to moisture and/or oxygen, said active component being arranged within an encapsulation barrier stack according to any of claims 1 to 39.
</P>
<P>
41. The electronic device of Claim 40, wherein the barrier stack forms a base substrate for supporting the reactive component.
</P>
<P>
42. The electronic device of Claim 40 or 41 , wherein the encapsulation barrier stack further comprises a covering layer arranged proximally over the active component to form a proximal encapsulation, said reactive component being sandwiched between the covering layer and the encapsulation barrier stack.
</P>
<P>
43. The electronic device of Claim 41 , wherein the shape of the covering layer conforms to the external shape of the reactive component.
</P>
<P>
44. The electronic device of any of Claims 39 to 42, wherein the encapsulation further comprises a cover substrate attached to the base substrate by means of an adhesive layer, said adhesive layer being arranged at least substantially along the edge of the cover substrate for forming a rim-sealed enclosure around the reactive component.
</P>
<P>
45. The electronic device of Claim 40, wherein the active component is arranged on a base substrate, and the encapsulation barrier stack forms an encapsulation layer over the reactive component that seals the reactive component against the base substrate.
</P>
<P>
46. The electronic device of any of Claims 40 to 45, wherein the reactive component is selected from the group consisting of an Organic
</P>
<P>
Light Emitting Device (OLED)1 charged-coupied device (CCD), and micro- electro-mechanical sensors (MEMS).
</P>
<P>
47. A method for the manufacture of an encapsulation barrier stack according to any of Claims 1 to 39, comprising: forming at least one barrier layer and at least one sealing layer in alternating sequence on a surface for receiving the barrier stack, wherein forming the at least one sealing layer comprises mixing a polymerisable compound with a hanoparticle dispersion to form a sealing mixture, and polymerising the sealing mixture over the at least one barrier layer under vacuum.
</P>
<P>
48. The method of any of Claims 47, further comprising providing a substrate for supporting the barrier stack, wherein said at least one sealing layer is first formed on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
49. The method of Claim 48, wherein the substrate comprises a barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
50. The method of Claim 48, wherein the substrate comprises a polymer substrate.
</P>
<P>
51. The method of any of Claims 48 to 50, wherein the substrate is degassed at a temperature of between about 30&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to about 100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C under vacuum for at least about 1 hour.
</P>
<P>
52. The method of any of Claims 48 to 51 , wherein the nanoparticle dispersion comprises nanoparticles dispersed in at least one organic solvent.
</P>
<P>
53. The method of Claim 52, wherein said at least one organic solvent is selected from ethers, ketones, aldehydes and glycols.
</P>
<P>
54. The method of any of Claims 48 to 52, wherein the sealing mixture is spin coated onto the barrier layer.
</P>
<P>
55. The method of any of Claims 46 to 49, further comprising carrying out sonification of the sealing mixture prior to polymerisation.
</P>
<P>
56. The method of Claim 55, wherein sonification is carried for at least about 30 minutes.
</P>
<P>
57. The method of any of Claims 48 to 55, wherein the mixing of the polymerisable compound with the nanoparticle dispersion is carried out in a polar organic solvent.
</P>
<P>
58. The method of Claim 57, wherein the polar organic solvent comprises a mixture of ethylene glycol and 2-methoxyethanol in 1 :1 molar ratio.
</P>
<P>
59. The method of any of Claims 48 to 58, wherein the poiymerisable compound is curable by ultraviolet light.
</P>
<P>
60. The method of Claim 59, wherein the poiymerisable compound is selected from acrylic acid, methyl acrylate, ethyl acrylate and butyl acrylate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2082619A4;WO2008057045A1;US2010089636A1;JP2010511267A;CN101518151A;AU2006350626A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
