<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Quantum information processing device
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2075745A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WILLIAMS DAVID [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
GORMAN JOHN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WILLIAMS, DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
GORMAN, JOHN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HITACHI LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HITACHI LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2075745
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070124170
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070124170
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G06N99/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G06N99/00K
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A quantum information processing device includes an isolated double quantum dot system (902 1 ), an electrometer (903 1 ) and an isolated conductive element (901 1 ) disposed between the isolated quantum dot system and the electrometer for coupling the isolated quantum dot system and the electrometer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A quantum information processing device including:
</P>
<P>
an isolated double quantum dot system;
</P>
<P>
an electrometer; and
</P>
<P>
an isolated conductive element disposed between the isolated quantum dot system and the electrometer for coupling the isolated quantum dot system and the electrometer.
</P>
<P>
2. A device according to claim 1, wherein the isolated conductive element comprises a region of semiconducting material.
</P>
<P>
3. A device according to claim 2, wherein the semiconducting material comprises silicon.
</P>
<P>
4. A device according to claim 3, wherein the semiconducting material is intrinsic or is doped with an impurity having an impurity concentration of at least 1*10&amp;lt;18&amp;gt; cm&amp;lt;-3&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
5. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated conductive element is arranged as an elongate bar.
</P>
<P>
6. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated conductive element is arranged is arranged to exhibit Coulomb blockade.
</P>
<P>
7. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated conductive element is arranged is arranged to exhibit quantised states.
</P>
<P>
8. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated conductive element is a double quantum dot system.
</P>
<P>
9. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated conductive element is formed in a layer having a thickness equal to or less than about 100 nm, preferably equal to or less than about 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
10. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated conductive element is elongate and has a longitudinal dimension equal to or less than about 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
11. A device according to claim 10, wherein the isolated conductive element is elongate and has a first, transverse dimension equal to or less than about 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
12. A device according to claim 9 or 10, wherein the isolated conductive element is elongate and has a second, transverse dimension equal to or less than about 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
13. A device according to claim 12, wherein the second, transverse dimension corresponds to a layer thickness.
</P>
<P>
14. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated double quantum dot system and the isolated conductive element are separated by a gap equal to or less than about 200 nm, preferably equal to or less than about 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
15. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated double quantum dot system and the isolated conductive element are separated by a gap equal to or more than about 10 nm, preferably equal to or more than about 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
16. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the electrometer and the isolated conductive element are separated by a gap equal to or less than about 500 nm, preferably between about 200 nm and 300 nm.
</P>
<P>
17. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated double quantum dot system comprises a region of semiconducting material.
</P>
<P>
18. A device according to claim 17, wherein the semiconducting material is silicon.
</P>
<P>
19. A device according to claim 17 or 18, wherein the semiconducting material is intrinsic or is doped with an impurity having an impurity concentration of at least 1*10&amp;lt;18&amp;gt; cm&amp;lt;-3&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
20. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein the isolated double quantum dot system is bilobate having first and second lobes.
</P>
<P>
21. A device according to any preceding claim, wherein isolated double quantum dot system is arranged is arranged to exhibit Coulomb blockade.
</P>
<P>
22. A device according to any preceding claim, comprising:
</P>
<P>
an array of isolated double quantum dot systems; and
</P>
<P>
at least one electrometer for determining charge distribution on at least one isolated double quantum dot system.
</P>
<P>
23. A device according to claim 22, wherein each isolated double quantum dot system is bilobate having first and second lobes.
</P>
<P>
24. A device according to claim 23, wherein isolated double quantum dot systems which are adjacent to each other in a row or column are arranged perpendicularly to each other.
</P>
<P>
25. A device according to claim 24, wherein isolated double quantum dot systems which are adjacent to each other in a row are arranged perpendicularly to each other and isolated double quantum dot systems which are adjacent to each other in a column are arranged in parallel or vice versa.
</P>
<P>
26. Apparatus comprising:
</P>
<P>
a device according to any preceding claim;
</P>
<P>
a radio frequency signal source; and
</P>
<P>
an antenna coupled to the source; the source and antenna arranged so as to excite the or each isolated double quantum dot system.
</P>
<P>
27. Apparatus comprising:
</P>
<P>
a device according to any preceding claim;
</P>
<P>
a refrigerator for cooling the device to a temperature equal to or less than 4.2 [deg.]K.
</P>
</Claims>
</BiblioData>
