<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
GROWTH OF CARBON NANOTUBES USING METAL- FREE NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2069234A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WHELAN CAROLINE [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
ESCONJAUREGUI SANTIAGO CRUZ [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
WHELAN, CAROLINE
</Name>
<Name>
ESCONJAUREGUI, SANTIAGO CRUZ
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
IMEC INTER UNI MICRO ELECTR [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
NANOCYL S A [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
INTERUNIVERSITAIR MICROELEKTRONICA CENTRUM
</Name>
<Name>
NANOCYL S.A
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2069234
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070815688
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007BE00109
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060846558P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J21/08
</Class>
<Class>
B01J23/14
</Class>
<Class>
B01J27/224
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a method for forming at least one carbon nanotube (16) by using metal-free catalyst nanoparticles (14), for example Si or Ge comprising nanoparticles. The method uses the step of decomposing a carbon source gas to form carbon fragments which then recombine at the metal-free catalyst nanoparticles (14) to grow carbon nanotubes (16). The method according to embodiments of the invention leads to carbon nanotubes (16) which do not comprise metal impurities.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1.- A method for forming at least one carbon nanotube (16), the method comprising: providing at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14), and growing a carbon nanotube (16) from the metal-free catalyst nanoparticle
</P>
<P>
(14).
</P>
<P>
2.- A method according to claim 1 , wherein the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) is provided to a Chemical Vapor Deposition reactor, and wherein growing a carbon nanotube (16) comprises - forming reactive carbon fragments by decomposing a carbon source gas in the Chemical Vapor Deposition reactor, and
</P>
<P>
- recombining the reactive carbon fragments on top of the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) so as to grow the at least one carbon nanotube (16). 3.- A method according to claim 2, wherein the carbon source gas is a hydrocarbon gas having one (C1 ) up to three (C3) carbon atoms. 4.- A method according to claim 3, wherein the carbon source gas is CH4,
</P>
<P>
02H4, C2H2 or C3H6.
</P>
<P>
5.- A method according to claim 2, wherein the carbon source gas is CO. 6.- A method according to any of claims 2 to 5, wherein providing at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) to the Chemical Vapor Deposition reactor is performed by:
</P>
<P>
- providing at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) on a substrate (10), and - transferring the substrate (10) with the at least one metal-free nanoparticle (14) on it to the Chemical Vapor Deposition reactor. 7.- A method according to claim 6, wherein providing at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) on a substrate (10) is performed by:
</P>
<P>
- providing a layer of metal-free material (12) onto the substrate (10), and
</P>
<P>
- annealing the layer (12) so as to form the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14).
</P>
<P>
8.- A method according to claim 7, wherein annealing is performed at temperatures of between 500&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and 800&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C. 9.- A method according to any of claims 6 to 8, wherein the method furthermore comprises, before providing the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) on the substrate (10), providing a barrier layer
</P>
<P>
(11 ) on the substrate (10) for preventing interaction of the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) with the substrate (10). 10.- A method according to any of claims 6 to 9, wherein, during decomposing the carbon source gas and growing the at least one carbon nanotube (16), the temperature of the substrate (10) is kept between 800&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and
</P>
<P>
1000&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C. 11.- A method according to any of claims 2 to 10, wherein decomposing the carbon source gas is performed by using a hot filament (2), by using a plasma, or by using a combination of both. 12.- A method according to claim 11 , wherein decomposing the carbon source gas is performed by using a hot filament (2) at a temperature of 950&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C. 13.- A method according to any of the previous claims, wherein providing at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) is performed by providing at least one semiconductor comprising nanoparticle (14). 14.- A method according to claim 13, wherein the at least one semiconductor comprising nanoparticle (14) is a SiC, a Si[theta]2, a pure silicon nanoparticle, a Ge[theta]2 or a pure Ge nanoparticle. 15.- A method according to any of the previous claims, wherein the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) has a diameter of between 0.4 nm and 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
16.- A method according to any of the previous claims, wherein the method furthermore comprises pre-treating the at least one metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) before growing the carbon nanotube (16). 17.- A carbon nanotube (16) grown from a metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14).
</P>
<P>
18.- Use of a metal-free catalyst nanoparticle (14) to grow a carbon nanotube
</P>
<P>
(16).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008034204A2;WO2008034204A3;US2010047152A1;JP2010504268A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
