<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Decoding of array sensors with microspheres
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2045334A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHEE MARK S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STUELPNAGEL JOHN R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CZARNIK ANTHONY W [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHEE, MARK S
</Name>
<Name>
STUELPNAGEL, JOHN R
</Name>
<Name>
CZARNIK, ANTHONY W
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ILLUMINA INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ILLUMINA, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2045334
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080021788
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
1999-06-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP19990931904
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-06-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19980090473P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1998-06-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19980189543
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1998-11-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J19/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/53
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/566
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C40B40/06
</Class>
<Class>
C40B60/14
</Class>
<Class>
C40B70/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J19/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68B10
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68B10A
</Class>
<Class>
C12Q1/68B2
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to compositions and methods for decoding microsphere array sensors, and to array compositions comprising at least a first and a second subpopulation of microspheres which are labelled with a different nucleic acid.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An array composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) a substrate with a surface comprising discrete sites; and
</P>
<P>
b) a population of microspheres distributed on the surface at the discrete sites, said microspheres comprising at least a first and a second subpopulation, wherein each subpopulation of microspheres comprises a different nucleic acid, said nucleic acid capable of binding decoder probes in order to identify the sequence of the nucleic acid.
</P>
<P>
2. A composition according to claim 1, wherein at least one decoder probe is bound to said nucleic acid.
</P>
<P>
3. A composition according to claim 1, wherein a plurality of decoder probes is bound to said nucleic acid.
</P>
<P>
4. A composition according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the microspheres in said first and second subpopulations lack a unique optical signature.
</P>
<P>
5. A method of making an array composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) forming a surface comprising individual sites on a substrate; and
</P>
<P>
b) distributing microspheres on said surface so that said individual sites contain microspheres, wherein said microspheres comprise at least a first and a second subpopulation, each subpopulation of microspheres comprising a different nucleic acid, said nucleic acid capable of binding decoder probes in order to identify the sequence of the nucleic acid.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to claim 5, wherein said microspheres are randomly distributed on said surface.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to claim 5 or claim 6, wherein said individual sites are depressions.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to any one of claims 5 to 7 further comprising applying energy to said array composition.
</P>
<P>
9. A method of decoding an array composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) providing an array composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
i) a substrate with a surface comprising discrete sites; and
</P>
<P>
ii) a population of microspheres distributed on said surface at said discrete sites, said population of microspheres comprising at least a first and a second subpopulation, each subpopulation of microspheres comprising a different nucleic acid, said nucleic acid capable of binding decoder probes in order to identify the sequence of the nucleic acid;
</P>
<P>
b) adding a plurality of decoder probes to said array composition, wherein the decoder probes bind to the nucleic acid; and
</P>
<P>
c) detecting the decoder probes, thereby decoding the array composition.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to claim 9, wherein said decoder probes are directly or indirectly labeled, and wherein decoding the array composition comprises detecting the presence of the label.
</P>
<P>
11. A method according to claim 9 or claim 10, wherein said microspheres in said first and second subpopulations lack a unique optical signature.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to any one of claims 9 to 11, wherein said plurality of decoder probes are added to said array composition in a sequential series of decoding steps, and wherein said sequential series of decoding steps generates a unique code for each nucleic acid.
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to any one of claims 9 to 12, wherein the location of microspheres of the first subpopulation is determined.
</P>
<P>
14. A method according to claim 13, wherein the location of microspheres of the second subpopulation is determined.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to any one of claims 9 to 14, wherein said microspheres are randomly distributed on said surface.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO9967641A2;WO9967641A3;US2005233318A1;US7033754B2;US2007231824A1;US2002132221A1;US7060431B2;US2006073513A1;US7455971B2;US2003157504A1;US7226734B2;JP2002519637A;EP1090293A2;EP1090293B1;EP2360271A1;CA2335951A1;AU4831599A;AU754952B2;AT423314T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
