<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
UV-CURING PROTECTIVE COAT FOR THERMOPLASTIC SUBSTRATES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2007835A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BUCKEL FRANK [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MALEIKA ROBERT [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KOEHLER WALTER [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MEYER REINER [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BUCKEL, FRANK
</Name>
<Name>
MALEIKA, ROBERT
</Name>
<Name>
KOEHLER, WALTER
</Name>
<Name>
MEYER, REINER
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BAYER MATERIALSCIENCE AG [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BAYER MATERIALSCIENCE AG
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2007835
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070723623
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP02677
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
DE200610016642
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B32B27/08
</Class>
<Class>
B32B27/30
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D133/06
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B32B27/30
</Class>
<Class>
B32B27/40
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D133/06
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a multi-layer product, the first layer being a UV-cured protective layer which contains SiO2 nanoparticles, and the second layer containing a thermoplastic substrate. In addition, the invention relates to the composition of the UV-curable first layer, a process for the production of the multi-layer products and products, such as e.g. glazing products, which contain the named multi-layer products.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A multi-layer product comprising a first layer (S1) and a second layer (S2), the first layer being prepared from
</P>
<P>
A) one or more aliphatic polymer precursors selected from the group consisting of
</P>
<P>
A.1) aliphatic oligomers containing urethane bonds or ester bonds with at least two acrylate functions per molecule or mixtures of corresponding oligomers and
</P>
<P>
A.2) aliphatic reactive diluents with at least two acrylate groups per molecule or mixtures of corresponding reactive diluents,
</P>
<P>
B) one or more fine-particle inorganic compounds,
</P>
<P>
C) at least one organic UV absorber selected from the group consisting of triazine derivatives and biphenyltriazine derivatives,
</P>
<P>
D) optionally one or more radical scavengers of the hindered amine light stabilizer (HALS) class
</P>
<P>
E) optionally one or more flow control agents
</P>
<P>
F) optionally one or more solvents, and
</P>
<P>
G) at least one special photoinitiator selected from the group consisting of acylphosphine oxide derivatives and [alpha]-aminoalkylphenone derivatives,
</P>
<P>
wherein the second layer comprises a thermoplastic polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein:
</P>
<P>
a) based on the amount of components A and B:
</P>
<P>
to 95 wt. % component A,
</P>
<P>
5 to 80 wt. % component B and
</P>
<P>
0.1 to 10 wt. % component G are used, with the total weight % of component A and component B being 100%,
</P>
<P>
b) an amount of component F is used such that a solids content of 20 to 50 wt. % for the mixture of components A, B and F results, and
</P>
<P>
c) based on the weight of solids in the mixture of components A, B and F:
</P>
<P>
0.1 to 20 wt. % component C,
</P>
<P>
0 to 10 wt. % component D and
</P>
<P>
0 to 5 wt. % component E are used.
</P>
<P>
3. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein the aliphatic reactive diluent (component A.2) is selected from the group consisting of 1,6-hexanediol diacrylate, tricyclodecane dimethanol diacrylate, trimethylol propane triacrylate, pentaerythritol tetraacrylate and the methacrylate derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein component B is silicon dioxide with a mean particle size (d50) of 1 to 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
5. A multi-layer product according to claim 4, wherein the silicon dioxide has a particle size distribution with a ((d90-d10)/d50) of the distribution of less than or equal to 2.
</P>
<P>
6. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein component C is a compound according to the following formula (IV)
</P>
<P>
EMI16.0
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
X-OR&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; , OCH2CH2OR&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; , OCH2CH(OH)CH2OR&amp;lt;6 &amp;gt; or OCH(R&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; )COOR&amp;lt;8 &amp;gt;
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; =branched or unbranched C1-C13 alkyl, C2-C20 alkenyl, C6-C12 aryl or -CO-C1-C18 alkyl
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; -H or branched or unbranched C1-C8 alkyl, and
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;8&amp;gt; -C1-C12 alkyl, C2-C12 alkenyl or C5-C6 cycloalkyl.
</P>
<P>
7. Multi-layer product according to one of claims 1 to 6, wherein component D is one or more compounds of the following formula (V)
</P>
<P>
EMI17.0
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
Y-H; R&amp;lt;6 &amp;gt; or OR&amp;lt;6 &amp;gt;
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;6 &amp;gt; branched or unbranched C1-C13 alkyl, C2-C20 alkenyl, C6-C12 aryl or -CO-C1-C18 alkyl, and
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;9&amp;gt; =Z-R&amp;lt;10&amp;gt; -Z-R&amp;lt;11&amp;gt; ,
</P>
<P>
EMI18.0
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
Z=a divalent functional group such as C(O)O, NH or NHCO
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;10&amp;gt; =a divalent organic radical such as (CH2)1 with 1=0 to 12, C-CH-Ph-OCH3
</P>
<P>
EMI19.0
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;11&amp;gt; -H or C1-C20 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
8. A multi-layer product according to claim 7, wherein component D is selected from the group consisting of bis(1-octyloxy-2,2,6,6-tetramethyl-4-piperidyl) sebacic acid ester, (3,5-di-tert.-butyl-4-hydroxy-benzyl)-butyl malonic acid-bis-(1,2,2,6,6-pentamethyl-4-piperidyl) ester and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein component F is one or more compounds selected from the group consisting of alkanes, alcohols, esters and ketones.
</P>
<P>
10. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein component G is one or more compounds selected from the group consisting of compounds of formula VI (acylphosphine oxide) and formula VIII ([alpha]-aminoalkylphenone),
</P>
<P>
EMI20.0
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;12&amp;gt; -C1-C30 alkyl, C5 to C6 cycloalkyl optionally substituted by C1 to C4 alkyl, and/or chlorine, bromine, C6 to C20 aryl, C6 to C20 aryloxy or C7 to C12 aralkyl
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;13&amp;gt; -C1-C30 alkyl, C1-C30 alkoxy, C5 to C6 cycloalkyl, optionally substituted by C1 to C4 alkyl, C1 to C4 alkoxy, C1 to C4 acyl and/or chlorine, bromine, C6 to C20 aryl, C6 to C20 aryloxy, C7 to C21 aroyl or C7 to C12 aralkyl,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;14&amp;gt; -C1 to C4 alkyl, C1 to C4 alkoxy,
</P>
<P>
n=0 to 5,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;15&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;16&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;17 &amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;18 &amp;gt; independently of one another C1-C30 alkyl, C5 to C6 cycloalkyl optionally substituted by C1 to C4 alkyl, and/or chlorine, bromine, C6 to C20 aryl or C7 to C12 aralkyl,
</P>
<P>
and wherein the radicals R&amp;lt;17 &amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;18 &amp;gt; can also be linked to a ring so that the nitrogen N shown in formula (VII) is part of a heterocyclic ring system,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;19&amp;gt; -C1 to C30 alkoxy, C1 to C30 alkylthio, C1 to C30 dialkyamino, C5 to C6 cycloalkyl optionally substituted by C1 to C4 alkyl, and/or chlorine, bromine, wherein the C atoms of the ring can also be substituted by heteroatoms such as N, O or S.
</P>
<P>
11. A multi-layer product according to claim 10, wherein component G is one or more compounds selected from the group consisting of bis(2,4,6-trimethylbenzoyl)-phenyl phosphine oxide, (2,4,6-trimethylbenzoyl) diphenyl phosphine oxide, bis(2,6-dimethylbenzoyl)(2,4,4-trimethyl-pentyl) phosphine oxide, bis(2,6-dimethoxybenzoyl)(2,4,4-trimethyl-pentyl) phosphine oxide, benzoyl phosphonic acid bis(2,6-dimethylphenyl) ester, 2,4,6-trimethylbenzoylethoxyphenyl phosphine oxide, 2-benzyl-2-(dimethylamino)-1-(4-morpholinophenyl)-1-butanone and 2-methyl-1-[4-(methylthio)phenyl]-2-morpholino-1-propanone (see formula VIIa, wherein Me=methyl).
</P>
<P>
EMI21.0
</P>
<P>
12. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein component G is selected from the group consisting of a) a mixture of bis(2,6-dimethoxy-benzoyl)(2,4,4-dimethylpentyl) phosphine oxide and (1-hydroxy-cyclohexyl)phenylmethanone and b) a mixture of bis(2,6-dimethoxy-benzoyl)(2,4,4-trimethylpentyl) phosphine oxide and 2-hydroxy-2-methyl-1-phenyl-1-propanone.
</P>
<P>
13. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein the second layer comprises one or more compounds selected from the group consisting of polycarbonate, polyester carbonate, polyester, polyphenylene ethers and graft copolymers.
</P>
<P>
14. A multi-layer product according to claim 1 further comprising UV protective layer (S3) which contains a UV stabiliser according to formula (IV)
</P>
<P>
EMI22.0
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
X-OR&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; , OCH2CH2OR&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; , OCH2CH(OH)CH2OR&amp;lt;6 &amp;gt; or OCH(R&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; )COOR&amp;lt;8 &amp;gt;
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; =branched or unbranched C1-C13 alkyl, C2-C20 alkenyl, C6-C12 aryl or -CO-C1-C18 alkyl
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; -H or branched or unbranched C1 to C8 alkyl, and
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;8&amp;gt; -C1-C12 alkyl; C2-C12 alkenyl or C5-C6 cycloalkyl,
</P>
<P>
and wherein the layer sequence is (S1)-(S2)-(S3) and layers (S1) and (S3) have the same or different compositions.
</P>
<P>
15. A coating obtained from
</P>
<P>
A) one or more aliphatic polymer precursors selected from the group consisting of
</P>
<P>
A.1) aliphatic oligomers containing urethane bonds or ester bonds with at least two acrylate functions per molecule or mixtures of corresponding oligomers and
</P>
<P>
A.2) aliphatic reactive diluents with at least two acrylate groups per molecule or mixtures of corresponding reactive diluents,
</P>
<P>
B) one or more fine-particle inorganic compounds,
</P>
<P>
C) at least one organic UV absorber selected from the group consisting of triazine derivatives and biphenyltriazine derivatives,
</P>
<P>
D) optionally one or more radical scavengers of the hindered amine light stabilizer (HALS) class
</P>
<P>
E) optionally one or more flow control agents
</P>
<P>
F) optionally one or more solvents, and
</P>
<P>
G) at least one special photoinitiator selected from the group consisting of
</P>
<P>
H) cylphosphine oxide derivatives and [alpha]-aminoalkylphenone derivatives which is suitable for the production of at least one layer of a multi-layer product according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
16. A process for the production of a multi-layer product according to claim 1, comprising
</P>
<P>
i) applying the first layer (S1) in the form of a coating formulation to the second layer (S2), and
</P>
<P>
ii) curing the coating formulation of the first layer by exposing the first layer to UV radiation.
</P>
<P>
17. A multi-layer product according to claim 1, wherein the second layer comprises a plastic molding.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007237967A1;TW200808540A;RU2008143913A;MX2008012963A;KR20090038842A;JP2009533242A;WO2007115678A1;DE102006016642A1;CN101466805A;CA2648463A1;BRPI0710646A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
