<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOCOMPOSITE PARTICLE AND PROCESS OF PREPARING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2069439A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FU GUOYI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AUGUSTINE STEVEN M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FU, GUOYI
</Name>
<Name>
AUGUSTINE, STEVEN, M
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MILLENNIUM INORGANIC CHEM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MILLENNIUM INORGANIC CHEMICALS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2069439
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070813971
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US75661
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060509339
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-08-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09C1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/42
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00H2
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanocomposite particle, its use as a catalyst, and a method of making it are disclosed. The nanocomposite particle comprises titanium dioxide nanoparticles, metal oxide nanoparticles, and a surface stabilizer. The metal oxide nanoparticles are formed hydrothermally in the presence of the titanium dioxide nanoparticles. The nanocomposite particle is an effective catalyst support, particularly for DeNOx catalyst applications.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
We ciaim:
</P>
<P>
1 , A nanocornposite particle comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) titanium dioxide nanopartici[beta]s;
</P>
<P>
(b) metal oxide nanoparticles selected from the group consisting of zirconium dioxide, cerium dioxide, hafnium oxide, tin oxide, niobium oxide and tantalum oxide; and
</P>
<P>
(c) a surface stabilizer selected from the group consisting of Silicon dioxide, aluminum oxide, phosphorus pentoxide, aluminum si[upsilon]cate and aluminum phosphate, wherein the metaf oxide nanoparticles are formed by hydrothermaily treating an amorphous hydraled metal oxide in the presence of the titanium dioxide nanopartictes,
</P>
<P>
2. The nanocomposite particle of ciaim 1 wherein [iota]he titanium dioxide nanoparticles are predominantly anatase. 3. The nanocomposite particle of claim 1 wherein the metai oxide nanoparticles are zirconium dioxide.
</P>
<P>
4. The nanocomposite particle of claim 1 comprising 50 to 95 weight percent titanium dioxide nanoparticles, 2 to 48 weight percent metai oxide nanoparticles, and 2 to 20 weight percent surface stabilizer. 5. The nanocomposite particle of ciaim 1 having a surface area greater than 60 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g after being calcined at 800[deg.] C for 8 hours.
</P>
<P>
6. A catalyst comprising the nanocomposite particie of ciaim 1 and at least one metai component comprising a metal selected from the group consisting of platinum, goid, silver, palladium, copper, tungsten, molybdenum, vanadium, iron, rhodium, nickel, manganese, chromium, cobalt, and ruthenium.
</P>
<P>
7. The catalyst of claim 6 wherein the metal component is selected from the group consisting of tungsten trioxide and vanadium pentoxide.
</P>
<P>
8. The catalyst of claim 7 comprising 0.1 to 10 weight percent vanadium pentoxide and 4 to 20 weight percent tungsten trioxide. 9. A process comprising contacting a waste stream containing nitrogen oxides with the catalyst of claim 7 to reduce the amount of nitrogen oxides in the waste stream,
</P>
<P>
10. A process for preparing a nanocomposite particle comprising: (a) forming a slurry comprising titanium dioxide nanoparticles, at least one soluble metal oxide precursor, and a solvent;
</P>
<P>
(b) precipitating the soluble metal oxide precursor to form a slurry comprising titanium dioxide nanoparticles, an amorphous faydrated metai oxide, and the solvent;
</P>
<P>
(c) hydrothermaliy treating the slurry of step (b) to convert the amorphous hydrated metai oxide to metai oxide [pi]a[pi]oparticies; and
</P>
<P>
(d) optionally, calcining the nanocomposite particle, wherein a surface stabiiizer is added before or immediately after the hydfothermai treatment,
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 10 wherein the hydrotherrna! treatment is performed at a temperature ranging from 60[deg.]C to 250[deg.]C and a pressure ranging from 20 to 500 psig. 12, The process of claim 10 wherein the titanium dioxide nanoparticles are predominantly anaiase,
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 10 wherein the soluble metal oxide precursor is selected from the group consisting of compounds of zirconium, cerium, aluminum, hafnium, tin and niobium, 14. The process of ciaim 10 wherein the surface stabilizer is selected from the group consisting of amorphous silicon dioxide, haiides or alkoxides of silicon and aluminum, and aluminum phosphate.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 10 wherein the nanocomposite particle comprises 50 to 95 weight percent titanium dioxide nanoparticies, 2 to 48 weight percent metal oxide na[pi]opartides, and 2 to 20 weight percent surface stabilizer.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 10 further comprising adding at least one metai component comprising a metal selected from the group consisting of platinum, gold, silver, palladium, tungsten, vanadium, molybdenum, and copper.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 16 wherein the metai component is selected from the group consisting of ammonium paratungstate and vanadium pentoxide.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of claim 17 wherein the nanocomposite particle comprises 0.1 to 10 weight percent vanadium pentoxide and 4 to 20 weight percent tungsten trioxide.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of claim 10 wherein the nanocomposite particle has a surface area greater than 60 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g after being calcined at 800&apos; C for 6 hours,
</P>
<P>
20. The process of claim 10 wherein the solvent [iota]s water.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2069439A4;WO2008024635A1;US2010099552A1;US7820583B2;US2009325787A1;US7842641B2;US2009324472A1;US8075859B2;MX2009002113A;KR20090057262A;CN101517013A;CA2663782A1;AU2007286908A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
