<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Magnetoresistive element with a biasing layer
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2023354A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KATTI ROMNEY R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KATTI, ROMNEY R
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
HONEYWELL INT INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HONEYWELL INTERNATIONAL INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2023354
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080157235
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070832416
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01F10/32
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N6A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An improved magnetoresistive element may include a pinned magnetic structure, a free magnetic structure, and a spacer layer coupled between the pinned magnetic structure and the free magnetic structure, where the free magnetic structure includes (i) a synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure (SAF) including two or more anti-ferromagnetically coupled ferromagnetic layers, and (ii) a first biasing layer coupled to the SAF that impedes a decoupling of the two or more anti-ferromagnetically coupled ferromagnetic layers. The first biasing layer may be an anti-ferromagnetic layer, and may be weakly coupled to the SAF.;  The free magnetic structure may also include (i) a second biasing layer coupled to the SAF that further impedes a decoupling of the two or more anti-ferromagnetically coupled ferromagnetic layers, and/or (ii) a non-magnetic layer coupled between the first biasing layer and the SAF that controls a coupling strength between the first biasing layer and the SAF.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A magnetoresistive element comprising:
</P>
<P>
a pinned magnetic structure;
</P>
<P>
a free magnetic structure; and
</P>
<P>
a spacer layer coupled between the pinned magnetic structure and the free magnetic structure,
</P>
<P>
wherein the free magnetic structure comprises:
</P>
<P>
a synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure including two or more anti-ferromagnetically coupled ferromagnetic layers; and
</P>
<P>
a first biasing layer coupled to the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure, wherein the first biasing layer impedes a decoupling of the two or more anti-ferromagnetically coupled ferromagnetic layers.
</P>
<P>
2. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein the first biasing layer comprises an anti-ferromagnetic layer.
</P>
<P>
3. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein the first biasing layer is weakly coupled to the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure.
</P>
<P>
4. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein a coupling strength between the first biasing layer and the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure is less than an anti-ferromagnetic coupling strength of the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure.
</P>
<P>
5. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein the first biasing layer is selected from a group consisting of:
</P>
<P>
an iron manganese layer;
</P>
<P>
a nickel manganese layer; and
</P>
<P>
a platinum manganese layer.
</P>
<P>
6. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein the free magnetic structure further comprises:
</P>
<P>
a second biasing layer coupled to the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure, wherein the second biasing layer further impedes a decoupling of the two or more anti-ferromagnetically coupled ferromagnetic layers.
</P>
<P>
7. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein the free magnetic structure further comprises:
</P>
<P>
a non-magnetic layer coupled between the first biasing layer and the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure, wherein the non-magnetic layer controls a coupling strength between the first biasing layer and the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure.
</P>
<P>
8. The magnetoresistive element of claim 1, wherein the synthetic anti-ferromagnetic structure comprises:
</P>
<P>
a first free ferromagnetic layer having a first magnetic moment vector;
</P>
<P>
a second free ferromagnetic layer having a second magnetic moment vector; and
</P>
<P>
an exchange layer coupled between the first free ferromagnetic layer and the second free ferromagnetic layer, wherein the first free ferromagnetic layer and the second free ferromagnetic layer are anti-ferromagnetically coupled through the exchange layer.
</P>
<P>
9. The magnetoresistive element of claim 8, wherein the first biasing layer is coupled to the first free ferromagnetic layer, and wherein the first biasing layer impedes a rotation of the first magnetic moment vector.
</P>
<P>
10. The magnetoresistive element of claim 9, wherein the free magnetic structure further comprises:
</P>
<P>
a second biasing layer coupled to the second free ferromagnetic layer, wherein the second biasing layer impedes a rotation of the second magnetic moment vector; and
</P>
<P>
a non-magnetic layer coupled between the first biasing layer and the first free ferromagnetic layer, wherein the non-magnetic layer controls a coupling strength between the first biasing layer and the first free ferromagnetic layer.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2023354A3;US2009034321A1;JP2009038343A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
