<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
RESIN COMPOSITION AND METHOD FOR PRODUCING SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2006332A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KUWAHARA HIROAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HONDA SUSUMU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BANDO YOSHIO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHI CHUNYI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANG CHENGCHUN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
GOLBERG DMITRI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KUWAHARA, HIROAKI
</Name>
<Name>
HONDA, SUSUMU
</Name>
<Name>
BANDO, YOSHIO
</Name>
<Name>
ZHI, CHUNYI
</Name>
<Name>
TANG, CHENGCHUN
</Name>
<Name>
GOLBERG, DMITRI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TEIJIN LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAT INST FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TEIJIN LIMITED
</Name>
<Name>
NATIONAL INSTITUTE FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2006332
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070714332
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-02-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP52802
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060033524
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060036145
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-02-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060153486
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-06-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/20
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/38
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
<Class>
C08L77/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08L79/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/205D
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/20H
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/18
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The object of this invention consists in providing a polyamide resin composition excellent in insulating properties, mechanical properties and dimensional stability. This invention is a resin composition containing 100 parts by weight of a polyamide resin and 0.01 to 50 parts by weight of boron nitride nanotubes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A resin composition comprising 100 parts by weight of a polyamide and 0.01 to 50 parts by weight of boron nitride nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
2. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the content of the boron nitride nanotubes per 100 parts by weight of the polyamide is 0.01 to 30 parts by weight.
</P>
<P>
3. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the boron nitride nanotubes have an average diameter of 0.4 nm to 1 m and an aspect ratio of 5 or more.
</P>
<P>
4. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide mainly contains recurring units of the following formula (1),
</P>
<P>
wherein X is
</P>
<P>
in which each of R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is independently an aliphatic hydrocarbon group having 2 to 16 carbon atoms or an aromatic hydrocarbon group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms,
</P>
<P>
Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is an aromatic hydrocarbon group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms,
</P>
<P>
Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is an aromatic hydrocarbon group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms or an aliphatic hydrocarbon group having 2 to 16 carbon atoms, and
</P>
<P>
each of Y&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and Y&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is independently a hydrogen atom or an alkyl group having 1 to 16 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
5. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide mainly contains recurring units of the following formula (2),
</P>
<P>
in which each of R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is independently an aliphatic hydrocarbon group having 4 to 16 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
6. The resin composition of claim 5, wherein R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is a tetramethylene group, a hexamethylene group, a decamethylene group or a 1,4-cyclohexylene group and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is a tetramethylene group, a hexamethylene group, a nonamethylene group or a 1,4-cyclohexylene group in the formula (2).
</P>
<P>
7. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide mainly contains recurring units of the following formula (3),
</P>
<P>
in which R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is a divalent aliphatic hydrocarbon group having 2 to 12 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
8. The resin composition of claim 7, wherein R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is a pentamethylene group, a decamethylene group or an undecamethylene group in the formula (3).
</P>
<P>
9. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide mainly contains recurring units of the following formula (2),
</P>
<P>
in which each of R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is independently an aromatic hydrocarbon group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
10. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide mainly contains recurring units of the following formula (2),
</P>
<P>
wherein R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is an aromatic hydrocarbon group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, and
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is an aliphatic hydrocarbon group having 2 to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
11. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide mainly contains recurring units of the following formula (4),
</P>
<P>
wherein Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is a trivalent aromatic hydrocarbon group having 5 to 20 carbon atoms, and
</P>
<P>
Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is a divalent aromatic hydrocarbon group having 5 to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
12. The resin composition of claim 11, wherein Ar&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is
</P>
<P>
and Ar&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is
</P>
<P>
or
</P>
<P>
13. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide main contains recurring units of the following formula (2),
</P>
<P>
in which R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is a phenylene group, and
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is an aliphatic hydrocarbon group having 3 to 16 carbon atoms and having a side chain or an alicyclic hydrocarbon group having 5 to 16 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
14. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide is amorphous.
</P>
<P>
15. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the polyamide is crystalline.
</P>
<P>
16. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the boron nitride nanotubes are coated with a conjugated polymer.
</P>
<P>
17. The resin composition of claim 1, wherein the conjugated polymer is polyphenylenevinylene, polythiophene, polyphenylene, polypyrrole, polyaniline or polyacetylene.
</P>
<P>
18. A formed article from the resin composition of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
19. The formed article of claim 14, which is a film or a fiber.
</P>
<P>
20. A process for the production of the resin composition of claim 1, which comprises the steps of
</P>
<P>
(i) mixing 0.01 to 50 parts by weight of boron nitride nanotubes with a solvent to obtain a dispersion,
</P>
<P>
(ii) adding a polyamide to the dispersion to obtain a dope such that the amount of the boron nitride nanotubes is 0.01 to 50 parts by weight per 100 parts by weight of the polyamide, and
</P>
<P>
(iii) removing the solvent.
</P>
<P>
21. The process for the production of a resin composition as recited in claim 1, wherein the polyamide and the boron nitride nanotubes are melt-kneaded.
</P>
<P>
22. The process for the production of a resin composition as recited in claim 1, wherein the polyamide is produced by polycondensation in the presence of the boron nitride nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
23. A process for the production of a formed article, which comprises wet-forming a dope containing 100 parts by weight of a polyamide, 0.01 to 50 parts by weight of boron nitride nanotubes and a solvent into the formed article.
</P>
<P>
24. A process for the production of a formed article, which comprises melt-forming a resin composition containing 100 parts by weight of a polyamide and 0.01 to 50 parts by weight of boron nitride nanotubes into the formed article.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2006332A4;US2009221734A1;WO2007091737A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
