<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Anisotropic magnetic flakes
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2039729A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RAKSHA VLADIMIR P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MARKANTES CHARLES T [US]
</Name>
<Name>
COOMBS PAUL G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PHILLIPS ROGER W [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KOHLMANN PAUL T [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RAKSHA, VLADIMIR P
</Name>
<Name>
MARKANTES, CHARLES T
</Name>
<Name>
COOMBS, PAUL G
</Name>
<Name>
PHILLIPS, ROGER W
</Name>
<Name>
KOHLMANN, PAUL T
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
JDS UNIPHASE CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
JDS UNIPHASE CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2039729
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080164504
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-09-17
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070973546P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-19
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00F
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00F10
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to anisotropic, reflective, magnetic flakes. In a liquid carrier and under influence of an external magnetic field, the flakes attract to one another side-by-side and form ribbons which provide higher reflectivity to a coating and may be used as a security feature for authentication of an object.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An anisotropic magnetic flake for forming a reflective coating,
</P>
<P>
comprising a layered structure
</P>
<P>
having a thickness in the range of 50 nm - 10 microns,
</P>
<P>
having a two-dimensional shape with a longest planar dimension in the range of 1 -
</P>
<P>
500 microns, and
</P>
<P>
comprising:
</P>
<P>
first and second reflector layers having reflectivity of greater than 40%, for providing reflectivity to the reflective coating, and
</P>
<P>
a magnetic layer between the first and second reflector layers, for aligning the flake substantially parallel to the surface of the reflective coating, when said flake is disposed in a liquid carrier under influence of an external magnetic field;wherein the magnetic layer has a structure which provides in-plane magnetic anisotropy forming an angle of at least 20 degrees with the longest planar dimension.
</P>
<P>
2. A flake defined in claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the magnetic layer is a continuous magnetic layer absent of a grating, the two-dimensional shape has two sides substantially parallel to each other,
</P>
<P>
and wherein the in-plane magnetic anisotropy of the magnetic layer is substantially orthogonal to said two sides for alignment of the flake side-by-side with one or more flakes of a same structure when said flakes are disposed in a liquid carrier under influence of an external magnetic field while forming the reflective coating.
</P>
<P>
3. A flake defined in claim 2, wherein the two-dimensional shape is a rectangular shape and the in-plane magnetic anisotropy of the magnetic layer is substantially parallel to a side of the rectangular shape.
</P>
<P>
4. A flake defined in claim 1, further comprising first and second dielectric layers supported by the first and second reflector layers, respectively, and first and second absorber layers supported by the first and second dielectric layers, respectively, for providing a color-shifting optical effect.
</P>
<P>
5. A method of manufacturing a flake defined in claim 2, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
a) providing a substrate for supporting a releasable coating, which includes the first and second reflector layers and the magnetic layer formed of a magnetic material;
</P>
<P>
b) embossing or etching the substrate with a plurality of frames having the two-dimensional shape with the two sides substantially orthogonal to a first direction, before or after the releasable coating is applied to the substrate;
</P>
<P>
c) coating the substrate with the releasable coating so as to provide the magnetic layer having a magnetic anisotropy in the first direction, wherein the releasable coating upon removal from the substrate breaks apart into the flakes; and,
</P>
<P>
d) removing the releasable coating from the substrate and breaking it into the flakes.
</P>
<P>
6. A method defined in claim 5, wherein in step (b) the substrate is moving in the first direction.
</P>
<P>
7. A method defined in claim 5, wherein the substrate is curved.
</P>
<P>
8. A method defined in claim 5, wherein step (b) includes using at least two sources of the magnetic material which provide the magnetic material to a same portion of the substrate at different angles.
</P>
<P>
9. A method defined in claim 8, wherein the at least two sources of the magnetic material provide the magnetic material to the same portion of the substrate simultaneously.
</P>
<P>
10. A method defined in claim 8, wherein the at least two sources of the magnetic material provide the magnetic material to the same portion of the substrate at different times.
</P>
<P>
11. A method defined in claim 5, wherein step (b) includes moving the substrate in the first direction and using two sources of magnetic material disposed so that a line connecting the two sources is substantially orthogonal to the first direction.
</P>
<P>
12. A method defined in claim 5, wherein step (b) includes moving the substrate in the first direction and using two sources of magnetic material disposed so that a line connecting the two sources is substantially parallel to the first direction.
</P>
<P>
13. A method defined in claim 5, wherein step (b) includes annealing of the magnetic material in a magnetic field.
</P>
<P>
14. A method defined in claim 5, wherein step (b) includes Xe-ion-irradiation of the magnetic material.
</P>
<P>
15. A coating comprising a solidified carrier and a plurality of flakes having the structure defined in claim 1 dispersed therein,
</P>
<P>
wherein all flakes of the plurality of flakes have a same two-dimensional shape, such that two sides thereof are substantially parallel to each other, and have the magnetic layer such that the in-plane magnetic anisotropy is substantially orthogonal to said two sides;
</P>
<P>
and wherein a portion of the flakes forms a ribbon of at least three flakes adjacent to one another so as to be side-by-side with gaps between the flakes of no greater than 500 nm, when said flakes are disposed in a liquid carrier under influence of an external magnetic field while forming the coating.
</P>
<P>
16. A coating defined in claim 15, wherein the portion of the flakes form two or more ribbons adjacent to one another so as to be side-by-side with gaps between the ribbons of no greater than 4 micron, whereby forming a tile array of flakes.
</P>
<P>
17. A method of authentication of an object having thereon a coating defined in claim 15, comprising the step of identifying a ribbon.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2039729A3;EP2039729B1;TW200921719A;JP2009102620A;CN101392103A;CA2639554A1;AU2008219354A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
