<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
HYPERTHERMIC TECHNOLOGIES AND THERAPEUTIC USES THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2026765A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TORTI SUZY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORTI FRANK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CARROLL DAVID LOREN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AKMAN STEVEN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NALAMASU OMKARAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AJAYAN PULICKEL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORTI, SUZY
</Name>
<Name>
TORTI, FRANK
</Name>
<Name>
CARROLL, DAVID, LOREN
</Name>
<Name>
AKMAN, STEVEN
</Name>
<Name>
NALAMASU, OMKARAM
</Name>
<Name>
AJAYAN, PULICKEL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV WAKE FOREST HEALTH [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIV WAKE FOREST [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RENSSELAER POLYTECH INST [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WAKE FOREST UNIVERSITY HEALTH SCIENCES
</Name>
<Name>
WAKE FOREST UNIVERSITY
</Name>
<Name>
RENSSELAER POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2026765
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070795351
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-05-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US12492
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060808399P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060854500P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K33/22
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K45/06
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K33/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K33/22
</Class>
<Class>
A61K33/44
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00U
</Class>
<Class>
A61K45/06
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/06
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18R4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00L8
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00Z4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides nanoscale and microscale compositions useful for a variety of purposes, including the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. In one embodiment, the present invention provides a disease treatment system comprising a thermal induction agent and a radiation source, wherein the thermal induction agent comprises at least one carbon nanotube, at least one carbon microtube, or a mixture thereof.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A disease treatment system comprising: a thermal induction agent; and a radiation source, wherein the thermal induction agent comprises at least one carbon nanotube, at least one carbon microtube, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
2. The disease treatment system of claim 1, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube is doped with boron, nitrogen, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
3. The disease treatment system of claim 2, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube comprises from about 0.01 weight percent nitrogen to about
</P>
<P>
30 weight percent nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
4. The disease treatment system of claim 1, wherein the at&apos; least one carbon microtube has a bent, curved, or folded structure.
</P>
<P>
5. The disease treatment system of claim 4, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a radius of gyration ranging from about 1 [mu]m to about 100 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
6. The disease treatment system of claim 4, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a substantially spherical shape.
</P>
<P>
7. The disease treatment system of claim 1 , wherein the at least one carbon nanotube comprises a multi- walled carbon nanotube. 8. The disease treatment system of claim 1, wherein the at least one carbon microtube comprises a multi-walled carbon microtube.
</P>
<P>
9. The disease treatment system of claim 1, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube further comprises iron.
</P>
<P>
10. The disease treatment system of claim 1, wherein the radiation source comprises an infrared radiation source, a microwave radiation source, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. A disease imaging and treatment system comprising: a magnetic field source; a radiation source; and a thermally inducting contrast agent, wherein the thermally inducting contrast agent comprises at least one carbon nanotube comprising iron, at least one carbon microtube comprising iron, or a mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The disease imaging and treatment system of claim 11 , wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube comprises at least 0.1 weight percent iron.
</P>
<P>
13. The disease imaging and treatment system of claim 11 , wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube is doped with boron, nitrogen, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The disease imaging and treatment system of claim 13, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube comprises from about 0.01 weight percent to about 30 weight percent nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
15. The disease treatment system of claim 11, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a bent, curved, or folded structure.
</P>
<P>
16. The disease treatment system of claim 15, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a radius of gyration ranging from about 1 [mu]m to about 100 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
17. The disease treatment system of claim 15, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a substantially spherical shape.
</P>
<P>
18. The disease treatment system of claim 11, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube comprises a multi-walled carbon nanotube. 19. The disease treatment system of claim 1 , wherein the at least one carbon microtube comprises a multi-walled carbon microtube.
</P>
<P>
20. A method for treating disease comprising: disposing at least one carbon nanotube, at least one carbon microtube, or a mixture thereof in a biological environment; and heating the biological environment with the at least one carbon nanotube, at least one carbon microtube, or the mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 20, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube is doped with boron, nitrogen, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 21, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube comprises from about 0.01 weight percent to about 30 weight percent nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 20, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a bent, curved, or folded structure.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 23, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a radius of gyration ranging from about 1 [mu]m to about 100 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 23, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a substantially spherical shape.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 20, further comprising dispersing the at least one carbon nanotube, the at least one carbon microtube, of the mixture thereof in a physiologically acceptable carrier.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 20, wherein heating the biological environment comprises irradiating the at least one carbon nanotube, the at least one carbon microtube, or the mixture thereof with infrared radiation, microwave radiation, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 20, wherein the biological environment comprises cancerous tissue.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of claim 28, wherein the cancerous tissue comprises a tumor. 30. The method of claim 29, wherein the at least one carbon nanoparticle, the at least one carbon microparticle, of the mixture thereof is disposed in the vasculature of the tumor.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 30, further comprising killing cells of the tumor wherein killing comprises inducing hyperthermia in the cells of the tumor.
</P>
<P>
32. A method of imaging and treating disease comprising: disposing at least one carbon nanoparticle comprising iron, at least one carbon microparticle comprising iron, or a mixture thereof in a biological environment; imaging the biological environment with the at least one carbon nanoparticle, the at least one carbon microparticle, or the mixture thereof; and heating the biological environment with the at least one carbon nanoparticle, the at &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; least one carbon microparticle, or the mixture thereof.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 32, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube comprises at least 0.1 weight percent iron.
</P>
<P>
34. The disease method of claim 32, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube is doped with boron, nitrogen, or a combination thereof. 35. The method of claim 34, wherein the at least one carbon nanotube or the at least one carbon microtube comprises from about 0.01 weight percent to about 30 weight percent nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of claim 32, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a bent, curved, or folded structure. 37. The method of claim 36, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a radius of gyration ranging from about 1 [mu]m to about 100 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of claim 36, wherein the at least one carbon microtube has a substantially spherical shape.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of claim 32, further comprising dispersing the at least one carbon nanotube, the at least one carbon microtube, or the mixture thereof in a physiologically acceptable carrier.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of claim 32, wherein imaging the biological environment comprises inducing a magnetic field and disposing the biological environment in the magnetic field.
</P>
<P>
41. The method of claim 32, wherein heating the biological environment comprises irradiating the at least one carbon nanotube, the at least one carbon microtube, or the mixture thereof with infrared radiation, microwave radiation, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
42. The method of claim 32, wherein the biological environment comprises cancerous tissue.
</P>
<P>
43. The method of claim 42, wherein the cancerous tissue comprises a tumor.
</P>
<P>
44. The method of claim 43, wherein the at least one carbon nanoparticle, the at least one carbon microparticle, of the mixture thereof is disposed in the vasculature of the tumor.
</P>
<P>
45. The method of claim 44, further comprising killing cells of the tumor wherein killing comprises inducing hyperthermia in the cells of the tumor.
</P>
<P>
46. A composition comprising: a solution, the solution comprising: a physiologically acceptable carrier; and a plurality of carbon nanotubes, a plurality of carbon microtubes, or a mixture thereof disposed in a physiologically acceptable carrier at a concentration ranging from about
</P>
<P>
0.1 [mu]g/ml to about 5 mg/ml.
</P>
<P>
47. The composition of claim 46, wherein the concentration ranges from about 10 [mu]g/ml to about 500 [mu]g/ml.
</P>
<P>
48. The composition of claim 46, wherein the concentration ranges from about 100 [mu]g/ml to about 200 [mu]g/ml.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2026765B1;WO2007139936A2;WO2007139936A3;US2010075925A1;ES2373588T3;EP2394639A1;AT524197T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
