<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FLUORESCENT SEMICONDUCTOR MICROPARTICLE ASSEMBLY, FLUORESCENT LABELING AGENT ASSEMBLY FOR BIOLOGICAL SUBSTANCE, AND BIOIMAGING METHOD AND BIOLOGICAL SUBSTANCE ANALYSIS METHOD USING THE ASSEMBLIES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2060916A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TSUKADA KAZUYA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKADA HISATAKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HOSHINO HIDEKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TSUKADA, KAZUYA
</Name>
<Name>
OKADA, HISATAKE
</Name>
<Name>
HOSHINO, HIDEKI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONICA MINOLTA MED &amp; GRAPHIC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KONICA MINOLTA MEDICAL &amp; GRAPHIC, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2060916
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070792854
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-08-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP66256
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060249208
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C12Q1/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/64
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/78
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/533
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/545
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/553
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/64S
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/533
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58J
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is a fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly comprising at least three kinds of fluorescent semiconductor microparticles with an average particle size of from 1 to 10 nm, having the same chemical composition, a different average particle size and a different emission maximum wavelength in the emission spectra, wherein a standard deviation of emission intensity in each of the at least three kinds of fluorescent semiconductor microparticles is not more than 15%.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly comprising at least three kinds of fluorescent semiconductor microparticles with a particle size of from 1 to 10 nm, having the same chemical composition, a different particle size and a different emission maximum wavelength in the emission spectra, characterized in that a standard deviation of emission intensity in each of the at least three kinds of fluorescent semiconductor microparticles is not more than 15%.
</P>
<P>
2. The fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly of claim 1, characterized in that the wavelength of emission maximum in the emission spectra is in the range of from 380 to 800 nm.
</P>
<P>
3. The fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly of claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the at least three kinds of fluorescent semiconductor microparticles having a different emission maximum wavelength in the emission spectra emit light on irradiation with one kind of excitation light.
</P>
<P>
4. A method of manufacturing the fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly of any one of claims 1 through 3, characterized in that the fluorescent semiconductor microparticles are manufactured according to a liquid phase method.
</P>
<P>
5. A fluorescent labeling agent assembly for a biological substance, characterized in that the fluorescent semiconductor microparticles, constituting the fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly of any one of claims 1 through 4, have on the surface a surface-modifying compound having a functional group through which is associated with a biological substance and a functional group through which is associated with the fluorescent semiconductor microparticle surface.
</P>
<P>
6. The fluorescent labeling agent assembly for a biological substance of claim 5, characterized in that the fluorescent semiconductor microparticles having a different particle size, constituting the fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly of any one of claims 1 through 4, have on the surface a different surface-modifying compound suitable for a different biological substance.
</P>
<P>
7. A bioimaging method characterized in that fluorescent dynamic imaging of at least three kinds of target or trace substances is simultaneously carried out, employing the fluorescent labeling agent assembly for a biological substance of claim 5 or 6.
</P>
<P>
8. A biological substance analysis method characterized in that multi-flow cytometry of a biological substance is carried out, employing polymer beads in which the fluorescent semiconductor microparticle assembly of any one of claims 1 through 3 is buried.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2060916A4;US2010041017A1;US8110407B2;WO2008032534A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
