<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Sidewall functionalization of carbon nanotubes with organosilanes for polymer composites
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2067741A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BARRERA ENRIQUE V [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHU JIANG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KHABASHESKU VALERY N [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MARGRAVE JOHN L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM JONG DAE [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG LEI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BARRERA, ENRIQUE, V
</Name>
<Name>
ZHU, JIANG
</Name>
<Name>
KHABASHESKU, VALERY, N
</Name>
<Name>
MARGRAVE, JOHN, L
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, JONG, DAE
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG, LEI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV RICE WILLIAM M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WILLIAM MARSH RICE UNIVERSITY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2067741
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090152390
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-07-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040779404
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-07-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20030490664P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-07-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/14
</Class>
<Class>
C08K7/24
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/44
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D6
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention is directed to methods of functionalizing carbon nanotubes (CNTs), particularly single-wall carbon nanotubes (SWNTs), with organosilane species, wherein such functionalization enables fabrication of advanced polymer composites. The present invention is also directed toward the functionalized CNTs, advanced CNT-polymer composites made with such functionalized CNTs, and methods of making such advanced CNT-polymer composites.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A composite material comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) carbon nanotubes (CNTs);
</P>
<P>
b) a quantity of fiber reinforcement material; and
</P>
<P>
c) polymer, wherein the CNTs serve as a bridge, chemically binding the fiber reinforcement material with the polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. The composite material of claim 1, wherein the CNTs are silane-functionalized.
</P>
<P>
3. The composite material of claim 1 or claim 2, wherein the CNTs are SWNTs.
</P>
<P>
4. The composite material of any of claims 1 to 3, wherein the fiber einforcement material is silane-functionalized.
</P>
<P>
5. The composite material of any of claims 1 to 4, wherein the fiber reinforcement material is glass fibers, wherein optionally the glass fibers have been resized.
</P>
<P>
6. The composite material of claim 5, wherein the glass fibers are present in the form of woven sheets.
</P>
<P>
7. The composite material of claim 6, wherein such woven sheets are stacked together with silane-functionalized CNTs and polymer between them.
</P>
<P>
8. The composite material of any of claims 1 to 7, wherein the polymer material is epoxy.
</P>
<P>
9. A method comprising :
</P>
<P>
a) adding carbon nanotubes (CNTs) to a quantity of fiber reinforcement material to form CNT-coated fibers;
</P>
<P>
b) contacting polymer material with the CNT-coated fibers to form composite material comprising CNTs, a fiber reinforcement material, and polymer material.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9, wherein the quantity of fiber reinforcement material comprises glass fiber, wherein optionally the glass fiber is resized with organosilane species.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9 or claim 10, wherein the CNTs are silane-functionalized.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of any of claims 9 to 11, wherein the step of adding CNTs to the fiber reinforcement material to form CNT-coated fibers comprises an incipient wetting process, which comprises:
</P>
<P>
a) dispersing CNTs and fiber reinforcement material in a solvent to form a mixture; and
</P>
<P>
b) removing said solvent to leave the fibers coated with CNTs.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12, wherein the CNTs are functionalized.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of any of claims 9 to 13, wherein the CNTs are chemically bound to the fiber reinforcement material through functional groups originating on either or both of the CNTs and fiber reinforcement material.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of any of claims 9 to 14, wherein the polymer material is selected from the group consisting of thermosets, thermoplastics, epoxies, vinylesters, polyester, bismaleimide, polystyrene, polybutadiene or polyisoprene and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of any of claims 9 to 15, wherein the polymer material comprises at least one polymer precursor.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 15 or claim 16 further comprising a step of polymerizing and/or curing the at least one polymer precursor.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of any of claims 9 to 17, wherein the fiber reinforcement material is sized with the CNTs.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of any of claims 9 to 18, wherein either or both of the CNTs and the fiber reinforcing material are chemically bound to the polymer material.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of any of claims 9 to 19 wherein the CNTs are selected from SWNTs, MWNTs, double-wall carbon nanotubes, and combinations thereof, wherein optionally the CNTs are SWNTs.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2005012171A2;WO2005012171A3;US2007298669A1;JP2007502246A;EP1660405A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
