<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
IMPROVED EXPLOSIVE MATERIALS BY STABILIZATION IN NANOTUBES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2066600A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BARKER DELMAR L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
OWENS WILLIAM R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BARKER, DELMAR, L
</Name>
<Name>
OWENS, WILLIAM, R
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
RAYTHEON CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RAYTHEON COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2066600
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070872291
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US78029
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060530081
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-08
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C06B45/00
</Class>
<Class>
C06B45/18
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C06B45/00
</Class>
<Class>
C06B45/18
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanotube containing an explosive compound, including a nanotube having an internal cavity defined by walls of the nanotube;  and an explosive compound contained within the internal cavity of the nanotube and a method of forming the explosive-compound containing nanotube. A process of providing energy to a predetermined location, including providing a nanotube at a predetermined location on a substrate, exposing the nanotube to an explosive compound;  and detonating the explosive compound within the nanotube to release energy at the predetermined location. A process of stabilizing an explosive compound, including providing an explosive compound, in which the explosive compound has a first sensitivity to shock and/or friction;  exposing a nanotube cavity to the explosive compound, so that the explosive compound enters the cavity;  in which, in the cavity, the explosive compound has a second sensitivity to shock and/or friction reduced in relation to the first sensitivity.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A nanotube containing an explosive compound, comprising: a nanotube having an internal cavity defined by a wall of the nanotube; and an explosive compound contained within the internal cavity of the nanotube.
</P>
<P>
2. The nanotube of claim 1 wherein the nanotube is a single-walled nanotube.
</P>
<P>
3. The nanotube of claim 1 wherein the internal cavity comprises an inside diameter ranging from about 1 nanometer to about 20 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
4. The nanotube of claim 1 wherein the explosive compound comprises one or more of a thacetone triperoxide, diacetone diperoxide, hexamethylene triperoxide diamine, a mononitrotoluene, a dinitrotoluene, a trinitrotoluene, ethylene glycol dinitrate, nitro methane, nitroglycerine, 1 ,3,5-trinitro-1 ,3,5-triazacyclooctane,
</P>
<P>
1 ,3,5,7-tetratnitro-1 ,3,5,7-tetraazacyclooctane, pentaerythhtol tetranitrate, ammonium nitrate, 1 ,2,3-propanetrial trinitrate, metal azides, polymorphic nitrogen and polynitrocubanes.
</P>
<P>
5. The nanotube of claim 1 wherein the explosive compound is stabilized as a result of its containment in the internal cavity of the nanotube.
</P>
<P>
6. The nanotube of claim 1 wherein the nanotube containing an explosive compound is itself contained within a larger nanotube.
</P>
<P>
7. The nanotube of claim 1 wherein a plurality of the nanotubes containing an explosive compound are arranged in an ordered array.
</P>
<P>
8. A macroscopic mass of conventional explosive material comprising a plurality of the explosive nanotubes of claim 1 distributed in at least a portion of the macroscopic mass.
</P>
<P>
9. A process for forming an explosive nanotube, comprising providing a nanotube, said nanotube having an internal cavity defined by a wall of the nanotube; exposing said nanotube to an explosive compound, wherein the explosive compound enters the internal cavity.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 9 wherein the explosive compound remains in the internal cavity following entry therein.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 9 wherein the exposing comprises exposing the explosive compound to the nanotube as a vapor, a liquid, a solution, a solid or in a super-critical fluid.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 9 further comprising irradiating the nanotube with electrons after filling.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 12 wherein, when the nanotube is a multiwalled nanotube, the irradiation shrinks the nanotube diameter and changes the crystal form of the material in the nanotube.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of claim 9 further comprising placing the nanotube in a selected location on a substrate.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 9 further comprising detonating the explosive compound within the nanotube.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 15 wherein the detonating is by application of electric current, electron beam, electromagnetic radiation, heat, pressure, heavy ion beam, alpha, beta or gamma rays, plasmons and/or phonons.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 9 further comprising placing the nanotube containing an explosive compound within a larger nanotube.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of claim 9 wherein the providing comprises arranging a plurality of the nanotubes in an ordered array.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of claim 9 further comprising combining a plurality of the explosive nanotubes with a mass of conventional explosive material.
</P>
<P>
20. The process of claim 19 wherein the plurality of explosive nanotubes are substantially uniformly distributed in at least a portion of the conventional explosive material.
</P>
<P>
21. The process of claim 19 further comprising applying microwave energy to the combined nanotubes and mass of conventional explosive, to initiate detonation of the explosive nanotubes and the explosive material.
</P>
<P>
22. The process of claim 21 wherein the microwave energy initiates substantially simultaneous detonation of substantially all of the explosive nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
23. A process of providing energy to a predetermined location, comprising: providing a nanotube at a predetermined location on a substrate, said nanotube having an internal cavity defined by a wall of the nanotube; exposing said nanotube to an explosive compound, wherein the explosive material enters the internal cavity; and detonating the explosive compound within the nanotube to release energy at the predetermined location.
</P>
<P>
24. The process of claim 23 wherein the nanotube is a single-walled nanotube.
</P>
<P>
25. The process of claim 23 wherein the explosive compound comprises one or more of a thacetone triperoxide, diacetone diperoxide, hexamethylene triperoxide diamine, a mononitrotoluene, a dinitrotoluene, a trinitrotoluene, ethylene glycol dinitrate, nitro methane, nitroglycerine, 1 ,3,5-trinitro-1 ,3,5-triazacyclooctane,
</P>
<P>
1 ,3,5,7-tetratnitro-1 ,3,5,7-tetraazacyclooctane, pentaerythritol tetranitrate, ammonium nitrate, 1 ,2,3-propanetrial trinitrate, metal azides, polymorphic nitrogen and polynitrocubanes.
</P>
<P>
26. The process of claim 23 wherein the explosive compound is stabilized as a result of its containment in the internal cavity of the nanotube.
</P>
<P>
27. The process of claim 23 further comprising placing the nanotube containing an explosive compound within a larger nanotube.
</P>
<P>
28. The process of claim 23 wherein the providing comprises arranging a plurality of the nanotubes in an ordered array.
</P>
<P>
29. The process of claim 28 wherein the ordered array is a component of a shaped charge explosive device.
</P>
<P>
30. The process of claim 23 wherein the substrate is a mass of conventional explosive material, and the step of exposing is carried out prior to the step of providing the nanotube on the substrate, and the step of providing comprises distributing the nanotubes throughout the mass.
</P>
<P>
31. A process of stabilizing an explosive compound, comprising: providing an explosive compound, wherein the explosive compound has a first sensitivity to shock and/or friction; providing a nanotube having an internal cavity defined by a wall of the nanotube; exposing the nanotube to the explosive compound, wherein the explosive compound enters the internal cavity; wherein in the cavity the explosive compound has a second sensitivity to shock and/or friction, and the second sensitivity is reduced in relation to the first sensitivity.
</P>
<P>
32. The process of claim 31 wherein the nanotube is a single-walled nanotube.
</P>
<P>
33. The process of claim 31 wherein the explosive compound comprises one or more of a thacetone triperoxide, diacetone diperoxide, hexamethylene triperoxide diamine, a mononitrotoluene, a dinitrotoluene, a trinitrotoluene, ethylene glycol dinitrate, nitro methane, nitroglycerine, 1 ,3,5-trinitro-1 ,3,5-triazacyclooctane,
</P>
<P>
1 ,3,5,7-tetratnitro-1 ,3,5,7-tetraazacyclooctane, pentaerythhtol tetranitrate, ammonium nitrate, 1 ,2,3-propanetrial trinitrate, metal azides, polymorphic nitrogen and polynitrocubanes.
</P>
<P>
34. The process of claim 31 further comprising placing the nanotube containing an explosive compound within a larger nanotube.
</P>
<P>
35. The process of claim 31 wherein the providing comprises arranging a plurality of the nanotubes in an ordered array.
</P>
<P>
36. The process of claim 35 wherein the ordered array is a component of a shaped charge explosive device.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008082724A2;WO2008082724A3;JP2010507549A;CA2661889A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
