<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD OF FORMING SUPPORTED NANOPARTICLE CATALYSTS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2043782A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MAO GUOPING [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HAUGEN GREGORY M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AGUILERA JACQUELINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MAO SHANE S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MAO, GUOPING
</Name>
<Name>
HAUGEN, GREGORY, M
</Name>
<Name>
AGUILERA, JACQUELINE
</Name>
<Name>
MAO, SHANE, S
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2043782
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070812587
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-07-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US72722
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060456724
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-11
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J37/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/86
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/90
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/92B
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/92S
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/92S2
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E60/50
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of forming a supported catalyst, the method comprising forming a colloidal suspension of platinum-iron catalyst nanoparticles in a solvent, depositing at least a portion of the catalyst nanoparticles onto support particles, and removing at least a portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of forming a supported catalyst, the method comprising: forming a colloidal suspension of catalyst nanoparticles in a solvent, the catalyst nanoparticles comprising platinum and iron; depositing at least a portion of the catalyst nanoparticles onto support particles; and removing at least a portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein removing the portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles comprises altering a solubility condition of the iron in the solvent, thereby leaching the portion of the iron from the catalyst nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 2, wherein altering the solubility condition of the iron in the solvent comprises lowering a pH of the solvent.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 2, wherein altering the solubility condition of the iron in the solvent comprises applying an electrical potential to the solvent.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1, wherein at least a portion of the deposited catalyst nanoparticles are porous after the iron removal.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1, wherein the catalyst nanoparticles have an average particle size of about 2 nanometers or less after the iron removal.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1, wherein the platinum constitutes at least about 50 molar percent of the catalyst nanoparticles in the colloidal suspension.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1, wherein forming the colloidal suspension comprises mixing a platinum-containing halogen and an iron-containing halogen in the solvent.
</P>
<P>
9. A method of forming a supported catalyst, the method comprising: forming a colloidal suspension of catalyst nanoparticles in a solvent having a pH of at least about 5, wherein the catalyst nanoparticles comprise platinum and iron; introducing support particles to the colloidal suspension; depositing at least a portion of the catalyst nanoparticles onto the support particles; and lowering the pH of the solvent to remove at least a portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9, wherein depositing the portion of the catalyst nanoparticles and lowering the pH of the solvent are performed substantially simultaneously.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9, further comprising applying an electrical potential to the solvent.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 9, further comprising removing the solvent from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 9, wherein the platinum constitutes at least about 50 molar percent of the catalyst nanoparticles in the colloidal suspension.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 9, wherein forming the colloidal suspension comprises mixing a platinum-containing halogen and an iron-containing halogen in the solvent.
</P>
<P>
15. A method of forming a fuel cell, the method comprising: forming a colloidal suspension of catalyst nanoparticles in a solvent, the catalyst nanoparticles comprising platinum and iron; depositing at least a portion of the catalyst nanoparticles onto support particles; removing at least a portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles, thereby forming a supported catalyst; coating the supported catalyst onto a layer of the fuel cell; and drying the supported catalyst.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 15, The method of claim 1, wherein removing the portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles comprises lowering a pH of the solvent, thereby leaching the portion of the iron from the deposited catalyst nanoparticles into the solvent.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 15, wherein at least a portion of the deposited catalyst nanoparticles are porous after the iron removal.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 15, wherein the layer of the fuel cell is selected from the group consisting of a gas diffusion layer and a polymer electrolyte membrane.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 15, wherein the catalyst nanoparticles have an average particle size of about 2 nanometers or less after the iron removal.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19, wherein the catalyst nanoparticles have a standard deviation of particle sizes of about 0.5 nanometers or less after the iron removal.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008008664A1;US2009215615A1;JP2009543681A;CN101489679A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
