<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SOLAR CELL EFFICIENCIES THROUGH PERIODICITY
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2018668A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BERMEL PETER [US]
</Name>
<Name>
JOANNOPOULOS JOHN D [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LUO CHIYAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BERMEL, PETER
</Name>
<Name>
JOANNOPOULOS, JOHN D
</Name>
<Name>
LUO, CHIYAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MASSACHUSETTS INST TECHNOLOGY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2018668
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070759997
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-04-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US65830
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060400911
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L31/0216
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0232
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/00M1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0216B3B
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0232
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/052B4
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E10/52
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A solar cell includes a photovoltaic material region. The photovoltaic material region is covered by a uniform anti-reflection coating. A photonic crystal structure is positioned on the photovoltaic material region. The photonic crystal structure provides a medium to produce a plurality of spatial orientations of an incident light signal received by the solar cell so as to allow trapping of a selective frequency of incident light in the solar cell.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A solar cell comprising:
</P>
<P>
a photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
a uniform anti-reflection coating that is positioned on said photovoltaic material region; and
</P>
<P>
a photonic crystal structure that that is positioned below the photovoltaic material region, said photonic crystal structure provides a medium to produce a plurality of spatial orientations of an incident light signal received by said solar cell so as to allow trapping of a selected frequency range of incident light in said solar cell.
</P>
<P>
2. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein said photovoltaic material region comprises silicon, or another indirect bandgap semiconductor
</P>
<P>
3. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein the diffractive component of said photonic crystal structure comprises holes of air or dielectric materials.
</P>
<P>
4. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein the reflective component of said photonic crystal structure comprises alternating layers of high and low index.
</P>
<P>
5. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 1D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
6. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 2D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
7. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 3D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
8. The solar cell of claim 2, wherein the diffractive component of said photonic crystal structure comprises a periodically etched grating on a DBR.
</P>
<P>
9. A method of forming a solar cell comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
forming a uniform anti-reflection coating that is positioned on said photovoltaic material region; and
</P>
<P>
forming a photonic crystal structure that that is positioned below the photovoltaic material region, said photonic crystal structure provides a medium to produce a plurality of spatial orientations of an incident light signal received by said solar cell so as to allow trapping of a selected frequency range of incident light in said solar cell.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9, wherein said photovoltaic material region comprises silicon, or another indirect bandgap semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9, wherein the diffractive component of said photonic crystal structure comprises holes of air or dielectric materials.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 9, wherein the reflective component of said photonic crystal structure comprises alternating layers of high and low index.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 9, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 1D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 9, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 2D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 9, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 3D photonic crystal structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 10, wherein the diffractive component of said photonic crystal structure comprises a periodically etched grating on a DBR.
</P>
<P>
17. A method of trapping light in a solar cell comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
forming a planar top surface;
</P>
<P>
positioning a uniform anti-reflection coating on top of the said photovoltaic material region; and
</P>
<P>
positioning a photonic crystal structure on said photovoltaic material region, said photonic crystal structure provides a medium to produce a plurality of spatial orientations of an incident light signal received by said solar cell so as to allow trapping of a selective frequency of incident light in said solar cell.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 17, wherein said photovoltaic material region comprises silicon, or another indirect bandgap semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 17, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises holes of air or dielectric.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 17, wherein the reflective component of said photonic crystal structure comprises alternating layers of high and low index.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 17, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 1D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 17, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 2D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 17, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 3D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 18, wherein the diffractive component of said photonic crystal structure comprises a periodically etched grating on a DBR.
</P>
<P>
25. A solar cell comprising:
</P>
<P>
a photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
a planar top surface of said photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
a uniform anti-reflection coating on top of said photovoltaic material region; and
</P>
<P>
a photonic crystal structure that surrounds a portion of said photovoltaic material region, said photonic crystal structure provides a medium to produce a plurality of spatial orientations of an incident light signal received by said solar cell so as to allow trapping of a selective frequency of incident light in said solar cell.
</P>
<P>
26. The solar cell of claim 25, wherein said photovoltaic material region comprises silicon or another indirect bandgap semiconductor
</P>
<P>
27. The solar cell of claim 25, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises holes of air or dielectric materials.
</P>
<P>
28. The solar cell of claim 25, wherein the reflective component of said photonic crystal structure comprises alternating layers of high and low index.
</P>
<P>
29. The solar cell of claim 25, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 1D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
30. The solar cell of claim 25, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 2D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
31. The solar cell of claim 1, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 3D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
32. The solar cell of claim 26, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a periodically etched grating on a DBR.
</P>
<P>
33. A method of forming a solar cell comprising
</P>
<P>
forming a photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
forming a planar surface on the top of said photovoltaic material region;
</P>
<P>
a uniform anti-reflection coating on top of said photovoltaic material region; and
</P>
<P>
forming a photonic crystal structure that only surrounds a portion of said photovoltaic material region, said photonic crystal structure provides a medium to produce a plurality of spatial orientations of an incident light signal received by said solar cell so as to allow trapping of a selective frequency of incident light in said solar cell.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 33, wherein said photovoltaic material region comprises silicon or another indirect bandgap semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of claim 33, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises holes of air or another dielectric material.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of claim 33, wherein the reflective component of said photonic crystal structure comprises alternating layers of high and low index.
</P>
<P>
37. The method of claim 33, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 1D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of claim 33, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 2D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of claim 33, wherein said photonic crystal structure comprises a 3D periodic dielectric structure with a reflector on the bottom.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of claim 34, wherein the reflective component of said photonic crystal structure comprises a periodically etched grating on a DBR.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007235072A1;WO2007121082A2;WO2007121082A3;JP2009533875A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
