<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ATTRACTION AND REPULSION OF MAGNETIC OF MAGNETIZABLE OBJECTS TO AND FROM A SENSOR SURFACE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2044416A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
PRINS MENNO WILLEM JOSE [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KAHLMAN JOSEPHUS ARNOLDUS HENRICUS MARIA [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
PRINS, MENNO, WILLEM, JOSE
</Name>
<Name>
KAHLMAN, JOSEPHUS, ARNOLDUS, HENRICUS, MARIA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONINKL PHILIPS ELECTRONICS NV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2044416
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070766662
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-06-06
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IB52133
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-06
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060117291
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-07-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070766662
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-06
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N15/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N35/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N15/06D
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/74B
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09B
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12M
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a magnetic sensor device a first magnetic field generating means (21a, 21b) for attracting magnetic or magnetizable objects (22), e.g. magnetic particles, to a sensor surface (23) and a second magnetic field generating means (25) for, in combination with the first magnetic field, repelling magnetic or magnetizable objects (22), e.g. magnetic particles, from the sensor surface (23). The magnetic fields generated by the first and second magnetic field generating means have substantially anti- parallel directions. The present invention furthermore provides a method for attracting and repelling magnetic or magnetizable objects (22), e.g. magnetic particles, to and from a sensor surface (23).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. A magnetic sensor device (20) having a surface (23) and comprising: a first integrated magnetic field generating means (21) for generating a first magnetic field in a first direction and having a first magnetic field strength, the first magnetic field being for attracting magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) to the surface (23) of the magnetic sensor device (20), at least one sensor element (24), a second magnetic field generating means for generating a second magnetic field in a second direction and having a second magnetic field strength, the second magnetic field in combination with the first magnetic field being for repelling magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) having a binding strength below a predetermined value from the surface (23) of the magnetic sensor device (20), the first and second direction being substantially anti-parallel to each other, and driving means for controlling modulation of the first and second magnetic field strengths.
</P>
<P>
2. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 1, wherein the second magnetic field generating means comprises an external magnetic field generating means.
</P>
<P>
3. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 1, wherein the second magnetic field generating means comprises at least an integrated magnetic field generating means (25).
</P>
<P>
4. A magnetic sensor device according to claim 1, wherein the driving means for controlling modulation of the first and second magnetic field strength is driving means for controlling switching on and switching off of the first integrated magnetic field generating means (21) and the second magnetic field generating means.
</P>
<P>
5. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 2, wherein the second magnetic field generating means furthermore comprises at least one integrated magnetic field generating means (25).
</P>
<P>
6. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 5, the at least one sensor element (24) and the first integrated magnetic field generating means extending in a first direction, wherein the at least one integrated magnetic field generating means (25) of the second magnetic field generating means is oriented in a second direction substantially perpendicular to the first direction.
</P>
<P>
7. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 3 or 5, wherein the at least one integrated magnetic field generating means (25) of the second magnetic field generating means is a current wire.
</P>
<P>
8. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 2 or 5, wherein the external magnetic field generating means is a permanent magnet.
</P>
<P>
9. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 2 or 5, wherein the generated external magnetic field has a magnitude between 200 A/m and 20000 A/m.
</P>
<P>
10. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 3, wherein the at least one integrated magnetic field generating means (25) of the second magnetic field generating means is oriented in a direction substantially parallel to the first integrated magnetic field generating means (21) and to the at least one sensor element (24).
</P>
<P>
11. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 1 , wherein the second magnetic field generating means comprises a plurality of current wires (25a-25d).
</P>
<P>
12. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 3, wherein the at least one integrated magnetic field generating means (25) of the second magnetic field generating means is located in between the sensor surface (23) and the first integrated magnetic field generating means (21).
</P>
<P>
13. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 1, wherein the first magnetic field generating means (21) comprises at least one current wire.
</P>
<P>
14. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 2, the at least one sensor element (24) extending in a first direction, wherein the first magnetic field generating means (21) comprises an integrated magnetic field generating means oriented in a second direction substantially perpendicular to the first direction.
</P>
<P>
15. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 1 or 14, wherein the magnetic sensor device (20) furthermore comprises third magnetic field generating means (28) for generating a third magnetic field, the third magnetic field being for orienting dipolar magnetic fields generated by magnetic moments of magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) in a sensitive direction of the at least one sensor element (24).
</P>
<P>
16. A magnetic sensor device (20) according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sensor element (24) is one of a GMR sensor element, a TMR sensor element, an AMR sensor element, a Hall sensor.
</P>
<P>
17. A biochip comprising at least one magnetic sensor device (20) according to any of the previous claims.
</P>
<P>
18. The use of the magnetic sensor device (20) according to any of claims 1 to 16 in biological or chemical sample analysis.
</P>
<P>
19. The use of the biochip according to claim 17 in biological or chemical sample analysis.
</P>
<P>
20. Method for attracting and repelling magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) from a sensor surface (23) of a sensor device (20), the method comprising: - modulating a first magnetic field strength of a first magnetic field generated by a first magnetic field generating means (21), the first magnetic field being for attracting magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) to the sensor surface (23), at least some of the attracted magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) hereby being given a possibility to bind to the sensor surface (23), and modulating a second field strength of a second magnetic field generated by a second magnetic field generating means, the second magnetic field, in combination with the first magnetic field, being for repelling from the sensor surface (23) magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) having a bonding strength below a predetermined value, wherein the first and second magnetic field are generated such that the first magnetic field has a first direction and the second magnetic field has a second direction, the first and second direction being substantially anti-parallel to each other.
</P>
<P>
21. Method according to claim 20, wherein modulating the first and second magnetic field strength is performed by: switching on the first integrated magnetic field generating means (21) for generating a first magnetic field for attracting magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) to the sensor surface (23), and switching on the second magnetic field generating means for generating a second magnetic field for, in combination with the first magnetic field, repelling from the sensor surface (23) magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) having a bonding strength below a predetermined value.
</P>
<P>
22. Use of the method according to claim 20 in biological or chemical sample analysis.
</P>
<P>
23. Use of the method according to claim 20 for determining the binding strength of magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) to a sensor surface (23).
</P>
<P>
24. Use of the method according to claim 20 for distinguishing between specific and non-specific bonds of magnetic or magnetizable objects (22) to a sensor surface (23).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008010110A1;US2009251136A1;JP2009544033A;CN101490528A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
