<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CALIBRATION OF A MAGNETIC SENSOR DEVICE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2013645A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KAHLMAN JOSEPHUS ARNOLDUS HENR [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
PRINS MENNO WILLEM JOSE [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KAHLMAN, JOSEPHUS, ARNOLDUS, HENRICUS, MARIA
</Name>
<Name>
PRINS, MENNO, WILLEM, JOSE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KONINKL PHILIPS ELECTRONICS NV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2013645
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070735500
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-04-16
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007IB51351
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060113113
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-04-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070735500
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01R33/12
</Class>
<Class>
G01V13/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/09B
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12
</Class>
<Class>
G01R33/12M
</Class>
<Class>
G01V13/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to the calibration of the magnetic sensor device comprising magnetic excitation wires (11, 13) and a magnetic sensor element, for example a GMR sensor (12), for measuring reaction fields (B2) generated by magnetic particles (2) in reaction to an excitation field (B1) generated by the excitation wires. The magnetic sensor element (12) can be calibrated by saturating the magnetic particles (2) with a magnetic calibration field (B3). Thus the direct (crosstalk) action of the excitation field (B1) on the magnetic sensor element (12) can be determined without disturbing contributions of the magnetic particles (2).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. A magnetic sensor device (10) for detecting magnetic particles (2) in an investigation region, comprising: a) at least one magnetic excitation field generator (11, 13) for generating a magnetic excitation field (Bi) in the investigation region; b) at least one magnetic calibration field generator (15) for generating a magnetic calibration field (B3) in the investigation region which has at least temporarily a sufficient magnitude to change the magnetization characteristics of magnetic particles (2) in the investigation region; c) at least one magnetic sensor element (12) for measuring magnetic reaction fields (B2) generated by magnetic particles (2) in the investigation region in reaction to the magnetic excitation field (Bi) and/or the magnetic calibration field (B3); d) an evaluation unit (16) for calibrating the magnetic sensor element (12) based on measurements during which a magnetic excitation field (Bi) and/or a magnetic calibration field (B3) and magnetic particles (2) are present in the investigation region.
</P>
<P>
2. A method for detecting magnetic particles (2) in an investigation region, comprising: a) generating a magnetic excitation field (Bi) in the investigation region with at least one magnetic excitation field generator (11, 13); b) generating a magnetic calibration field (B3) in the investigation region with at least one magnetic calibration field generator (15), wherein said field has at least temporarily a sufficient magnitude to change the magnetization characteristics of magnetic particles (2) in the investigation region; c) measuring magnetic reaction fields (B2) with at least one magnetic sensor element (12), wherein said fields are generated by magnetic particles (2) in the investigation region in reaction to the magnetic excitation field (Bi) and/or the magnetic calibration field (B3); d) calibrating the magnetic sensor element (12) based on measurements during which a magnetic excitation field (Bi) and/or a magnetic calibration field (B3) and magnetic particles (2) are present in the investigation region.
</P>
<P>
3. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the amount of magnetic particles (2) in the investigation region is determined based on measurements generated while the magnetic calibration field (B3) vanishes.
</P>
<P>
4. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic calibration field (B3) repeatedly vanishes.
</P>
<P>
5. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic calibration field (B3) saturates the magnetic particles (2) at least temporarily.
</P>
<P>
6. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic excitation field (Bi) has an excitation frequency fi &amp;gt; 0.
</P>
<P>
7. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic calibration field (B3) has a calibration frequency f3 &amp;gt; 0.
</P>
<P>
8. The magnetic sensor device (10) or the method according to claims 7 and 8, characterized in that the excitation frequency f[iota] has at least approximately the same value as the calibration frequency f3.
</P>
<P>
9. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic sensor element (12) is driven with a sensing frequency f2 &amp;gt; 0.
</P>
<P>
10. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic calibration field (B3) in the magnetic sensor element (12) is adjusted to be essentially zero in the sensitive direction of said element.
</P>
<P>
11. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the component of the measurement signals is determined which is due to the magnetic calibration field (B3) in the magnetic sensor element (12).
</P>
<P>
12. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic excitation field generator and/or the magnetic calibration field generator comprises at least one conductor wire (11, 13).
</P>
<P>
13. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic excitation field generator and the magnetic calibration field generator are at least partially realized by the same hardware.
</P>
<P>
14. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the magnetic calibration field generator comprises at least one coil (15).
</P>
<P>
15. The magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 or the method according to claim 2, characterized in that the sensor unit comprises a Hall sensor or a magneto -resistive element like a GMR (12), a TMR, or an AMR element.
</P>
<P>
16. Use of the magnetic sensor device (10) according to claim 1 for molecular diagnostics, biological sample analysis, and/or chemical sample analysis, particularly the detection of small molecules.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2007122542A2;WO2007122542A3;US2009072815A1;JP2009535615A;CN101427157A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
