<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
GRADED GLASS/ZIRCONIA/GLASS STRUCTURES FOR DAMAGE RESISTANT CERAMIC DENTAL AND ORTHOPEDIC PROSTHESES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2083744A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ZHANG YU [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM JAE-WON [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG, YU
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, JAE-WON
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV NEW YORK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NEW YORK UNIVERSITY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2083744
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070861876
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US23599
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060858234P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61C13/00
</Class>
<Class>
B32B7/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/486
</Class>
<Class>
C04B41/00V
</Class>
<Class>
C04B41/50M4
</Class>
<Class>
C04B41/86
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass sandwich system for use in damage resistant, ceramic and orthopedic prosthesis. The functionally graded glass/substrate/glass composite structure comprises an outer residual glass layer, a graded glass- ceramic layer, and a dense interior ceramic. The functionally graded glass/substrate/glass composite structure may further comprise a veneer on an exterior surface. The present invention also provides a method for preparing a functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass sandwich system. A powdered glass-ceramic composition is applied to the accessible surfaces of a presintered zirconia substrate to thereby substantially cover the substrate surfaces. The glass of the composition has a CTE similar to that of the substrate material.;  The glass-ceramic composition is infiltrated into and densifies the substrate by heating the assembly to at least the sintering temperature of the substrate.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method for preparing a functionally graded glass/zirconia/glass (G/Z/G) sandwich material comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) applying a powdered glass-ceramic composition to accessible surfaces of a presintered zirconia substrate thereby covering the zirconia substrate surfaces with a layer of the composition wherein the CTE of the glass and the substrate material are substantially the same;
</P>
<P>
(b) infiltrating the glass-ceramic composition into the substrate; and
</P>
<P>
(c) densifying the substrate by heating said substrate.
</P>
<P>
2. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the substrate comprises yttria-tetragonal zirconia polycrystal (Y-TZP).
</P>
<P>
3. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the substrate is presintered at a temperature of 900[deg.]C to l400[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
4. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein said densifying is performed in a single firing cycle at a temperature of 1200[deg.]C to 155O&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
5. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the powdered glass-ceramic composition is dispersed in an aqueous based solution.
</P>
<P>
6. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the powdered glass-ceramic composition comprises one or more oxides selected from the group consisting of SiO2, Al2O3, K2O, Na2O, BaO, Tb4O7, and CaO.
</P>
<P>
7. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the CTE of the glass-ceramic is approximately 10.3 in/in/[deg.]C, from O to 430&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, and the CTE of the zirconia is approximately 10.3 in/iiV[deg.]C, from O to 430&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
8. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the presintered zirconia substrate is presintered by a microwave technique.
</P>
<P>
9. A method in accordance with claim 1, wherein the glass/zirconia/glass (G/Z/G) sandwich material is densified by a microwave technique.
</P>
<P>
10. A functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass composite structure comprising an outer residual glass layer, an underlying graded glass-ceramic layer, and a dense interior ceramic.
</P>
<P>
11. A functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass composite structure in accordance with claim 10, substantially non-susceptible to warppage or bending.
</P>
<P>
12. A functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass composite structure in accordance with claim 10, wherein the underlying ceramic comprises yttria-tetragonal zirconia polycrystal (Y-TZP).
</P>
<P>
13. A functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass in accordance with claim 10 wherein the CTE of the glass is substantially the same as the CTE of the yttria-tetragonal zirconia polycrystal (Y- TZP).
</P>
<P>
14. A functionally graded glass/ceramic/glass in accordance with claim 10 further comprising a veneer on an outer surface.
</P>
<P>
15. A medical or dental prosthesis comprising a functionally graded glass- ceramic/ceramic/glass-ceramic composite structure or a graded glass-ceramic/ceramic structure.
</P>
<P>
16. A medical or dental prosthesis according to claim 15 selected from the group consisting of an aesthetic and damage-resistant ceramic orthopedic prosthesis, an orthopedic stem, an orthopedic or dental anchor, an orthopedic or dental implant, a dental prosthesis, and an endodontic post.
</P>
<P>
17. A medical or dental prosthesis according to claim 15 wherein the ceramic comprises zirconia.
</P>
<P>
18. A functionally graded glass/zirconia/glass (G/Z/G) sandwich material produced by the method of claim 1.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008060451A2;WO2008060451A3;US2008241551A1;US7871706B2;US2011070452A1;JP2010509336A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
