<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Carbonaceous material with broad aggregate size distribution and improved dispersibility
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2088174A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WANG WEIDONG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HERD CHARLES R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AYALA JORGE A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WANG, WEIDONG
</Name>
<Name>
HERD, CHARLES R
</Name>
<Name>
AYALA, JORGE A
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
COLUMBIAN CHEM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
COLUMBIAN CHEMICALS COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2088174
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090155855
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2005-05-13
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20050748323
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-05-13
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20040845368
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-05-13
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/48
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/48
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A carbon black with a D50/M greater than about 0.9. The carbon black may have an aggregate heterogeneity index (HI) via QTM of greater than about 2.3. The carbon black may have a D50 via DCP of greater than about 0.07. The QTM-HI of the present carbon black is unique for N100-200 series carbon blacks, as is the D50. The carbon black may be a N200 carbon black with an oil absorption number (OAN) less than about 135 and HI of greater than about 2.3. The carbon black may also be a N200 carbon black with an oil absorption number (OAN) less than about 135 and a D50 of greater than about 0.07. The present invention also relates to a polymeric composition and to tires comprising a carbon black of the present invention.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A carbonaceous material with a [Delta]D50/M greater than about 0.9 and a [Delta]D50 via DCP greater than about 0.07.
</P>
<P>
2. The carbonaceous material of claim 1, wherein the carbonaceous material is carbon black.
</P>
<P>
3. A carbon black with a [Delta]D50/M greater than about 0.9 and a [Delta]D50 via DCP greater than about 0.07.
</P>
<P>
4. The carbon black of claim 3, wherein the fineness is within the range of ASTM N200 grade carbon blacks.
</P>
<P>
5. The carbon black of claim 3 or 4, wherein the HI via QTM is greater than about 2.3.
</P>
<P>
6. The carbon black of any one of claims 3 to 5, wherein when said carbon black is incorporated into an elastomeric composition, the dispersibility of the elastomeric composition is improved compared to the same elastomeric composition having conventional N200 series carbon black.
</P>
<P>
7. The carbon black of any one of claims 3 to 5, wherein when said carbon black is incorporated into an elastomeric composition and the composition subsequently cured, the hot tear of the cured elastomeric composition is improved compared to the same cured elastomeric composition having conventional N200 series carbon black.
</P>
<P>
8. The carbon black of any one of claims 3 to 5, wherein when said carbon black is incorporated into an elastomeric composition, and the composition subsequently cured the abrasion of the cured elastomeric composition is improved compared to the same cured elastomeric composition having conventional N200 series carbon black.
</P>
<P>
10. An ASTM N200 grade carbon black with a [Delta]D50 via DCP of greater than about 0.07.
</P>
<P>
11. The carbon black of claim 10, with an OAN of less than about 135.
</P>
<P>
12. A polymeric composition comprising a polymer and a carbon black with a [Delta]D50/M greater than about 0.9 and a [Delta]D50 via DCP greater than about 0.07.
</P>
<P>
13. The polymeric composition of claim 12, wherein the polymer comprises rubber.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2088174A3;WO2005113688A2;WO2005113688A3;US2005256249A1;US7238741B2;US2009247686A1;MY144288A;EP1753828A2;EP1753828B1;CN102161842A;CN101426862A;CN101426862B;CA2566650A1;BRPI0509785A;AT553161T;AR048842A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
