<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
TRANSPARENT AND ELECTRICALLY CONDUCTIVE SINGLE WALL CARBON NANOTUBE FILMS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2082404A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHEN ZHIHONG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RINZLER ANDREW G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHEN, ZHIHONG
</Name>
<Name>
RINZLER, ANDREW, G
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV FLORIDA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA RESEARCH FOUNDATION, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2082404
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070874463
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-10-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US81770
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060583545
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-10-19
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/30
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D6
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/04
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An optically transparent and electrically conductive single walled carbon nanotube (SWNT) film comprises a plurality of interpenetrated single walled carbon nanotubes, wherein for a 100 nm film the film has sufficient interpenetration to provide a 25 DEG  C. sheet resistance of less than 200 ohm/sq. The film also provides at least 20% optical transmission throughout a wavelength range from 0.4 mum to 5 mum.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
We claim:
</P>
<P>
1. An optically transparent and electrically conductive single walled carbon nanotube (SWNT) film, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of interpenetrated single walled carbon nanotubes (SWNTs), wherein for a 100 nm film said film has sufficient interpenetration to provide a 25[deg.] C. sheet resistance of less than 200 ohm/sq and at least 20% optical transmission throughout a wavelength range from 0.4 [mu]m to 5 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
2. The SWNT film of claim 1, wherein a morphology of said film comprises stacked planes, said SWNTs having random orientation in said planes.
</P>
<P>
3. The SWNT film of claim 1, wherein said optical transmission is at least 30%.
</P>
<P>
4. The SWNT film of claim 1, wherein SWNTs include at least one dopant, wherein for said 100 nm thick film said sheet resistance is &amp;lt;50 ohm/square.
</P>
<P>
5. The SWNT film of claim 4, wherein said dopant is selected from the group consisting of halogens and graphite intercalants.
</P>
<P>
6. The SWNT film of claim 1, wherein said film consists essentially of said SWNTs.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007141345A1;US7776444B2;WO2008118201A2;WO2008118201A3;US2010272981A1;US7972699B2;SG175653A1;KR20090074803A;JP2010506824A;CN101578666A;CN101578666B;CA2667048A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
