<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
LOW TEMPERATURE PROCESS FOR PRODUCING NANO- SIZED TITANIUM DIOXIDE PARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2074064A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KIM INSOO [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
LEE WOO JIN [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM YOUNG JIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SMITH CHARLES E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, INSOO
</Name>
<Name>
LEE, WOO, JIN
</Name>
<Name>
KIM, YOUNG, JIN
</Name>
<Name>
SMITH, CHARLES, E
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOKUSEN U S A INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TOKUSEN U.S.A., INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2074064
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070837981
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-09-11
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US19674
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060846231P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053B
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process for synthesizing nano-sized rutile, anatase, or a mixture of rutile and anatase TiO2 powder. The process includes the steps of: 1 ) forming a Ti-peroxo complex by mixing H2O2 with a Ti compound, and 2) heating the Ti-peroxo complex at a temperature of above 50 DEG C. A primary particle size of TiO2 particles, synthesized by the method, is below 50nm, and an agglomerated particle size thereof after a washing/dry process is below about 10 [mu]m. The major characteristics of the present invention are that it is a low temperature process, a highly concentrated synthesis, and high production yield of above 90%.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A process for producing nano-sized TiO2, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) forming a Ti-peroxo complex by mixing H2O2 and a titanium compound; and
</P>
<P>
(b) heating the Ti-peroxo complex at a temperature of above 50&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 , wherein said titanium compound is selected from the group consisting of TiCI4, TiOCI2, TiCb, TiBr4, Ti(SO4)2 mH2O, TiOSO4 nH2O, Tetra Methoxy Titanium, Tetra Ethoxy
</P>
<P>
Titanium, Tetra-n-Propoxy Titanium, Tetra lso Propoxy Titanium, Tetra-n- Butoxy Titanium, Tetra lso Butoxy Titanium, Tetra-Sec-Butoxy Titanium, Tetra-T-Butoxy Titanium, Tetra Alkoxy Titanium, and Tetra Stearly Oxy Titanium and a combination of the proceeding.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 , wherein in step (a), said H2O2 and said titanium compound are mixed with a chemical selected from the group consisting of an alkali, a compound containing SO4&amp;lt;2&apos;&amp;gt;, NO3&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt; and F and a combination of the proceeding to accelerate the formation of anatase TiO2.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 3, wherein said alkali is selected from the group consisting of NH4OH, NaOH, KOH, LiOH, Ca(OH)2, Mg(OH)2, Ba(OH)2, Na(CO)3, K(CO)3, Hydroxyl amine, Hydrazine and Ethanol amine.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 3, wherein said compound containing
</P>
<P>
SO4&amp;lt;2&quot;&amp;gt;, NO3&amp;lt;&quot;&amp;gt; and F ions is selected from the group consisting of H2SO4, HNO3 and NaF.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claims 1 or 3, wherein in step (a), said H2O2 and said titanium compound are mixed with a salt of a metal to form metal-coated or doped TiO2 particles.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 1 or 3, further comprising the step of adding a salt of a metal to the nano-sized Ti[theta]2 solution formed by steps (a) and (b) to form metal-coated or doped TiO2 particles.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 6, wherein said metal is selected from the group consisting of V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Ge1 Mo, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ag, Sn, W, R, Au, Sr, Al and Si.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 7, wherein said metal is selected from the group consisting of V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Ge, Mo, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ag,
</P>
<P>
Sn, W, R, Au, Sr, Al and Si.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 1 , where said temperature is 80&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to 100&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008036176A1;US2010226851A1;KR20090064576A;JP2010504272A;CN101595059A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
