<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PHOTONIC CRYSTAL SENSORS WITH INTEGRATED FLUID CONTAINMENT STRUCTURE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2091646A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CUNNINGHAM BRIAN T [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI CHARLES [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CUNNINGHAM, BRIAN T
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI, CHARLES
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV ILLINOIS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SRU BIOSYSTEMS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS
</Name>
<Name>
SRU BIOSYSTEMS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2091646
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070861768
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-06
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US23408
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-06
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060865093P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01L3/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/25
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01L3/5085
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/25B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Photonic crystal (PC) sensors, and sensor arrays and sensing systems incorporating PC sensors are described which have integrated fluid containment and/or fluid handling structures. Sensors and sensing systems of the present disclosure are capable of high throughput sensing of analytes in fluid samples, bulk refractive index detection, and label-free detection of a range of molecules, including biomolecules and therapeutic candidates. The present disclosure also provides a commercially attractive fabrication platform for making photonic crystal sensors and systems wherein an integrated fluid containment structure and a photonic crystal structure are fabricated in a single molding or imprinting processing step amendable to high throughput processing.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
We claim:
</P>
<P>
1. A photonic crystal biosensor with an integrated fluid containment structure, the biosensor adapted for measurement of a sample, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a fluid containment structure having a cavity for receiving said sample, said cavity having at least one internal surface; and
</P>
<P>
a photonic crystal sensor comprising a periodic surface grating structure formed in the internal surface of said fluid containment structure;
</P>
<P>
wherein said fluid containment structure and periodic surface grating structure of said photonic crystal sensor comprise a integral, monolithic structure.
</P>
<P>
2. The sensor of claim 1, wherein said integral, monolithic structure comprises an integral polymer structure comprising an optically clear substrate layer, a cured polymer layer, and a relatively high index of refraction material deposited on the cured polymer layer.
</P>
<P>
3. The sensor of claim 1, wherein said cavity comprises a sample well, and wherein the integral monolithic structure further comprises a port for receiving the sample, a channel having a surface, the channel providing a fluid path for connecting the port to the fluid containment structure, and a second photonic crystal sensor comprising a periodic surface grating structure formed in a surface of the channel.
</P>
<P>
4. The sensor of claim 1 wherein said periodic surface grating structure comprises a nanosized structure, and wherein said cavity of said fluid containment structure comprises a micron-sized feature.
</P>
<P>
5. The sensor of claim 4 wherein said periodic surface grating structure is formed on a bottom surface of said cavity and wherein said periodic surface grating structure extends from a first side of said cavity to a second side of said cavity.
</P>
<P>
6. The sensor of claim 1, wherein the fluid containment structure comprises a microfiuidic flow channel, with the sample flowing through the flow channel over the photonic crystal structure.
</P>
<P>
7. The sensor of claim 1, wherein the fluid containment structure comprises a micro well.
</P>
<P>
8. The sensor of claim 1 further comprising a cover layer enclosing said fluid containment structure.
</P>
<P>
9. The sensor of claim 9, wherein said cover layer has an inlet hole and an outlet hole for conducting the sample into and out of the fluid containment structure.
</P>
<P>
10. The sensor of claim 1 wherein the integral, monolithic structure further comprises a polymer substrate supporting said fluid containment structure and said photonic crystal structure.
</P>
<P>
11. The sensor of claim 1 further comprising a target material bound to the periodic grating structure of the photonic crystal structure.
</P>
<P>
12. The sensor of claim 11 , wherein said target material is selected from the group of target materials consisting of proteins, peptides, DNA molecules, RNA molecules, oligonucleotides, lipids, carbohydrates, polysaccharides; glycoproteins, lipoproteins, sugars, cells, bacteria, virus, and candidate molecules.
</P>
<P>
13. A biosensor comprising: an integral, monolithic substrate having a port, a plurality of sample wells connected to the port, and a plurality of flow channels connecting the port to the sample wells, and
</P>
<P>
a plurality of photonic crystal sensors integrally formed in the structure, each of the sensors positioned in a flow channel connecting the port to the sample wells.
</P>
<P>
14. The biosensor of claim 13, wherein each of the flow channels have substantially the same path length between the inlet port and the sample wells.
</P>
<P>
15. The biosensor of claim 13 , wherein the plurality of photonic crystal sensors are spatially arranged in an aligned condition.
</P>
<P>
16. The biosensor of claim 13, wherein the biosensor comprises an array of N x M sample wells, where N represents an integer number of rows of sample wells and M represents an integer number of columns of wells, wherein the biosensor includes an inlet port for each of the M columns of wells, and wherein each of the inlet ports are connected to each of the N wells in each column of wells by a flow channel, each flow channel in the biosensor incorporating a photonic crystal sensor.
</P>
<P>
17. The biosensor of claim 16, wherein each of the columns of wells are in a substantially aligned condition and wherein the flow channels are constructed such that the photonic crystal sensors in the flow channels for each column of wells are also in a substantially aligned condition.
</P>
<P>
18. The biosensor of claim 13, wherein each of the sample wells includes a photonic crystal sensor positioned within each of the sample wells.
</P>
<P>
19. A method of making a photonic crystal sensor having an integrated fluid containment structure, said method comprising the steps of: providing a master template having an external surface with a pattern comprising a photonic crystal periodic surface grating structure and structure for forming a fluid containment structure, the periodic surface grating structure located within the structure forming the fluid containment structure;
</P>
<P>
transferring the pattern of said master template to a material such that the material forms a fluid containment structure having a cavity with the photonic crystal periodic surface grating structure positioned within the cavity; and
</P>
<P>
depositing a thin dielectric film on the photonic crystal periodic surface grating structure to thereby forming a photonic crystal sensor.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19, wherein the cavity comprises a sample well.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 19, wherein the cavity comprises a fluid flow channel.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 19 wherein said step of transferring is carried out via replica molding.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 21 wherein said step of transferring is carried out via imprint lithography.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 21 wherein said material comprises a curable fluid material, and wherein said step of transferring comprises the steps of: contacting said external surface of said master template with the curable fluid material, wherein said curable fluid material conforms to the shape of the external surface of the master template; curing said curable fluid material while in contact with the external surface of the master template; and separating the cured fluid material from the master template.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 18, wherein the external surface of the master template is configured to form a plurality of sample wells, at least one port, and fluid channels connecting the port to the sample wells, and wherein the external surface is patterned to form a photonic crystal periodic surface grating in at least one of 1) each of the fluid channels, and 2) each of the sample wells.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008060415A1;US2008219615A1;US7742662B2;US2008265137A1;US7531786B2;NZ576760A;JP2010509590A;CA2668943A1;AU2007319975A1;AU2007319975B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
