<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR SYNTHESIZING NANOTUBES, ESPECIALLY CARBON NANOTUBES, AND THEIR USES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2086878A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
PLEE DOMINIQUE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
DUBOIS JEAN-LUC [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
PIGAMO ANNE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
PLEE, DOMINIQUE
</Name>
<Name>
DUBOIS, JEAN-LUC
</Name>
<Name>
PIGAMO, ANNE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ARKEMA FRANCE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
ARKEMA FRANCE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2086878
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070847425
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP62900
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
FR20060055226
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070878827P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The subject of the present invention is a process for synthesizing nanotubes, especially carbon nanotubes, by decomposition of a gas source, at a temperature ranging from 400 to 1200  DEG C in a reactor, by bringing it into contact with at least one (one or more) multivalent transition metals, the transition metal(s) being supported on a support having a specific surface area determined by the BET method of greater than 50 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g, especially within the range from 70 m2/g to 400 m2/g. The support according to the invention is especially an inorganic support, for example an alumina having a multimodal porosity. The subject of the invention is also the nanotubes thus obtained and their use for improving the mechanical and/or electrical and/or thermal properties of materials, especially polymeric materials.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Process for synthesizing nanotubes, especially carbon nanotubes, by decomposition of a gas source, at a temperature of between 400 and 1200 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, by bringing it into contact with at least one or more multivalent transition metals, characterized in that the transition metal or metals are supported on a support having a BET specific surface area of greater than 50 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
2. Nanotube synthesis process according to Claim 1 , characterized in that the transition metal or metals are supported on a support having a BET specific surface area lying within the range from 70 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g to 400 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
3. Nanotube synthesis process according to Claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the transition metal or metals are supported on an inorganic support.
</P>
<P>
4. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the support consists of at least one alumina whose intraparticle porosity is multimodal.
</P>
<P>
5. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the support is an alumina, the total mercury pore volume of which is greater than 0.9 cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;/g, said alumina having at least one porosity peak in the range from 50 to 3000 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the amount of transition metal(s) represents up to 50% by weight of the final catalyst.
</P>
<P>
7. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the amount of transition metal(s) lies within the range from 10 to 50% by weight of the final catalyst.
</P>
<P>
8. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the support particles have a mean diameter lying within the range from 20 to 500 [mu]m. 9. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the catalyst is prepared by impregnating the support particles with an impregnation solution containing at least one transition metal salt.
</P>
<P>
10. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that said catalyst is prepared by impregnating the support particles at a temperature lying within the range from room temperature to the boiling point of the solution, the support particles being at all times in contact with a sufficient amount of impregnation solution to ensure formation of a film of the impregnation solution on the surface of the support particles.
</P>
<P>
11. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the catalyst is prepared by impregnating the support particles with an iron impregnation solution. 12. Process according to one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the catalyst is calcined in a furnace before the nanotubes are synthesized. 13. Process according to one of the preceding claims, in which the catalyst is reduced in situ and does not see air again before the synthesis of the nanotubes. 14. Process according to any one of the preceding claims, characterized in that the gas source is a carbon source.
</P>
<P>
15. Nanotubes that can be obtained by the process as defined in any one of the preceding claims.
</P>
<P>
16. Use of the nanotubes, especially carbon nanotubes, obtained according to any one of Claims 1 to 14 as agents for improving the mechanical and/or electrical and/or thermal conductivity properties, especially in compositions based on polymers and/or resins.
</P>
<P>
17. Use according to the preceding claim of the compositions based on polymers in fuel lines, antistatic coatings or in electrodes for the energy sector.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008065121A1;KR20090087454A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
