<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Method of making high- purity (&amp;gt;99%) MoO2 powders, products made from MoO2 powders, deposition of MoO2 thin films, and methods of using such materials
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2072469A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MCHUGH LAWRENCE F [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KUMAR PRABHAT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MEENDERING DAVID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WU RICHARD [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WOETTING GERHARD [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MCHUGH, LAWRENCE, F
</Name>
<Name>
KUMAR, PRABHAT
</Name>
<Name>
MEENDERING, DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
WU, RICHARD
</Name>
<Name>
WOETTING, GERHARD
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
STARCK H C INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
H.C. STARCK INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2072469
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090151622
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-06-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040816761
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-06-29
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20030489217P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-07-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20040540911P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-01-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G39/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/52
</Class>
<Class>
H05B33/14
</Class>
<Class>
H01L33/42
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G39/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/52B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to high purity MoO 2 powder by reduction of ammonium molybdate or molybdenum trioxide using hydrogen as the reducing agent in a rotary or boat furnace. Consolidation of the powder by press/sintering, hot pressing, and/or HIP is used to make discs, slabs, or plates, which are used as sputtering targets. The MoO 2 disc, slab, or plate form is sputtered on a substrate using a suitable sputtering method or other physical means to provide a thin film having a desired film thickness. The thin films have properties such as electrical, optical, surface roughness, and uniformity comparable or superior to those of indium-tin oxide (ITO) and zinc-doped ITO in terms of transparency, conductivity, work function, uniformity, and surface roughness. The MoO 2 and MoO 2 containing thin films can be used in organic light-emitting diodes (OLED), liquid crystal display (LCD), plasma display panel (PDP), field emission display (FED), thin film solar cell, low resistivity ohmic contacts, and other electronic and semiconductor devices.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for making a plate comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) isopressing a greater than 99% stoichiometric MoO2 powder component to a billet;
</P>
<P>
(b) vacuum sintering the billet under conditions to maintain the greater than 99% MoO2 stochiometry; and
</P>
<P>
(c) forming a plate comprising greater than 99% stochiometric MoO2.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein the billet is vacuum sintered for 6 hours at a temperature of at least 1250 C.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein the MoO2 powder is isopressed at a pressure ranging from 10,000 psi to 40,000 psi.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, wherein the plate is subjected to hot isostatic pressing.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1, wherein the plate has a density that is from 90% to 100% of the theoretical density of MoO2.
</P>
<P>
6. A plate made in accordance to the method of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
7. A method for making a plate comprising subjecting a greater than 99% stoichiometric MoO2, powder component to hot pressing conditions, and thereby forming a plate that includes greater than 99% stoichiometric MoO2.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of Claim 7, wherein the hot pressing is carried out with transient liquid phase assisted hot pressing.
</P>
<P>
9. A method for making a thin film comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
(a) sputtering a plate comprising greater than 99% stoichiometric MoO2 of claim 6; (b) removing MoO2 molecules from the plate; and
</P>
<P>
(c) depositing the MoO2 molecules onto a substrate and thereby forming a thin film.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9, wherein the thin film has a thickness ranging from 0.5 nm to 10 [micro]m.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2005040044A2;WO2005040044A3;RU2006105325A;JP2007500661A;EP1648828A2;CA2533110A1;BRPI0412811A;AU2004284043A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
