<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Apparatus for producing nanoparticles
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2042233A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
JI JUN HO [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
NOH HYUNG SOO [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
JI, JUN HO
</Name>
<Name>
NOH, HYUNG SOO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO LTD [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2042233
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090150383
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2005-10-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20050109589
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-10-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20040114032
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-12-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
KR20040115263
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-12-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J6/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J6/00
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanoparticle generator includes a heating unit directly heating material for generating nanoparticles. Due to the structure of the heating unit directly heating the material, a space between the heating unit and the material is eliminated such that a volume of the nanoparticle generator is remarkably reduced and the nanoparticle generator is easily minimized. The nanoparticle generator comprises a cyclone chamber.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A nanoparticle generator comprising:
</P>
<P>
a main body;
</P>
<P>
a heating unit which heats a material accommodated in the main body to vaporize the material into a gas;
</P>
<P>
a passage, passing through the main body, through which nanoparticles generated by condensing the gas vaporized from the material by a fluid are discharged out of the main body;wherein the heating unit has an open-sided material accommodating room for accommodating the material, a side of the heating unit adjacent to the material accommodating room is positioned in the passage, and the passage is parallel to a moving direction of the gas vaporized from the material.
</P>
<P>
2. The nanoparticle generator according to claim 1, wherein the main body forms a cyclone chamber.
</P>
<P>
3. The nanoparticle generator according to claim 2, wherein the cyclone chamber comprises:
</P>
<P>
an upper cylinder;
</P>
<P>
a lower cone; and
</P>
<P>
an inlet formed in a lateral side of the upper cylinder in the tangential direction; and
</P>
<P>
an outlet formed in an upper side of the upper cylinder.
</P>
<P>
4. The nanoparticle generator according to claim 3, further comprising a guide tube which is disposed in the outlet and extended a predetermined distance to an inside of the cyclone chamber adjacent to the heating unit to such that the nanoparticles discharged out of the cyclone chamber are guided by the guide tube.
</P>
<P>
5. The nanoparticle generator according to claim 4, wherein the material accommodating room faces the guide tube.
</P>
<P>
6. The nanoparticle generator according to one of the previous claims, wherein the side of the heating unit disposed in the passage is spaced apart from a sidewall of the passage.
</P>
<P>
7. The nanoparticle generator according to one of the previous claims, wherein the material accommodating room has an opened top and the passage is disposed in a vertical direction of the main body.
</P>
<P>
8. The nanoparticle generator according to one of the previous claims, wherein the heating unit comprises: an insulator which has the material accommodating room; and a heater which is disposed in the insulator to form at least one side of the material accommodating room.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2042233A3;EP1676631A1;US2009175604A1;US2006140596A1;US7750270B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
