<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
TITANIUM OXIDE COMPLEX PARTICLE, DISPERSION SOLUTION OF THE PARTICLE, AND PROCESS FOR PRODUCTION OF THE PARTICLE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2000150A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KANEHIRA KOKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SONEZAKI SHUJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OGAMI YUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAMURA TOMOMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KANEHIRA, KOKI
</Name>
<Name>
SONEZAKI, SHUJI
</Name>
<Name>
OGAMI, YUMI
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAMURA, TOMOMI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOTO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TOTO LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2000150
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070739321
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-03-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP55878
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060083512
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-03-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060254912
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-09-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K33/24
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/32
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/34
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/36
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/08
</Class>
<Class>
A61P35/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61P43/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K33/24
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00H4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00H6
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00M4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00W
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48H4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48H4C
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48H4L
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48K4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48K6
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48K6P
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48R2T
</Class>
<Class>
A61K51/12H
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00L8
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/16K
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed are titanium oxide composite particles and a dispersion of the titanium oxide composite particles, which can improve retentivity in blood and accumulation in cancer cells while satisfactorily developing the catalytic activity of titanium oxide particles to be excited upon exposure to ultrasonic waves or ultraviolet light. The titanium oxide composite particles comprise titanium oxide particles;  and a nonionic hydrophilic polymer bound to the surface of the titanium oxide particles through at least one functional group selected from carboxyl group, amino group, diol group, salicylic acid group, and phosphoric acid group. The composite particles can be rendered cytotoxic upon ultrasonic or ultraviolet irradiation to efficiently kill cells to be killed, such as cancer cells.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Titanium oxide composite particles comprising:
</P>
<P>
titanium oxide particles; and
</P>
<P>
a nonionic hydrophilic polymer bound to a surface of the titanium oxide particles through at least one functional group selected from carboxyl group, amino group, diol group, salicylic acid group, and phosphoric acid group.
</P>
<P>
2. The titanium oxide composite particles according to claim 1, wherein the hydrophilic polymer is at least one member selected from the group consisting of polyethylene glycol, polyvinyl alcohol, polyethylene oxide, and dextran.
</P>
<P>
3. The titanium oxide composite particles according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the functional group is provided by a carboxylic acid or an amine, and at least an end of the hydrophilic polymer is modified with the carboxylic acid or the amine.
</P>
<P>
4. The titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the functional group is provided by the carboxylic acid or the amine, and the carboxylic acid or the amine gets together with the hydrophilic polymer to form a copolymer.
</P>
<P>
5. The titanium oxide composite particles according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the functional group is provided by a polycarboxylic acid as a linker.
</P>
<P>
6. The titanium oxide composite particles according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the functional group is provided by a polyamine as a linker.
</P>
<P>
7. The titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 6, which further comprise a ligand molecule containing the functional group and wherein the hydrophilic polymer is bound to the surface of the titanium oxide particles through the ligand molecule.
</P>
<P>
8. The titanium oxide composite particles according to claim 7, wherein the ligand molecule is at least one member selected from the group consisting of protocatechuic acid, gallic acid, methyldopa, 4-aminosalicylic acid, and quinic acid.
</P>
<P>
9. The titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 8, which have a zeta potential of -20 to +20 mV.
</P>
<P>
10. The titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 9, which have a diameter of 20 to 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
11. The titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 10, which are rendered cytotoxic upon ultrasonic irradiation.
</P>
<P>
12. A dispersion liquid comprising the titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 11 and a solvent for dispersing the particles.
</P>
<P>
13. The dispersion liquid according to claim 12, wherein the solvent is an aqueous solvent.
</P>
<P>
14. A process for producing the titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 11, the process comprising:
</P>
<P>
dispersing titanium oxide particles and a nonionic hydrophilic polymer modified with at least one functional group selected from carboxyl group, amino group, diol group, salicylic acid group, and phosphoric acid group, in an aprotic solvent, to obtain a dispersion liquid; and
</P>
<P>
heating the dispersion liquid at 80 to 220 deg. C to obtain the titanium oxide composite particles.
</P>
<P>
15. A process for producing titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 11, the process comprising:
</P>
<P>
dispersing titanium oxide particles, a ligand molecule containing at least one functional group selected from diol group, salicylic acid group and phosphoric acid group, and a nonionic hydrophilic polymer, in an aprotic solvent, to obtain a dispersion liquid; and
</P>
<P>
heating the dispersion liquid at 80 to 220 deg. C to obtain the titanium oxide composite particles.
</P>
<P>
16. A process for producing titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 11, the process comprising:
</P>
<P>
dispersing titanium oxide particles and a polycarboxylic acid in an aprotic solvent to obtain a dispersion liquid;
</P>
<P>
heating the dispersion liquid at 80 to 220 deg. C to obtain a dispersion liquid of the titanium oxide particles to which the polycarboxylic acid is bound; and
</P>
<P>
adding a nonionic hydrophilic polymer modified with the functional group to the dispersion liquid thus heated to allow a reaction to proceed in an aqueous solution at pH 8 to 10 to obtain the titanium oxide composite particles.
</P>
<P>
17. A process for producing titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 11, the process comprising:
</P>
<P>
dispersing titanium oxide particles and a polyamine in an aprotic solvent to obtain a dispersion liquid;
</P>
<P>
heating the dispersion liquid at 80 to 220 deg. C to obtain a dispersion liquid of titanium oxide particles to which the polyamine is bound; and
</P>
<P>
adding a nonionic hydrophilic polymer modified with the functional group to the dispersion liquid thus heated to allow a reaction to proceed in an aqueous solution at pH 8 to 10 to obtain the titanium oxide composite particles.
</P>
<P>
18. A process for producing titanium oxide composite particles according to any one of claims 1 to 11, the process comprising:
</P>
<P>
dispersing titanium oxide particles and a ligand molecule containing at least one functional group selected from diol group, salicylic acid group, and phosphoric acid group in an aprotic solvent to obtain a dispersion liquid;
</P>
<P>
heating the dispersion liquid at 80 to 220 deg. C to obtain a dispersion liquid of titanium oxide particles to which the ligand molecule is bound; and
</P>
<P>
adding a nonionic hydrophilic polymer to the dispersion liquid thus heated to obtain the titanium oxide composite particles.
</P>
<P>
19. The process according to any one of claims 14 to 18, wherein the aprotic solvent is at least one member selected from the group consisting of dimethylformamide, dioxane, and dimethylsulfoxide.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2000150A9;US2009130050A1;WO2007122956A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
