<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Carbon black dispersion liquid and water base ink
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2065445A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MOMOSE MASAYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KANAYA MIHARU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ITOH SOHKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAGYU TATSUYA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MOMOSE, MASAYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
KANAYA, MIHARU
</Name>
<Name>
ITOH, SOHKO
</Name>
<Name>
YAGYU, TATSUYA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SEIKO EPSON CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ORIENT CHEMICAL IND [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SEIKO EPSON CORPORATION
</Name>
<Name>
ORIENT CHEMICAL INDUSTRIES, LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2065445
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090003702
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-12-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030786381
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-12-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20020381301
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-12-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20030091214
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-03-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20030100252
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-04-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09C1/56
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/16
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/18
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/56B
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/17
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/18
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/324
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to a carbon black dispersion having a modified carbon black dispersed in water. The invention further relates to a water-based ink containing the modified carbon black. The modified carbon black is obtained by carrying out oxidation treatment on a carbon black having a primary particle diameter of 11 to 18 nm, a BET specific surface area of at least 180 m 2 /g, a DBP oil absorption of at least 180 mL/100g, and a value of the BET specific surface area (m 2 /g) divided by the DBP oil absorption (mL/100g) of 0.75 to 1.3, the modified carbon black characterized in that at least lactone groups and carboxyl groups are introduced onto the surface thereof, and the ratio of the mean particle diameter to the primary particle diameter is at least 8.5.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A carbon black dispersion, characterized by having a modified carbon black dispersed in water, the modified carbon black being obtained by carrying out oxidation treatment on a carbon black having a primary particle diameter of 11 to 18 nm, a BET specific surface area of at least 180 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g, a DBP oil absorption of at least 180 mL/100g. and a value of the BET specific surface area (m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g) divided by the DBP oil absorption (mL/100g) of 0.75 to 1.3, the modified carbon black characterized in that at least lactone groups and carboxyl groups are introduced onto the surface thereof, and the ratio of the mean particle diameter to the primary particle diameter is at least 8.5.
</P>
<P>
2. A water-based ink, characterized by containing a modified carbon black obtained by carrying out oxidation treatment on a carbon black having a primary particle diameter of 11 to 18 nm, a BET specific surface area of at least 180 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g, a DBP oil absorption of at least 180 mL/100g, and a value of the BET specific surface area (m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g) divided by the DBP oil absorption (mL/100g) of 0.75 to 1.3, the modified carbon black characterized in that at least lactone groups and carboxyl groups are introduced onto the surface thereof, and the ratio of the mean particle diameter to the primary particle diameter is at least 8.5.
</P>
<P>
3. The water-based ink of claim 2, characterized by having a penetrability such that the penetration time upon applying the ink onto a recording medium in an amount of 1 mg/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is less than 1 second.
</P>
<P>
4. The water-based ink of claim 2 or 3, characterized by having a surface tension at 20[deg.]C of not more than 45 mN/m.
</P>
<P>
5. The water-based ink of any of claims 2 to 4, characterized by containing a glycol butyl ether type aqueous organic solvent.
</P>
<P>
6. The water-based ink of any of claims 2 to 5, characterized by containing a nonionic surfactant.
</P>
<P>
7. The water-based ink of claim 6, characterized in that the nonionic surfactant is an acetylene glycol type surfactant.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2065445A3;EP2065445B1;EP1479732A1;EP1479732A4;EP1479732B1;US2005120914A1;US7232480B2;JP4769081B2;WO2004061015A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
