<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FORM, MICROPROCESSED ARTICLE, AND THEIR MANUFACTURING METHODS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2163367A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KUSUURA TAKAHISA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITRA ANUPAM [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TAKAYA YOSHIAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SATSUKA TAKURO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KUSUURA, TAKAHISA
</Name>
<Name>
MITRA, ANUPAM
</Name>
<Name>
TAKAYA, YOSHIAKI
</Name>
<Name>
SATSUKA, TAKURO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SCIVAX CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MARUZEN PETROCHEM CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SCIVAX CORPORATION
</Name>
<Name>
MARUZEN PETROCHEMICAL CO. LTD
</Name>
<Name>
MARUZEN PETROCHEMICAL CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2163367
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080763996
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP01399
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070148213
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070312424
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C33/40
</Class>
<Class>
B29C59/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/027
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B29C33/42C
</Class>
<Class>
B29C33/56
</Class>
<Class>
B29C59/02C
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A mold 100 for imprinting has a mold pattern 2A for transferring a pattern to a processing object. A base layer 1 having a predetermined base pattern 1A is formed by imprinting on a thermoplastic resin, a thermosetting resin, a photo-curable resin, or the like, and a mold layer 2 is formed in such a way that the mode pattern 2A is shapened along a surface of the base pattern 1A by a surface preparation technique, such as CVD, PVD, or plating. Accordingly, there is provided a mold which has the same functions as those of conventionally-used silicon mold and metal mold and which facilitates manufacturing thereof.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A mold for nanoimprinting, the mold including a mold pattern to be transferred to a processing object, the mold comprising:
</P>
<P>
a base layer formed of a resin and including a predetermined base pattern; and
</P>
<P>
a mold layer formed along the base pattern so as to shape the mold pattern.
</P>
<P>
2. A mold for nanoimprinting, the mold including a mold pattern to be transferred to a processing object, the mold comprising:
</P>
<P>
a base layer including a predetermined base pattern; and
</P>
<P>
a mold layer formed along the base pattern so as to shape the mold pattern and having a thickness less than or equal to 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
3. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the mold layer is formed of a material harder than the resin at least at a molding temperature of performing imprinting on the processing object.
</P>
<P>
4. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the mold layer is formed of an inorganic compound.
</P>
<P>
5. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the mold layer is formed of platinum or nickel.
</P>
<P>
6. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, further including a hydrophilic group on a surface of the mold layer.
</P>
<P>
7. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the resin is a thermoplastic resin.
</P>
<P>
8. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the resin is any one of followings: a cyclic olefin-based resin; an acrylic resin; polycarbonate; vinyl ether; and fluorinated resin.
</P>
<P>
9. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the resin is a thermosetting resin or a photo-curable resin.
</P>
<P>
10. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the resin has a water absorption percentage less than or equal to 3 %.
</P>
<P>
11. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the base pattern has a minimum size in a planar direction less than or equal to 100 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
12. The mold according to claim 1 or 2, further comprising a demolding layer formed on a surface of the mold pattern and suppressing any adhesion with the processing object.
</P>
<P>
13. The mold according to claim 12, wherein the demolding layer is a fluorinated mold release agent.
</P>
<P>
14. A method of manufacturing a mold for nanoimprinting, the mold including a mold pattern to be transferred to a processing object, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
a base layer formation step of forming a base layer formed of a resin and including a predetermined base pattern; and
</P>
<P>
a mold layer formation step of forming a mold layer along the base pattern so as to shape the mold pattern.
</P>
<P>
15. A method of manufacturing a mold for nanoimprinting, the mold including a mold pattern to be transferred to a processing object, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
a base layer formation step of forming a base layer including a predetermined base pattern; and
</P>
<P>
a mold layer formation step of forming a mold layer along the base pattern so as to shape the mold pattern and so as to have a thickness less than or equal to 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
16. The mold manufacturing method according to claim 14 or 15, wherein the mold layer formation step forms the mold layer by any one of following fashions: physical vapor deposition (PVD); chemical vapor deposition (CVD); and plating.
</P>
<P>
17. The mold manufacturing method according to claim 14 or 15, wherein the base layer formation step forms the base layer by imprinting.
</P>
<P>
18. The mold manufacturing method according to claim 14 or 15, further comprising a demolding layer formation step of forming a demolding layer on a surface of the mold pattern, the demolding layer suppressing any adhesion with the processing object.
</P>
<P>
19. A fine pattern product comprising:
</P>
<P>
the mold according to claim 1 or 2; and
</P>
<P>
a molded layer formed by joining with the mold.
</P>
<P>
20. A method of manufacturing a fine pattern product by joining and imprinting the mold according to claim 1 or 2 with a processing object.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2163367A4;US2010304087A1;KR20100031522A;WO2008149544A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
