<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYMER-COATED NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2125028A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YING JACKIE Y [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
ERATHODIYIL NANDANAN [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
JANA NIKHIL R [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
YING, JACKIE, Y
</Name>
<Name>
ERATHODIYIL, NANDANAN
</Name>
<Name>
JANA, NIKHIL, R
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AGENCY SCIENCE TECH &amp; RES [SG]
</Name>
<Name>
AGENCY FOR SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY AND RESEARCH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2125028
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070749537
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-01-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US02536
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K47/48
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K47/48W14B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Polymers for coating nanoparticles (e.g., colloid nanoparticles and quantum dots) and methods associated therewith are provided. Such polymers may be derived from amino acids comprising suitable functional groups for associating the polymer to the nanoparticle. For example, in some embodiments, the polymer includes a polypeptide backbone (e.g., polyaspartic acid) with amino acid side groups (e.g., cysteine and/or methionine). Such a polymer can enable strong binding of the polymer to the nanoparticle surface via its multiple thiol groups, which can lead to excellent colloidal stability. Moreover, the carboxylic acid and amine functional groups of the polymer can facilitate attachment of binding partners (e.g., antibodies) to the polymer, which can allow the polymer-coated nanoparticle to be used in a variety of applications including protein detection and cell labeling.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A coated nanoparticle comprising: a nanoparticle comprising a colloidal or semiconductor material; and a polymer coating on at least a portion of a surface of the nanoparticle, the polymer coating comprising a polypeptide backbone functionalized with amino acid side groups.
</P>
<P>
2. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1 , wherein the polymer coating comprises a polymer including functional groups selected to attach the coating to the nanoparticle surface and functional groups selected to participate in covalent attachment of a chemical or biological entity to the coating, wherein the polymer is selected such that the coating resists separation from the nanoparticle under conditions of covalent attachment of the chemical or biological entity to the coating.
</P>
<P>
3. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1 , wherein the polymer coating comprises a backbone that is charged.
</P>
<P>
4. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the polymer coating comprises a backbone that is negatively charged.
</P>
<P>
5. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the polymer coating comprises a polyaspartic acid backbone.
</P>
<P>
6. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the polymer coating comprises a polyglutamic acid backbone.
</P>
<P>
7. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1 , wherein the polymer is functionalized with cysteine and/or methionine side groups or derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein at least a portion of the amino acid side groups comprises a thiol.
</P>
<P>
9. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the polymer has a molecular weight of from about 10 kDa to about 20 kDa.
</P>
<P>
10. A coated nanoparticle as in claim I5 wherein the polymer comprises a chemical or biological entity covalently attached to the polymer.
</P>
<P>
11. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the chemical or biological entity is a binding partner for a complementary chemical or biological entity.
</P>
<P>
12. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle comprises a colloidal material.
</P>
<P>
13. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 12, wherein the colloidal material is Au or Ag.
</P>
<P>
14. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle comprises a semiconductor material.
</P>
<P>
15. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle is a quantum dot.
</P>
<P>
16. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1 , wherein the nanoparticle is formed of a magnetic material.
</P>
<P>
17. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle comprises zinc.
</P>
<P>
18. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1 having a size of less than or equal to 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
19. A coated nanoparticle as in claim 1 having a size of less than or equal to 5 nm.
</P>
<P>
20. A polymer comprising a polypeptide backbone functionalized with amino acid side groups that can bind to a surface of a nanoparticle, and that can participate in covalent attachment of a chemical or biological entity to the polymer, present in a sufficient quantity such that when the polymer is applied to a nanoparticle, at least a portion of the nanoparticle surface is coated with the polymer so as to form a single, isolated polymer-coated nanoparticle having a size of less than or equal to 10 nanometers, presenting for attachment functional groups able to participate in covalent attachment of a chemical or biological entity, wherein the polymer has a molecular weight of from about 10 kDa to about 20 kDa.
</P>
<P>
21. A polymer as in claim 20, wherein the backbone is charged.
</P>
<P>
22. A polymer as in claim 20, wherein the backbone is negatively charged. negatively charged.
</P>
<P>
23. A polymer as in claim 20, wherein the backbone comprises polyaspartic acid.
</P>
<P>
24. A polymer as in claim 20, wherein at least a portion of the amino acid side groups comprises cysteine or a derivative thereof.
</P>
<P>
25. A polymer as in claim 20, wherein at least a portion of the amino acid side groups comprises a thiol.
</P>
<P>
26. A method of forming a polymer-coated nanoparticle comprising: selecting a nanoparticle and a polymer comprising a polypeptide backbone functionalized with amino acid side groups, the polymer comprising functional groups that can bind to a surface of the nanoparticle; and coating at least a portion of the nanoparticle surface with the polymer so as to form single, isolated polymer-coated nanoparticle having a size of less than or equal to 10 nanometers.
</P>
<P>
27. A method as in claim 26, wherein coating at least a portion of the nanoparticle surface with the polymer comprises introducing the nanoparticle to an aqueous in nonaqueous emulsion.
</P>
<P>
28. A method as in claim 26, wherein coating at least a portion of the nanoparticle surface with the polymer comprises contacting the nanoparticle with a surfactant.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008094144A1;US2011014473A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
