<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SYSTEMS, METHODS AND APPARATUS FOR LOCAL PROGRAMMING OF QUANTUM PROCESSOR ELEMENTS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2126800A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BERKLEY ANDREW J [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
BUNYK PAUL I [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
ROSE GEORDIE [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
BERKLEY, ANDREW J
</Name>
<Name>
BUNYK, PAUL I
</Name>
<Name>
ROSE, GEORDIE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DWAVE SYS INC [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
D-WAVE SYSTEMS INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2126800
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070855474
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007CA02192
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060868654P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G06J3/00
</Class>
<Class>
G06N99/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L39/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L39/22
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G06N99/00K
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Systems, methods and apparatus for a scalable quantum processor architecture. A quantum processor is locally programmable by providing a memory register with a signal embodying device control parameters), converting the signal to an analog signal;  and administering the analog signal to one or more programmable devices.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A quantum processor, comprising: a plurality of programmable devices, wherein each programmable device is connected to at least one communication conduit; and a memory administration system, wherein the memory administration system is linked to at least one programmable device via at least one of the communication conduits.
</P>
<P>
2. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein at least one programmable device and at least a portion of the memory administration system are formed by a material that is superconducting below a critical temperature.
</P>
<P>
3. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein the programmable devices are selected from the group consisting of superconducting flux qubits, superconducting charge qubits, superconducting phase qubits, superconducting hybrid qubits, quantum dots, trapped ions, trapped neutral atoms, qubit couplers, superconducting qubit couplers, impurities, nuclear spin qubits, electronic spin qubits, and photonic qubits.
</P>
<P>
4. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein at least one communication conduit communicates between two or more programmable devices.
</P>
<P>
5. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein the memory administration system comprises a plurality of components and at least one communication conduit communicates between at least one programmable device and at least one component of the memory administration system.
</P>
<P>
6. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein the memory administration system comprises a plurality of components and at least one communication conduit communicates between two or more components of the memory administration system.
</P>
<P>
7. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein the memory administration system includes a digital-to-analog converter (DAC).
</P>
<P>
8. The quantum processor of claim 7 wherein the DAC includes a superconducting flux DAC, and wherein digital signals are represented by discrete magnetic flux quanta.
</P>
<P>
9. The quantum processor of claim 1 wherein the memory administration system includes at least one device capable of storing digital information.
</P>
<P>
10. The quantum processor of claim 9 wherein at least one device capable of storing digital information includes a memory register.
</P>
<P>
11. The quantum processor of claim 10 wherein at least two memory registers are communicably coupled in series with one another, the coupling being established by at least one communication conduit.
</P>
<P>
12. The quantum processor of claim 9 wherein the memory administration system includes a routing system wherein at least two devices capable of storing digital information are communicably coupled to the routing system by at least one communication conduit.
</P>
<P>
13. The quantum processor of claim 12 wherein the routing system includes a demultiplexer circuit.
</P>
<P>
14. The quantum processor of claim 10 wherein the memory administration system includes at least one DAC and digital signals are administered between at least one memory register and at least one DAC.
</P>
<P>
15. The quantum processor of claim 14 wherein at least one memory register and at least one DAC are configured to administer digital signals in the form of magnetic flux quanta.
</P>
<P>
16. The quantum processor of claim 15 wherein the magnetic flux quanta are administered between the at least one memory register and the at least one DAC via galvanic coupling.
</P>
<P>
17. The quantum processor of claim 15 wherein the magnetic flux quanta are administered between the at least one memory register and the at least one DAC via inductive coupling.
</P>
<P>
18. The quantum processor of claim 14 wherein at least one DAC is communicably coupled to at least one programmable device, such that data signals may be coupled therebetween.
</P>
<P>
19. The quantum processor of claim 14 wherein at least two DACs are communicably coupled to one programmable device, such that data signals may be coupled therebetween at a controlled rate.
</P>
<P>
20. The quantum processor of claim 18 wherein the data signals are administered between the at least one DAC and the at least one programmable device via inductive coupling.
</P>
<P>
21. The quantum processor of claim 20 wherein the inductive coupling between the at least one DAC and the at least one programmable device is mediated by an intermediate coupling device.
</P>
<P>
22. The quantum processor of claim 21 wherein at least one intermediate coupling device is inductively coupled to the at least one DAC and the at least one programmable device.
</P>
<P>
23. The quantum processor of claim 22 wherein the intermediate coupling device is communicably coupled to an activation communication conduit and the intermediate coupling device is capable of being switched between an active state and an inactive state via the activation communication conduit.
</P>
<P>
24. The quantum processor of claim 23 wherein a plurality of intermediate coupling devices are connected in series to the activation communication conduit and each intermediate coupling device is capable of being switched between an active state and an inactive state by the activation communication conduit.
</P>
<P>
25. The quantum processor of claim 23 wherein the activation communication conduit is analog variable between the active state and the inactive state.
</P>
<P>
26. The quantum processor of claim 9 wherein at least one device capable of storing digital information includes a superconducting flux-based shift register.
</P>
<P>
27. The quantum processor of claim 26 wherein the superconducting flux-based shift register includes a single flux quantum (SFQ) shift register.
</P>
<P>
28. A method of programming a quantum processor comprising at least one programmable device, the method comprising: locally programming at least one information storage device with a data signal embodying at least one programmable device control parameter; converting the data signal to an analog signal; and administering the analog signal to the programmable device.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of claim 28 wherein converting the data signal to an analog signal includes generating an analog signal having a magnitude proportional to the data signal.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 29 wherein administering the analog signal to the programmable device includes administering the analog signal to an intermediate coupling device.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 30 wherein the intermediate coupling device is configurable to an active state and an inactive state and wherein the intermediate coupling device administers the analog signal to the programmable device when the intermediate coupling device is in the active state.
</P>
<P>
32. The method of claim 30 wherein the intermediate coupling device is tunable between an active state and an inactive state and wherein the intermediate coupling device administers at least a portion of the analog signal to the programmable device when the intermediate coupling device is tuned away from the inactive state.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 28 wherein programming at least one information storage device with a data signal embodying at least one programmable device control parameter includes serially programming a plurality of programmable devices.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 28 wherein programming at least one information storage device with a data signal embodying at least one programmable device control parameter includes routing the data signal to a corresponding information storage device.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of claim 34 wherein programming at least one information storage device with a data signal embodying at least one programmable device control parameter includes programming a plurality of programmable devices with a demultiplexer circuit.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2126800A4;WO2008067664A1;US2012005456A1;US2008215850A1;US7876248B2;US2011055520A1;US8035540B2;KR20090090326A;JP2010511946A;CN101548288A;CA2669816A1;AU2007329156A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
