<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ELECTROABSORPTION MODULATORS WITH A WEAKLY GUIDED OPTICAL WAVEGUIDE MODE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2195704A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MOODIE DAVID GRAHAM [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
MOODIE, DAVID, GRAHAM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CT FOR INTEGRATED PHOTONICS LT [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
THE CENTRE FOR INTEGRATED PHOTONICS LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2195704
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080788775
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-09-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008GB50806
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-09-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070017606
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G02B6/42
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/017
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/025
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/122
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/017C
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/025
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An electroabsorption modulator comprises an absorption layer (7) between at least one layer of p-doped semiconductor (6) and at least one layer of n-doped semiconductor (8). The layers form a ridge waveguide structure. The thickness of the absorption layer is between 9 and 60 nm and the width of the ridge is between 4.5 and 12 microns.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. An electroabsorption modulator comprising an absorption layer between at least one layer of p-doped semiconductor and at least one layer of n-doped semiconductor, wherein the layers form a ridge waveguide structure, the thickness of the absorption layer is between 9 and 60 nm and the width of the ridge is between 4.5 and 12 microns.
</P>
<P>
2. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 1, wherein the absorption layer comprises multiple quantum wells.
</P>
<P>
3. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 2, wherein the absorption layer comprises three or fewer quantum wells.
</P>
<P>
4. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 1 or 2, wherein the sum of the thicknesses of the multiple quantum wells is between 9 and 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
5. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 4, wherein the sum of the thicknesses of the multiple quantum wells is between 18 and 25 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the absorption layer has a thickness between 20 and 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the width of the ridge is between 5.5 and 8 microns.
</P>
<P>
8. A buried heterostructure electroabsorption modulator comprising an absorption layer between at least one layer of p-doped semiconductor and at least one layer of n- doped semiconductor, wherein the absorption layer is formed in a mesa with a width of between 0.6 and 3 microns and the thickness of the absorption layer is between 9 and 65 nm.
</P>
<P>
9. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 8, wherein the absorption layer comprises multiple quantum wells. 10. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 9, wherein the absorption layer comprises three or fewer quantum wells.
</P>
<P>
11. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in claim 9 or 10, wherein the sum of the thicknesses of the multiple quantum wells is between 20 and 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
12. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in any of claims 8 to 11, wherein the absorption layer has a thickness between 20 and 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
13. An electroabsorption modulator as claimed in any of claims 8 to 12, wherein the width of the mesa is between 1 and 2 microns.
</P>
<P>
14. An electroabsorption modulator substantially as hereinbefore described with reference to the Figures.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009034381A1;US2010215308A1;JP2010539522A;GB2454452A;GB2454452B;CN101939689A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
