<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CHROMIUM HYDROXIDE, METHOD FOR PRODUCING THE SAME, TRIVALENT CHROMIUM- CONTAINING SOLUTION USING THE SAME, AND CHROMIUM PLATING METHOD
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2141125A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HOSHINO SHIGEO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMPO RYOKICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA YASUYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HOSHINO, SHIGEO
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMPO, RYOKICHI
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA, YASUYUKI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NIPPON CHEMICAL IND [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HOSHINO SHIGEO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMPO RYOKICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NIPPON CHEMICAL INDUSTRIAL CO., LTD
</Name>
<Name>
HOSHINO, SHIGEO
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMPO, RYOKICHI
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2141125
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080738913
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP55725
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070119907
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G37/02
</Class>
<Class>
C25D21/14
</Class>
<Class>
C25D3/06
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G37/02
</Class>
<Class>
C25D21/14
</Class>
<Class>
C25D3/06
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Chromium hydroxide of the invention has an average particle size D determined from a scanning electron micrograph of 40 to 200 nm and a degree of agglomeration of 10 and more and less than 70, the degree of agglomeration being defined to be a ratio of a volume average particle size D50 determined with a particle size analyzer to the average particle size D, D50/D. The chromium hydroxide is suitably obtained by adding an aqueous solution containing trivalent chromium to an aqueous solution of an inorganic alkali at a reaction temperature of 0 DEG C or higher and lower than 50 DEG C. The inorganic alkali is preferably an alkali metal hydroxide.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Chromium hydroxide having an average particle size D determined from a scanning electron micrograph of 40 to 200 nm and a degree of agglomeration of 10 and more and less than 70, the degree of agglomeration being defined to be a ratio of a volume average particle size D50 determined with a particle size analyzer to the average particle size D, D50/D.
</P>
<P>
2. The chromium hydroxide according to claim 1, obtained by adding an aqueous solution containing trivalent chromium to an aqueous solution of an inorganic alkali at a reaction temperature of 0[deg.]C or higher and lower than 50[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
3. The chromium hydroxide according to claim 1, being in the form of a slurry in pure water, the slurry being substantially free from an impurity ion.
</P>
<P>
4. A process of preparing chromium hydroxide comprising the step of adding an aqueous solution containing trivalent chromium to an aqueous solution of an inorganic alkali at a reaction temperature of 0[deg.]C or higher and lower than 50[deg.]C, wherein the addition of the aqueous solution containing trivalent chromium is such that the amount of trivalent chromium is not locally excessive relative to the amount of the alkali.
</P>
<P>
5. The process according to claim 4, wherein the inorganic alkali is an alkali metal hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
6. The process according to claim 4, further comprising the steps of filtering the reaction system after the formation of chromium hydroxide and washing the filter cake with water until the washing has a conductivity of 5 mS/cm or less.
</P>
<P>
7. A trivalent chromium-containing liquid for use in chromium plating or surface treatment or chromate treatment of metals, prepared by using the chromium hydroxide according to claim 1 as a trivalent chromium source.
</P>
<P>
8. A chromium plating method using the trivalent chromium-containing liquid according to claim 7.
</P>
<P>
9. A replenisher for a trivalent chromium-containing liquid for use in chromium plating or surface treatment or chromate treatment of metals, comprising a slurry of the chromium hydroxide according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
10. A chromium plating method comprising conducting plating using a trivalent chromium plating bath comprising 100 to 300 g/l of chromium chloride hexahydrate (CrCl3.6H2O), 20 to 30 g/l of boric acid (H3BO3), 30 to 50 g/l of glycine (NH2CH2COOH), 70 to 150 g/l of ammonium chloride (NH4Cl), and 20 to 50 g/l of aluminum chloride hexahydrate (AlCl3-6H2O) and replenishing the bath with a replenisher, the replenisher being a slurry of the chromium hydroxide according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
11. The chromium plating method according to claim 10, wherein the plating is conducted at a current density of 20 to 80 A/dm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; and a bath temperature of 35[deg.] to 65[deg.]C using a carbon plate or a titanium-platinum plate as an anode.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2141125A4;US2010116679A1;TW200911699A;KR20100027110A;JP4576456B2;WO2008136223A1;CN101795973A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
