<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
HIGH HARMONICS GENERATION OF LIGHT
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2153277A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MOISEYEV NIMROD [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
FLEISCHER AVNER [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
MOISEYEV, NIMROD
</Name>
<Name>
FLEISCHER, AVNER
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TECHNION RES &amp; DEV FOUNDATION [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
TECHNION RESEARCH &amp; DEVELOPMENT FOUNDATION LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2153277
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080738316
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008IL00615
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070924314P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G02F1/35
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/355
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/35W
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of generating light is disclosed. The method comprises irradiating a substance (12) with first optical field (16) of a first frequency and second optical field (20) of a second frequency. The second frequency being higher than a cutoff frequency of a harmonics generation HGS spectrum characterizing the interaction of the substance (12) with the first optical field (16). Furthermore, an apparatus (10) comprises the substance (12), a first light source (14) for generating the first optical field (16) and a second light source (18)- for generating the second optical field (20).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of generating light, comprising irradiating a substance with first optical field of a first frequency and second optical field of a second frequency, said second frequency being higher than a cutoff frequency of a harmonics generation spectrum characterizing the interaction of said substance with said first optical field.
</P>
<P>
2. Apparatus for generating light, comprising a substance, a first light source for generating in the direction of said substance first optical field of a first frequency and a second light source for generating in the direction of said substance second optical field of a second frequency, said second frequency being higher than a cutoff frequency of a harmonics generation spectrum characterizing the interaction of said substance with said first optical field.
</P>
<P>
3. An imaging system for imaging an object or a scene, comprising the apparatus of claim 2 arranged to direct light to the object or scene, and an imager configured for imaging the object or scene based on light emitted thereby, reflected therefrom or transmitted therethrough.
</P>
<P>
4. A spectroscopy system for determining the concentration of analyte in a sample, comprising the apparatus of claim 2 arranged to direct light to the sample, and a light detector configured for detecting light emitted by, reflected from or transmitted through the sample.
</P>
<P>
5. A lithography system, comprising the apparatus of claim 2 arranged to direct a light beam to a substrate to form patterns thereon, and alignment mechanism for aligning said substrate with said light beam.
</P>
<P>
6. A micro-machining system, comprising the apparatus of claim 2.
</P>
<P>
7. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said first frequency is in the infrared range.
</P>
<P>
8. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said second frequency is in the ultraviolet range.
</P>
<P>
9. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said second frequency is in the extreme ultraviolet range.
</P>
<P>
10. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said second frequency is in the X-ray range.
</P>
<P>
11. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein the ratio between said second frequency and said first frequency is an integer.
</P>
<P>
12. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein the ratio between said second frequency and said first frequency is non-integer.
</P>
<P>
13. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said first optical field has an intensity which is substantially higher than the intensity of said second optical field.
</P>
<P>
14. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said first optical field has an intensity which approximately equals the intensity of said second optical field.
</P>
<P>
15. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein said first optical field has an intensity which is lower than the intensity of said second optical field.
</P>
<P>
16. The method, apparatus or system of claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, wherein a combination of said first optical field and said second optical field results in emission of a harmonics generation spectrum from said substance, said emitted harmonics generation spectrum having at least one harmonic which is enhanced relative to a respective harmonic of the harmonics generation spectrum that would have been emitted had said substance been irradiated solely by said first optical field.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008139449A1;US2010207034A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
