<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD OF PREPARING A WELL- DISPERSABLE MICROCRYSTALLINE TITANIUM DIOXIDE PRODUCT
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2178798A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LAMMINMAEKI RALF-JOHAN [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
LATVA-NIRVA ESA [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
LINHO RIITTA [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
NIINIMAEKI JOHANNA [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
VEHMANEN VISA [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
LAMMINMAEKI, RALF-JOHAN
</Name>
<Name>
LATVA-NIRVA, ESA
</Name>
<Name>
LINHO, RIITTA
</Name>
<Name>
NIINIMAEKI, JOHANNA
</Name>
<Name>
VEHMANEN, VISA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SACHTLEBEN PIGMENTS OY [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
SACHTLEBEN PIGMENTS OY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2178798
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080787739
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-08-15
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008FI50466
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-08-15
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
FI20070000618
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/29
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D4B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D4D
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D8
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/29
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12D2B
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12N1
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to a method of preparing a well-dispersable, rutile-structured, microcrystalline titanium dioxide product, a product prepared by the method, and an effect paint and a lacquer provided by means of the product. In the method, the titanium dioxide starting material is first treated with a base to have an alkaline pH value, after which it is treated with an acid to have a hydrochloric acid content of 8 to 30 g/l, neutralized, processed, and calcinated. In particular, the preparation method is characterized by the use of a pretreatment chemical before the calcination stage to improve the dispersability.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A method of preparing a well-dispersable, rutile-structured, microcrystalline titanium dioxide product having a crystal size of less than 60 nm from a titanium dioxide starting material, the method comprising the stages: A. Treating the titanium dioxide starting material to convert it into titanium dioxide so that
</P>
<P>
A1. The titanium dioxide starting material is treated with a base to have an alkaline pH value;
</P>
<P>
A2. The precipitate obtained from stage A1 is further treated with hydrochlo- ric acid so that the final hydrochloric acid content is adjusted to 8 to 35 g/l;
</P>
<P>
A3. The precipitate obtained from stage A2 is neutralized into slurry to a pH value of 4.0 to 6.0;
</P>
<P>
A4. The neutralized slurry obtained from stage A3 is primed with a pretreat- ment chemical; A5. The primed slurry obtained from stage A4 is calcinated; and
</P>
<P>
B. The titanium dioxide obtained from stage A is further treated to convert it into a titanium dioxide end product.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to Claim 1 , characterized in that the said pretreat- ment chemical is potassium dihydrogen phosphate, KH2PO4, or a mixture of po- tassium and phosphor compounds, which before or during calcination reacts into potassium dihydrogen phosphate or a compound similar to potassium dihydrogen phosphate.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to Claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the said pre- treatment chemical is added in an amount of 0.2 to 1% by weight, calculated as potassium dihydrogen phosphate.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to any of Claims 1 to 3, characterized in that the said pretreatment chemical is added as solid powder to the neutralized slurry, which is in mixing and which is obtained from stage A3.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to any of Claims 1 to 4, characterized in that the said titanium dioxide starting material is a solid titanium dioxide hydrate.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to Claim 5, characterized in that the said titanium dioxide hydrate is prepared from ilmenite by means of a sulphate process. 7. The method according to Claim 1 , characterized in that the said crystal size is less than 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any of Claims 1 to 7, characterized in that, at stage A2, the product obtained from stage A1 is elutriated in water by raising the temperature of the slurry by 40-45&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and, after that, by adjusting the content of hydrochloric acid to the said final hydrochloric acid content of stage A2.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to any of Claims 1 to 8, characterized in that, at stage A3, the neutralization is carried out with sodium hydroxide or sodium carbonate, after which the product is filtered and washed.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to any of Claims 1 to 9, characterized in that the further processing stage B comprises the following successive stages:
</P>
<P>
B1. The mass obtained from calcination is wet-ground; B2. The mass obtained from wet-grinding is surface-treated; B3. The surface-treated mass is filtered and washed; B4. The mass obtained from stage B3 is wet-ground again; and
</P>
<P>
B5. The mass obtained from stage B4 is spray-dried and spray-ground to prepare the final titanium dioxide product.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to Claim 10, characterized in that, at stage B4, the mass obtained from stage B3 is elutriated in water and an organic additive is added to the slurry.
</P>
<P>
12. The method according to Claim 11 , characterized in that the said organic additive contains trimethylol propane.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to Claim 10 or 11 , characterized in that the said organic additive is added in an amount of 2 to 8% by weight. 14. A well-dispersable, rutile-structured, microcrystalline titanium dioxide product having a crystal size of less than 60 nm,
</P>
<P>
a) the U/V*100 p rat value defined from its turbidity curve being 500 or more; b) its specific surface area, BET, being 55 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g or less; c) its particle size distribution d50 being less than 0.150 [mu]m; and d) the transmission of the transmission curve of the lacquer film containing particles being at least as permeable as the transmission of the curve B&apos; shown in Fig. 3. 15. A well-dispersable, rutile-structured, microcrystalline titanium dioxide product having a crystal size of less than 60 nm, characterized in being prepared by the method according to any of Claims 1 to 13.
</P>
<P>
16. The titanium dioxide product according to Claim 14 or 15, characterized in that the said crystal size is less than 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
17. The titanium dioxide product according to any of Claims 14 to 16, characterized in that its photostability, expressed as the formation speed of acetone, is less than 10 ppm/h.
</P>
<P>
18. The titanium dioxide product according to any of Claims 14 to 17, character- ized in that its crystal size is 20 to 40 nm.
</P>
<P>
19. An effect paint containing the titanium dioxide product according to any of Claims 14 to 18 for giving the paint a flip flop effect.
</P>
<P>
20. The effect paint according to Claim 19, characterized in that, in the flip flop effect provided by the same, the flip effect 20[deg.] b* is higher than or as high as 8 and the flop effect 115[deg.] b* is lower than or as low as -11.
</P>
<P>
21. A wood lac composition containing the titanium dioxide product according to any of Claims 14 to 18 as a UV protective agent.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2178798B1;WO2009022061A2;WO2009022061A3;US2011192322A1;US8182602B2;JP2010536689A;FI20070618A;AT554053T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
