<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PHOTOELECTRIC CONVERTER AND SOLAR CELL USING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2175502A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SATO YOSHIHARU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAMURA EIICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NIINOMI TAKAAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MATSUO YUTAKA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HASHIGUCHI MASAHIKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SATO, YOSHIHARU
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAMURA, EIICHI
</Name>
<Name>
NIINOMI, TAKAAKI
</Name>
<Name>
MATSUO, YUTAKA
</Name>
<Name>
HASHIGUCHI, MASAHIKO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MITSUBISHI CHEM CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUBISHI CHEMICAL CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2175502
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080777806
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP62054
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070179271
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20080022919
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C07F7/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/42
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07F7/08C4D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M16
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M2B2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M4B2
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E10/50
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a photoelectric conversion device having at least a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor and a compound as an electron donor between a pair of electrodes, wherein the fullerene derivative has 2 to 4 organic groups which each independently have 1 to 50 carbon atoms, and wherein when the fullerene derivative has two organic groups, these organic groups do not bind to each other to form a ring.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A photoelectric conversion device having at least a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor and a compound as an electron donor between a pair of electrodes, wherein the fullerene derivative has 2 to 4 organic groups which each independently have 1 to 50 carbon atoms, and wherein when the fullerene derivative has two organic groups, these organic groups do not bind to each other to form a ring.
</P>
<P>
2. The photoelectric conversion device according to claim 1, wherein the fullerene derivative has 2 or 3 organic groups which each independently have 1 to 50 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
3. The photoelectric conversion device according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the fullerene is at least one selected from the group consisting of fullerene C60 and fullerene C70.
</P>
<P>
4. A photoelectric conversion device having at least a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor represented by the following formula (1):
</P>
<P>
C60(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;)(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;) (1)
</P>
<P>
(wherein in formula (1): R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; are each independently an organic group having 1 to 50 carbon atoms; and R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; do not bind to each other to form a ring), and a compound as an electron donor between a pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
5. A photoelectric conversion device having at least a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor represented by any one of the following formulae (1A) to (1G):
</P>
<P>
(wherein in the formulae (1A) to (1G): R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; are each independently an organic group having 1 to 50 carbon atoms; and R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; do not bind to each other to form a ring), and a compound as an electron donor between a pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
6. A photoelectric conversion device having at least a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor represented by the following formula (1A):
</P>
<P>
(wherein in the formula (1A): R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; are each independently an organic group having 1 to 50 carbon atoms; and R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; do not bind to each other to form a ring), and a compound as an electron donor between a pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
7. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein one or more of the organic groups having 1 to 50 carbon atoms are each independently a group comprising an aromatic ring.
</P>
<P>
8. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein one or more of the organic groups having 1 to 50 carbon atoms are each independently a group represented by the following formula (3):
</P>
<P>
(wherein in the formula (3): W is an atom belonging to group 4B of the periodic table; R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;, R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; are each independently an hydrogen atom, a hydrocarbon group having 1 to 50 carbon atoms, alkoxy or amino; and n is an integer from 1 to 10).
</P>
<P>
9. The photoelectric conversion device according to claim 8, wherein R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;, R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; are each independently a hydrocarbon group having 1 to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
10. The photoelectric conversion device according to claim 8, wherein: R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; and R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; are an alkyl group having 1 to 3 carbon atoms; and R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; is a hydrocarbon group having 1 to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
11. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 8 to 10, wherein: n is an integer from 1 to 5; and W is Si.
</P>
<P>
12. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 4 to 6, wherein in the formula (1) or in the formulae (1A) to (1G): R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is a group represented by the following formula (31):
</P>
<P>
(wherein in the formula (31), R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; is an alkyl group having 1 to 20 carbon atoms or phenyl); and R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is a group represented by the following formula (32):
</P>
<P>
(wherein in the formula (32), R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; is methyl or phenyl).
</P>
<P>
13. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the compound as the electron donor is a polymer compound.
</P>
<P>
14. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the compound as the electron donor is a heterocyclic polymer compound.
</P>
<P>
15. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the compound as the electron donor is a porphyrin compound or phthalocyanine compound.
</P>
<P>
16. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the compound as the electron donor is polythiophene or a copper phthalocyanine complex.
</P>
<P>
17. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein the compound as the electron donor is tetrabenzoporphyrin.
</P>
<P>
18. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 17, which has a mixture layer comprising at least a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor and a compound as an electron donor between a pair of electrodes.
</P>
<P>
19. The photoelectric conversion device according to claim 18, wherein the mixture layer is formed by applying a solution in which a mixture comprising a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor and a compound as an electron donor is dissolved.
</P>
<P>
20. The photoelectric conversion device according to claim 18, wherein the mixture layer is formed by evaporating a fullerene derivative as an electron acceptor and a compound as an electron donor.
</P>
<P>
21. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 20, wherein a p-type semiconductor layer is formed between the mixture layer, which comprises the fullerene derivative as the electron acceptor and the electron donor, and a positive electrode.
</P>
<P>
22. The photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 21, wherein an n-type semiconductor layer is formed between the mixture layer, which comprises the fullerene derivative as the electron acceptor and the electron donor, and a negative electrode.
</P>
<P>
23. A solar cell comprising the photoelectric conversion device according to any one of claims 1 to 22.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2175502A4;US2011005597A1;TW200919797A;JP2009206470A;WO2009008323A1;CN101689611A;CN101689611B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
