<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
BRIDGED POLYCYCLIC COMPOUND BASED COMPOSITIONS FOR THE INHIBITION AND AMELIORATION OF DISEASE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2125026A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WHITEFORD JEFFERY A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WHITEFORD, JEFFERY A
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ALLACCEM INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ALLACCEM, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2125026
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080730417
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-02-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US54611
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070902577P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070964312P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070965154P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080029332P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K47/48
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K47/48H4K
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48W18
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A pharmaceutically active agent, a pharmaceutically active agent carrier and method of use thereof are described. In some embodiments, a system may include a composition. The composition may include one or more bridged polycyclic compounds. At least one of the bridged polycyclic compounds may include at least two cyclic groups, and at least two pharmaceutically active agents may be associated with the bridged polycyclic compound. In some embodiments, a bridged polycyclic compound may be pharmaceutically active. In some embodiments, a bridged polycyclic compound may be function as a carrier for pharmaceutically active agents.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A chemical composition comprising: a chemical compound, wherein the chemical compound comprises one or more bridged poly cyclic compounds, wherein at least one cyclic group of the bridged polycyclic compound is defined in part by at least two amine moieties, wherein at least one bridge of the bridged polycyclic compound comprises at least one atom, and wherein at least one of the bridges couples at least two non-adjacent atoms common to at least two of the cyclic groups; at least two pharmaceutically active agents per bridged polycyclic compound, wherein the pharmaceutically active agent is configured to inhibit and/or ameliorate at least one malady.
</P>
<P>
2. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising at least six pharmaceutically active agents per bridged polycyclic compound.
</P>
<P>
3. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising at least eight pharmaceutically active agents per bridged polycyclic compound. 4. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising at least twelve pharmaceutically active agents per bridged polycyclic compound.
</P>
<P>
5. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one cyclic group of the bridged polycyclic compound is defined in part by at least two quaternary ammonium moieties.
</P>
<P>
6. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one pharmaceutically active agent is coupled to the bridged polycyclic compound.
</P>
<P>
7. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one pharmaceutically active agent is a counterion to the bridged polycyclic compound forming a salt.
</P>
<P>
8. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least two cyclic groups are defined in part by quaternary ammonium moieties. 9. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the bridged polycyclic compounds comprises at least four quaternary ammonium moieties which define at least two of the cyclic groups forming the bridged polycyclic compounds.
</P>
<P>
10. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising one or more polymerizable compounds. 11. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising one or more polymerizable compounds, wherein the chemical composition is configured such that, when the chemical composition is applied to a surface and cured, then at least a portion of the composition forms an antimicrobial coating over at least a portion of the surface.
</P>
<P>
12. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound is a salt of the chemical compound.
</P>
<P>
13. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound is a salt of the chemical compound, and wherein at least one counterion forming the salt is an acetate ion.
</P>
<P>
14. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises a polymer or a prepolymer.
</P>
<P>
15. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises a polymer or a prepolymer, wherein at least one polymer is poly(vinyl acetate-co-crotonic acid).
</P>
<P>
16. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises at least one solvent.
</P>
<P>
17. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises water. 18. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises an alcohol.
</P>
<P>
19. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises an alcohol, wherein at least one alcohol is ethanol.
</P>
<P>
20. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises a pharmaceutically acceptable viscous liquid.
</P>
<P>
21. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical composition comprises glycerin.
</P>
<P>
22. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure (Ia):
</P>
<P>
wherein each R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is independently an alkyl-aryl group, a substituted alkyl-aryl group, an alkyl group, a substituted alkyl group, an aryl group, a substituted aryl group, N, N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;H, N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;, a heterocycle group, or a substituted heterocycle group; wherein each R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is independently an alkyl-aryl group, a substituted alkyl-aryl group, an alkyl group, a substituted alkyl group, an aryl group, a substituted aryl group, a heterocycle group, a substituted heterocycle group, a covalent bond, or an alkene; wherein each R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is independently hydrogen, a pharmaceutically active agent, an alkyl-aryl group, a substituted alkyl-aryl group, an alkyl group, a substituted alkyl group, an aryl group, a substituted aryl group, a heterocycle group, a substituted heterocycle group, an alkene, an ether, a guanidine moiety, a PEG, a PEI, or any combination of these; wherein each R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; is independently an alkyl-aryl group, a substituted alkyl-aryl group, an alkyl group, a substituted alkyl group, an aryl group, a substituted aryl group, a heterocycle group, a substituted heterocycle group, an ether, an amide, an alcohol, an ester, a sulfonamide, a sulfanilamide, or an alkene; and wherein Z comprises at least one bridge, wherein at least one of the bridges is - R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; - N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;2 - R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; - N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;2- R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; -, - R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; - NR&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; - R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; - N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;2- R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; -, - R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; - NR&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; - R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; - NR&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; - R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; -, or - R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; - N = R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; = N- R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;
</P>
<P>
-, and wherein each bridge independently couples R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; to R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
23. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure:
</P>
<P>
24. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure:
</P>
<P>
25. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure:
</P>
<P>
26. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure:
</P>
<P>
27. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure:
</P>
<P>
28. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure:
</P>
<P>
29. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; is
</P>
<P>
30. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; comprises a guanidine moiety.
</P>
<P>
31. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; comprises a halogenated aryl moiety.
</P>
<P>
32. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; comprises guanidine moiety and a halogenated aryl moiety.
</P>
<P>
33. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound has a general structure (I):
</P>
<P>
34. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is an anion.
</P>
<P>
35. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is a polymer and/or a monomer.
</P>
<P>
36. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is a halogen. 37. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X contains boron.
</P>
<P>
38. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is a borate.
</P>
<P>
39. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X tetrafluoroborate. 40. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X contains nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
41. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is a nitrate.
</P>
<P>
42. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is PY6, wherein Y is a halogen 43. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is hexafluorophosphate.
</P>
<P>
44. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one X is NTf2, and wherein Tf is bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide.
</P>
<P>
45. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is a quaternary ammonium salt, wherein the quaternary ammonium salt is -
</P>
<P>
C C((OO))((CCHH22))nnCC((OO))NNRR&amp;lt;55&amp;gt;((CCHH22))nnNNRR&amp;lt;33&amp;gt;33,, aanndd wwlherein R&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; is hydrogen, alkyl, substituted alkyl, aryl, substituted aryl, heteroaryl, or substituted heteroaryl.
</P>
<P>
46. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; comprises at least one quaternary ammonium moiety.
</P>
<P>
47. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is a chloro substituted aryl group.
</P>
<P>
48. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein Z is one bridge such that the chemical compound has a general structure (Ha):
</P>
<P>
49. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein Z is one bridge such that the chemical compound has a general structure (II):
</P>
<P>
50. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein Z is two bridges such that the chemical compound has a general structure (Ilia):
</P>
<P>
51. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein Z is two bridges such that the chemical compound has a general structure (III):
</P>
<P>
52. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is an antiviral agent.
</P>
<P>
53. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is an anticancer agent.
</P>
<P>
54. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is an anti-inflammatory agent.
</P>
<P>
55. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is an antimicrobial agent. 56. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a lipase inhibitor.
</P>
<P>
57. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a bile acid sequestrant.
</P>
<P>
58. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a cholesterol reduction agent.
</P>
<P>
59. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises a statin.
</P>
<P>
60. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises Atorvastatin, Cerivastatin, Ezetimibe, Fluvastatin, Lovastatin, Mevastatin, Niacin, Pitavastatin, Pravastatin, Rosuvastatin, Simvastatin, or derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
61. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises pravastatin, fluvastatin, atorvastatin, or derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
62. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to inhibit and/or ameliorate otic maladies. 63. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises a quinolone or a derivative thereof.
</P>
<P>
64. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises enrofloxicin or derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
65. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to inhibit and/or ameliorate renal maladies.
</P>
<P>
66. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to inhibit and/or ameliorate renal maladies by binding phosphates.
</P>
<P>
67. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to bind phosphates.
</P>
<P>
68. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to bind salts.
</P>
<P>
69. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to bind metals. 70. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to bind metal ions.
</P>
<P>
71. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to bind water.
</P>
<P>
72. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising a polymeric acid. 73. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising a polymeric acid, wherein the polymeric acid comprises a polyethyleneglycol acid.
</P>
<P>
74. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising Methoxypolyethylene glycol 5,000 acetic acid and/or Methoxypolyethylene glycol 5,000 propionic acid.
</P>
<P>
75. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to inhibit and/or ameliorate parrot fever.
</P>
<P>
76. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises a quinolonecarboxylic acid or derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
77. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises a nalidixic acid or derivatives thereof. 78. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises an MTP inhibitor.
</P>
<P>
79. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to regulate fat absorption.
</P>
<P>
80. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is configured to regulate intestinal fat absorption.
</P>
<P>
81. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a periodontal disease agent.
</P>
<P>
82. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a periodontal bacteria attachment inhibitor 83. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a periodontal disease enzyme inhibitor. 84. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a periodontal disease enzyme attachment inhibitor.
</P>
<P>
85. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is a periodontal Stomatitis inhibitor.
</P>
<P>
86. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents is an oral cavity disease FORLS (Feline Odontoclastic Resorptive
</P>
<P>
Lesions) inhibitor.
</P>
<P>
87. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises a halogenated aryl moiety.
</P>
<P>
88. The chemical composition of any one of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the pharmaceutically active agents comprises a guanidine moiety and a halogenated aryl moiety.
</P>
<P>
89. A method of inhibiting or ameliorating a malady comprising administering to a subject an effective amount of a pharmaceutically acceptable formulation comprising a chemical composition as described in any one of the preceding claims.
</P>
<P>
90. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation is applied to an oral surface.
</P>
<P>
91. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation is applied to an oral surface forming a coating over at least a portion of the oral surface.
</P>
<P>
92. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the oral surface comprises at least a portion of a tooth surface, at least a portion of a gum, at least a portion of soft tissue, and/or at least a portion of a dental fixture.
</P>
<P>
93. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the oral surface comprises at least a portion of a dental fixture, wherein a dental fixture comprises a filling, at least a portion of a bridge, and/or at least a portion of a denture.
</P>
<P>
94. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation is applied to an otic surface.
</P>
<P>
95. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation is applied to an otic surface forming a coating over at least a portion of the otic surface.
</P>
<P>
96. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the malady is a fungal infection, an infection, a viral infection, a disease, bacteria based, microbial based, mold based, yeast based, and/or results from parasitic invasion of a subject.
</P>
<P>
97. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the subject is a mammal, a canine, a feline, human, animal, avian, and/or a protein source animal.
</P>
<P>
98. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein administering the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation to a subject comprises administering the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation to a subject parenterally, subcutaneously, orally, topically, and/or intracoronary administration.
</P>
<P>
99. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein administering the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation to a subject comprises administering at least two different pharmaceutically active agents.
</P>
<P>
100. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein administering the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation to a subject comprises administering at least two different pharmaceutically active agents, wherein the agents are coupled to the same and/or different bridged polycyclic compounds. 101. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein administering the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation to a subject comprises administering the pharmaceutically acceptable formulation to a subject in the form of an emulsion or in the form of a gel.
</P>
<P>
102. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chemical compound may decompose during use, wherein one or more of the products of the decomposition may be more biologically active relative to the chemical compound.
</P>
<P>
103. A chemical composition comprising a chemical compound, wherein the chemical compound comprises one or more bridged polycyclic compounds.
</P>
<P>
104. A method of inhibiting or ameliorating a malady comprising administering to a subject an effective amount of a pharmaceutically acceptable formulation comprising a chemical composition comprising a chemical compound, wherein the chemical compound comprises one or more bridged polycyclic compounds.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008103847A2;WO2008103847A3;US2008275141A1;NZ579785A;CA2683383A1;AU2008218275A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
