<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Dry etching method for magnetic material
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2184381A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KODAIRA YOSHIMITSU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HIROMI TAICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KODAIRA, YOSHIMITSU
</Name>
<Name>
HIROMI, TAICHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CANON ANELVA CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
CANON ANELVA CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2184381
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100001014
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-07-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040254457
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-07-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20030201254
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-07-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C23F4/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/31
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/14
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/34
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/3065
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/3213
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23F4/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30D6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/12
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for manufacturing a tunneling magnetoresistance (TMR) device comprises providing with an element comprising a first ferromagnetic layer, a second ferromagnetic layer, an insulating layer positioned between the first ferromagnetic layer and the second ferromagnetic layer and an antiferromagnetic layer, and then forming a non-organic layer positioned at the top surface of the element, and then forming a photo-resist mask on the non-organic layer, thereby providing with a pre-TMR device;  providing with a container 2 having a plasma generating means 1, an exhausting means 21, a first gas feeding means 3 and second gas feeding means;  exhausting an inner space of the container by using the exhausting means 21;  introducing the pre-TMR device into the exhausted inner space of the container 2;  a first etching for etching the non-organic layer by using a process comprising: feeding a first etching gas into said exhausted inner space by using the first gas feeding means 3 and generating a plasma by using the plasma generating means 1, thereby forming a pattern of the non-organic layer according to the photo-resist mask pattern;  and a second etching for etching the element by using a process comprising: feeding a second etching gas selected from the group consisting of an alcohol gas, a ketone gas and a non-substituted hydrocarbon gas into said exhausted inner space by using the second gas feeding means and generating a plasma by using the plasma generating means 1, thereby forming a pattern of the element according to the patterned non-organic layer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for manufacturing a tunneling magnetoresistance, TMR, device comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing with an element comprising a first ferromagnetic layer, a second ferromagnetic layer, an insulating layer positioned between the first ferromagnetic layer and the second ferromagnetic layer and an antiferromagnetic layer, and then forming a non-organic layer positioned at the top surface of the element, and then forming a photo-resist mask on the non-organic layer, thereby providing with a pre-TMR device;
</P>
<P>
providing with a container having a plasma generating means, an exhausting means, a first gas feeding means and second gas feeding means;
</P>
<P>
exhausting an inner space of the container by using the exhausting means;
</P>
<P>
introducing the pre-TMR device into the exhausted inner space of the container;
</P>
<P>
a first etching for etching the non-organic layer by using a process comprising:
</P>
<P>
feeding a first etching gas into said exhausted inner space by using the first gas feeding means and generating a plasma by using the plasma generating means, thereby forming a pattern of the non-organic layer according to the photo-resist mask pattern; and
</P>
<P>
a second etching for etching the element by using a process comprising:
</P>
<P>
feeding a second etching gas selected from the group consisting of an alcohol gas, a ketone gas and a non-substituted hydrocarbon gas into said exhausted inner space by using the second gas feeding means and generating a plasma by using the plasma generating means, thereby forming a pattern of the element according to the patterned non-organic layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1, wherein said non-organic layer is a layer comprising a material selected from the group consisting of Ta, Ti, Al and Si.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 1, wherein said non-organic layer is a layer comprising a material selected from the group consisting of an oxide or nitride of Ta, Ti, Al and Si.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 1, 2 or 3, wherein said second etching gas comprises an added gas.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 4, wherein said added gas is one or both of oxygen gas and water added at a respective content of not more than 25% relative to the second etching gas.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein said second etching gas comprises an inert gas.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to claim 6, wherein said inert gas is added at a respective content of not more than 90% relative to the second etching gas.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein said alcohol is an alcohol selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol and propanol.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein said non-substituted hydrocarbon is an alkane selected from the group consisting of methane, ethane, propane and butane.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1500720A1;US2005016957A1;US7060194B2;USRE40951E1;KR20050012144A;KR101041049B1;JP2005042143A;EP2184380A1;CN101624701A;CN101624701B;CN1603468A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
