<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
IMPROVED PARTICLE BEAM GENERATOR
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2126955A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
EASTHAM DEREK ANTHONY [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
EASTHAM, DEREK ANTHONY
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NFAB LTD [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
NFAB LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2126955
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080702133
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-24
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008GB50050
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070001470
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070007958
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070013447
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070015495
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070017927
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01J37/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01J37/065
</Class>
<Class>
H01J37/073
</Class>
<Class>
H01J37/12
</Class>
<Class>
H01J37/28
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A particle beam generator comprising particle extraction means disposed adjacent a particle source and operable to extract particles from such a source into an extraction aperture of the extraction means to form a particle beam, particle accelerating means operable to accelerate the extracted particles to increase the energy of the beam, and focussing means operable to focus the particle beam, each of said extraction means, accelerating means and focussing means being arranged in sequence and having apertures therethrough and in alignment to define a passageway through which the particles are constrained to move, characterised in that the extraction means comprises a lens structure comprising at least a pair of electrodes separated by a layer of insulating material allowing the application of different potentials to each of the lens structure electrodes, one of said electrodes comprising an extraction plate having an extraction aperture formed therein, by means of which extraction plate particles may be drawn from the particle source and through the extraction aperture by means of a potential difference between the source and said extraction plate.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1 . A particle beam generator comprising: particle extraction means disposed adjacent a particle source and operable to extract particles from such a source into an extraction aperture of the extraction means to form a particle beam, particle accelerating means operable to accelerate the extracted particles to increase the energy of the beam, and focussing means operable to focus the particle beam, each of said extraction means, accelerating means and focussing means being arranged in sequence and having apertures therethrough and in alignment to define a passageway through which the particles are constrained to move, characterised in that the extraction means comprises a lens structure comprising at least a pair of electrodes separated by a layer of insulating material allowing the application of different potentials to each of the lens structure electrodes, one of said electrodes comprising an extraction plate having an extraction aperture formed therein, the extraction plate being arranged whereby particles may be drawn from the particle source and through the extraction aperture by means of a potential difference between the particle source and said extraction plate.
</P>
<P>
2. A generator as claimed in claim 1 wherein the focussing means comprises an Einzel lens structure having an overall length of the order of from around 1 to around 10 microns.
</P>
<P>
3. A generator as claimed in claim 1 or claim 2 wherein the extraction means comprises a nano-scale Einzel lens structure (NEZL) having an overall length of no more than 500nm.
</P>
<P>
4. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the extraction means comprises two electrodes.
</P>
<P>
5. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 3 wherein the extraction means comprises three electrodes.
</P>
<P>
6. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 3 to 5 wherein the NEZL structure comprises said extraction plate.
</P>
<P>
7. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 3 to 5 wherein the extraction plate is provided between the particle source and the NEZL structure.
</P>
<P>
8. A generator as claimed in claim 7 wherein the NEZL structure is provided sufficiently close to the extraction plate to have an immediate influence on particles extracted from the particle source by the extraction plate.
</P>
<P>
9. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the focussing means comprises primary and secondary focussing means, each of said extraction means, accelerating means and primary focussing means being arranged in sequence, the secondary focussing means being disposed remotely from an end of the primary focusing means such that said primary and secondary focussing means are essentially separated, the secondary focussing means having an average aperture having a size that is greater than that of the primary focussing means.
</P>
<P>
10. A generator as claimed in claim 9 wherein the secondary focussing means comprises alignment means for aligning the secondary focussing means coaxially with said primary focussing means.
</P>
<P>
1 1 . A generator as claimed in claim 10 wherein the alignment means comprises a nanopositioning member operable to achieve coaxiality between the primary and secondary focussing means to within 10nm, preferably 1 nm, and most preferably to within 0.1 nm.
</P>
<P>
12. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 9 to 1 1 wherein a first electrode of the secondary focussing means being an electrode of the secondary focussing means closest to the primary focussing means is provided with a knife-edged opening aperture arranged to collimate a particle beam arriving thereat.
</P>
<P>
13. A generator as claimed in claim 12 wherein a diameter of said knife-edged opening aperture of the secondary focussing means is greater than a diameter of a particle beam aperture of the primary focussing means.
</P>
<P>
14. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 9 to 1 1 wherein a first electrode of the secondary focussing means being an electrode of the secondary focussing means closest to the primary focussing means is arranged to have a diameter greater than that of a beam of electrons arriving at the secondary focussing means from the primary focussing means.
</P>
<P>
15. A generator as claimed in claim 14 wherein the first electrode of the secondary focussing means has a diameter of at least substantially 2[mu]m.
</P>
<P>
16. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 15 wherein the particle source comprises a nanotip member.
</P>
<P>
17. A generator as claimed in claim 16 wherein the nanotip member has a tip portion having a free end having a diameter of from around 1 atomic diameter to around 50nm.
</P>
<P>
18. A generator as claimed in claim 16 or claim 17 wherein the tip portion is in the form of a nanopyramid structure or similar stable electron emitter structure of atomic or substantially atomic dimensions.
</P>
<P>
19. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 16 to 18 wherein the nanotip member comprises at least a portion in the form of a length of wire.
</P>
<P>
20. A generator as claimed in any one of claims 17 to 19 wherein the tip portion is formed from at least one selected from amongst platinum, tungsten, platinum iridium alloy, cobalt, gold and silver.
</P>
<P>
21 . A generator as claimed in any one of claims 17 to 20 wherein the tip portion is formed of a material configured to be resistant to reaction with oxygen.
</P>
<P>
22. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the extraction aperture has a diameter of from around 1 nm to around 10[mu]m, preferably from around 1 nm to around 1000nm, more preferably from around 2nm to around 20nm.
</P>
<P>
23. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the accelerating section is arranged to accelerate particles from said particle source by generating an electric field of a value whereby a diameter of the particle beam is substantially constant along a length of the accelerating section, the diameter of the beam being substantially equal to a diameter of said extraction aperture.
</P>
<P>
24. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the accelerating section is arranged to accelerate particles from said source by means of an electric field having a value of from around 100 to around 10OOV/[mu]m.
</P>
<P>
25. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the particle source is configured to provide a source of electrons.
</P>
<P>
26. A generator as claimed in any preceding claim wherein the particle source is configured to provide a source of ions.
</P>
<P>
27. A particle beam generator comprising particle extraction means disposed adjacent a particle source and operable to extract particles from such a source into an extraction aperture within said extraction means to form a particle beam, particle accelerating means operable to accelerate the extracted particles to increase the energy of the beam, and primary focussing means operable to focus the particle beam, each of said extraction means, accelerating means and primary focussing means being arranged in sequence and having apertures therethrough and in alignment to define a passageway through which the particles are constrained to move, characterised in that the particle generator further includes a secondary focussing means disposed remotely from the end of the primary focusing means such that said primary and secondary focussing means are essentially separated, the secondary focussing means having an average aperture size which is greater than that for the primary focussing means.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008090380A1;US2010187433A1;JP2010517233A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
