<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FABRICATION OF MICROSTRUCTURES AND NANOSTRUCTURES USING ETCHING RESIST
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2122417A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MIRKIN CHAD A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HUANG LING [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SANEDRIN RAYMOND [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MIRKIN, CHAD, A
</Name>
<Name>
HUANG, LING
</Name>
<Name>
SANEDRIN, RAYMOND
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV NORTHWESTERN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2122417
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070873494
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-17
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US25722
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060875447P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070886839P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Nanostructures and microstructures are formed by patterning methods such as Dip Pen Nanolithography (DPN) or microcontact printing of organic molecules functioning as a resist on a substrate followed by an etching step. The etch resist is a patterning composition and can contain on a substrate including polyethylene glycol (PEG). Positive and negative etch methods can be used.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of forming nanostructures or microstrucrures comprising the steps of: performing direct- write nanolithography to pattern a surface of a substrate with a patterning composition comprising an oligomeric or polymeric compound and to provide an exposed substrate, wherein the patterning composition is physisorbed to the substrate surface; and etching the exposed substrate on the patterned surface to form the nanostructures or microstructures.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 , wherein the patterning composition comprises a water soluble oligomeric or polymeric compound.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises a heteroatom in the backbone.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises an oxygen atom.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1, wherein the patterning composition comprises polyethyleneglycol (PEG) or polyethylene oxide (PEO).
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1, wherein the patterning composition comprises polypropylene glycol, wax, polyethylene imine, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1 , comprising the step of applying the patterning composition to a tip.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1 , wherein patterning a surface of a substrate comprises transfer of the patterning composition from a tip to the surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 8, wherein the tip is a scanning probe microscope tip.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 8, wherein the tip is an atomic force microscope tip.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 8, wherein the tip is a hollow tip.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 8 wherein the tip is a non-hollow tip.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 8, wherein patterning a surface of a substrate is carried out at a relative humidity of at least about 40%.
</P>
<P>
14. A method of forming nanostructures or microstructures comprising the steps of: performing microcontact printing to pattern the surface of a substrate with a patterning composition comprising an oligomeric or polymeric compound and to provide an exposed substrate, wherein the patterning composition is physisorbed to the substrate surface; and etching the exposed substrate on the patterned surface to form the nanostructures or microstructures.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14, wherein the patterning composition comprises a water soluble oligomeric or polymeric compound.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 14, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises a heteroatom in the backbone.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 14, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises an oxygen atom.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 14, wherein the patterning composition comprises polyethyleneglycol (PEG) or polyethylene oxide (PEO).
</P>
<P>
19. A method of forming nanostructures or microstructures comprising the steps of: performing direct- write nanolithography to pattern a surface of a substrate with a patterning composition comprising an oligomeric or polymeric compound, wherein the patterning composition is physisorbed to the substrate surface; coating the non-patterned region of the substrate surface with a passivating compound; removing the patterning composition to provide exposed substrate; and etching the exposed substrate to form nanostructures or microstructures.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19, wherein the patterning composition comprises a water soluble oligomeric or polymeric compound.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of claim 19, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises a heteroatom in the backbone.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 19, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises an oxygen atom.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of claim 19, wherein the patterning composition comprises polyethyleneglycol (PEG) or polyethylene oxide (PEO).
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 19, wherein the patterning composition comprises polypropylene glycol, wax, polyethylene imine or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of claim 19, comprising the step of applying the patterning composition to a tip.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 19, wherein patterning a surface of a substrate comprises transfer of the patterning composition from a tip to the surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 26, wherein the tip is a scanning probe microscope tip.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 26, wherein the tip is an atomic force microscope tip.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of claim 26, wherein the tip is a hollow tip.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 26 wherein the tip is a non-hollow tip.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 26, wherein patterning a surface of a substrate is carried out at a relative humidity of at least about 40%.
</P>
<P>
32. A method of forming nanostructures or microstructures comprising the steps of: performing microcontact printing to pattern the surface of a substrate with a patterning composition comprising an oligomeric or polymeric compound; coating the non-patterned region the substrate surface with a passivating compound, wherein the patterning composition is physisorbed to the substrate surface; removing the patterning composition and provide exposed substrate; and etching the exposed substrate to form nanostructures or microstructures.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 32, wherein the patterning composition comprises a water soluble oligomeric or polymeric compound.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 32, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises a heteroatom in the backbone.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of claim 32, wherein the oligomeric or polymeric compound comprises an oxygen atom.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of claim 32, wherein the patterning composition comprises polyethyleneglycol (PEG) or polyethylene oxide (PEO).
</P>
<P>
37. A method comprising: disposing an ink composition on a tip, wherein the ink composition comprises poly( ethylene glycol) or poly( ethylene oxide), transferring the ink composition to a substrate surface to form a deposit, exposing the substrate to etching conditions.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of claim 37, wherein transferring is carried out by scanning probe contact printing or dip pen nanolithography.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008121137A2;WO2008121137A3;US2012141731A1;KR20090101943A;JP2010530126A;CA2671289A1;AU2007350336A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
