<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESSES FOR THE FLUX CALCINATION PRODUCTION OF TITANIUM DIOXIDE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2111370A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TORARDI CARMINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI, CARMINE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E. I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2111370
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070868040
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US26328
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060882338P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Processes for the production of rutile titanium dioxide from titanyl hydroxide using calcination with a flux are provided. Calcination in the presence of sodium chloride flux has been found to lower the calcination temperature used to produce the rutile form of titanium dioxide and to improve control of particle size.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS What is claimed:
</P>
<P>
1. A process for producing titanium dioxide comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) mixing sodium chloride with titanyl hydroxide and, optionally, one or more morphology control additives, to form a mixture;
</P>
<P>
b) heating the mixture to a target temperature of 800 to 1200 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C to form a mixture of titanium dioxide and sodium chloride; and
</P>
<P>
c) optionally, separating the sodium chloride from the titanium dioxide.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 wherein the heating is carried out over a time period of about 0.5 hours to about 48 hours.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture is held at the target temperature for up to 72 hours.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 1 wherein the amount of sodium chloride is from 1 wt% to 50 wt% based on the amount of titanium dioxide that can be recovered from the titanyl hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 1 wherein the amount of sodium chloride is from
</P>
<P>
1 wt% to 30 wt% based on the amount of titanium dioxide that can be recovered from the titanyl hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 1 wherein the amount of sodium chloride is from 1 wt% to 10 wt% based on the amount of titanium dioxide that can be recovered from the titanyl hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 1 wherein the sodium chloride is in solid form.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 1 wherein the sodium chloride is in solution.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixing comprises stirring, shaking, or tumbling for several minutes up to several days.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 1 wherein the morphology control additives contain ions selected from the group consisting of phosphate, potassium, sodium, and aluminum.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 1 wherein the titanyl hydroxide is produced from titanyl sulfate solution.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 1 wherein the titanyl hydroxide is produced from titanium oxychloride solution.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 1 wherein the titanyl hydroxide is produced from ammonium titanyl oxalate solution.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of claim 1 wherein the heating is performed in a rotary calciner.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 1 wherein the heating is performed in a static calciner.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 1 wherein the sodium chloride is separated from the titanium dioxide by water washing.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 1 wherein the sodium chloride is separated from the titanium dioxide by vacuum distillation.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of claim 1 wherein the titanium dioxide comprises the rutile form.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of claimi[delta] wherein the rutile titanium dioxide has a particle size of 50 to 1000 nm.
</P>
<P>
20. The process of claim 18 wherein the rutile titanium dioxide has a particle size of 50 to 500 nm.
</P>
<P>
21. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture is heated to a temperature of 800-1000 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
22. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture is heated to a temperature of 800-900 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
23. The process of claim 1 wherein the target temperature is reached within a time period of 0.5 to 48 hours.
</P>
<P>
24. The process of claim 1 wherein the target temperature is reached within a time period of 1 to 24 hours.
</P>
<P>
25. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture is held at the target temperature for up to 72 hours.
</P>
<P>
26. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture is held at the target temperature for up to 48 hours.
</P>
<P>
27. The process of claim 1 wherein the mixture is held at the target temperature for up to 24 hours.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008085475A1;US2010028252A1;MX2009007019A;JP2010514657A;CN101573297A;AU2007342420A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
