<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
A PROCESS FOR THE SYNTHESIS OF NANOTUBES AND FULLERENE- LIKE NANOSTRUCTURES OF TRANSITION METALS DICHALCOGENIDES, QUASI ONE- DIMENSIONAL STRUCTURES OF TRANSITION METALS AND OXIDES OF TRANSITION METALS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2132142A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MRZEL ALES [SI]
</Name>
<Name>
REMSKAR MAJA [SI]
</Name>
<Name>
JESIH ADOLF [SI]
</Name>
<Name>
VIRSEK MARKO [SI]
</Name>
<Name>
MRZEL, ALES
</Name>
<Name>
REMSKAR, MAJA
</Name>
<Name>
JESIH, ADOLF
</Name>
<Name>
VIRSEK, MARKO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
INST JOSEF STEFAN [SI]
</Name>
<Name>
INSTITUT &amp;#034
</Name>
<Name>
JOSEF STEFAN &amp;#034
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2132142
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080724390
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008SI00023
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
SI20070000081
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
SI20070000233
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B17/20
</Class>
<Class>
C01B19/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G33/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G35/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G39/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G39/06
</Class>
<Class>
C01G41/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B17/20
</Class>
<Class>
C01B19/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C01G33/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G35/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G39/06
</Class>
<Class>
C01G41/00
</Class>
<Class>
C30B25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/46
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/60B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The object of the invention is a process for the synthesis of nanotubes of transition metal dichalcogenides, of fullerene-like nanostructures of transition metal dichalcogenides, of nanotubes of transition metal dichalcogenides, filled with fullerene-like nanostructures of transition metal dichalcogenides, of quasi one- dimensional structures (nanowires, microwires and ribbons) of transition metal oxides and of quasi one-dimensional structures of transition metal dichalcogenides, consisting of fine crystallites of transition metal dichalcogenides. The process is characterized in that the synthesis occurs by the chemical transformation of quasi one-dimensional compounds with a sub-micron diameter, described by the formula M6CyH2, 8.2&amp;lt;y+z&amp;lt;10, where M is a transition metal (Mo, W, Ta, Nb), C is a chalcogen (S, Se, Te), H is a halogen (I).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. The process for the synthesis of nanotubes of transition metal dichalcogenides, of fullerene-like nanostructures of transition metal dichalcogenides, and of nanotubes of transition metal dichalcogenides, filled with fullerene-like nanostructures of transition metal dichalcogenides, characterized in that the synthesis occurs by the chemical transformation of quasi one-dimensional materials, consisting of nanowires with a diameter of under one micrometer, described by the formula M6CyHz, 8.2&amp;lt;y+z&amp;lt;10, where M is a transition metal (Mo, W, Ta, Nb), C is a chalcogen (S, Se, Te), H is a halogen (I).
</P>
<P>
2. The process according to claim 1 , characterized in that the chemical transformation of quasi one-dimensional materials, described by the formula M5CyH2, 8.2&amp;lt;y+z&amp;lt;=10, where M is a transition metal (Mo, W, Ta, Nb), C is a chalcogen (S, Se, Te), H is a halogen (I), is carried out in the presence of at least one reactive reagent, containing a chalcogen.
</P>
<P>
3. The process according to claim 1 , characterized in that the chemical transformation of quasi one-dimensional materials, described by the formula M[beta]CyHz, 8.2&amp;lt;y+z&amp;lt;=10, where M is a transition metal (Mo, W, Ta, Nb), C is a chalcogen (S, Se, Te), H is a halogen (I), is carried out under conditions in which the reactive reagent, containing a chalcogen, is in vapour phase.
</P>
<P>
4. The morphology of the material of transition metal dichalcogenides, obtained by the process according to claims 1 to 3, characterized in that fullerene-like nanostructures of transition metal dichalcogenides are inside nanotubes of transition metal dichalcogenides.
</P>
<P>
5. The process for the synthesis of quasi one-dimensional structures of metal oxides of transition metals and of quasi one-dimensional structures of transition metal dichalcogenides, consisting of fine crystallites of transition metal dichalcogenides, characterized in that the synthesis occurs by the chemical reaction of quasi one-dimensional materials, consisting of nanowires with a diameter of under one micrometer, described by the formula M6CyH2, 8.2&amp;lt;y+z&amp;lt;10, where M is a transition metal (Mo, W, Ta, Nb), C is a chalcogen (S, Se, Te), H is a halogen (I), whereby the said quasi one-dimensional material is first heated in the air or otherwise in the presence of oxygen, at an elevated temperature and is transformed into quasi one-dimensional metal oxides of transition metals; described by the formula MOx, 0.3&amp;lt;x&amp;lt;=3, where M is a transition metal (Mo, W, Ta, Nb), O is oxygen; which is followed by the chemical transformation of said quasi one-dimensional metal oxides in a quartz tube with a gas, containing an active reagent, which contains a chalcogen, whereby the process occurs at an elevated temperature.
</P>
<P>
6. The process according to claim 5, characterized in that the said quasi one- dimensional material is heated in the presence of oxygen at temperatures above 200 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and below 1800 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, preferably at temperatures above 300 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C and below 1800 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
7. The process according to claim 5, characterized in that the chemical transformation of quasi one-dimensional metal oxides into quasi one-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides occurs with a gas, containing an active reagent, which contains a chalcogen, whereby the gas preferably contains 98 volume percent of carrier gas, preferably of argon, preferably one volume percent of H2 and preferably one volume percent of H2S.
</P>
<P>
8. The process according to claim 5, characterized in that the said chemical transformation occurs at an elevated temperature under conditions, in which the active reagent, containing a chalcogen, is in vapour phase, preferably at temperatures above 300 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008121081A2;WO2008121081A3;US2010129285A1;US8007756B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
