<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
BLOCK FUNCTIONALIZATION METHODS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2125969A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SIMARD BENOIT [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
GUAN JINGWEN [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
DENOMMEE STEPHANE [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
SIMARD, BENOIT
</Name>
<Name>
GUAN, JINGWEN
</Name>
<Name>
DENOMMEE, STEPHANE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CANADA NAT RES COUNCIL [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
NATIONAL RESEARCH COUNCIL OF CANADA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2125969
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080714706
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-02-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008CA00386
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070903836P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C08F281/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F291/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F293/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F297/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F8/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08L63/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/44
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D6
</Class>
<Class>
C08F281/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F291/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F293/00B
</Class>
<Class>
C08F297/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F8/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/44
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Epoxy resins are chemically attached to carbon nanotubes (CNTs), in a one-step process in which a reaction mixture comprising the epoxy polymer, the CNTs and a bridging agent which is a chemical compound capable of forming living polymers, e.g. styrene or MMA is formed and radical formation is initiated in the reaction mixture;  the epoxy polymer or monomer grafts onto the CNTs through the intermediary block of the bridging agent.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1 A process of chemically attaching epoxy resin monomer or polymer to carbon nanotubes (CNTs) and adjusting the solubility and plasticity in one-step, which comprises: forming a reaction mixture comprising the epoxy polymer or monomer, the CNTs and a bridging agent which is a chemical compound capable of forming living polymers; and initiating radical formation in the reaction mixture; whereby the epoxy polymer or monomer grafts onto the CNTs through the intermediary block of the bridging agent.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 wherein the polymer or monomer is an epoxy resin.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 or claim 2 wherein initiation is induced radically, thermally, cationically or photolytically.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of any preceding claim wherein the bridging agent is an olefin, an olefin derivative, a lactone or a lactam.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 4 wherein the bridging agent is styrene.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 4 wherein the bridging agent is methyl methacrylate.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of any of claims 2 - 6 wherein from 1 to 10,000 units of bridging agent are interspersed between the CNT and the epoxy monomer or polymer, by controlling the concentration ratio of bridging agent to epoxy resin.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 7 wherein from 100 to 2000 units of bridging agent are so interspersed
</P>
<P>
9. The process of any preceding claim which is conducted in solution in an inert solvent.
</P>
<P>
10. A functionalized carbon nanotube composite corresponding to the general formula:
</P>
<P>
CNT - [Block l]-[Block 2] wherein CNT represents the carbon nanotube, &quot;Block 1&quot; represents at least 1 monomelic unit derived from an olefin, olefin derivative, lactone or lactam bridging agent, and &quot;Block 2&quot; represents an epoxy resin.
</P>
<P>
11. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10 wherein &quot;Block 1&quot; has from 1 to 10,000 monomelic units.
</P>
<P>
12. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10 wherein
</P>
<P>
&quot;Block 1&quot; has from 10 to 2,000 monomelic units.
</P>
<P>
13. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10, claim 11 or claim 12 wherein &quot;Block 1&quot; comprises polymerized styrene units.
</P>
<P>
14. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10, claim 11 or claim 12 wherein &quot;Block 1&quot; comprises polymerized methyl methacrylate units.
</P>
<P>
15. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of any of claims 10 - 14 wherein CNT is a single walled carbon nanotube. AMENDED CLAIMS received by the International Bureau on 30 July 2008 (30.07.08)
</P>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS;
</P>
<P>
1 A process of chemically attaching epoxy resin monomer or polymer to carbon nanotubes (CNTs) and adjusting the solubility and plasticity of the chemically attached CNT in 5 one reaction step, which comprises: forming a reaction mixture comprising the epoxy polymer or monomer, the CNTs and a bridging agent which is a chemical compound that forms living polymers; and initiating radical formation in the reaction mixture; whereby the epoxy polymer o[tau] monomer grafts onto the CNTs through the intermediary 10 block of the brid ging agent.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 wherein the polymer or monomer is an epoxy resin.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 or claim 2 wherein initiation is induced radically, \ 5 thermally, cationically or photolytically.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of any preceding claim wherein the bridging agent is an olefin, an olefin derivative, a lactone or a lactam.
</P>
<P>
20 5. The process of claim 4 wherein the bridging agent is styrene.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 4 wherein the bridging agent is methyl methacrylate.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of any of claims 2 - 6 wherein from 1 to 10,000 units of bridging 25 agent are interspersed between the CNT and the epoxy monomer or polymer, by controlling the concentration ratio of bridging agent to epoxy resin.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 7 wherein from 100 to 2000 units of bridging agent are so interspersed
</P>
<P>
30
</P>
<P>
9. The process of any preceding claim which is conducted in solution.
</P>
<P>
10. A functionalized carbon nanotube composite corresponding to the general foimula:
</P>
<P>
AMENDED SHEET (ARTICLE 19) CNT - [Block l]-[Block 2] wherein CNT represents the caibon nanotube, &quot;Block 1&quot; represents at least 1 monomeric unit derived from an olefin, olefin derivative, lactone or lactam bridging agent, and &quot;Block 2&quot; represents an cpoxy resin.
</P>
<P>
1 1 - The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10 wherein &quot;Block 1&quot; has from 1 to 10,000 monomeric units.
</P>
<P>
12. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10 wherein &quot;Block 1&quot; has from 10 to 2,000 monomeric units.
</P>
<P>
13. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10, claim 1 1 or claim 12 wherein &quot;Block 1 &quot; comprises polymerized styrene units.
</P>
<P>
14. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of claim 10, claim 11 or claim 12 wherein &quot;Block 1&quot; comprises polymerized methyl methacrylate units.
</P>
<P>
15. The functionalized carbon nanotube composite of any of claims 10 - 14 wherein CNT is a single walled carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
AMENDED SHEET (ARTICLE 19)
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2125969A4;WO2008104078A1;US2010069604A1;JP2010519062A;CA2679275A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
