<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SERS NANOTAG ASSAYS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2147295A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NATAN MICHAEL J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NATAN, MICHAEL J
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BECTON DICKINSON CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BECTON, DICKINSON AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2147295
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080826290
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US60871
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070912599P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C40B70/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/65
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C40B70/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/65D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering spectrum which is useful for certain types of assays, in particular proximity assays. The method includes providing two SERS-active nanoparticles. The first SERS-active nanoparticle will absorb a photon at a first wavelength and emit a Raman-shifted photon at a second wavelength. The second SERS-active nanoparticle will absorb a photon at the second wavelength and emit a Raman-shifted photon at a third wavelength. Accordingly, when the first and second SERS-active nanoparticles are proximate to one another and the first SERS-active nanoparticle is illuminated at the first wavelength a Raman-shifted photon at the second wavelength may be emitted. This photon can be absorbed by the second SERS-active nanoparticle causing detectable emission of a second Raman-shifted photon at the third wavelength.;  Various assays may be designed based upon the above. Proximity assays using two SERS-active nanoparticles will have advantageous background signal characteristics.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims:
</P>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum comprising: providing a first SERS active nanoparticle which, will absorb a photon at a first wavelength and emit a Raman shifted photon at a second wavelength; providing a second SERS active nanoparticle which will absorb a photon at the second wavelength and emit a Raman shifted photon at a third wavelength; bringing the first and second SERS active nanoparticles proximate to one another; and illuminating the first SERS active nanoparticle at the first wavelength causing the first SERS active nanoparticle to emit a Raman shifted photon at the second wavelength which is absorbed by the second SERS active nanoparticle causing emission of a second Raman shifted photon at the third, wavelength.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 1 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle and the second SERS active nanoparticle have different shapes.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 2 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle is spherical and the second SERS active nanoparticle is non-spherical.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 2 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle is solid and the second SERS active nanoparticle is hollow.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 2 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle is of uniform composition and the second SERS active nanoparticle has different compositions in a core and shell.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 2 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle comprises a single metal and the second SERS active nanoparticle comprises a mixture or alloy of two metals.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 6 wherein the second SERS active nanoparticle comprises a mixture or alloy of Au and Ag.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of producing a surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) spectrum of claim 1 wherein an absorbance maximum of the first SERS active nanoparticle is separated from an absorbance maximum of the second SERS active nanoparticle by between 200cm&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt; and 3500 cm&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
9. A proximity assay comprising: a first SERS active nanoparticle which will absorb a photon at a first wavelength and emit a Raman shifted photon at a second wavelength; a second SERS active nanoparticle which will absorb a photon at the second wavelength and emit a Raman shifted photon at a third wavelength; and a light source configured to emit light at the first wavelength; and a detector configured to detect light at the third wavelength.
</P>
<P>
10. The proximity assay of claim 9 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle and the second SERS active nanoparticle have different shapes.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The proximity assay of claim 10 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle is spherical and the second SERS active nanoparticle is non-spherical.
</P>
<P>
12. The proximity assay of claim 10 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle is solid and the second SERS active nanoparticle is hollow.
</P>
<P>
13. The proximity assay of claim 10 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle is of uniform composition and the second SERS active nanoparticle has different compositions in a core and shell.
</P>
<P>
14. The proximity assay of claim 10 wherein the first SERS active nanoparticle comprises a single metal and the second SERS active nanoparticle comprises a mixture or alloy of two metals.
</P>
<P>
15. The proximity assay of claim 14 wherein the second SERS active nanoparticle comprises a mixture or alloy of Au and Ag.
</P>
<P>
16. The proximity assay of claim 9 wherein an absorbance maximum of the first SERS active nanoparticle is separated from an absorbance maximum of the second. SERS active nanoparticle by between 200cm&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt; and 3500 cm&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
17. A method of detecting an analyte of interest comprising: associating the analyte of interest with a Raman reporter having a
</P>
<P>
SERS active vibrational peak at energy vl; illuminating the Raman reporter with light having a frequency of L; and detecting emitted light at a frequency of L-(2vl),
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2147295A4;WO2009009198A2;WO2009009198A3;US2010177306A1;JP2010525333A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
