<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
BORON NITRIDE FIBER PAPER AND METHOD FOR PRODUCING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2123828A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KUWAHARA HIROAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BANDO YOSHIO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHI CHUNYI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANG CHENGCHUN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
GOLBERG DMITRI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KUWAHARA, HIROAKI
</Name>
<Name>
BANDO, YOSHIO
</Name>
<Name>
ZHI, CHUNYI
</Name>
<Name>
TANG, CHENGCHUN
</Name>
<Name>
GOLBERG, DMITRI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TEIJIN LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAT INST FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TEIJIN LIMITED
</Name>
<Name>
NATIONAL INSTITUTE FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2123828
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080721663
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP54247
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070054089
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
D04H1/42
</Class>
<Class>
D21H13/46
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
D21H13/46
</Class>
<Class>
H05K1/03C4C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A boron nitride fiber paper having a very small fiber diameter and exhibiting excellent heat resistance, mechanical properties and heat conductivity. The fiber paper is composed of a fiber assembly which contains boron nitride fibers having a fiber diameter of not more than 1 [mu]m in an amount of not less than 40 wt%.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A fiber paper comprises a fiber assembly which contains boron nitride fibers having a fiber diameter of not more than 1 [micro]m in an amount of not less than 40 wt%.
</P>
<P>
2. The fiber paper according to claim 1, wherein the average fiber diameter of the fibers constituting the fiber assembly is 0.4 nm to 1 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
3. The fiber paper according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the average aspect ratio of the fibers constituting the fiber assembly is not less than 5.
</P>
<P>
4. The fiber paper according to claim 1, wherein the boron nitride fibers are boron nitride nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
5. The fiber paper according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the fiber assembly contains the boron nitride nanotubes in an amount of 1 to 100 wt%.
</P>
<P>
6. A process of manufacturing the fiber paper of claim 1, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
dispersing a fiber assembly which contains boron nitride fibers having a fiber diameter of not more than 1 [micro]m in an amount of not less than 40 wt% into a surfactant aqueous solution or an organic solvent; and
</P>
<P>
making paper from the obtained dispersion.
</P>
<P>
7. The process according to claim 6, wherein a surfactant aqueous solution or an organic solvent is used as a dispersion solvent.
</P>
<P>
8. The process according to claim 6, wherein the organic solvent is at least one selected from the group consisting of an alcohol, amine, organic carboxylic acid, organic carboxylate ester, organic acid amide, ketone, ether, sulfoxide, sulfone and sulfolane, each of them having 1 to 10 carbon atoms.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010108276A1;US8025766B2;TW200912088A;KR20090127399A;WO2008108484A1;CN101627161A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
