<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD OF PRODUCING MICROCHANNEL AND NANOCHANNEL ARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2125643A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
D URSO BRIAN R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
D&apos;URSO, BRIAN, R
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UT BATTELLE LLC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UT-BATTELLE, LLC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2125643
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080732206
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US56978
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070687201
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C03B23/207
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
C03B37/012B
</Class>
<Class>
C03B37/028
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/02P6C2A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of making an article having channels therethrough includes the steps of: providing a ductile structure defining at least one macro-channel, the macro-channel containing a salt;  drawing the ductile structure in the axial direction of the at least one macro-channel to reduce diameter of the macro-channel;  and contacting the salt with a solvent to dissolve the salt to produce an article having at least one microchannel.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of making an article having channels therethrough comprising:
</P>
<P>
a. providing a ductile structure defining at least one macro-channel, said macro-channel containing a salt;
</P>
<P>
b. drawing said ductile structure in the axial direction of said at least one macro-channel to reduce diameter of said macro-channel; and
</P>
<P>
c. contacting said salt with a solvent to dissolve said salt to produce an article having at least one microchannel.
</P>
<P>
2. A method in accordance with claim 1 wherein said ductile structure comprises a glass composition.
</P>
<P>
3. A method in accordance with claim 1 wherein said salt is characterized by a melting temperature that is lower than a drawing temperature of said ductile structure.
</P>
<P>
4. A method in accordance with claim 1 wherein said salt is characterized by a melting temperature that is higher than a fusing temperature of said ductile structure.
</P>
<P>
5. A method of making an article having microchannels therethrough comprising:
</P>
<P>
a. providing a ductile structure defining at least one macro-channel therethrough;
</P>
<P>
b. depositing a salt composition into said at least one macro-channel;
</P>
<P>
c. heating said ductile structure to a sufficient temperature so that said ductile structure can be drawn and so that said salt melts;
</P>
<P>
d. drawing said ductile structure so that the diameters of said at least one macro-channel is reduced;
</P>
<P>
e. cooling said drawn ductile structure; and
</P>
<P>
f. contacting said salt with a solvent to dissolve said salt to produce an article having at least one microchannel.
</P>
<P>
6. A method in accordance with claim 5 wherein said ductile structure comprises a glass composition.
</P>
<P>
7. A method in accordance with claim 5 wherein said salt is characterized by a melting temperature that is lower than a drawing temperature of said ductile structure.
</P>
<P>
8. A method in accordance with claim 5 wherein said salt is characterized by a melting temperature that is higher than a fusing temperature of said ductile structure.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2125643B1;US2008223080A1;US7707854B2;WO2008115781A2;WO2008115781A3;KR20100015329A;JP2010521407A;CA2681223A1;CA2681223C;AT514658T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
