<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
DETECTION OF ANALYTES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2122350A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GABBAI ERAN [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
GABBAI, ERAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DO COOP TECHNOLOGIES LTD [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
DO-COOP TECHNOLOGIES LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2122350
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080702612
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008IL00024
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070878388P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-04
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C12M1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12M1/34
</Class>
<Class>
C12M3/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/53
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/544
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/551
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/553
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58J
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A kit and article of manufacture for detecting an analyte is disclosed. The kit comprises: (i) a detectable agent;  and (ii) a liquid composition having a liquid and nanostructures, each of the nanostructures comprising a core material of a nanometric size surrounded by an envelope of ordered fluid molecules, the core material and the envelope of ordered fluid molecules being in a steady physical state.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A kit for detecting an analyte comprising: (i) a detectable agent; and
</P>
<P>
(ii) a liquid composition having a liquid and nanostructures, each of said nanostructures comprising a core material of a nanometric size surrounded by an envelope of ordered fluid molecules, said core material and said envelope of ordered fluid molecules being in a steady physical state.
</P>
<P>
2. The kit of claim 1 , wherein the analyte is a biomolecule.
</P>
<P>
3. The kit of claim 2, wherein said biomolecule is selected from the group consisting of a polypeptide, a polynucleotide, a carbohydrate, a lipid and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. The kit of claim 1, wherein said detectable agent is non-directly detectable.
</P>
<P>
5. The kit of claim 4, wherein said non-directly detectable agent is a substrate for an enzymatic reaction capable of generating a detectable product.
</P>
<P>
6. The kit of claim 1, wherein said detectable agent is directly detectable.
</P>
<P>
7. The kit of claim 1, wherein said detectable agent comprise an affinity recognition moiety.
</P>
<P>
8. The kit of claim 7, wherein said affinity recognition moiety is selected from the group consisting of an avidin derivative, a polynucleotide and an antibody.
</P>
<P>
9. The kit of claim 6, wherein said directly detectable agent is selected from the group consisting of a phosphorescent agent, a chemiluminescent agent and a fluorescent agent.
</P>
<P>
10. The kit of claim 5, further comprising an enhancer of said enzymatic reaction.
</P>
<P>
11. The kit of claim 10, wherein said enhancer is selected from the group consisting of p-iodophenol, 3,4-dichlorophenol, p-hydroxycinnamic acid, 1,2,4- triazole, 3,3&apos;, 5,5&apos;-tetramethyl- benzidine, phenol, 2-naphthol, 10-methylphenothiazine, cetyltrimethyl ammonium bromide, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The kit of claim 5, further comprising an oxidizing agent.
</P>
<P>
13. The kit of claim 12, wherein said oxidizing agent is selected from the group consisting of hydrogen peroxide, urea hydrogen peroxide, sodium carbonate hydrogen peroxide, a perborate salt, potassium ferricyanide and Nitro blue tetrazolium (NBT).
</P>
<P>
14. The kit of claim 5, further comprising an enzyme for said enzymatic reaction.
</P>
<P>
15. The kit of claim 14, wherein said enzyme is selected from the group consisting of alkaline phosphatase, [beta]-galactosidase, horseradish peroxidase (HRP), chloramphenicol acetyl transferase, luciferase and [beta]-glucuronidase.
</P>
<P>
16. The kit of claim 14, wherein said enzyme is conjugated to an antibody or an avidin derivative.
</P>
<P>
17. The kit of claim 5, further comprising an inhibitor of said enzymatic reaction.
</P>
<P>
18. The kit of claim 5, wherein said detectable product is selected from the group consisting of a fluorescent product, a chemiluminescent product, a phosphorescent product and a chromogenic product.
</P>
<P>
19. The kit of claim 18, wherein a substrate capable of generating said fluorescent product comprises a fluorophore.
</P>
<P>
20. The kit of claim 19, wherein said fluorophore is derived from a molecule selected from the group consisting of coumarin, fluorescein, rhodamine, resorufin and DDAO.
</P>
<P>
21. The kit of claim 18, wherein a substrate capable of generating said fluorescent product is selected from the group consisting of fluorescein di-[beta]-D- galactopyranoside (FDG), resorufin [beta]-D-galactopyranoside, DDAO galactoside, [beta]- methylumbelliferyl [beta]-D-galactopyranoside, 6,8-Difluoro-4-methylumbelliferyl [beta]-D- galactopyranoside, 3-carboxyumbelliferyl-[beta]-D-galactopyranoside, ELF 97 phosphate, 5-chloromethylfluorescein di-[beta]-D-galactopyranoside (CMFDG), 4- methylumbelliferyl-[beta]-D-glucuronide, Fluorescein di-[beta]-D-glucuronide, PFB Aminofluorescein Diglucuronide, ELF 97-[beta]-D-glucuronide, BODIPY FL chloramphenicol substrate(TM), and 10-acetyl-3,7-dihydroxyphenoxazine.
</P>
<P>
22. The kit of claim 18, wherein a substrate capable of generating said chromogenic product is selected from the group consisting of BCIP, 5-bromo-4- chloro-3-indolyl-[beta]-D-glucuronic acid (X-GIcU) and 5-bromo-6-chloro-3-indolyl -[beta]-D- glucuronide, 5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl -[beta]-D-galactopyranoside (X-GaI), diaminobenzidine (DAB), Tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) and o-Phenylenediamine (OPD).
</P>
<P>
23. The kit of claim 18, wherein a substrate capable of generating said chemiluminescent product is selected from the group consisting of luciferin, luminol, isoluminol, acridane, phenyl- lO-methylacridane-9-carboxylate, 2,4,6-trichlorophenyl- 1- O-methylacridane-9-carboxylate, pyrogallol, phloroglucinol and resorcinol.
</P>
<P>
24. The kit of claim 1, wherein at least a portion of said fluid molecules are identical to molecule of said liquid.
</P>
<P>
25. The kit of claim 1, wherein said at least a portion of said fluid molecules are in a gaseous state.
</P>
<P>
26. The kit of claim 1, wherein a concentration of said nanostructures is lower than 10&amp;lt;20&amp;gt; nanostructures per liter.
</P>
<P>
27. The kit of claim 1, wherein said nanostructures are capable of forming clusters of said nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
28. The kit of claim 1, wherein said nanostructures are capable of maintaining long range interaction thereamongst.
</P>
<P>
29. The kit of claim 1, wherein said liquid composition comprises a buffering capacity greater than a buffering capacity of water.
</P>
<P>
30. The kit of claim 1, wherein said liquid composition is formulated from hydroxyapatite.
</P>
<P>
31. An article of manufacture comprising packaging material and a liquid composition identified for enhancing detection of a detectable moiety being contained within said packaging material, said liquid composition having a liquid and nanostructures, each of said nanostructures comprising a core material of a nanometric size surrounded by an envelope of ordered fluid molecules, said core material and said envelope of ordered fluid molecules being in a steady physical state.
</P>
<P>
32. The article of manufacture of claim 31, wherein said detectable moiety is selected from the group consisting of a fluorescent moiety, a chemiluminescent moiety and a phosphorescent moiety.
</P>
<P>
33. The article of manufacture of claim 31, wherein at least a portion of said fluid molecules are identical to molecule of said liquid.
</P>
<P>
34. The article of manufacture of claim 31, wherein said at least a portion of said fluid molecules are in a gaseous state.
</P>
<P>
35. The article of manufacture of claim 31, wherein a concentration of said nanostructures is lower than 10&amp;lt;20&amp;gt; nanostructures per liter.
</P>
<P>
36. The article of manufacture of claim 31 , wherein said nanostructures are capable of forming clusters of said nanostructures.
</P>
<P>
37. The article of manufacture of claim 31 , wherein said nanostructures are capable of maintaining long range interaction thereamongst.
</P>
<P>
38. The article of manufacture of claim 31, wherein said liquid composition comprises a buffering capacity greater than a buffering capacity of water.
</P>
<P>
39. The article of manufacture of claim 31 , wherein said nanostructures are formulated from hydroxyapatite.
</P>
<P>
40. A method of dissolving or dispersing cephalosporin comprising contacting the cephalosporin with nanostructures and liquid under conditions which allow dispersion or dissolving of the substance, wherein said nanostructures comprise a core material of a nanometric size enveloped by ordered fluid molecules of said liquid, said core material and said envelope of ordered fluid molecules being in a steady physical state.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2122350A4;WO2008081455A2;WO2008081455A3;ZA200904558A;US2010086929A1;KR20090095674A;JP2010528256A;CA2674118A1;AU2008203627A1;AU2008203627A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
