<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PHOTODIODE, OPTICAL COMMUNICATION DEVICE, AND OPTICAL INTERCONNECTION MODULE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2110864A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FUJIKATA JUNICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKAMOTO DAISUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MAKITA KIKUO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NISHI KENICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHASHI KEISHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUJIKATA, JUNICHI
</Name>
<Name>
OKAMOTO, DAISUKE
</Name>
<Name>
MAKITA, KIKUO
</Name>
<Name>
NISHI, KENICHI
</Name>
<Name>
OHASHI, KEISHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NEC CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NEC CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2110864
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070832626
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP72904
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060342336
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G02B6/122
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0224
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/105
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/108
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/122S
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/105
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/108B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Intended is to provide a device structure, which makes the light receiving sensitivity and the high speediness of a photodiode compatible. Also provided is a Schottky barrier type photodiode having a conductive layer formed on the surface of a semiconductor layer. The photodiode is so constituted that a light can be incident on the back side of the semiconductor layer, and that a periodic structure, in which a light incident from the back side of the semiconductor layer causes a surface plasmon resonance, is made around the Schottky junction of the photodiode.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A Schottky barrier type photodiode having a conductive layer formed on a surface of a semiconductor layer, said photodiode configured so that light can be incident on a back side of said semiconductor layer, wherein a periodic structure in which the light incident from the back side of said semiconductor layer causes a surface plasmon resonance is made around a Schottky junction of said photodiode.
</P>
<P>
2. A p-i-n type photodiode having a p-i-n type junction formed on a surface of a semiconductor layer, said photodiode configured so that light can be incident on a back side of said semiconductor layer, wherein a conductive layer is formed, and a periodic structure in which the light incident from the back side of said semiconductor layer causes a surface plasmon resonance is made around the p-i-n junction of said photodiode.
</P>
<P>
3. A photodiode having metal-semiconductor-metal junctions intervally arranged on a surface of a semiconductor layer, said photodiode configured so that light can be incident on a back side of said semiconductor layer, wherein a conductive layer is formed, and a periodic structure in which the light incident from the back side of said semiconductor layer causes a surface plasmon resonance is made around the metal-semiconductor-metal junction of said photodiode.
</P>
<P>
4. The photodiode as claimed in Claim 3;
</P>
<P>
wherein an interval of the metal-semiconductor-metal junctions arranged on the surface of the semiconductor layer is equal to or less than [lambda]/n (where [lambda]: a wavelength of the light incident from the back side of the semiconductor layer, and n: a refractive index of the light in the semiconductor layer); and
</P>
<P>
wherein said metal layer is a layer in which a metal layer forming a Schottky junction with said semiconductor, and a layer comprised of a conductive material capable of inducing a surface plasmon have been laminated, or a metal layer capable of forming the Schottky junction with said semiconductor, and yet of inducing the surface plasmon.
</P>
<P>
5. The photodiode as claimed in Claim 3 or Claim 4,
</P>
<P>
wherein, with respect to the metal-semiconductor-metal junction, at least one of metal-semiconductor junctions facing each other is a Schottky barrier junction.
</P>
<P>
6. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 5,
</P>
<P>
wherein the periodic structure for causing the surface plasmon resonance is a structure in which the conductive layers capable of inducing the surface plasmon have been laminated on the surface of the semiconductor layer having roughness formed thereon.
</P>
<P>
7. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 6,
</P>
<P>
wherein the periodic structure for causing the surface plasmon resonance is a structure in which the conductive layers capable of inducing the surface plasmon have been laminated on the surface of a dielectric layer having roughness formed thereon.
</P>
<P>
8. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 7,
</P>
<P>
wherein the periodic structure for preventing the surface plasmon resonance from being generated is made outside the periodic structure for causing the surface plasmon resonance.
</P>
<P>
9. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 8,
</P>
<P>
wherein a stepped structure for reflecting the surface plasmon is made outside the periodic structure for causing the surface plasmon resonance.
</P>
<P>
10. The photodiode as claimed in Claim 9, wherein the stepped structure is comprised of a projected shape higher than [lambda]/nd (where nd is a refractive index of the light in the semiconductor layer or the dielectric layer neighboring a conductive film and [lambda] is a wavelength of the light).
</P>
<P>
11. The photodiode as claimed in Claim 9 or Claim 10,
</P>
<P>
wherein the stepped structure is comprised of a grooved shape deeper than [lambda]/nd (where nd is a refractive index of the light in the semiconductor layer or the dielectric layer neighboring the conductive film and [lambda] is a wavelength of the light).
</P>
<P>
12. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 9 to Claim 11, wherein the stepped structure is comprised of a shape formed in the conductive material, said shape having bores of which a diameter is equal to or smaller than the wavelength of the incident light arrayed thereon.
</P>
<P>
13. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 9 to Claim 12, wherein the stepped structure is comprised of a shape formed in the conductive material, said shape having slits of which a width is equal to or smaller than the wavelength of the incident light arrayed thereon.
</P>
<P>
14. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 9 to Claim 13, wherein the conductive layer is configured of at least one metal selected from a group consisting of Al, Ag, Au and, Cu, or an alloy thereof.
</P>
<P>
15. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 14, wherein a junction area in the photodiode is 100 square microns or less.
</P>
<P>
16. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 14, wherein a junction area in the photodiode is 10 square microns or less.
</P>
<P>
17. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 14, wherein a junction area in the photodiode is one square micron or less.
</P>
<P>
18. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 17, wherein a thickness of the semiconductor absorption layer in the photodiode is 1 [micro]m or less.
</P>
<P>
19. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 17, wherein a thickness of the semiconductor absorption layer in the photodiode is 200 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
20. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 19, wherein the semiconductor absorption layer in the photodiode is configured of at least one member selected from a group consisting of Si, SixGel-x (where x is a positive number less than 1), Ge, GaN, GaAs, GaInAs, GaInP, and InP.
</P>
<P>
21. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 20:
</P>
<P>
wherein the semiconductor absorption layer in the photodiode is configured of at least one member selected from a group consisting of Ge, and SixGel-x (where x is a positive number less than 1); and
</P>
<P>
wherein a layer comprised of an alloy of Ni and Ge is formed between said semiconductor absorption layer and the conductive layer.
</P>
<P>
22. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 21, said photodiode configured on an optical waveguide comprised of the semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
23. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 21, said photodiode configured so that it can receives the light from the optical waveguide formed on a substrate side, said light reflected by a mirror.
</P>
<P>
24. The photodiode as claimed in one of Claim 1 to Claim 23, wherein a substrate of the photodiode is configured of a material transparent to the incident light.
</P>
<P>
25. An optical communication device, wherein any of the photodiodes of Claim 1 to Claim 24 is formed on a light receiving portion.
</P>
<P>
26. An optical interconnection module, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a Si substrate having any of the photodiodes of Claim 1 to Claim 24 configured thereon; and
</P>
<P>
an LSI electronic circuit formed monolithically with said photodiode on said Si substrate.
</P>
<P>
Amended claims under Art. 19.1 PCT
</P>
<P>
1. (Amended) A Schottky barrier type photodiode having a conductive layer formed on a surface of a semiconductor layer:
</P>
<P>
wherein a periodic structure for causing a surface plasmon resonance is formed adjacently to said conductive layer in a circumference of a Schottky junction of said photodiode;
</P>
<P>
wherein said semiconductor layer is formed on a surface in which said periodic structure of said conductive layer has been formed;
</P>
<P>
wherein a dielectric layer of which a refractive index is lower than that of said semiconductor layer is formed around said semiconductor layer; and
</P>
<P>
wherein said photodiode is configured so that light can be incident on a surface in which said periodic structure has been made.
</P>
<P>
2. (Amended) A p-i-n type photodiode having a p-i-n type junction formed on a surface of a semiconductor layer:
</P>
<P>
wherein a conductive layer is formed and a periodic structure for causing a surface plasmon resonance is formed adjacently to said conductive layer in a circumference of the p-i-n junction of said photodiode;
</P>
<P>
wherein said semiconductor layer is formed on a surface in which said periodic structure of said conductive layer has been formed;
</P>
<P>
wherein a dielectric layer of which a refractive index is lower than that of said semiconductor layer is formed around said semiconductor layer; and
</P>
<P>
wherein said photodiode is configured so that light can be incident on a surface in which said periodic structure has been made.
</P>
<P>
3. (Amended) A photodiode having metal-semiconductor-metal junctions intervally arranged on a surface of a semiconductor layer:
</P>
<P>
wherein a conductive layer is formed and a periodic structure for causing a surface plasmon resonance is formed adjacently to said conductive layer in a circumference of the metal-semiconductor-metal junction of said photodiode;
</P>
<P>
wherein said semiconductor layer is formed on a surface in which said periodic structure of said conductive layer has been formed;
</P>
<P>
wherein a dielectric layer of which a refractive index is lower than that of said semiconductor layer is formed around said semiconductor layer; and
</P>
<P>
wherein said photodiode is configured so that light can be incident on a surface in which said periodic structure has been made.
</P>
<P>
4. The photodiode as claimed in Claim 3;
</P>
<P>
wherein an interval of the metal-semiconductor-metal junctions arranged on the surface of the semiconductor layer is equal to or less than [lambda]/n (where [lambda]: a wavelength of the light incident from the back side of the semiconductor layer, and n: a refractive index of the light in the semiconductor layer); and
</P>
<P>
wherein said metal layer is a layer in which a metal layer forming a Schottky junction with said semiconductor, and a layer comprised of a conductive material capable of inducing a surface plasmon have been laminated, or a metal layer capable of forming the Schottky junction with said semiconductor, and yet of inducing the surface plasmon.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2110864A4;US2010200941A1;WO2008075542A1;CN101563790A;CN101563790B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
