<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SPHERICAL FERRITE NANOPARTICLE AND METHOD FOR PRODUCTION THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2128095A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ABE MASANORI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA HIROSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAGAWA TAKASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TADA MASARU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMAZU RYUICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA TOSHIYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ABE, MASANORI
</Name>
<Name>
HANDA, HIROSHI
</Name>
<Name>
NAKAGAWA, TAKASHI
</Name>
<Name>
TADA, MASARU
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMAZU, RYUICHI
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA, TOSHIYUKI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOKYO INST TECH [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TAMAGAWA SEIKI CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TOKYO INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
<Name>
TAMAGAWA SEIKI KABUSHIKI KAISHA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2128095
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070860449
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP75246
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070000649
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61J3/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K41/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/02
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/04
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/32
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/34
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/50
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K41/00U
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48W8B
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18R6
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/50T
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51H2
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51P
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00C
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00C2
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00E10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for producing spherical ferrite nanoparticles includes the steps of: preparing a first aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions;  and conducting particle growth in the first aqueous solution to produce the spherical ferrite nanoparticles.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for producing spherical ferrite nanoparticles, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
preparing a first aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions; and
</P>
<P>
conducting particle growth in the first aqueous solution to produce the spherical ferrite nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
2. The method as set forth in claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first aqueous solution is prepared by adding the seed particles and the divalent iron ions into a second aqueous solution containing the disaccharide, the alkaline and the oxidation agent.
</P>
<P>
3. The method as set forth in claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first aqueous solution is prepared by adding the alkaline and the seed particles into a third aqueous solution containing the divalent iron ions and the disaccharide to form a fourth aqueous solution and adding the oxidation agent into the fourth aqueous solution.
</P>
<P>
4. The method as set forth in claim 1, further comprising,
</P>
<P>
the step of adding trivalent iron ions into the first aqueous solution.
</P>
<P>
5. The method as set forth in claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein a concentration of the disaccharide in the first aqueous solution is set within a range of 0.1M to 5M; and
</P>
<P>
wherein a ratio of a concentration of the divalent iron ions to the concentration of the disaccharide is set within a range of 0.002 to 50.
</P>
<P>
6. The method as set forth in claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the oxidation agent is at least one selected from the group consisting of a nitric acid, a nitrous acid, a nitrate and a nitrite.
</P>
<P>
7. Spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in a first aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions.
</P>
<P>
8. The spherical ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 7,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first aqueous solution is prepared by adding the seed particles and the divalent iron ions into a second aqueous solution containing the disaccharide, the alkaline and the oxidation agent.
</P>
<P>
9. The spherical ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 7,
</P>
<P>
wherein the first aqueous solution is prepared by adding the alkaline and the seed particles into a third aqueous solution containing the divalent iron ions and the disaccharide to form a fourth aqueous solution and adding the oxidation agent into the fourth aqueous solution.
</P>
<P>
10. The spherical ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 7, comprising,
</P>
<P>
a number-averaged particle size within a range of 30 nm to 250 nm,
</P>
<P>
wherein a ratio of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles falling within a range of +-40% for the number-averaged particle size are 95% or more for all of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
11. Surface-modified ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions; and
</P>
<P>
at least one surface modification agent selected from the group consisting of a surface-active agent, a hydroxyl acid and a sugar alcohol, the at least one surface modification agent modifying surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
12. Composite ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions; and
</P>
<P>
at least one surface covering agent selected from the group consisting of a polystyrene, a polyethylene, a polyacrylic acid ester, a polymethacrylic acid ester, a polyethylene glycol (PEG), a polyglycidyl methacrylate, a silica, and silane coupling agent; the at least one surface covering agent covering surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
13. Composite ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions;
</P>
<P>
at least one surface modification agent selected from the group consisting of a surface-active agent, a hydroxyl acid and a sugar alcohol, the at least one surface modification agent modifying surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles; and
</P>
<P>
at least one surface covering agent selected from the group consisting of a polystyrene, a polyethylene, a polyacrylic acid ester, a polymethacrylic acid ester, a polyethylene glycol (PEG), a polyglycidyl methacrylate, a silica, and a silane coupling agent; the at least one surface covering agent covering modified surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles by the at least one surface modification agent.
</P>
<P>
14. Functional ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions;
</P>
<P>
linker molecules coupled with surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles; and
</P>
<P>
probe molecules coupled with the linker molecules and capable of being specifically coupled with a substance to be examined.
</P>
<P>
15. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles functions as a test regent for recognizing, analyzing or screening at least one selected from the group consisting of a medical agent, an antigenic agent, an antibody, a receptor, a hapten, an enzyme, a protein, a nucleic acid, a hormone, a saccharide, a pathogen and a toxin.
</P>
<P>
16. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for detecting at least one selected from the group consisting of a diagnostic agent, a cell marking agent, an enzyme-immobilizing agent and a protein-refining agent.
</P>
<P>
17. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one selected from the group consisting of a magnetic hyperthermia heating element, an MRI contrast medium and a medical agent transferring carrier.
</P>
<P>
18. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for a diagnostic method to detect a magnetization by a magnetic detector.
</P>
<P>
19. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for chromatography.
</P>
<P>
20. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for at least one selected from the group consisting of soil improvement, water purification and air purification.
</P>
<P>
21. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 14,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one of an absorbing agent and a sensor.
</P>
<P>
22. Functional ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
surface-modified ferrite nanoparticles including spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions, and at least one surface modification agent selected from the group consisting of a surface-active agent, a hydroxyl acid and a sugar alcohol, the at least one surface modification agent modifying surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles;
</P>
<P>
linker molecules coupled with surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles; and
</P>
<P>
probe molecules coupled with the linker molecules and capable of being specifically coupled with a substance to be examined.
</P>
<P>
23. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles functions as a test regent for recognizing, analyzing or screening at least one selected from the group consisting of a medical agent, an antigenic agent, an antibody, a receptor, a hapten, an enzyme, a protein, a nucleic acid, a hormone, a saccharide, a pathogen and a toxin.
</P>
<P>
24. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for detecting at least one selected from the group consisting of a diagnostic agent, a cell marking agent, an enzyme-immobilizing agent and a protein-refining agent.
</P>
<P>
25. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one selected from the group consisting of a magnetic hyperthermia heating element, an MRI contrast medium and a medical agent transferring carrier.
</P>
<P>
26. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for a diagnostic method to detect a magnetization by a magnetic detector.
</P>
<P>
27. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forthin claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for chromatography.
</P>
<P>
28. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forthin claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for at least one selected from the group consisting of soil improvement, water purification and air purification.
</P>
<P>
29. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 22,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one of an absorbing agent and a sensor.
</P>
<P>
30. Functional ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
composite ferrite nanoparticles including spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions, and at least one surface covering agent selected from the group consisting of a polystyrene, a polyethylene, a polyacrylic acid ester, a polymethacrylic acid ester, a polyethylene glycol (PEG), a polyglycidyl methacrylate, a silica, and silane coupling agent, the at least one surface covering agent covering surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticlessurface-modified ferrite nanoparticles including spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions, and at least one surface modification agent selected from the group consisting of a surface-active agent, a hydroxyl acid and a sugar alcohol, the at least one surface modification agent modifying surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles;
</P>
<P>
linker molecules coupled with surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles; and
</P>
<P>
probe molecules coupled with the linker molecules and capable of being specifically coupled with a substance to be examined.
</P>
<P>
31. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles functions as a test regent for recognizing, analyzing or screening at least one selected from the group consisting of a medical agent, an antigenic agent, an antibody, a receptor, a hapten, an enzyme, a protein, a nucleic acid, a hormone, a saccharide, a pathogen and a toxin.
</P>
<P>
32. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for detecting at least one selected from the group consisting of a diagnostic agent, a cell marking agent, an enzyme-immobilizing agent and a protein-refining agent.
</P>
<P>
33. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one selected from the group consisting of a magnetic hyperthermia heating element, an MRI contrast medium and a medical agent transferring carrier.
</P>
<P>
34. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for a diagnostic method to detect a magnetization by a magnetic detector.
</P>
<P>
35. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forthin claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for chromatography.
</P>
<P>
36. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forthin claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for at least one selected from the group consisting of soil improvement, water purification and air purification.
</P>
<P>
37. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 30,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one of an absorbing agent and a sensor.
</P>
<P>
38. Functional ferrite nanoparticles, comprising:
</P>
<P>
composite ferrite nanoparticles including spherical ferrite nanoparticles produced through a particle growth in an aqueous solution containing a disaccharide, an alkaline, an oxidation agent, seed particles and divalent iron ions, at least one surface modification agent selected from the group consisting of a surface-active agent, a hydroxyl acid and a sugar alcohol, the at least one surface modification agent modifying surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles, and at least one surface covering agent selected from the group consisting of a polystyrene, a polyethylene, a polyacrylic acid ester, a polymethacrylic acid ester, a polyethylene glycol (PEG), a polyglycidyl methacrylate, a silica, and a silane coupling agent, the at least one surface covering agent covering modified surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles by the at least one surface modification agent;
</P>
<P>
linker molecules coupled with surfaces of the spherical ferrite nanoparticles; and
</P>
<P>
probe molecules coupled with the linker molecules and capable of being specifically coupled with a substance to be examined.
</P>
<P>
39. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles functions as a test regent for recognizing, analyzing or screening at least one selected from the group consisting of a medical agent, an antigenic agent, an antibody, a receptor, a hapten, an enzyme, a protein, a nucleic acid, a hormone, a saccharide, a pathogen and a toxin.
</P>
<P>
40. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for detecting at least one selected from the group consisting of a diagnostic agent, a cell marking agent, an enzyme-immobilizing agent and a protein-refining agent.
</P>
<P>
41. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one selected from the group consisting of a magnetic hyperthermia heating element, an MRI contrast medium and a medical agent transferring carrier.
</P>
<P>
42. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for a diagnostic method to detect a magnetization by a magnetic detector.
</P>
<P>
43. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for chromatography.
</P>
<P>
44. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forthin claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed for at least one selected from the group consisting of soil improvement, water purification and air purification.
</P>
<P>
45. The functional ferrite nanoparticles as set forth in claim 38,
</P>
<P>
wherein the functional ferrite nanoparticles are employed as at least one of an absorbing agent and a sensor.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2128095A4;US2010040553A1;JP2008201666A;WO2008081917A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
