<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
OPTOFLUIDIC MICROSCOPE DEVICE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2135058A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YANG CHANGHUEI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PSALTIS DEMETRI [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
YANG, CHANGHUEI
</Name>
<Name>
PSALTIS, DEMETRI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CALIFORNIA INST OF TECHN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CALIFORNIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2135058
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080730664
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-02-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US54908
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070686095
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B32B27/04
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/64P4C
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An optofluidic microscope device is disclosed. The device includes a fluid channel having a surface and an object such as a bacterium or virus may flow through the fluid channel. Light transmissive regions of different sizes may be used to image the object.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. An optofluidic microscope device comprising: a body comprising a fluid channel having a surface; light transmissive regions in the body, wherein the light transmissive regions have different dimensions; an illumination source adapted to provide illumination through the light transmissive regions; and an optical detector adapted to receive light from the illumination source through the light transmissive regions.
</P>
<P>
2. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the surface is the bottom of a fluid channel.
</P>
<P>
3. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the light transmissive regions are holes, and wherein the different dimensions are different diameters.
</P>
<P>
4. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the optical detector comprises a charge coupled device.
</P>
<P>
5. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the optical detector includes a plurality of discrete light detecting elements, wherein the light detecting elements respectively correspond to the light transmissive regions.
</P>
<P>
6. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the fluid channel has a bottom with a width of less than about 1 micron.
</P>
<P>
7. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the light transmissive regions comprise an optically transparent material.
</P>
<P>
8. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the array of holes extends from a first side of the surface to a second side of the surface.
</P>
<P>
9. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the array of light transmissive regions is a first array of light transmissive regions and the optical device comprises a second array of light transmissive regions, wherein the second array of light transmissive regions form a reference point.
</P>
<P>
10. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the surface is part of a bottom wall, and wherein optical detector is attached to the bottom wall.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the array of light transmissive regions forms a slanted line.
</P>
<P>
12. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein illumination source provides white light.
</P>
<P>
13. The optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 wherein the body comprises a polymeric material.
</P>
<P>
14. A method of using the optofluidic microscope device of claim 1 , wherein the method comprises: flowing a fluid comprising an object through the fluid channel.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14 wherein the light transmissive regions have circular radial cross-sections.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 15 wherein the light transmissive regions comprise holes.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 15 wherein the light transmissive regions are holes with a high index of refraction material in the holes.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 14 wherein the object is a cell.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 14 further comprising: detecting a transmission spectrum using the light passing through the light transmissive regions.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19 further comprising: determining a shape of the object using the transmission spectrum.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2135058A4;WO2008112416A2;WO2008112416A3;US2010296094A1;US2007207061A1;US7751048B2;JP2010521671A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
