<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PIEZOELECTRIC SLIP- STICK DRIVE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2162929A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
RYCHEN JOERG [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
RYCHEN, JOERG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SPECS ZURICH GMBH [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
SPECS ZURICH GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2162929
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070720178
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-06-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007CH00281
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L41/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q10/02
</Class>
<Class>
H02N2/06D2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The driver (10) for a piezoelectric slip-stick drive charges a capacitor (15) while applying a ramp voltage to a piezoelectric actuator (11) in such a manner that the charges on the capacitor (15) and the actuator (11) are equal but of opposite sign. At the end of the ramp, a switch (14) is used to connect the actuator (11) to the capacitor (15), which leads to a fast discharge.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. [Alpha] piezoelectric slip-stick drive comprising at least one piezoelectric actuator (11) and at least one driver (10) for applying a voltage to said actuator (11) , wherein said driver (10) is adapted to operate said actuator (11) in cycles, each cycle&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt; comprising a ramp phase (R) and a transition phase (T) , wherein, in said ramp phase (R) a voltage ovex said actuator (11) varies much more slowly than in said transition phase (T) , wherein said drive comprises a capacitor (15) and a switch (14) for connecting said capacitor (15) to said actuator (11) , thereby initiating a charge transfer between said actuator (11) and said capacitor (15) for generating said transition phase (T) , and wherein said driver (10) comprises a first output (12) for applying said voltage over said actuator (11) during said ramp phase (R) and a second output (13) for charging said capacitor (15) .
</P>
<P>
2. The drive of claim 1 further comprising a first amplifier (3, 3&apos;) connected to said first output (12) and a second amplifier (4, 4&apos;) connected to said second output (13) .
</P>
<P>
3. The drive of any of the claims 1 or 2 wherein, during said ramp phase (R) , a current through said first output (12) is opposite to a current through said second output (13) . 4. The drive of any of the preceding claims further comprising a measuring device (16, 18, R) measuring a current through said actuator (11) or a voltage over said actuator (11) .
</P>
<P>
5. The drive of claim 4 comprising a current source (4) connected to said second output (13), wherein, during said ramp phase (R) , said current source (4) gen-erates a current equal magnitude as but of opposite sign to the current measured by said measuring device.
</P>
<P>
6. A method for operating a slip-stick drive comprising at least one actuator (11), wherein said ac- tuator (11) is operated in cycles, each cycle comprising a ramp phase (R) and a transition phase (T) , wherein, in said ramp phase (R) a voltage over said actuator (11) varies much more slowly than in said transition phase (T) , said method comprising the steps of during said ramp phase (R) , charging said actuator (11) with a first charge and charging a capacitor (15) with a second charge, and during said transition phase (T) , connecting said actuator (11) to said capacitor (15) , thereby initi- ating a charge transfer between said actuator (11) and said capacitor (15) for generating a voltage step over said actuator (11) .
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 6 wherein, in said ramp phase (R) , said actuator (11) - and said capacitor (15) are charged with equal but opposite charges.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of any of the claims 6 or 7 wherein at least part of said cycles comprise an initialization phase (I) prior to said ramp phase (R) , wherein, during at least part of said initialization phase, said actuator (11) and said capacitor (15) are connected and a desired starting voltage is applied over the actuator (11) and the capacitor (15) .
</P>
<P>
9. The method of any of the claims 6 to 8 wherein, during said ramp phase (R) , a current that is equal to but opposite to a current fed to said actuator (11) is fed to said capacitor (15) .
</P>
<P>
10. The method of any of the claims 6 to 9 comprising the step of measuring the current through or a voltage over said actuator (11) during said ramp phase (R) -
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10 wherein the measured current through or voltage over said actuator (11) is used to determine at least one parameter from the following group: a) a temperature of said actuator (11) , b) a depolarization of said actuator (11) , and c) an undesired discharge in said actuator
</P>
<P>
(11) -
</P>
<P>
12. Use of the drive or the method of any of the preceding claims for positioning applications in scanning probe microscopy.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2162929B1;WO2008148224A1;ES2370157T3;AT519235T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
