<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Nanocrystals
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2159044A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NAASANI IMAD [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NAASANI, IMAD
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LIFE TECHNOLOGIES CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LIFE TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2159044
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090172526
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2002-09-17
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20020803277
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-09-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20010322982P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2001-09-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20020379208P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-05-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B32B9/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B19/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09K11/08
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58J
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Provided herein are compositions of functionalized, fluorescent nanocrystals comprising fluorescent nanocrystals coated with an imidazole-containing compound;  compositions of funcionalized, fluorescent nanocrystals comprising fluorescent nanocrystals coated with an imidazole-containing compound and cross-linked with a phosphine cross-linking compound;  compositions of functionalized fluorescent nanocrystals operably bound to molecular probe;  a process of making funcionalized, fluorescent nanocrystals;  and a process of using funcionalized, fluorescent nanocrystals in a detection system.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal comprising:
</P>
<P>
- a fluorescent nanocrystal; and
</P>
<P>
- a coating over said fluorescent nanocrystal, wherein said coating comprises complexes comprised of imidazole-containing compound operably bound to a metal cation, where the imidazole ring nitrogens serve as co-ordinating ligand to operably bind the metal ion;optionally wherein said fluorescent nanocrystal is selected from core semiconductor materials, core/shell semiconductor nanocrystals, doped metal oxide nanocrystals, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
2. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of claim 1, wherein said metal cation comprises semiconductor material.
</P>
<P>
3. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of claim 1, wherein the metal cation comprises one or more of Zn&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt;, Cu&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt;, Fe&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt;, Ni&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt;, Cd&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; and Co&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
4. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim, wherein the coating comprises imidazole-containing compound operably bound to Cd&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; or Zn&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; by imidazole complexation.
</P>
<P>
5. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim, wherein said metal cation is Zn&amp;lt;2+&amp;gt; operably bound to a sulfur containing compound.
</P>
<P>
6. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim, further comprising a molecular probe, one or more molecules of which are operably bound to the coated fluorescent material.
</P>
<P>
7. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim, further comprising cross-linking of the coating, optionally wherein the reactive functionalities used to cross-link are selected from amino groups, carboxyl groups, and a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim, wherein the coating further comprises a phosphine cross-linking compound, optionally wherein the phosphine cross-linking compound comprises a hydroxymethyl-phosphine compound.
</P>
<P>
9. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim, wherein the imidazole-containing compound comprises an amino acid or an oligopeptide.
</P>
<P>
10. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of claim 9, wherein the imidazole-containing compound comprises a dipeptide.
</P>
<P>
11. The functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any of claims 1 to 10, wherein the imidazole-containing compound comprises histidine, carnosine, anserine, baleine, homocarnasine, 1-methylhistidine, 3-methylhistidine, imidazolysine, 5-methylimidazalone, [beta]-2-imidazolyl-L-a-alanine, carcine or histamine, and optionally wherein the imidazole-containing compound comprises histidine or carnosine.
</P>
<P>
12. The nanocrystal of any preceding claim, wherein the nanocrystal is comprised of a core comprised of at least one Group II-VI semiconductor material, and optionally coated with a Group II-VI semiconductor shell.
</P>
<P>
13. The nanocrystal of claim 12, wherein the nanocrystal is comprised of ZnS, or CdSe.
</P>
<P>
14. The nanocrystal of any of claim 12 or claim 13, wherein the semiconductor core is coated with a shell comprised of YZ wherein Y is Cd or Zn, and Z is S or Se, and the imidazole-containing compound.
</P>
<P>
15. A detection system, comprising a functionalized fluorescent nanocrystal of any preceding claim and an excitation source suitable to elicit fluorescence from the coated fluorescent nanocrystal.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2159044B1;US2003059635A1;US6955855B2;US2005112376A1;US7198847B2;WO03054507A2;WO03054507A3;JP2010048812A;JP2005513471A;EP1456022A2;EP1456022A4;EP1456022B1;AU2002365124A8;AU2002365124A1;AT448077T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
