<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SUSPENSIONS OF TITANIUM (IV) OXIDE PARTICLES AND PROCESS FOR THEIR PRODUCTION
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2109585A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SCOTT DAVID M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI CARMINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GRUSHIN VLADIMIR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SCOTT, DAVID, M
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI, CARMINE
</Name>
<Name>
GRUSHIN, VLADIMIR
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E. I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2109585
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070874180
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US26106
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060876218P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The disclosure pertains to a process for making a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, comprising: vigorously mixing (a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and (b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1, wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide,;  the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and a ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the suspension of the finely divided particles to form in the mixture. The suspensions can be dried to recover a powder. Typically the particles are nanoparticles.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A process for making a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, comprising: vigorously mixing
</P>
<P>
(a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and
</P>
<P>
(b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium
</P>
<P>
(IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1 , wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and a ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the suspension of the finely divided particles to form in the mixture.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base and the second aqueous base is the same or different.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base or the second aqueous base or both is a weak base.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 1 in which the amount of water of the first component is provided by the alcohol wherein the alcohol comprises water of hydration.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 1 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is up to and including about 20 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component when the activator is an aqueous base comprising a tetraalkyl ammonium cation.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 1 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is no greater than about 6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 1 in which the activator ranges from about 0.2 to about 1.6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 1 in which the activator is about 0.8 wt. % based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 1 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component ranges from about 1 to abouti to about 9 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 1 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component is about 3 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 1 in which the titanium alkoxide has the chemical structure:
</P>
<P>
Ti(ORi)(OR2)(OR3)(OR4)
</P>
<P>
wherein R1 to R4 are the same or different alkyl groups of 1 to about 10 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 1 in which the titanium alkoxide is selected from the group consisting of titanium (IV) isopropoxide, titanium (IV) n- butoxide, titanium (IV) methoxide, titanium (IV) ethoxide, and titanium (IV) n-propoxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is a tetraalkylammonium hydroxide in which the alkyl group contains from 1 to 8 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of tetraethylammonium hydroxide, tetra-n-butylammonium hydroxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is in a concentration up to about 0.2 M in the first component.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of tetraalkylammonium hydroxides in which the alkyl group contains from 1 to 8 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of claim 18 in which the base of the second aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of tetraethylammonium hydroxide, tetra-n-butylammonium hydroxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is in a concentration ranging from about 0.001 M to about 0.030 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
21. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is tetraethylammonium hydroxide or tetra-n-butylammonium hydroxide in a concentration up to about 0.5 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
22. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second second aqueous base is ammonium hydroxide in a concentration ranging from about 0.006 M to about 14.8 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
23. The process of claim 1 in which the alcohol is a monohydric or dihydric Ci to Cio aliphatic alcohol.
</P>
<P>
24. The process of claim 1 in which the alcohol is selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, isopropanol, ethylene glycol, and butanediol and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
25. The process of claim 1 in which the activator consists essentially of water and is substantially free of base.
</P>
<P>
26. The process of claim 1 in which the second component is substantially free of base.
</P>
<P>
27. The process of claim 1 in which the mixing vigor is determined by the shear rate of mixing and the shear rate of the mixing is greater than about 100s&amp;lt;&apos;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
28. The process of claim 1 in which the mixing is accomplished in a homogenizer wherein the rotor speed is greater than about 500 rpm.
</P>
<P>
29. The process of claim 1 further comprising drying the suspension of titanium (IV) oxide to form a powder having the chemical composition:
</P>
<P>
wherein x ranges from 0-2 and n is no greater than about 2.
</P>
<P>
30. The process of claim 1 in which the suspension comprises the titanium (IV) oxide particles in a liquid medium and the process further comprises concentrating the suspension by removing at least a portion of the liquid medium.
</P>
<P>
31. The process of claim 1 further comprising mixing the suspension with a polymer.
</P>
<P>
32. The process of claim 1 in which the suspension has an optical transparency greater than about 5% over a 1 cm path length.
</P>
<P>
33. The process of claim 1 in which the suspension has an optical transparency greater than about 90% over a 1 cm path length.
</P>
<P>
34. The process of claim 1 in which the second component is free of alcohol.
</P>
<P>
35. The process of claim 1 in which the finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles are nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
36. A suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles made by a process, comprising: vigorously mixing
</P>
<P>
(a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and
</P>
<P>
(b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1 , wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and a ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the suspension of the finely divided particles to form in the mixture.
</P>
<P>
37. The suspension of claim 36 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is up to and including about 20 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component when the base of the first aqueous base comprises a tetraalkyl ammonium cation.
</P>
<P>
38. The suspension of claim 36 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is no greater than about 6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
39. The suspension of claim 36 in which the activator ranges from about 0.2 to about 1.6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
40. The suspension of claim 36 in which the activator is in an amount of about 0.8 wt. % based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
41. The suspension of claim 36 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component ranges from about 1 to about 1 to about 9 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
42. The suspension of claim 36 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component is about 3 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
43. The suspension of claim 36 in which the titanium alkoxide is selected from the group consisting of titanium (IV) isopropoxide, titanium (IV) n-butoxide, titanium (IV) methoxide, titanium (IV) ethoxide, and titanium (IV) n-propoxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
44. The suspension of claim 36 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
45. The suspension of claim 36 in which the base of the first aqueous base is in a concentration up to about 0.2 M in the first component.
</P>
<P>
46. The suspension of claim 36 in which the alcohol is selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, isopropanol, ethylene glycol, and butanediol and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
47. The suspension of claim 36 in which the mixing vigor is determined by the shear rate of mixing and the shear rate of the mixing is greater than about 100s&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
48. The suspension of claim 36 in which the mixing is accomplished in a homogenizer wherein the rotor speed is greater than about 500 rpm.
</P>
<P>
49. The suspension of claim 36 having an optical transparency greater than about 5% over a 1 cm pathlength.
</P>
<P>
50. The suspension of claim 36 having an optical transparency greater than about 90% over a 1 cm pathlength.
</P>
<P>
51. The suspension of claim 36 in which the second component is free of alcohol.
</P>
<P>
52. The suspension of claim 36 in which the finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles are nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
53. The process of claim 36 further comprising drying the suspension of titanium (IV) oxide to form a powder having the chemical composition:
</P>
<P>
wherein x ranges from 0-2 and n is no greater than about 2.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008136818A2;WO2008136818A3;US2010055028A1;US7998453B2;AU2007352583A1;AU2007352583A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
