<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NITRIDE NANOWIRES AND METHOD OF PRODUCING SUCH
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2102899A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SEIFERT WERNER [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
ASOLI DAMIR [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
BI ZHAOXIA [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
SEIFERT, WERNER
</Name>
<Name>
ASOLI, DAMIR
</Name>
<Name>
BI, ZHAOXIA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
QUNANO AB [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
QUNANO AB
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2102899
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080705308
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008SE50036
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
SE20070000102
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-12
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C30B25/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/20
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C30B25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/40B2
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/60
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4B1B1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1B1
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C5M6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3C
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/20B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to the growing of nitride semiconductors, applicable for a multitude of semiconductor devices such as diodes, LEDs and transistors. According to the method of the invention nitride semiconductor nanowires are grown utilizing a CVD based selective area growth technique. A nitrogen source and a metal-organic source are present during the nanowire growth step and at least the nitrogen source flow rate is continuous during the nanowire growth step. The V/III-ratio utilized in the inventive method is significantly lower than the V/III-ratios commonly associated with the growth of nitride based semiconductor.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A method of growing nitride based semiconductor nanowires utilising a CVD based selective area growth technique, wherein a nitrogen source and a metal-organic source is present during a nanowire growth step, the method characterized in that the nitrogen source flow rate is continuous during the nanowire growth step.
</P>
<P>
2. The nanowire growth method according to claim 1 , wherein the metal-organic source flow rate is continuous during the nanowire growth step.
</P>
<P>
3. The nanowire growth method according to claim 2, wherein the relations between the nitrogen source flow rate and the metal- organic source flow rate, hereinafter referred to as the V/ Ill-ratio, is in the range of 1- 100.
</P>
<P>
4. The nanowire growth method according to claim 3, wherein the relations between the flow rates are such that the V/ Ill-ratio is in the range of 1-50.
</P>
<P>
5. The nanowire growth method according to claim 4, wherein the relations between the flow rates are such that the V/ Ill-ratio is in the range of 5-50.
</P>
<P>
6. The nanowire growth method according to any of claims 2 to 5, wherein the V/ Ill-ratio is constant during the nanowire growth step.
</P>
<P>
7. The nanowire growth method according to any of claims 2 to 6, wherein the nitride based semiconductor is GaN, and the nitrogen source is ammonia, NH3 and the metal-organic source is trimethylgallium, TMG.
</P>
<P>
8. The nanowire growth method according to any of claims 1 to 7, comprising the steps of: -(a) Providing a growth mask ( 1 1 1) on a substrate ( 1 10); -(b) Produce openings ( 1 13) in the growth mask ( 1 1 1); -(c) Growing Nanowires by a CVD based process wherein the precursor source flows are continuous.
</P>
<P>
9. The nanowire growth method according to claim 8, further comprising a pre-treatment step (c&apos;) wherein at least one of precursor source flows are active, but the conditions are adjusted such that no nanowire growth appears.
</P>
<P>
10. The nanowire growth method according to claim 8, wherein the pre- treatment step comprises an annealing step.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The nanowire growth method according to any of claims 8 to 10, further comprising a planar growth phase to be taken after the nanowire growth step (c), the planar growth phase comprising at least one growth step resulting in a shell layer on the nanowires, wherein a V/ Ill-ratio is utilized which is higher than the V/ Ill-ratio of the nanowire growth step.
</P>
<P>
12. The nanowire growth method according to claim 1 1 , wherein the /Ill-ratio of the planar growth step is at least 10 times higher than the V/III-ratio of the nanowire growth step.
</P>
<P>
13. The nanowire growth method according to any of claims 1 to 12, wherein a doping source is introduced to stabilize the nanowire growth conditions.
</P>
<P>
14. A nanowire ( 1 10) of a nitride semiconductor, the nanowire epitaxially connected and upstanding from a substrate ( 105), characterized in that the nanowire ( 1 10) has the same crystal structure through its entire length.
</P>
<P>
15. A semiconductor device comprising a plurality of nanowires (105), the nanowires epitaxially connected and upstanding from a substrate ( 105), characterized in that at least a majority of the nanowires each has the same crystal structure through their respective entire length.
</P>
<P>
16. The semiconductor device according to claim 15, wherein at least 90% of the nanowires each has the same crystal structure through their respective entire length.
</P>
<P>
17. The semiconductor device according to claim 16, wherein at least 99% of the nanowires each has the same crystal structure through their respective entire length.
</P>
<P>
18. The semiconductor device according to claim 15, wherein the nanowires are provided with a volume element ( 1 15) comprising at least one shell layer ( 1 16).
</P>
<P>
19. The semiconductor device according to claim 18, wherein the semiconductor device is a LED, wherein the plurality of nanowires are individual nanostructured LEDs, and the pn-junction associated with the LED functionality is provided by the nanowires
</P>
<P>
(105) combined with their respective volume elements ( 1 15).
</P>
<P>
20. The semiconductor device according to claim 15, wherein the nanowires are of GaN.
</P>
<P>
21. The semiconductor device according to claim 19 and 20, wherein the volume elements comprises a plurality of shell layers and at least one of the shell layers is of InGaN.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008085129A1;US2011143472A1;US2010163840A1;US7829443B2;KR20090101960A;JP2010515651A;CN101681813A;CA2674448A1;AU2008203934A1;AU2008203934A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
