<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ATOMIC FORCE MICROSCOPE AS AN ANALYZING TOOL FOR BIOCHIP
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2164986A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
PARK JOON WON [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
HONG BONG JIN [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
KWON SUNG HONG [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
PARK, JOON WON
</Name>
<Name>
HONG, BONG JIN
</Name>
<Name>
KWON, SUNG HONG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
POSTECH ACAD IND FOUND [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
POSCO [KR]
</Name>
<Name>
POSTECH ACADEMY-INDUSTRY FOUNDATION
</Name>
<Name>
POSCO
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2164986
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080873039
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-16
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008IB03959
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070944056P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N33/48
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y35/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68A10
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/42
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present application discloses a method for detecting a presence of target ligand in a fluid medium which includes the steps of: (i) contacting the fluid medium with a solid substrate that includes an array of dendrons on its surface, wherein each of the dendron includes a central atom, a probe that is attached to the central atom optionally through a linker, and a base portion attached to the central atom and having a plurality of termini that are attached to the surface of the solid support; ;  and (ii) determining the presence of a probe-target ligand complex by measuring binding force between the bound ligand and detection molecule tethered to the tip of an atomic force microscope (&quot;AFM&quot;), which detection molecule has affinity for the ligand, wherein measurement of an increase in force between the probe-target ligand complex and the detection molecule by AFM indicates the presence of the probe-target ligand complex.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for detecting a presence of target ligand in a fluid medium comprising:
</P>
<P>
(i) contacting the fluid medium with a solid substrate, wherein the solid substrate comprises:
</P>
<P>
array of dendrons on its surface, wherein each of said dendron comprises:
</P>
<P>
a central atom;
</P>
<P>
a probe that is attached to the central atom optionally through a linker; and
</P>
<P>
a base portion attached to the central atom and having a plurality of termini that are attached to the surface of the solid support; and
</P>
<P>
(ii) determining the presence of a probe-target ligand complex by measuring binding force between the bound ligand and detection molecule that has affinity for the ligand, wherein the detection molecule is tethered to surface of a tip of an atomic force microscope (&quot;AFM&quot;), wherein measurement of an increase in force between the probe-target ligand complex and the detection molecule indicates the presence of the probe-target ligand complex.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein the probe-target ligand complex is an oligonucleotide-complementary nucleic acid complex.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein the probe-target ligand complex is detected in the presence of low concentration of the target ligand, which is at a concentration of at least about 1 aM.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 3, wherein the target ligand is at a concentration of between about 1 aM to about 1000 aM.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 2, wherein said method is capable of discriminating a single nucleotide polymorphism in the oligonucleotide-complementary nucleic acid complex.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1, wherein the detection molecule is detection nucleic acid.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1, wherein the detection molecule is comprised of a poly-dT oligomer sufficiently complementary to a poly-dA section of RNA.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1, wherein the solid substrate is a non-porous solid support.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 8, wherein the solid substrate is a planar non-porous solid support.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1, wherein the solid substrate is a biochip.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 1, wherein the tip of the atomic force microscope (&quot;AFM&quot;) is coated with dendron.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1, wherein the target ligand is not labeled.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 1, comprising further cross-linking the probe-ligand complex.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 1, wherein the probe-ligand complex is covalently linked to an affinity molecule, and detection molecule specifically binds to the affinity molecule.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14, wherein the affinity molecule is an antigen or an antibody.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 1, wherein the detection molecule is a protein that selectively binds to double stranded DNA.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 1, wherein the probe-ligand complex forms a triple helix formation with the detection molecule.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 1, wherein the detection molecule is a DNA intercalating agent.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 1, wherein the detection molecule is a protein, which selectively binds to a mismatched section of a double stranded DNA.
</P>
<P>
20. A system for detection of target nucleic acid, comprising, (i) a biochip immobilized with probe molecules, and (ii) an atomic force microscope (&quot;AFM&quot;) comprising a tip on which is tethered detection molecule.
</P>
<P>
21. The system according to claim 20, wherein the biochip is coated with dendrons on which are tethered probe molecules.
</P>
<P>
22. The system according to claim 21, wherein the tip of the AFM is coated with dendrons, on which are immobilized detection molecules.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2164986A4;US2009048120A1;US2010261615A9;JP2010529474A;WO2009109809A2;WO2009109809A3;CN101849021A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
