<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
LATERAL COLLECTION PHOTOVOLTAICS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2171763A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FONASH STEPHEN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NAM WOOK JUN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FONASH, STEPHEN
</Name>
<Name>
NAM, WOOK, JUN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SOLARITY INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SOLARITY, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2171763
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080781048
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US68446
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070946250P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080972491
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US50780
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L31/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0224B2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0224B2B
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0352
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/18G4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/42D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/42H2B
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E10/50
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Lateral collection photovoltaic (LCP) structures based on micro- and nano-collecting elements are used to collect photogenerated carriers. In one set of embodiments, the collecting elements are arrayed on a conducting substrate. In certain versions, the collecting elements are substantially perpendicular to the conductor. In another set of embodiments, the micro- or nano-scale collecting elements do not have direct physical and electrical contact to any conducting substrate. In one version, both anode and cathode electrodes are laterally arrayed. In another version, the collecting elements of one electrode are a composite wherein a conductor is separated by an insulator, which is part of each collector element, from the opposing electrode residing on the substrate.;  In still another version, the collection of one electrode structure is a composite containing both the anode and the cathode collecting elements for collection. An active material is positioned among the collector elements.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Atty. Docket No. 25416-0002
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A lateral collecting photovoltaic structure comprising: a plurality of alternating anode and cathode collecting elements disposed in an active layer, wherein in positions of the collecting elements being determined by pattern transfer of an alternating depth trench pattern into a material to undergo solid phase crystalization such that one depth corresponds to the elements of an electrode and the other depth corresponds to the elements of the counter-electrode; a deeper set of trenches being enhanced in depth to reach through an insulator to an electrically conducting layer disposed across a substrate and a second shallower set of trenches terminates in the material to undergo solid phase crystallization; the shallower set of trenches having an electrically conducting material at a trench bottom; the metal electrode collecting elements disposed on said conducting layer and said material; and at least one of which set of elements also serving to enhance solid phase crystallization thereby resulting a crystalline phase active layer from the material undergoing solid phase crystallization.
</P>
<P>
2. A lateral collecting photovoltaic structure comprising: alternating anode and cathode collecting elements in an active layer; said element positions determined by pattern transfer of an alternating depth trench pattern into the active layer material such that one depth corresponds to the elements of an electrode and the other depth corresponds to the elements of the counter-electrode; where the deeper set of trenches is enhanced in depth to reach through an insulator to an electrically conducting layer disposed across the substrate; Atty. Docket No. 25416-0002
</P>
<P>
and where the second shallower set of trenches terminates in the active layer; where the shallower set of trenches has an electrically conducting material at the trench bottom; and with metal electrode elements disposed on the said layer and said material and serving as electrode and counter-electrode.
</P>
<P>
3. A lateral collecting photovoltaic structure comprising: alternating anode and cathode collecting elements in an active layer; said element positions determined by pattern transfer of an alternating depth trench pattern into amorphous silicon to undergo solid phase crystallization such that one depth corresponds to the elements of an electrode and the other depth corresponds to the elements of the counter-electrode; where the deeper set of trenches is enhanced in depth to reach through an insulator to an electrically conducting layer disposed across the substrate; and where the second shallower set of trenches terminates in the material to undergo solid phase crystallization; where the shallower set of trenches has an electrically conducting material at the trench bottom; where at least one of said conducting layer or conducting material is a catalyst for vapor-liquid-solid silicon growth; thereby giving in at least one set of trenches doped semiconductor growth of a material to serve as the catalyst for silicon induced solid phase crystallization; and with at least said one of which set of elements resulting in the active layer amorphous silicon undergoing solid phase crystallization.
</P>
<P>
4. The structure of claim 3 in which all silicon materials are replaced with another semiconductor.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009003150A2;WO2009003150A3;US2011023955A1;KR20100051055A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
