<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SEMICONDUCTOR LASER AND METHOD FOR MANUFACTURING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2169792A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
AKIYAMA TOMOYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUGAWARA MITSURU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
AKIYAMA, TOMOYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
SUGAWARA, MITSURU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
QD LASER INC [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
QD LASER INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2169792
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080765318
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP60517
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070186352
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01S5/22
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/343
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01S5/22
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a semiconductor laser including a first conductive type of a lower clad layer 12, an active layer 14 provided on the lower clad layer 12, the active layer 14 including a plurality of quantum dots, and a second conductive type of an upper clad layer 18, the upper clad layer 18 being provided on the active layer 14 so as to have an isolated ridge portion 30 such that W1   Wtop + 0.4 [mu]m where Wtop is the width of a top of the ridge portion 30 and W1 is the width of the ridge portion 30 at a height of 50 nm from a bottom of the ridge portion 30. The present invention also provides a method for manufacturing such a semiconductor laser.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A semiconductor laser characterized by comprising:
</P>
<P>
a first conductive type of a lower clad layer;
</P>
<P>
an active layer provided on the lower clad layer, the active layer including a plurality of quantum dots;
</P>
<P>
a second conductive type of an upper clad layer that is opposite to the first conductive type, the upper clad layer being provided on the active layer so as to have an isolated ridge portion such that
</P>
<P>
where Wtop is a width of a top of the ridge portion and W1 is a width of the ridge portion at a height of 50 nm from a bottom of the ridge portion; and
</P>
<P>
an electrode provided on the upper clad layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The semiconductor laser as recited in claim 1, characterized in that:
</P>
<P>
the upper clad layer includes a first layer and a second layer provided on the first layer, and
</P>
<P>
the first layer has a minimum width of the ridge portion.
</P>
<P>
3. The semiconductor laser as recited in claim 2, characterized in that:
</P>
<P>
the first layer and the second layer comprise an AlGaAs layer, and
</P>
<P>
an Al compositional ratio of the first layer is higher than that of the second layer.
</P>
<P>
4. The semiconductor laser as recited in claim 2 or 3, characterized by comprising a third layer provided on the second layer, the third layer having a concentration of the second conductive type of carriers that is higher than those of the first layer and the second layer.
</P>
<P>
5. The semiconductor laser as recited in any one of claims 1 to 4, characterized in that:
</P>
<P>
the plurality of quantum dots is formed of InGaAs or InAs, and
</P>
<P>
the active layer includes a barrier layer of AlGaAs or GaAs that surrounds the plurality of quantum dots.
</P>
<P>
6. The semiconductor laser as recited in claim 5, characterized in that:
</P>
<P>
the first conductive type is p-type, and the second conductive type is n-type, and
</P>
<P>
the barrier layer has a p-type layer.
</P>
<P>
7. The semiconductor laser as recited in any one of claims 1 to 6, characterized by comprising an undoped layer between the active layer and the upper clad layer.
</P>
<P>
8. A method for manufacturing a semiconductor laser, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
a step of sequentially stacking, on a first conductive type of a lower clad layer, an active layer including a plurality of quantum dots, a first layer included in a second conductive type of an upper clad layer that is opposite to the first conductive type, and a second layer included in the upper clad layer;
</P>
<P>
a step of dry-etching the second layer and wet-etching the first layer so as to form the upper clad layer into an isolated ridge portion on the active layer; and
</P>
<P>
a step of forming an electrode on the upper clad layer.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for manufacturing a semiconductor laser as recited in claim 8, characterized in that the first layer and the second layer comprise an AlGaAs layer, and
</P>
<P>
an Al compositional ratio of the first layer is higher than that of the second layer.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for manufacturing a semiconductor laser as recited in claim 8 or 9, characterized in that the first layer has a minimum width of the ridge portion.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010195688A1;US8160116B2;WO2009011184A1;CN101743670A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
