<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SILVER FINE POWDER, METHOD FOR PRODUCING THE SAME, AND INK
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2119518A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SATO KIMITAKA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OKANO TAKU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SATO, KIMITAKA
</Name>
<Name>
OKANO, TAKU
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DOWA ELECTRONICS MATERIALS CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
DOWA ELECTRONICS MATERIALS CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2119518
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080703172
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-08
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP50308
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-08
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070001298
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070173732
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F1/02
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/22
</Class>
<Class>
H01B13/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B5/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/288
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/00A4C
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/52
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/22
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A silver fine powder comprising silver particles with an average particle diameter of 20 nm or less and having an organic protective material on the surface thereof, wherein the proportion of the organic protective material present is 0.05 to 25% by mass based on the total mass of the silver particles and the organic protective material. An amine compound having a molecular weight of 100 to 1,000 is preferably used as the organic protective material, and that having one or more unsaturated bond in one molecule is particularly preferred. This silver fine powder has, for example, a crystallite diameter in (111) crystal plane of silver particle of 20 nm or less. The present invention further provides an ink comprising particles of the silver fine powder dispersed in an organic solvent in the silver concentration of 10% by mass or more, the ink having a viscosity of 50 mPas or less.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A silver fine powder comprising silver particles with an average particle diameter of 20 nm or less and having an organic protective material on the surface thereof, wherein the proportion of the organic protective material present is 0.05 to 25% by mass based on the total mass of the silver particles and the organic protective material.
</P>
<P>
2. The silver fine powder according to claim 1, wherein a compound constituting the organic protective material is an amine compound.
</P>
<P>
3. The silver fine powder according to claim 1 or 2, wherein a compound constituting the organic protective material is a material having one or more unsaturated bond in one molecule.
</P>
<P>
4. The silver fine powder according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein a compound constituting the organic protective material is a material having a molecular weight of 100 to 1,000.
</P>
<P>
5. The silver fine powder according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein a crystallite diameter in (111) crystal plane of silver is 20 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
6. An ink comprising particles of the silver fine powder of any one of claims 1 to 5 dispersed in an organic solvent in the silver concentration of 10% by mass or more, the ink having a viscosity of 50 mPa.s or less.
</P>
<P>
7. A process for producing the silver fine powder of any one of claims 1 to 5, comprising using an amine compound having a molecular weight of 100 to 1,000 as an organic compound having one or more unsaturated bond in one molecule in precipitating silver particles by subjecting a silver compound to reduction treatment in the presence of the organic compound in an alcohol or a polyol using the alcohol or the polyol as a reducing agent.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010006002A1;US7981326B2;KR20090098838A;JP2008190025A;CN101583449A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
