<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Conductive polyolefins with good mechanical properties
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2144254A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DUPIRE MARC [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
NAGY B JANOS [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
MICHEL JACQUES [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
PIRLOT CHRISTOPHE [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
DUPIRE, MARC
</Name>
<Name>
NAGY B., JANOS
</Name>
<Name>
MICHEL, JACQUES
</Name>
<Name>
PIRLOT, CHRISTOPHE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
TOTAL PETROCHEMICALS RES FELUY [BE]
</Name>
<Name>
TOTAL PETROCHEMICALS RESEARCH FELUY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2144254
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090172983
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-03-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030718686
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-03-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20020076054
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-03-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20090172983
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-03-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C55/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01B3/44
</Class>
<Class>
H01B7/17
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01B3/44B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
This invention discloses a polymeric material reinforced with single-wall nanotubes (SWNT) or multiple-wall nanotubes (MWNT) with good electrical and mechanical properties. It also discloses a process for preparing said reinforced polymeric material and their use in electrically dissipative material.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A polymeric material reinforced with single-wall carbon nanotubes (SWNT) or multiple-wall carbon nanotubes (MWNT) and prepared by mixing in solution, characterized in that said carbon nanotubes are free of support and catalyst particles, said reinforced polymeric material having simultaneously improved electrical and mechanical properties.
</P>
<P>
2. The reinforced polymeric material of claim 1, wherein the polymeric material is a polyolefin.
</P>
<P>
3. The reinforced polymeric material of claim 2, wherein the polyolefin is an atactic, isotactic or syndiotactic homopolymer or copolymer of propylene.
</P>
<P>
4. The reinforced polymeric material according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the carbon nanotubes have an aspect ratio of at least 100.
</P>
<P>
5. The reinforced polymeric material according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the amount of carbon nanotubes added is of from 0.1 to 20 wt% based on the weight of the polymer.
</P>
<P>
6. The reinforced polymeric material according to any one of the preceding claims that is further oriented.
</P>
<P>
7. The reinforced polymeric material according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the carbon nanotubes are free of pyrolytic carbon content.
</P>
<P>
8. The reinforced polymeric material according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the carbon nanotubes are functionalised.
</P>
<P>
9. The reinforced polymeric material according to any one of the preceding claims further comprising carbon black.
</P>
<P>
10. A process for preparing the reinforced polymeric material according to claims 1 to 9 that comprises the steps of:
</P>
<P>
a) providing a polymeric matrix,
</P>
<P>
b) providing carbon nanotubes free of support and catalyst particles,
</P>
<P>
c) dispersing the said carbon nanotubes in the polymer matrix wherein the polymer and fillers are dissolved in a solvent and thoroughly mixed followed by the evaporation of the solvent,
</P>
<P>
d) optionally orienting the polymer/nanotubes mixture of step c) by stretching in the molten or in the solid state.
</P>
<P>
11. Use of carbon nanotubes free of support and catalyst particles to prepare reinforced polymeric material according to any one of claims 1 to 7 and claim 9, said polymeric material having an improved balance of electrical and mechanical properties.
</P>
<P>
12. Use of functionalised carbon nanotubes free of support and catalyst particles to prepare reinforced polymeric material according to any one of claims 1 to 7 and claim 9, said polymeric material having an improved balance of electrical and mechanical properties.
</P>
<P>
13. Electrically dissipative material for automotive, textile or other applications prepared with the reinforced polymeric material according to any one of claims 1 to 9.
</P>
<P>
14. Shields for wires and cables prepared with the reinforced polymeric material according to any one of claims 1 to 9.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2144254A3;EP2144254B1;EP1349179A1;US2006001013A1;US2009221782A1;US7863366B2;PT2144254E;PT2031602E;KR20110007257A;KR20100070360A;JP2009120836A;JP2005520889A;ES2378928T3;ES2378908T3;EP2031602A2;EP2031602A3;EP2031602B1;EP2028662A2;EP2028662A3;EP1485924A1;WO03079375A1;DK2144254T3;DK2031602T3;CN101081902A;CN1643620A;CN1320555C;AU2003222760A1;AT543779T;AT543778T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
