<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD OF POLISHING GLASS SUBSTRATE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2156926A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KOJIMA HIROSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ITO MASABUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KOJIMA, HIROSHI
</Name>
<Name>
ITO, MASABUMI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ASAHI GLASS CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ASAHI GLASS COMPANY, LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2156926
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080765044
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP60231
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070149705
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B24B37/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F1/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B24B37/04B
</Class>
<Class>
B24B49/16
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C03C19/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F1/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An object of the present invention is to provide a polishing method for diminishing concave defects of a glass substrate used in a reflective mask for EUVL and the like. The invention relates to a method of polishing a glass substrate which comprises polishing a major surface of the glass substrate while feeding a polishing slurry between the glass substrate and a pad surface of a polishing pad, wherein the polishing load of the polishing pad is from 1 to 60 g/cm 2 . The pad surface of the polishing pad is preferably dressing-processed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of polishing a glass substrate, which comprises polishing a major surface of the glass substrate while feeding a polishing slurry between the glass substrate and a pad surface of a polishing pad, wherein the polishing load of the polishing pad is from 1 to 60 g/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to claim 1, wherein the polishing pad is a suede-based pad having a pad surface with the difference in height between the maximum peak and the minimum peak on the surface of 50 [micro]m or less.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the polishing load of the polishing pad is from 1 to 25 g/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the pad surface of the polishing pad is dressing-processed with a dress plate.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to claim 4, wherein the dress plate is electrodeposited diamond.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the polishing pad has an average open pore diameter of from 5 to 50 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein the polishing pad has as average open pore diameter of from 5 to 30 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the surface to be polished of the glass substrate is preliminarily polished so as to have a surface roughness Rms of 3 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein the polishing slurry comprises an abrasive material which is silica or ceria having an average primary particle diameter of 60 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 9, wherein the glass substrate is a glass substrate for a mask blank.
</P>
<P>
11. A mask for exposure produced using a glass substrate for a mask blank that has been polished by the method of polishing a glass substrate according to any one of claims 1 to 9.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010075577A1;US8070557B2;TW200906550A;KR20100019989A;JP2009012164A;WO2008149864A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
