<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SELF-DEAGGLOMERATING SUSPENSIONS OF TITANIUM (IV) OXIDES AND METHODS FOR MAKING THEM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2111371A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SCOTT DAVID M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI CARMINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GRUSHIN VLADIMIR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SCOTT, DAVID, M
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI, CARMINE
</Name>
<Name>
GRUSHIN, VLADIMIR
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E. I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2111371
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070874178
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US26102
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060876384P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process for making a self-deagglomerating suspension, in particular, a suspension which self-deagglomerates to form a substantially transparent suspension, of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, comprising: vigorously mixing (a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and (b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles,;  the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1, wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the mixture to be initially opaque and subsequently spontaneously form into a substantially optically transparent suspension.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A process for making a self-deagglomerating suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, comprising: vigorously mixing
</P>
<P>
(a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and an aqueous base, and (b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1 , wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the mixture to be initially opaque and subsequently spontaneously form into a substantially optically transparent suspension.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base and the second aqueous base are the same or different.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is up to and including about 20 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component when the activator is an aqueous base comprising a tetraalkyl ammonium cation.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 1 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is no greater than about 6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 1 in which the activator ranges from about 0.2 to about 1.6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 1 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component ranges from about 1 to about 1 to about 3 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 1 in which the titanium alkoxide is selected from the group consisting of titanium (IV) isopropoxide, titanium (IV) n- butoxide, titanium (IV) methoxide, titanium (IV) ethoxide, and titanium (IV) n-propoxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is a tetraalkylammonium hydroxide in which the alkyl group contains from 1 to 8 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of tetraethylammonium hydroxide, tetra-n-butylammonium hydroxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is in a concentration up to about 0.2 M in the first component.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is in a concentration ranging from about 0.001 M to about 0.030 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of tetraethylammonium hydroxide and tetra-n-butylammonium hydroxide in a concentration up to about 0.5 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is ammonium hydroxide in a concentration ranging from about 0.006 M to about 14.8 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 1 in which the alcohol is selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, isopropanol, ethylene glycol, and butanediol and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 1 in which the mixing vigor is determined by the shear rate of mixing and the shear rate of the mixing is greater than about 100s&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 1 in which the mixing is accomplished in a homogenizer wherein the rotor speed is greater than about 500 rpm.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of claim 1 in which the transparent suspension has an optical transparency greater than about 4% over a 1 cm path length.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of claim 1 in which the transparent suspension has an optical transparency greater than about 90% over a 1 cm pathlength.
</P>
<P>
20. A self-deagglomerating suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles made by a process, comprising: vigorously mixing (a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and (b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1 , wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the the activator, the mixing vigor, and the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the mixture to be initially opaque and subsequently spontaneously form into a substantially optically transparent suspension
</P>
<P>
21. The suspension of claim 20 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is up to and including about 20 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component when the base of the first aqueous base comprises a tetraalkyl ammonium cation.
</P>
<P>
22. The suspension of claim 20 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is no greater than about 6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
23. The suspension of claim 20 in which the activator ranges from about 0.2 to about 1.6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
24. The suspension of claim 20 in which the activator is in an amount of about 0.8 wt. % based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
25. The suspension of claim 20 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component ranges from about 1 to about 1 to about 3 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
26. The suspension of claim 20 in which the titanium alkoxide is selected from the group consisting of titanium (IV) isopropoxide, titanium (IV) n-butoxide, titanium (IV) methoxide, titanium (IV) ethoxide, and titanium (IV) n-propoxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
27. The suspension of claim 20 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
28. The suspension of claim 20 in which the base of the first aqueous base is in a concentration up to about 0.2 M in the first component.
</P>
<P>
29. The suspension of claim 20 in which the alcohol is selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, isopropanol, ethylene glycol, and butanediol and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
30. The suspension of claim 20 in which the mixing vigor is determined by the shear rate of mixing and the shear rate of the mixing is greater than about 100s&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
31. The suspension of claim 20 in which the mixing is accomplished in a homogenizer wherein the rotor speed is greater than about 500 rpm.
</P>
<P>
32. The suspension of claim 20 having an optical transparency greater than about 5% over a 1 cm pathlength.
</P>
<P>
33. The suspension of claim 20 having an optical transparency greater than about 90% over a 1 cm pathlength.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008140506A2;WO2008140506A3;US2010144518A1;US8114804B2;AU2007353425A1;AU2007353425A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
