<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
USE OF NANOTUBES, ESPECIALLY CARBON NANOTUBES, TO IMPROVE THE HIGH TEMPÉRATURE MECHANICAL PROPERTIES OF A POLYMERIC MATRIX
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2160285A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MC ANDREW THOMAS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HOCHSTETTER GILLES [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
WERTH MICHAEL [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
BOUILLOUX ALAIN [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
BRULE BENOIT [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
PICCIONE PATRICK [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
EL BOUNIA NOUR EDDINE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
ROGER CHRISTOPHE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BRESSAND EMILY [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MC ANDREW, THOMAS
</Name>
<Name>
HOCHSTETTER, GILLES
</Name>
<Name>
WERTH, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
BOUILLOUX, ALAIN
</Name>
<Name>
BRULE, BENOIT
</Name>
<Name>
PICCIONE, PATRICK
</Name>
<Name>
EL BOUNIA, NOUR EDDINE
</Name>
<Name>
ROGER, CHRISTOPHE
</Name>
<Name>
BRESSAND, EMILY
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ARKEMA FRANCE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
ARKEMA FRANCE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2160285
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080807496
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008IB53504
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070946517P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C70/10
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B29C70/12
</Class>
<Class>
B29K707/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/22L
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The présent invention pertains to the use of nanotubes of at least one chemical élément chosen from éléments of groups IHa, IVa and Va of the periodic table to improve the high température mechanical properties of a polymeric matrix comprising at least one semi-crystalline thermoplastic polymer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Use of nanotubes of at least one chemical element chosen from elements of groups Ilia, IVa and Va of the periodic table to improve the high temperature mechanical properties of a polymeric matrix comprising at least one semi-crystalline thermoplastic polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. Use according to Claim 1, characterized in that the mechanical properties are the resistance to flow and/or the modulus .
</P>
<P>
3. Use according to Claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the nanotubes are made from carbon, boron, phosphorus and/or nitrogen.
</P>
<P>
4. Use according to Claim 3, characterized in that the nanotubes are made from carbon nitride, boron nitride, boron carbide, boron phosphide, phosphorus nitride or carbon nitride boride.
</P>
<P>
5. Use according to any one of Claims 1 to 4, characterized in that the nanotubes are carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
6. Use according to any one of Claims 1 to 5, characterized in that the nanotubes have a mean diameter between 0.1 and 150 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. Use according to any one of Claims 1 to 6, characterized in that the nanotubes represent from 0.5 to 30 wt %, preferably from 0.5 to 10 wt %, more preferably from 1 to 5 wt % of the thermoplastic polymer.
</P>
<P>
8. Use according to any one of Claims 1 to 7, characterized in that the thermoplastic polymer is chosen from:
</P>
<P>
- polyamides such as polyamide 6 (PA-6) , polyamide 11 (PA-Il), polyamide 12 (PA-12), polyamide 6.6 (PA-6.6), polyamide 4.6 (PA-4.6), polyamide 6.10 (PA-6.10) and polyamide 6.12 (PA-6.12), some of which are marketed by ARKEMA under the trade name Rilsan&amp;lt;(R)&amp;gt; with the fluid grade polymers such as Rilsan&amp;lt;(R)&amp;gt; AMNO TLD being preferred, as well as copolymers, including block copolymers, comprising amide monomers and other monomers such as polytetramethylene glycol (PTMG) (Pebax&amp;lt;(R)&amp;gt;) ;
</P>
<P>
- aromatic polyamides such as polyphthalamides;
</P>
<P>
- fluoropolymers comprising at least 50 mol % and preferably consisting of monomers of formula (I) :
</P>
<P>
CFX=CHX&apos; (I) wherein X and X&apos; independently designate a hydrogen or halogen atom (especially fluorine or chlorine) or a perhalogenated alkyl radical (especially a perfluorated radical) , such as (preferably [alpha]) polyvinylidene fluoride
</P>
<P>
(PVDF), copolymers of vinylidene fluoride and for instance hexafluoropropylene (HFP) , fluoroethylene / propylene copolymers (FEP) , and copolymers of ethylene with any of fluoroethylene/propylene (FEP) , tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) , perfluoromethylvinyl ether (PMVE) or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE) , some of which are available from ARKEMA under the trade name Kynar&amp;lt;(R)&amp;gt; with the injection grade polymers such as Kynar&amp;lt;(R)&amp;gt; 710 ou 720 being preferred;
</P>
<P>
- polyolefins such as polyethylene and polypropylene; - thermoplastic polyurethanes (TPU) ;
</P>
<P>
- polyesters such as polyethylene terephthalate (PET) or cyclic polybutylene terephthalate (CPBT) ;
</P>
<P>
- silicon polymers; and - their mixtures.
</P>
<P>
9. Use according to any one of Claims 1 to 8, characterized in that the polymeric matrix further includes at least one additive chosen from plasticizers, anti-oxygen stabilizers, light stabilizers, colouring agents, anti- impact agents, flame retardants, lubricants and their mixtures .
</P>
<P>
10. Use according to any one of Claims 1 to 9, characterized in that the nanotubes are used as dispersed in a low-melting, low molecular weight resin, such as cyclic polybutylene terephthalate .
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009001324A2;WO2009001324A3;WO2009001324A9;US2011251331A1;KR20100027164A;JP2010531911A;CN101790453A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
