<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYMERIC DYES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2155805A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CREMER CHRISTIAN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
RIGGS RICHARD LEWIS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
FROEHLING BEATE [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MUELLER MARTIN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
CREMER, CHRISTIAN
</Name>
<Name>
RIGGS, RICHARD LEWIS
</Name>
<Name>
FROEHLING, BEATE
</Name>
<Name>
MUELLER, MARTIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BASF SE [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BASF SE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2155805
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080736564
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-25
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008EP55038
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-25
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070108002
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080736564
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-25
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C07F7/08
</Class>
<Class>
C08G77/22
</Class>
<Class>
C08G77/26
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/10
</Class>
<Class>
D06M13/513
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/643
</Class>
<Class>
D06P1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/11
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/26
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/898
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q5/06D
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07F7/18C4B
</Class>
<Class>
C08G77/22
</Class>
<Class>
C08G77/26
</Class>
<Class>
C08L83/08
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/00S
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/10B
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/10D
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/10K
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/10M
</Class>
<Class>
C09B69/10R
</Class>
<Class>
D06P1/00M
</Class>
<Class>
D06P3/14N
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A highly crosslinked polysiloxane dye comprising at least 10 Si atoms, including at least one moiety of the formula (I) whose open Si-bonds each are linked to an oxygen atom and open O-bond is linked to a silicon atom in the rest of the polysiloxane, and wherein T is a direct bond or an organic spacer group such as C1-C18alkylene, C2-C12alkenylene, C5-C10cycloalkylene, C5-C10arylene, -C5-C10arylene-(C1-C10alkylene)-, each of which may be end-capped towards the linkage to Dye by CO, COO, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CS, CSS, CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, O, S, SO, SO2, C5-C10cycloalkylene, C5-C10arylene;  or T is C3-C18alkylene interrupted, and optionally end- capped towards the linkage to Dye, by CO, COO, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CS, CSS, CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, O, S, SO, -SO2-, C5-C10cycloalkylene, C5-C10arylene;  or is CO;  (CH2CH2-O)1-5;  COO;  N(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;);  CON(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;);  O;  S;  SO;  SO2;  R&amp;lt;1 &amp;gt;is hydrogen;  unsubstituted or substituted, straight-chain or branched, monocyclic or polycyclic, interrupted or uninterrupted C1-C14alkyl;  C2-C14alkenyl;  C6-C10aryl;  C6-C10aryl-C1- C10alkyl;  or C5-C10alkyl(C5-C10aryl);  and Dye is a residue of an organic dye, is useful for dyeing of organic materials, such as keratin-containing fibers, wool, leather, silk, cellulose or polyamides.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A highly crosslinked polysiloxane dye comprising at least 10 Si atoms, including at least one moiety of the formula (I)
</P>
<P>
- Si-O-
</P>
<P>
I T. [deg.]y&amp;lt;e&amp;gt; (i) whose open Si-bonds each are linked to an oxygen atom and open O-bond is linked to a silicon atom in the rest of the polysiloxane, and wherein T is a direct bond or an organic spacer group such as CrCi8alkylene, C2-Ci2alkenylene, C5-Ci0cycloalkylene, C5-Ci0arylene, -C5-Cioarylene-(Ci-CiOalkylene)-, each of which may be end-capped towards the linkage to Dye by CO, COO, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CS, CSS, CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, O, S, SO, SO2, C5-Ci0cycloalkylene, C5-Ci0arylene; or T is C3-Ci8alkylene interrupted, and optionally end- capped towards the linkage to Dye, by CO, COO, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CS, CSS, CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, O, S, SO, -SO2-, C5-Ci0cycloalkylene, C5-Ci0arylene; or is CO; (CH2CH2-O)I-5; COO; N(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;); CON(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;); O; S; SO; SO2; R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is hydrogen; unsubstituted or substituted, straight-chain or branched, monocyclic or polycyclic, interrupted or uninterrupted Ci-Ci4alkyl; C2-Ci4alkenyl; C6-Ci0aryl; C6-Ci0aryl-Ci- Cioalkyl; or C5-Cioalkyl(C5-Cioaryl); and Dye is a residue of an organic dye, especially a cationic organic dye.
</P>
<P>
2. A polysiloxane dye according to claim 1 , which is represented by the formula (II)
</P>
<P>
wherein T is as defined in claim 1 ,
</P>
<P>
Dyh is a residue Dye or a cationic moiety other than the one of an organic dye or is hydrogen; n equals the number of silicon atoms in the polysiloxane and is a number from 10 to about 10&amp;lt;9&amp;gt;, while at least 3 moieties Dyh in the polysiloxane of formula (II), for example 10 to 100% of the moieties Dyh in the polysiloxane of formula (II), are a residue Dye; Z1 and Z2 independently are bonds each linked to an oxygen atom of the rest of the polysiloxane or are OH or alkoxy such as C-i-Csalkoxy or halogen; or Z2 may also be Ci-C8alkyl or -T-Dyh;
</P>
<P>
Z3 is a bond linked to a silicon atom of the rest of the polysiloxane or is OH or alkoxy such as Ci-C8alkoxy or halogen; or Z3 together with one of Z1 or Z2 commonly form the same chemical bond.
</P>
<P>
3. A polysiloxane dye according to claim 1 or 2 in the form of particles whose dimensions, in at least one, especially all 3, spatial direction(s) are in the nanoparticle size range from 5 to 1000 nm.
</P>
<P>
4. A polysiloxane dye according to claim 1 or 2 wherein the number of organic dye moieties Dye ranges from 3 to 10&amp;lt;8&amp;gt;, and the total number of Si atoms is at least 30.
</P>
<P>
5. A polysiloxane dye according to claim 1 or 2 wherein the organic dye moietes Dye are selected from cationic dye moieties selected from those of anthraquinone, acridine, azo, azamethine, hydrazomethine, triphenylmethane, benzodifuranone, coumarine, diketopyrrolopyrrol, dioxazine, diphenylmethane, formazane, indigoid indophenol, naph- thalimide, naphthoquinone, nitroaryl, merocyanine, methine oxazine, perinone, perylene, pyrenequinone, phtalocyanine, phenazine, quinoneimine, quinacridone, quinophtalone, styryl, stilbene, xanthene, thiazine and thioxanthene dyes; more preferably from those of cationic azo, azomethine, hydrazomethine, merocyanine, methine, triphenylmethane and styryl dye radicals, whose positive charges are compensated by suitable anions.
</P>
<P>
6. A polysiloxane dye according to claim 1 or 2 wherein the organic dye moietes Dye are selected from those of the formulae
</P>
<P>
where
</P>
<P>
An&amp;lt;&quot;&amp;gt; stands for an equivalent of a colorless anion; Ku is a divalent radical of a coupling component of the aniline or phenol series or the radical of a heterocyclic coupling component,
</P>
<P>
L is O, S or NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;;
</P>
<P>
Y is CR&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; or N;
</P>
<P>
R is Ci-C4alkyl; R&apos; is hydrogen, C--C4alkyl, Cl, nitro, amino, C--C4monoalkylamino or di-C--C4alkylamino;
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is H or Ci-C4alkyl;
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is H, Ci-C4alkyl, or d-C4alkyl substituted by OH-, C--C4alkoxy-, halogen-, CN-, amino-,
</P>
<P>
C--C4monoalkylamino- or di-C--C4alkylamino;
</P>
<P>
R8, Rg, Ri 0&apos; ^1 1 &amp;gt; ^21 &amp;lt;an(&amp;gt;^ ^22 &amp;lt;are eacn&amp;gt; independently of the others hydrogen or C- - C4alkyl;
</P>
<P>
R-12, R&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt;i2&apos; Ri3&amp;gt; R&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt;13&apos; ^20 &amp;lt;an(&amp;gt;* ^ 20 &amp;lt;are eacn&amp;gt; independently of the other hydrogen, C--
</P>
<P>
C4alkyl or C--C4alkoxy; or one or more pairs of residues R8, Rg, R13, R&apos;13; and/or R10, Rn, Ri2, R&apos;12; and/or R20, R&apos;2o,
</P>
<P>
R2i, R22, bonding directly to the same phenyl ring or connected via nitrogen to said ring, together with the atoms they are attached to and further intermediary atoms, if present, form an aliphatic or aromatic, preferably 5- or 6-membered, ring.
</P>
<P>
7. Process for the preparation of a highly crosslinked polysiloxane dye according to claim 1 , wherein a silane reaction mixture comprising a monomer of the formula (III)
</P>
<P>
X3Si-T-Dye (III),
</P>
<P>
wherein X is a leaving group such as halogen or alkoxy, especially Cl or d-Csalkoxy; T is a direct bond or an organic spacer group such as CrCi8alkylene, C2-Ci2alkenylene, C5- Ciocycloalkylene, C5-Ci0arylene, -C5-Cioarylene-(Ci-CiOalkylene)- , each of which may be end-capped towards the linkage to Dye by CO, COO, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CS, CSS, CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, O, S, SO, -SO2-, C5-Ci0cycloalkylene, C5-Ci0arylene; or T is C3- d8alkylene interrupted, and optionally end-capped towards the linkage to Dye, by CO, COO, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CONR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, CS, CSS, CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, NR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;CSNR&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;, O, S, SO, -SO2-, C5-
</P>
<P>
Ciocycloalkylene, C5-Ci0arylene; or is CO-; -(CH2CH2-O)I-5-; COO; N(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;); CON(R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;); O; S; SO; -SO2-;
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is hydrogen; unsubstituted or substituted, straight-chain or branched, monocyclic or polycyclic, interrupted or uninterrupted Ci-Ci4alkyl; C2-Ci4alkenyl; C6-Ci0aryl; C6-Ci0aryl-Ci- Cioalkyl; or C5-Cioalkyl(C5-CiOaryl); and Dye is a residue of an organic dye, is subjected to polycondensation.
</P>
<P>
8. Process according to claim 7, wherein the reaction mixture additionally contains one or more further copolymerizable silane monomers of the formulae
</P>
<P>
X3Si-T-H (Ilia),
</P>
<P>
X3Si-T-A (NIb),
</P>
<P>
X2Si(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)-T-Dye (IV)
</P>
<P>
X2Si(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)-T-H (IVa), X2Si(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)-T-A (IVb),
</P>
<P>
where those monomers containing no radical Dye are contained in an amount of up to 90 mol-% of the total silane monomers in the initial reaction mixture;
</P>
<P>
and/or one or more of the above monomers of the formulae (Ilia), (1Mb), (IV), (IVa), (IVb), or of the formulae or one or more of the above monomers of the formulae (Ilia), (1Mb), (IV), (IVa), (IVb), or of the formulae X3AI (Ia),
</P>
<P>
X4Si (Ib),
</P>
<P>
X2AI-T-H (NIc),
</P>
<P>
X-AI(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)-T-H (IVc),
</P>
<P>
XSi(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)2-T-Dye (V),
</P>
<P>
XSi(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)2-T-H (Va),
</P>
<P>
XSi(R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;)2-T-A (Vb),
</P>
<P>
are added to the reaction mixture after commence of the polycondensation reaction, preferably after 90% of the silane monomers initially present in the reaction mixture have been reacted; and wherein
</P>
<P>
A is a cationic moiety other than the one of an organic dye, whose charge is balanced by a suitable anion, R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is Ci-C8alkyl or -T-Dye or -T-H or -T-A.
</P>
<P>
9. Highly crosslinked polysiloxane dye obtainable by a process according to claim 7 or 8.
</P>
<P>
10. A composition comprising at least one polysiloxane dye as defined in claim 1 and a further component selected from synthetic organic polymers, natural organic polymers, cosmetically acceptable carriers, further dyes, oxidative agents and detergents.
</P>
<P>
1 1. A composition according to claim 10 comprising in addition at least one single further direct dye and/or an oxidative agent.
</P>
<P>
12. A composition according to claim 10 or 11 in form of a shampoo, a conditioner, a gel or an emulsion.
</P>
<P>
13. A method of dyeing an organic material, which comprises treating the organic material with at least one dye according to claim 1 , or a composition according to any of claims 10 to 12.
</P>
<P>
14. A method according to claim 13, wherein the organic material is selected from keratin- containing fibers such as human hair.
</P>
<P>
15. Compound of one of the formulae
</P>
<P>
wherein R independently is CrC4alkyl, especially ethyl, and X&amp;lt;&quot;&amp;gt; stands for an equivalent of a colorless anion.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008138726A2;WO2008138726A3;US2010192312A1;US7976585B2;TW200904908A;JP2010526897A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
