<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESSES FOR THE HYDROTHERMAL PRODUCTION OF TITANIUM DIOXIDE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2104644A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HUTCHENSON KEITH W [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LI SHENG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CORBIN DAVID RICHARD [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI CARMINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MCCARRON EUGENE MICHAEL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZAHER JOSEPH JAMES [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HUTCHENSON, KEITH, W
</Name>
<Name>
LI, SHENG
</Name>
<Name>
CORBIN, DAVID, RICHARD
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI, CARMINE
</Name>
<Name>
MCCARRON, EUGENE, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
ZAHER, JOSEPH JAMES
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E. I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2104644
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20060848318
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-12-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2006US49545
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides hydrothermal processes for the production of titanium dioxide from titanyl hydroxide. The use of specific crystallization directors, or additives, can promote the formation of rutile, anatase, or brookite. Variation of process operating parameters can lead to either pigmentary-sized or nano-sized rutile.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A process comprising: f) mixing amorphous titanyl hydroxide with water to obtain a titanium-containing slurry; g) adding to the titanium-containing slurry 0.16 to 20 weight percent of a free acid selected from the group consisting of HCI, H2C2O4^H2O, HNO3, HF, and HBr to form an acidified titanium-containing slurry; h) adding to the acidified titanium-containing slurry 0.01 to
</P>
<P>
15 weight percent of a rutile-directing additive to form a mixture; i) heating the mixture to a temperature of at least 150&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C but less than 374 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C for less than 24 hours in a closed vessel to form rutile and a residual solution; and j) separating the rutile from the residual solution.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 wherein the rutile-directing additive is selected from the group consisting of halides, oxalates, oxides, and hydroxides of zinc, tin, ammonium, and the group I and group Il metals. 3. A process comprising: f) mixing amorphous titanyl hydroxide with water to obtain a titanium-containing slurry; g) adding to the titanium-containing slurry 0.16 to 0.41 wt% of a free acid selected from the group consisting of HCI, HNO3, HF, H2C2O4^H2O, and HBr to form an acidified titanium-containing slurry; h) adding to the acidified titanium-containing slurry 0.5 to 15 weight percent of a pigmentary rutile-directing additive to form a mixture; i) heating the mixture to a temperature of at least 220 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C but less than 374 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C for 24 hours or less in a closed vessel to form pigmentary rutile and a residual solution; and j) separating the pigmentary rutile from the residual solution. 4. The process of claim 3 wherein the pigmentary rutile- directing additive is selected from the group consisting of halides, oxalates, oxides, and hydroxides of zinc, tin, ammonium, and the group I and group Il metals.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 3 wherein the pigmentary rutile- directing additive is selected from the group consisting of ZnCb, ZnO, MgCI2, and NaCI.
</P>
<P>
6. A process comprising: a) mixing amorphous titanyl hydroxide with water to obtain titanium-containing slurry; b) adding to the titanium-containing slurry 0.3 to 20 weight percent of a free acid selected from the group consisting of HCI, H2C2O4-2H2O, HNO3, HF1 and HBr to form an acidified titanium-containing slurry; c) adding 0.01 to 15 weight percent of a rutile-directing additive selected from the group consisting of the halides, oxalates, oxides, and hydroxides of zinc, tin, ammonium and the group I and group Il metals to the acidified titanium-containing slurry to form a mixture; d) heating the mixture to a temperature of at least 150 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C but less than 250 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C for less than 24 hours in a closed vessel to form nano rutile arid a residual solution; e) separating the nano rutile from the residual solution.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 6 wherein the rutile-directing additive is selected from the group consisting of halides, oxalates, oxides, and hydroxides of zinc, tin, ammonium, and the group I and group Il metals
</P>
<P>
8. A process comprising: f) mixing amorphous titanyl hydroxide with water to obtain a titanium-containing slurry; g) optionally adding less than 0.16 wt% of an acid selected from the group consisting of HCI, HF, HBr, HNO3, and
</P>
<P>
H2C2O4^H2O or up to 20 wt. % of H2SO4 to the titanium-containing slurry to form an acidified slurry; h) adding 0.01-15 weight percent of an anatase-directing additive to the slurry to form a mixture; i) heating the mixture to a temperature of at least 150 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C but less than 374 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C for 24 hours or less in a closed vessel to form anatase and a residual solution; j) separating the anatase from the residual solution.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 8 wherein the anatase-directing additive is selected from the group consisting of KH2PO4, AI2(SO^,
</P>
<P>
ZnSO4, and Na2SO4.
</P>
<P>
10. A process comprising: a) mixing amorphous titanyl hydroxide with water to obtain a titanium-containing slurry; b) adding a NH4OH/NH3 solution to the titanium- containing slurry such that the slurry has a pH greater than 9.0; c) adding to the slurry 0.01 to15 weight percent of a brookite-directing additive to the titanium-rich slurry to form a mixture; d) heating the mixture to a temperature of at least 150 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C but less than the 374&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C for 24 hours or less in a closed vessel to form brookite and a residual solution; e) separating the brookite from the residual solution.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 10 wherein the brookite-directing additive is selected from the group consisting of AICI3-6H2O, alpha-AI2O3l AI(OH)3, and AIOOH.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008088312A2;WO2008088312A3;MX2009007013A;JP2010514654A;CN101668704A;AU2006352688A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
