<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
MAGNETIC IRON OXIDE PARTICLE, MAGNETIC MATERIAL, AND RADIO WAVE ABSORBER
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2165975A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
OHKOSHI SHIN-ICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SAKURAI SHUNSUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YORINAGA TAKENORI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MATSUMOTO KAZUYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SASAKI SHINYA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHKOSHI, SHIN-ICHI
</Name>
<Name>
SAKURAI, SHUNSUKE
</Name>
<Name>
YORINAGA, TAKENORI
</Name>
<Name>
MATSUMOTO, KAZUYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
SASAKI, SHINYA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV TOKYO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
DOWA ELECTRONICS MATERIALS CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
THE UNIVERSITY OF TOKYO
</Name>
<Name>
DOWA ELECTRONICS MATERIALS CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2165975
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080764894
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP59976
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070146182
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070260071
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G49/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G51/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/37
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C01G51/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C01G53/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/26H
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/26K
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628B2B
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628B2D
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628B2H8
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/34B2
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/37
</Class>
<Class>
H01Q17/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is a magnetic material having high Hc and and High Curie point, which is capable of controlling such magnetic characteristics without requiring rare or expensive raw materials. Specifically disclosed is a magnetic material composed of particles of a magnetic iron oxide which is represented by the following general formula: [mu]-A x B y Fe 2-x-y O 3 or [mu]-A x B y C z Fe 2-x-y-z O 3 (wherein A, B and C each represents a metal excluding Fe and different from each other, satisfying 0 &amp;lt; x, y, z &amp;lt; 1), with [mu]-Fe 2 O 3 as a main phase.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A magnetic iron oxide particle, with [epsilon]-Fe2O3 as a main phase, which is expressed by a general formula [epsilon]-AxByFe2-x-yO3(wherein A and B are mutually different metals excluding Fe, satisfying 0 &amp;lt; x, y &amp;lt; 1).
</P>
<P>
2. A magnetic iron oxide particle, with [epsilon]-Fe2O3 as a main phase, which is expressed by a general formula [epsilon]- AxByCzFe2-x-yO3 (wherein A and B are mutually different metals excluding Fe, satisfying 0 &amp;lt; x, y, z &amp;lt; 1).
</P>
<P>
3. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to the claim 1 or 2, wherein A is bivalent metal, B is quadrivalent metal, and C is trivalent metal.
</P>
<P>
4. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein A is one or more kinds of metals selected from Co, Ni, Mn, and Zn.
</P>
<P>
5. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein B is Ti.
</P>
<P>
6. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to any one of claims 2 to 5, wherein C is one or more kinds of metals selected from In, Ga, and Al.
</P>
<P>
7. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein a longest length of the magnetic iron oxide particle is 5nm or more and 120nm or less.
</P>
<P>
8. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein a coercive force Hc is 39.8kA/m or more and 1194.3kA/m or less.
</P>
<P>
9. The magnetic iron oxide particle according to any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein saturation magnetization [sigma]s at 25[deg.]C is 0.1Am&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/kg or more and 100Am&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/kg or less.
</P>
<P>
10. A magnetic material containing the magnetic iron oxide particle of any one of claims 1 to 9, and a binder.
</P>
<P>
11. A radio wave absorber, with the magnetic iron oxide particle of any one of claims 1 to 9 dispersed in rubber or resin.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2165975A4;US2010171066A1;WO2008149785A1;CN101687665A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
