<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING NANOPARTICLE OF PRUSSIAN BLUE TYPE METAL COMPLEX, PRUSSIAN BLUE TYPE METAL COMPLEX NANOPARTICLE OBTAINED BY THE SAME, DISPERSION OF THE NANOPARTICLES, METHOD OF REGULATING COLORATION OF THE NANOPARTICLES, AND ELECTRODE AND TRANSMITTED- LIGHT REGULATOR BOTH EMPLOYING THE NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2116511A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KAWAMOTO TOHRU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA HISASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HARA SHIGEO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KURIHARA MASATO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SAKAMOTO MASATOMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KAWAMOTO, TOHRU
</Name>
<Name>
TANAKA, HISASHI
</Name>
<Name>
HARA, SHIGEO
</Name>
<Name>
KURIHARA, MASATO
</Name>
<Name>
SAKAMOTO, MASATOMI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NAT INST OF ADVANCED IND SCIEN [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ADVANCED INDUSTRIAL SCIENCE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2116511
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070860468
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007JP75265
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20060355513
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070241576
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01C3/11
</Class>
<Class>
C01C3/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01C3/11
</Class>
<Class>
C01C3/12
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
To provide a method of producing Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles without necessarily requiring complicated steps and an excessive amount of raw materials, but allowing one to obtain nanometer-size fine particles having desired fine particle properties, and Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles obtained by the method, a dispersion of the nanoparticles, a method of regulating the color of the nanoparticles, and an electrode and a transmitted light-regulator each using the nanoparticles;  Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles are produced by: mixing an aqueous solution containing a metal cyano complex anion having predetermined metal atom M A as a central metal and an aqueous solution containing a cation of predetermined metal atom M B ;  thereby precipitating the crystal of a Prussian blue-type metal complex having the metal atom M A and the metal atom M B ;  and then mixing the Prussian blue-type metal complex with an aqueous solution containing a metal cyano complex anion having the metal atom M C as a central metal and/or an aqueous solution containing a cation of the metal atom M D . The thus-obtained Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles have a preferable electrochemical responsiveness, and the particles can be used for forming a thin film including them to construct a light-transmitted regulator.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of producing Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles, comprising, mixing a crystal of a Prussian blue-type metal complex having the following metal atom MA and the following metal atom MB of being crosslinked via a cyano group CN with an aqueous solution containing a metal cyano complex anion having the following metal atom MC as a central metal and/or an aqueous solution containing a cation of the following metal atom MD.
</P>
<P>
[the metal atom MA: at least one metal atom, or two or more metal atoms, selected from the group consisting of vanadium, chromium, molybdenum, tungsten, manganese, iron, ruthenium, cobalt, nickel, platinum, and copper; the metal atom MB: at least one metal atom, or two or more metal atoms, selected from the group consisting of vanadium, chromium, manganese, iron, ruthenium, cobalt, rhodium, nickel, palladium, platinum, copper, silver, zinc, lanthanum, europium, gadolinium, lutetium, barium, strontium, and calcium; the metal atom MC: at least one metal atom , or two or more metal atoms, selected from the group consisting of vanadium, chromium, molybdenum, tungsten, manganese, iron, ruthenium, cobalt, nickel, platinum, and copper; and the meta atom MD: at least one metal atom, or two or more metal atoms, selected from the group consisting of vanadium, chromium, manganese, iron, ruthenium, cobalt, rhodium, nickel, palladium, platinum, copper, silver, zinc, lanthanum, europium, gadolinium, lutetium, barium, strontium, and calcium.]
</P>
<P>
2. The method of producing Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 1, wherein the crystal of a Prussian blue-type metal complex having the metal atom MA and the metal atom MB precipitated by mixing an aqueous solution containing a metal cyano complex anion having the following metal atom MA as a central metal and an aqueous solution containing a cation of the following metal atom MB is used as the crystal of the Prussian blue-type metal complex having the MA and the MB of being crosslinked with the cyano group CN.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of producing Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 1 or 2, wherein a particle size adjustor and/or an optical responsiveness adjustor is added upon precipitating the crystal of a Prussian blue-type metal complex having the metal atom MA and the metal atom MB by mixing an aqueous solution containing a metal cyano complex anion having the following metal atom MA as a central metal and an aqueous solution containing a cation of the following metal atom MB, as a preparation process of the crystal of the Prussian blue-type metal complex having the MA and the MB of being crosslinked with the cyano group CN.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of producing Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the nanoparticles are obtained as a powder by removing the solvent from the mixed liquid.
</P>
<P>
5. Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles having an average particle size of 500 nm or less produced by the production method according to any one of claims 1 to 4.
</P>
<P>
6. A dispersion of Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles, comprising the dispersion containing nanoparticles produced by the method according to any one of claims 1 to 3, or the nanoparticles of re-dispersing the nanoparticle powder produced by the method according to claim 4 in a solvent.
</P>
<P>
7. Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles, comprising: a crystal of a Prussian blue-type metal complex, and a metal cyano complex anion and/or a metal cation adsorbed on the surface of the crystal.
</P>
<P>
8. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 7, wherein the complex crystal is substantially insoluble in water, and the surface of each fine particle is negatively or positively charged by the adsorption of the anion and/or the cation so as to make the fine particle soluble or dispersible in water.
</P>
<P>
9. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 7 or 8, wherein the complex crystal forms a core portion, and the anion and the cation adsorbed on the core portion form a shell portion in combination thereof, so that the shell portion formed in having metal composition different from that of the core portion a Prussian blue-type metal complex structure.
</P>
<P>
10. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 9, wherein the nanoparticles are each provided with multiple shell portions of being identical to or different from each other in metal composition.
</P>
<P>
11. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to any one of claims 7 to 10, further comprising: ligands adsorbed on the outer surfaces of the nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
12. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 11, wherein the ligand has 4 or more and 100 or less carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
13. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 11 or 12, wherein the protecting ligand is represented by any one of formulae 1 to 3:
</P>
<P>
wherein R1 and R2 each independently represent a hydrogen atom, or, an alkyl group, alkenyl group, or alkynyl group, of having 8 or more carbon atoms;
</P>
<P>
wherein R3 represents an alkyl group, alkenyl group, or alkynyl group, of having 8 or more carbon atoms;
</P>
<P>
wherein R4 represents an alkyl group, alkenyl group, or alkynyl group, of having 6 or more carbon atoms; and R5 represents an alkyl group, an alkenyl group, or an alkynyl group.
</P>
<P>
14. The Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to claim 13, wherein the substituents R1 to R4 each represent an alkenyl group.
</P>
<P>
15. A method of regulating the color of Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles, comprising: providing the nanoparticles each having a core-shell structure according to any one of claims 9 to 14; and, adjusting the amount of the shell portion.
</P>
<P>
16. Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles, wherein the color of the nanoparticles is regulated by the method according to claim 15.
</P>
<P>
17. An electrode, comprising: a substrate; and the Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to any one of claims 5, 7 to 14, and 16 provided on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
18. A transmitted light-regulator, comprising the Prussian blue-type metal complex nanoparticles according to any one of claims 5, 7 to 14, and 16.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010133487A1;WO2008081923A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
