<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHODS AND MATERIALS FOR FABRICATING LAMINATE NANOMOLDS AND NANOPARTICLES THEREFROM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2117725A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ROLLAND JASON P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MAYNOR BENJAMIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HENN ROBERT L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ROLLAND, JASON, P
</Name>
<Name>
MAYNOR, BENJAMIN
</Name>
<Name>
HENN, ROBERT, L
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LIQUIDIA TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LIQUIDIA TECHNOLOGIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2117725
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070874162
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US24910
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060633763
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-04
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B05D3/12
</Class>
<Class>
B32B1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B29C33/40
</Class>
<Class>
B29L31/756
</Class>
<Class>
B32B3/30
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A laminate nanomold includes a layer of perfluoropolyether defining a cavity that has a predetermined shape and a support layer coupled with the layer of perfluoropolyether. The laminate can also include a tie-layer coupling the layer of perfluoropolyether with the support layer. The tie-layer can also include a photocurable component and a thermal curable component. The cavity can have a broadest dimension of less than 500 nanometers.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A laminate nanomold; comprising:
</P>
<P>
a layer of perfluoropolyether, wherein the layer of perfluoropolyether defines a cavity having a predetermined shape; and
</P>
<P>
a support layer coupled with the layer of perfluoropolyether.
</P>
<P>
2. The laminate of claim 1, further comprising a tie-layer coupling the layer of perfluoropolyether with the support layer.
</P>
<P>
3. The laminate of claim 2, wherein the tie-layer comprises a dual cure material.
</P>
<P>
4. The laminate of claim 1, further comprising a plurality of cavities defined in the perfluoropolyether layer.
</P>
<P>
5. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities comprise a predetermined shape selected from the group consisting of cylindrical, 200 nm diameter cylinders, cuboidal, 200 nm cuboidal, crescent, and concave disc.
</P>
<P>
6. The laminate of claim 4, wherein the plurality of cavities comprise cavities of a variety of predetermined shapes.
</P>
<P>
7. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 10 micrometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
8. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 5 micrometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
9. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 1 micrometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
10. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 750 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
11. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 500 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
12. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 300 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
13. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 200 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
14. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 100 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
15. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 75 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
16. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 50 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
17. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 40 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
18. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 30 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
19. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 20 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
20. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 10 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
21. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 50 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
22. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 40 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
23. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 30 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
24. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 20 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
25. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 15 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
26. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 10 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
27. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the support layer comprises a polymer.
</P>
<P>
28. The laminate of claim 27, wherein the polymer of the support layer comprises polyethylene terephthalate.
</P>
<P>
29. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the support layer is less than about 20 mil thick.
</P>
<P>
30. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the support layer is less than about 15 mil thick.
</P>
<P>
31. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the support layer is less than about 10 mil thick.
</P>
<P>
32. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the support layer is less than about 5 mil thick.
</P>
<P>
33. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the support layer introduces a modulus of greater than 1000 to the laminate.
</P>
<P>
34. The laminate of claim 3, wherein the layer of perfluoropolyether is coupled with the support layer by photoinitiator coupling and thermalinitiator coupling.
</P>
<P>
35. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether comprises a photocurable component.
</P>
<P>
36. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the layer of perfluoropolyether has a footprint greater than about 25 square centimeters.
</P>
<P>
37. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the layer of perfluoropolyether has a footprint greater than about 50 square centimeters.
</P>
<P>
38. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the layer of perfluoropolyether has a footprint greater than about 100 square centimeters.
</P>
<P>
39. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 5 micrometers from an adjacent cavity.
</P>
<P>
40. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 2 micrometer from an adjacent cavity.
</P>
<P>
41. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 1 micrometers from an adjacent cavity.
</P>
<P>
42. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 750 nanometers from an adjacent cavity.
</P>
<P>
43. The laminate of claim 4, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 500 nanometers from an adjacent cavity.
</P>
<P>
44. The laminate of claim 1, wherein the perfluoropolyether has less than about 10 percent sol fraction.
</P>
<P>
45. A method of making a laminate nanomold; comprising:
</P>
<P>
positioning a patterned master adjacent to a support layer;
</P>
<P>
inserting the positioned patterned master and adjacent support layer between nips of a roll laminator;
</P>
<P>
delivering a curable perfluoropolyether between the patterned master and the support layer adjacent an input side of the roll laminator;
</P>
<P>
activating the roll laminator to laminate the patterned master with the support layer, wherein the curable perfluoropolyether is dispersed between the patterned master and the support layer; and
</P>
<P>
treating the laminate to activate a curable component of the curable perfluoropolyether such that the perfluoropolyether is solidified.
</P>
<P>
46. The method of claim 45, further comprising before positioning the patterned master adjacent the support layer, configuring a tie-layer with the support layer such that when activated the curable perfluoropolyether binds with the tie-layer.
</P>
<P>
47. The method of claim 46, wherein the tie-layer comprises a dual cure material.
</P>
<P>
48. The method of claim 45, wherein the patterned master includes a plurality of cavities comprising a predetermined shape selected from the group consisting of cylindrical, 200 nm diameter cylinders, cuboidal, 200 nm cuboidal, crescent, and concave disc.
</P>
<P>
49. The method of claim 48, wherein the plurality of cavities comprise cavities of a variety of predetermined shapes.
</P>
<P>
50. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 10 micrometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
51. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 5 micrometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
52. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 1 micrometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
53. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 750 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
54. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 500 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
55. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 300 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
56. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 200 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
57. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 100 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
58. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 75 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
59. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 50 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
60. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 40 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
61. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 30 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
62. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 20 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
63. The method of claim 48, wherein each cavity of the plurality of cavities is less than about 10 nanometers in a largest dimension.
</P>
<P>
64. The method of claim 45, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 50 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
65. The method of claim 45, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 40 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
66. The method of claim 45, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 30 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
67. The method of claim 45, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 20 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
68. The method of claim 45, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 15 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
69. The method of claim 45, wherein the perfluoropolyether layer is less than about 10 micrometers thick.
</P>
<P>
70. The method of claim 45, wherein the support layer comprises a polymer.
</P>
<P>
71. The method of claim 70, wherein the polymer of the support layer comprises polyethylene terephthalate.
</P>
<P>
72. A laminate polymer mold, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a first polymer layer;
</P>
<P>
a second polymer layer; and
</P>
<P>
a tie-layer disposed between the first polymer layer and the second polymer layer, wherein the tie-layer comprises a dual cure fluoropolymer.
</P>
<P>
73. The laminate polymer mold of claim 72, wherein the polymer of the first or second layers includes a fluoropolymer.
</P>
<P>
74. The laminate polymer mold of claim 73, wherein the polymer of the first or second layers includes a perfluoropolyether.
</P>
<P>
75. The laminate polymer mold of claim 72, wherein the polymer of the first or second layers includes a polyethylene terephthalate.
</P>
<P>
76. The laminate polymer mold of claim 72, wherein the fluoropolymer of the tie-layer includes a perfluoropolyether.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008131692A1;US8128393B2;WO2008143650A2;WO2008143650A3;KR20090096493A;JP2010511544A;CN101668594A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
