<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYCARBONATE RESIN COMPOSITION AND PROCESS FOR PRODUCING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2172521A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SOUMA MINORU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MOROHOSHI KATSUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ITOU TOMOHIRO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KAI YASUAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MURAMATSU HIRONOBU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ODA TAKASHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UNNO HARUO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UESUGI KENJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SOUMA, MINORU
</Name>
<Name>
MOROHOSHI, KATSUMI
</Name>
<Name>
ITOU, TOMOHIRO
</Name>
<Name>
KAI, YASUAKI
</Name>
<Name>
MURAMATSU, HIRONOBU
</Name>
<Name>
ODA, TAKASHI
</Name>
<Name>
UNNO, HARUO
</Name>
<Name>
UESUGI, KENJI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MITSUBISHI CHEM CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NISSAN MOTOR [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUBISHI CHEMICAL CORPORATION
</Name>
<Name>
NISSAN MOTOR CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2172521
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080791040
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP62482
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070185846
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08J3/20
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/22
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/42
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/521
</Class>
<Class>
C08K5/524
</Class>
<Class>
C08L69/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/205D
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/20E
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/215
</Class>
<Class>
C08J3/21D
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
There is provided a polycarbonate resin composition containing aluminum oxide nanoparticles and being capable of showing good moldability and retention heat stability and combining high transparency and dimensional stability with excellent mechanical properties. The polycarbonate resin composition is characterized by containing an organic acid and aluminum oxide and in that: the resin composition has a melt mass flow rate of 11 g/10min or higher as measured according to JIS K 7210 under the conditions of a temperature of 280 DEG C, a nominal load of 2.16 Kg and a nozzle dimension L/D of 8/2;  and a No.2 dumbbell-shaped specimen according to JIS K 7113 formed by heat-press molding the resin composition into a film of 0.2 mm in thickness and cutting the film has a breaking stress of 8 MPa or higher as measured under the conditions of a temperature of 23 DEG C, a humidity of 50%RH and a tensile rate of 50 mm/min. The organic acid is preferably an organic sulfonic acid having a carbon number of 8 or greater, more preferably the one containing an aromatic ring in the molecule.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A polycarbonate resin composition containing an organic acid and aluminum oxide,
</P>
<P>
wherein the resin composition has a melt mass flow rate of 11 g/10min or higher as measured according to JIS K 7210 under the conditions of a temperature of 280[deg.]C, a nominal load of 2.16 Kg and a nozzle dimension L/D of 8/2; and
</P>
<P>
wherein a No.2 dumbbell-shaped specimen according to JIS K 7113 formed by heat-press molding the resin composition into a film of 0.2 mm in thickness and cutting the film has a breaking stress of 8 MPa or higher as measured under the conditions of a temperature of 23[deg.]C, a humidity of 50%RH and a tensile rate of 50 mm/min.
</P>
<P>
2. The polycarbonate resin composition according to claim 1, wherein the film of 0.2 mm thickness formed by heat press molding the resin composition has an elastic modulus of 2.7 GPa or higher as measured according to JIS K7171 under the conditions of a temperature of 23[deg.]C and a humidity of 50% RH.
</P>
<P>
3. The polycarbonate resin composition according to claim 2, wherein the film of 0.2 mm thickness formed by heat press molding the resin composition has a haze value of 20 or smaller as measured according to JIS K 7105.
</P>
<P>
4. The polycarbonate resin composition according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the organic acid is a sulfonic acid having a carbon number of 8 or greater.
</P>
<P>
5. The polycarbonate resin composition according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the organic acid has an aromatic ring in the molecule.
</P>
<P>
6. The polycarbonate resin composition according to any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the organic acid is contained in an amount of 5 parts by weight or more per 100 parts by weight of the aluminum oxide.
</P>
<P>
7. The polycarbonate resin composition according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein the aluminum oxide is contained in an amount of 3 to 70% by weight.
</P>
<P>
8. The polycarbonate resin composition according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the aluminum oxide has an aspect ratio of 5 or greater.
</P>
<P>
9. The polycarbonate resin composition according to any one of claims 1 to 8, wherein the aluminum oxide is one kind or two or more kinds selected from the group consisting of boehmite and pseudo boehmite.
</P>
<P>
10. A production process of a polycarbonate resin composition, comprising:
</P>
<P>
treating aluminum oxide with an organic acid having a carbon number of 8 or greater; and then
</P>
<P>
mixing the aluminum oxide with a polycarbonate resin.
</P>
<P>
11. The production process of the polycarbonate resin composition according to claim 10, wherein the mixing of the aluminum oxide and the polycarbonate resin is performed using a dispersion liquid of the aluminum oxide and/or a solution of the polycarbonate resin.
</P>
<P>
12. The production process of the polycarbonate resin composition according to claim 10, wherein the mixing of the aluminum oxide and the polycarbonate resin is performed by melt-mixing the polycarbonate resin with a powder of the aluminum oxide.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010256270A1;US8207250B2;JP2009041001A;WO2009011278A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
