<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CARBON NANOFIBER, METHOD FOR PRODUCING THE SAME, AND USE OF THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2159308A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ORIJI GAKU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KAMBARA EIJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ORIJI, GAKU
</Name>
<Name>
KAMBARA, EIJI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SHOWA DENKO KK [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHOWA DENKO K.K
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2159308
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080764903
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP59985
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070145225
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-31
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J23/847
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/847B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02B2
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02B6
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/08
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127D
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to (1) carbon nanofiber containing iron (Fe) of 6 mass % or less and vanadium. (V) of 3 mass % or less as a metal impurity other than carbon, which does not substantially contain metal elements other than Fe and V, (2) a method for producing carbon nanofiber characterized in contacting a catalyst in which Fe and V are supported on a carbon support and a carbon-containing compound at a high temperature, (3) a resin composite material in which the carbon nanofiber is blended and (4) use thereof. According to the invention, an inexpensive carbon fiber filler material can be obtained which has a low content of metal impurities and enables to exhibit electric conductivity when added to resin in a small amount.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Carbon nanofiber containing iron (Fe) of 6 mass % or less and vanadium (V) of 3 mass % or less as a metal element other than carbon, which does not substantially contain metal elements other than Fe and V.
</P>
<P>
2. A method for producing carbon nanofiber characterized in contacting a catalyst in which Fe and V are supported on a carbon support and a carbon-containing compound at a temperature of 400 to 1100[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
3. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, wherein the specific surface area of the carbon support is 30 to 500 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
4. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, wherein the carbon support is carbon black having specific surface area of 500 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g or more subjected to heat treatment at 2000 to 3000[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
5. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, wherein the catalyst having an iron concentration of 5 to 30 mass % is used when the iron concentration in the catalyst is calculated by the following formula:
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, using a catalyst wherein a vanadium concentration in the catalyst is 20 to 100 mol % based on the number of moles of the iron.
</P>
<P>
7. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, wherein the carbon-containing compound is at least one member selected from CO, CO2, aliphatic hydrocarbon and aromatic hydrocarbon.
</P>
<P>
8. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, wherein the carbon-containing compound is ethylene.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 2, wherein a carrier gas is used in addition to the carbon-containing compound.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for producing carbon nanofiber as claimed in claim 9, wherein the carrier gas is a gas containing hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
11. Carbon nanofiber obtained by a method claimed in any one of claims 2 to 10.
</P>
<P>
12. A composite material of carbon nanofiber and resin, wherein the carbon nanofiber claimed in claim 1 or 11 is blended into resin.
</P>
<P>
13. A container for electric or electronic devices using the composite material of carbon nanofiber and resin claimed in claim 12.
</P>
<P>
14. An electroconductive slide member using the composite material of carbon nanofiber and resin claimed in claim 12.
</P>
<P>
15. An electroconductive and thermally-conductive member using the composite material of carbon nanofiber and resin claimed in claim 12.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2159308A4;US2011089365A1;TW200912061A;KR20100014263A;WO2008149792A1;CN101600824A;CN101600824B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
