<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOEMULSION THERAPEUTIC COMPOSITIONS AND METHODS OF USING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2152304A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BAKER JAMES R JR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RATHINAVELU SIVAPRAKASH [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MAKIDON PAUL E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LIPUMA JOHN J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NIGAVEKAR SHRADDHA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BAKER, JAMES R.,JR
</Name>
<Name>
RATHINAVELU, SIVAPRAKASH
</Name>
<Name>
MAKIDON, PAUL E
</Name>
<Name>
LIPUMA, JOHN J
</Name>
<Name>
NIGAVEKAR, SHRADDHA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV MICHIGAN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2152304
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080747554
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US62506
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070927309P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A23L1/03
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/22
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/337
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/573
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/7048
</Class>
<Class>
A61K35/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K36/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K39/12
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/107
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A23L1/035
</Class>
<Class>
A23L1/30M
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/22
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/337
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/573
</Class>
<Class>
A61K31/7048
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00M20B5
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/107D
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to methods and compositions for treating pulmonary infection. In particular, the present invention provides nanoemulsion compositions and methods of using the same to treat bacteria associated with biofilms (e.g., found in pulmonary infections). Compositions and methods of the present invention find use in, among other things, clinical (e.g. therapeutic and preventative medicine), industrial, and research applications.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
We Claim:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for killing and/or inhibiting growth of bacteria associated with a biofilm comprising:
</P>
<P>
A) providing: i) bacteria associated with a biofilm; and ii) a composition comprising: a nanoemulsion and ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid
</P>
<P>
(EDTA), wherein said nanoemulsion comprises: a) about 5 vol. % of Poloxamer-407; b) about 8 vol. % of ethanol; c) about 1 vol. % of cetylpyridinium chloride (CPC); d) about 64 vol. % of oil (e.g., soybean oil), and e) about 22 vol. % of water; and
</P>
<P>
B) exposing said bacteria associated with a biofilm to said composition under conditions such that said composition kills and/or inhibits growth of said bacteria.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said composition further comprises a hypertonic salt solution.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of Claim 2, wherein said hypertonic salt solution is a 7% sodium chloride solution.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said nanoemulsion comprises 10 mM - 20 mM EDTA.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of Claim 4, wherein said nanoemulsion comprises 20 mM EDTA.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said nanoemulsion comprises droplets having an average diameter of about 400 nM.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said nanoemulsion is administerd via pulmonary administration.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of Claim 7, wherein a nebulizer is utilized for said pulmonary administration.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said nanoemulsion is co-administered with an antimicrobial agent.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1, wherein said composition comprises 20% nanoemulsion.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said bacteria associated with a biofilm reside within the pulmonary system of a subject.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of Claim 11 , wherein said subject displays signs and/or symptoms of a respiratory infection.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said bacteria associated with a biofilm reside on and/or within a subject with cystic fibrosis.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of Claim 1, wherein said bacteria associated with a biofilm are selected from the group consisting of Burkholderia cepacia and Ps eudomonas aeruginosa.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of Claim 1 , wherein said bacteria associated with a biofilm is an Acinetobacter species.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of Claim 1, wherein said bacteria associated with a biofilm is selected from the group consisting of a Burkholderia multivorans , B. cenocepacia, B. stabilis, B. vietnamiensis , B. dolosa, B. ambifaria, B. anthina, B. pyrrocinia, B. gladioli,, Achromobacter xylosoxidans , Stenotrophomonas maltophilia, Pandoraea apista, Pandoraea pnomenusa, Pandoraea pulmonicola, Pandoraea norimburgensis , Pandoraea sputorum, Ralstonia mannitolilytica, Ralstonia pickettii, Staphylococcus aureus, Streptococcus pneumonia, Moraxella, M. tuberculosis, Klebsiella, Haemophilus influenzae and Staphylococcus epidermidis.
</P>
<P>
17. A composition comprising: a) a nanoemulsion; b) ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA); and c) a hypertonic salt solution.
</P>
<P>
18. The composition of Claim 17, wherein said composition comprises 20 mM EDTA.
</P>
<P>
19. The composition of Claim 17, wherein said nanoemulsion comprises: a) about 5 vol. % of Poloxamer-407; b) about 8 vol. % of ethanol; c) about 1 vol. % of cetylpyridinium chloride (CPC); d) about 64 vol. % of oil (e.g., soybean oil), and e) about 22 vol. % of water.
</P>
<P>
20. The composition of Claim 17, wherein said hypertonic salt solution is a 7% sodium chloride solution.
</P>
<P>
21. The composition of Claim 17, wherein said composition is an aerosolized solution.
</P>
<P>
22. The composition of Claim 17, wherein said nanoemulsion comprises droplets having an average diameter of about 400 nM.
</P>
<P>
23. A method of treating a subject comprising: a) providing a subject, wherein said subject exhibits signs and/or symptoms of a respiratory infection; b) a composition comprising a nanoemulsion; and b) administering said composition to said subject under conditions such that said signs and/or symptoms of respiratory infection are ameliorated in said subject.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of Claim 23, wherein said respiratory infection is a microbial infection.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of Claim 23, wherein said subject is selected from the group consisting of a subject with bronchitis, a subject with bronchiectasis, a subject with pneumonia, a subject with tuberculosis, a subject with cystic fibrosis, and a subject with emphysema radiation pneumonitis.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of Claim 23, wherein said microbial infection is selected from the group consisting of bacterial infection, fungal infection, viral infection, and a combination of two or more of the same.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of Claim 26, wherein said bacterial infection is caused by bacteria selected from the group consisting of Burkholderia cepacia and Pseudomonas aeruginosa.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of Claim 23, wherein said nanoemulsion comprises EDTA.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of Claim 28, wherein said nanoemulsion comprises 10 mM - 20 mM EDTA.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of Claim 23, wherein said nanoemulsion is P4075EC.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of Claim 23, wherein said nanoemulsion is administerd via pulmonary administration.
</P>
<P>
32. The method of Claim 23, wherein said nanoemulsion is co-administered with an antimicrobial agent.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of Claim 32, wherein said antimicrobial agent is an antibiotic.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 23, wherein said composition comprises 20% nanoemulsion.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of Claim 23, wherein said nanoemulsion is co-administered with a hypertonic salt solution.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of Claim 35, wherein said hypertonic salt solution is a 6%-7% sodium chloride solution.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008137747A1;US2008317799A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
