<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
A method for the production of conductive and transparent nano- coatings
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2154212A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GARBAR ARKADY [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
DE LA VEGA FERNANDO [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
MATZNER EINAT [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
GARBAR, ARKADY
</Name>
<Name>
DE LA VEGA, FERNANDO
</Name>
<Name>
MATZNER, EINAT
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CIMA NANO TECH ISRAEL LTD [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
CIMA NANO TECH ISRAEL LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2154212
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090174803
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-06-12
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030730448
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-06-12
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20020387919P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-06-13
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09D101/10
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D175/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09D201/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/38
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12
</Class>
<Class>
C23C24/08
</Class>
<Class>
C23C30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/22
</Class>
<Class>
H05K1/09
</Class>
<Class>
H05K3/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D11/52
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/38
</Class>
<Class>
C23C24/08
</Class>
<Class>
C23C30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/22
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides for a cost-effective method for coating a substrate by conductive and/or transparent nano-powders in either ordered or random pattern, wherein said pattern is obtained either spontaneously or as a result of a printing technique. The present invention also provides for a conductive and transparent coating layer comprising metal nano-powders, and for conductive and transparent ink characterized by self-assembled network pattern, coating a substrata without altering significantly its transparency and/or conductivity characterizations.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for the production of transparent and conductive coatings comprising metal nanopowders, said method comprising:
</P>
<P>
a. admixing the following ingredients in the manner that an emulsion is formed:
</P>
<P>
(i) metal nano-powder; (ii) an organic solvent; (iii); water, water-miscible solvent, or mixture of water-miscible solvents; and (iv) at least one ingredient of the group selected from binder, surfactant, additive, polymer, buffer, dispersant, and/or coupling agent;
</P>
<P>
b. applying the emulsion on a surface to be coated;
</P>
<P>
c. evaporating (i) the organic solvent and (ii) the water, water-miscible solvent or mixture of water-miscible solvents from the emulsion in the manner that a self-assembled network-like pattern is developed in situ; and
</P>
<P>
d. sintering the network-like pattern to form a transparent and conductive coating on the surface.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1, wherein the sintering step is conducted at a temperature in the range of 50[deg.]C to 150[deg.]C for 2 to 30 minutes.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 1, wherein the concentration of the metal nano-powder in the emulsion is between 1% (wt) and 50% (wt).
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 1, wherein the concentration of the metal nano-powder in the emulsion is between 2% (wt) and 10% (wt).
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 1, wherein the concentration of water, water-miscible solvent, or mixture of water-miscible solvents in the emulsion is between 5% (wt) and 70% (wt).
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 1, wherein the concentration of water, water-miscible solvent, or mixture of water-miscible solvents in the emulsion is between 15% (wt) and 55% (wt).
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to claim 1, wherein the surface to be coated is selected from glass, flexible polymeric films or sheets, relatively non-flexible polymeric films or sheets, polyethylene products, polypropylene products, acrylate-containing products, polymethylmethacrylate (PMMA), copolymers, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to claim 1, wherein the surface to be coated is a polymeric film selected from polyesters, polyamides, polycarbonates, polyethylene, polypropylene, copolymers thereof, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to claim 1, wherein the metal nano-powder is selected from silver, gold, platinum, palladium, nickel, cobalt, copper, or combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. The method according to claim 1, wherein the metal nano-powder is characterized by a D90 value of less than 0.1 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
11. The method according to claim 1, wherein the additive is selected from the group consisting of a metal colloid, metal reducible salt, organic metal complex, organo-metal compounds that decompose to form conductive materials, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The method according to claim 1, comprising applying the emulsion to the surface according to an ordered or random pattern.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to claim 1, wherein the transparent and conductive coating is characterized by a light transparency between 40% and 90% in the visible range of 400 nm to 700 nm, a resistance between 0.1 ohms/square and 9,000 ohms/square, and a haze value between 1% and 10%.
</P>
<P>
14. A conductive and transparent coating produced according to the method of any one of claims 1-13.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO03106573A1;KR20110049923A;KR20060012542A;KR101043307B1;JP2005530005A;HK1083223A1;ES2336779T3;EP1521811A1;EP1521811B1;CN1668712A;CN1322075C;AU2003241128A1;AT450581T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
