<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CNT-INFUSED FIBER AND METHOD THEREFOR
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2115191A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SHAH TUSHAR K [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GARDNER SLADE H [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ALBERDING MARK R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SHAH, TUSHAR, K
</Name>
<Name>
GARDNER, SLADE, H
</Name>
<Name>
ALBERDING, MARK, R
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LOCKHEED CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LOCKHEED MARTIN CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2115191
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070869060
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US86875
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070619327
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-03
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
D01F11/12
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D01F11/12H
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/12
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/127D4
</Class>
<Class>
D01F9/133
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A carbon nanotube-infused fiber and a method for its production are disclosed. Nanotubes are synthesized directly on a parent fiber by first applying a catalyst to the fiber. The properties of the carbon nanotube-infused fiber will be a combination of those of the parent fiber as well as those of the infused carbon nanotubes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method comprising :
</P>
<P>
(a) disposing a carbon-nanotube forming catalyst on a surface of a parent fiber; and
</P>
<P>
(b) synthesizing carbon nanotubes directly on said parent fiber, thereby forming carbon nanotube-infused fiber.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 further comprising spreading said parent fiber before disposing said catalyst on said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 further comprising removing a sizing material from said parent fiber before disposing said catalyst on said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1 wherein said catalyst is a transition metal catalyst.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 wherein the operation of disposing said catalyst on said parent fiber further comprises:
</P>
<P>
(a) forming a solution of said catalyst in a liquid;
</P>
<P>
(b) spraying said solution on to said catalyst.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1 further comprising heating said fiber after disposing said catalyst on said parent fiber, wherein said fiber is heated to a softening temperature.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1 further comprising heating said fiber after disposing said catalyst on said parent fiber, wherein said fiber is heated to a temperature that is between about 500 [deg.]C and 1000 [deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1 wherein said parent fiber is carbon fiber and wherein the method further comprises heating said fiber after disposing said catalyst on said parent fiber, wherein said fiber is heated to about 800 [deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1 wherein the operation of synthesizing carbon nanotubes further comprises:
</P>
<P>
(a) forming a carbon plasma; and
</P>
<P>
(b) directing said carbon plasma onto the catalyst-laden parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1 further comprising applying resin to said carbon nanotube-infused fiber.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10 further comprising winding said carbon nanotube- infused fiber about a mandrel after applying said resin.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 10 wherein said parent fiber is selected from the group consisting of graphite tow and glass roving.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 1 further comprising synthesizing a first amount of said carbon nanotubes on said parent fiber, wherein said first amount is selected so that said carbon nanotube-infused fiber exhibits a second group of properties that differ from a first group of properties exhibited by said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13 wherein said first group of properties and said second group of properties include at least some of the same properties, and further wherein a value of at least one of said same properties differs between said first group and said second group.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 13 wherein said second group of properties of said carbon nanotube-infused fiber includes a property that is not included among said first group of properties exhibited by said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 1 further comprising depositing a first amount of said carbon nanotubes, wherein said first amount is selected so that the value of at least one property selected from the group consisting of tensile strength, Young&apos;s Modulus, density, electrical conductivity, and thermal conductivity of said carbon nanotube-infused fiber differs from the value of said at least one property of said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
17. A method comprising : removing sizing material from a parent fiber; applying a carbon nanotube-forming catalyst to said parent fiber after sizing removal; heating said fiber to at least 500 [deg.]C; and synthesizing carbon nanotubes on said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
18. A composition comprising a carbon nanotube-infused fiber, wherein said carbon nanotube-infused fiber comprises: a parent fiber; and carbon nanotubes covalently bonded to said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
19. The composition of claim 18 wherein the electrical resistivity of said carbon nanotube-infused fiber is lower than the electrical resistivity of said parent fiber.
</P>
<P>
20. The carbon nanotube-infused fiber of claim 17 wherein said composition further comprises a resin.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008085634A1;ZA200904640A;US2012065300A1;US2010276072A1;US8158217B2;KR20090086277A;JP2010531934A;EP2290139A1;EP2290139B1;EP2261404A1;CA2673891A1;AU2007342249A1;AT557118T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
