<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
COSMETIC COMPOSITION CONTAINING NOVEL FRACTAL PARTICLE- BASED GELS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2125176A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BROWN STEVEN E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CURTIS ERNEST S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BROWN, STEVEN E
</Name>
<Name>
CURTIS, ERNEST S
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
AVON PROD INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
AVON PRODUCTS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2125176
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070868794
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US85170
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060643583
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/06
</Class>
<Class>
B01F3/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/04A
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/19
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/25
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/26
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/27
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/28
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q1/02
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q1/10
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of instantly reducing the appearance of wrinkles and skin imperfections while smoothing the skin, which comprises applying a cosmetic composition comprising a fractal particle based gel.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A cosmetic composition for application to a biologic substrate wherein said composition comprises a fractal gel comprising a first fractal particle and a second fractal particle of opposite surface charge at a given pH.
</P>
<P>
2. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, wherein the cosmetic composition is an emulsion.
</P>
<P>
3. The cosmetic composition of claim 2, wherein the emulsion is an oil-in-water emulsion.
</P>
<P>
4. The cosmetic composition of claim 3, wherein the emulsion is a silicone-in-water emulsion.
</P>
<P>
5. The cosmetic composition as in claim 1, wherein said fractal particles have a diameter of between about 50-300 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. The cosmetic composition as in claim 5, wherein said fractal particles have a diameter of between about 100-250 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. The cosmetic composition as in claim 1, wherein said fractal particles are metal oxide particles selected from the group consisting of fumed silica, fumed alumina, fumed titania, fumed zirconia, fumed ceria, fumed zinc oxide, fumed indium tin oxide, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The cosmetic composition as in claim 1, wherein said fractal particles comprise from about 5% to about 80% by weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
9. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising a solvent.
</P>
<P>
10. The cosmetic composition of claim 9, wherein the solvent is selected from the group consisting of water, organic fluids, silicone fluids, hydrophilic and hydrophobic polymers.
</P>
<P>
11. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising polymeric light diffusing agents selected from the group consisting of nylon, poly(methyl acrylic acid), boron nitride, barium sulfate, polyethylene, polystyrene, ethylene/acrylic acid copolymer, fluorinated hydrocarbons, silicates and silicone, and mixtures and derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising a particle content of about 1% to about 85% solids by weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
13. The cosmetic composition of claim 12, further comprising a particle content of about 10% to about 40% solids by weight of the composition.
</P>
<P>
14. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising a film forming agent.
</P>
<P>
15. The cosmetic composition of claim 20, wherein said film forming agent is selected from the group consisting of cyclopentasiloxane and amino propyldimethicone, cyclomethicone and dimethicone, and a blend of low and high viscosity polydimethylsiloxane.
</P>
<P>
16. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising a pigment.
</P>
<P>
17. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising an emulsifying agent.
</P>
<P>
18. The cosmetic composition of claim 17 wherein said emulsifying agent comprises an oil-in-water emulsifier.
</P>
<P>
19. The cosmetic composition of claim 18, wherein said oil-in-water emulsifier comprises a silicone emulsifier.
</P>
<P>
20. The cosmetic composition of claim 1, further comprising one or more ingredients selected from the group consisting of electrolytes, water, humectants, emollients, moisturizers, anti-wrinkle ingredients, concealers, matte finishing agents, pigments, proteins, anti-oxidants, chelating agents, solvents, emulsifiers, sunscreens, ultraviolet absorbing agents, oil absorbing agents, fragrances, preservatives, pH adjusting agents, and combinations thereof, the ingedients being present in an amount to provide their intended function.
</P>
<P>
21. A foundation composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) a fractal gel network of two or more types of fractal particles having opposite surface charge at a given pH;
</P>
<P>
b) a pigment; and
</P>
<P>
c) a film forming agent.
</P>
<P>
22. A cosmetic composition according to claim 21, wherein such composition is in the form selected from the group consisting of powder, cake, pencil, stick, ointment, cream, milk, lotion, liquid-phase, gel, emulsion, emulsified gel, mousse, foam, spray, wipes. liquid (e.g. suspension or solution), paste, serum, milk, balm, aerosol, liposomes, solid (e.g. pressed powders), anhydrous oil and wax composition.
</P>
<P>
23. A primer composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) a fractal gel network of two or more types of fractal particles having opposite surface charge at a given pH; and
</P>
<P>
b) a film forming agent.
</P>
<P>
24. A cosmetic composition according to claim 22, wherein such composition is in the form selected from the group consisting of powder, cake, pencil, stick, ointment, cream, milk, lotion, liquid-phase, gel, emulsion, emulsified gel, mousse, foam, spray, wipes. liquid (e.g. suspension or solution), paste, serum, milk, balm, aerosol, liposomes, solid (e.g. pressed powders), anhydrous oil and wax composition.
</P>
<P>
25. A cosmetic composition according to claim 1, such that the composition a skin care cosmetic selected from the group consisting of a skin lotion, skin milk, skin cream, gel, foundation, foundation primer base, blush, lip stick, eye shadow, eye liner, nail enamel, concealer, mascara, body make-up product, and sunscreen.
</P>
<P>
26. A cosmetic composition according to claim 1, wherein the composition is a make-up composition and/or a care composition for the skin and lips.
</P>
<P>
27. A method of improving the aesthetic appearance of skin by reducing and/or masking one or more of wrinkles, fine lines, pores, skin imperfections, and skin topology wherein said method comprises the step of applying to the areas of skin to be treated an effective amount of the composition of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
28. A method of improving the aesthetic appearance of skin by reducing and/or masking one or more of wrinkles, fine lines, pores, skin imperfections, and skin topology wherein said method comprises:
</P>
<P>
(a) applying to the areas of skin to be treated an effective amount of the composition of claim 16; and
</P>
<P>
(b) applying any foundation over (a).
</P>
<P>
29. A method of improving the aesthetic appearance of hair comprising the step of applying to the hair to be treated an effective amount of the composition of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 29 wherein the composition further comprises a film former and a pigment.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 30 wherein the hair is at least one eyelash and wherein the application of the cosmetic compositions volumizes the eyelash.
</P>
<P>
32. A cosmetic kit comprising: a) a cosmetic composition as in claim 1; b) instructions on how to use said cosmetic composition; and c) a container for holding both a) and b).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008152681A1;WO2008079559A2;WO2008079559A9;WO2008079559A3;TW200838564A;MX2009005068A;JP2010513543A;CN101616727A;CA2671245A1;AR064611A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
