<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ALIGNMENT SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR A SUBSTRATE IN A NANO- IMPRINT PROCESS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2171537A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NIMMAKAYALA PAWAN K [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI BYUNG-JIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NIMMAKAYALA, PAWAN, K
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI, BYUNG-JIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2171537
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080794586
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US08817
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070951002P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080175258
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
<Class>
G03F9/70D
</Class>
<Class>
G03F9/70M
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A transparent imprint template mold is configured with gratings surrounding the active imprint area. The gratings are fabricated at the same time as the active area and thus accurately define the active area with respect to the gratings. The substrate is positioned in tool coordinates under the template mold. A sensor system generates a beam of optical energy and receives reflected energy only at a specific angular window and is used to locate the template mold. The sensor system is scanned to locate the substrate and the gratings in tool coordinates. In this manner, the relative position of the template mold is determined with respect to the substrate in tool coordinates. The substrate is then accurately positioned with respect to the template mold. The system may be used to track imprinted pattern position relative to the substrate and to determine concentricity of patterns to substrates.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A system for aligning a template mold to a substrate comprising: a sensor system disposed above the template mold and the substrate that generates a beam of optical energy and is configured to receive only portions of the optical energy reflected in an angular window from detection surfaces of the substrate and the template mold; and gratings disposed around an active area of the template mold, wherein the gratings have detection surfaces at a pitch corresponding to a predetermined dimensional increment.
</P>
<P>
2. The system of claim 1, further comprising a tool positioning system for positioning the substrate relative to the template mold in tool coordinates in response to substrate control signals.
</P>
<P>
3. The system of claim 2, further comprising a positioning stage disposed between the sensor system and the substrate, the positioning stage configured to position an active area of the template mold relative to a surface of the substrate in the tool coordinates in response to template control signals.
</P>
<P>
4. The system of claim 3, further comprising a controller for generating the substrate and template control signals and positioning the substrate and template mold relative to the sensor system in response to signals generated by the sensor system responding to variations in received optical energy reflected from the detection surfaces of the gratings and the substrate.
</P>
<P>
5. The system of claim 1, wherein the gratings are formed as imprint features on the template mold at the same time as imprint features of the active area of the template mold are formed.
</P>
<P>
6. The system of claim 1 , wherein the sensor system comprises a laser light emitter that generates the beam of optical energy, and a photo detector sensitive to a frequency of the laser light that receives the portions of the optical energy reflected in an angular window from detection surfaces. 7. The system of claim 6, wherein the laser light emitter and photo detector are relatively positioned such that only laser light reflected within a predetermined angular window from a detection surface impinges on the photo detector.
</P>
<P>
8. The system of claim 1, wherein the gratings are configured as a series of parallel equally spaced rectangular peaks and valleys having a pitch corresponding to a predetermined distance parameter.
</P>
<P>
9. The system of claim 1, wherein the gratings are imprinted on the substrate at the same time features of the active area are imprinted on the substrate.
</P>
<P>
10. The system of claim 1, wherein a chuck holding the substrate is configured with detection surfaces to facilitate locating edges of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The system of claim 9, wherein the imprinted active area on the substrate is located with respect to edges of the substrate by scanning the substrate with the imprinted gratings.
</P>
<P>
12. The system of claim 11, wherein the substrate with imprinted gratins is scanned bi- directionally by the sensor system along an orthogonal axis through a center of the substrate to determine a concentricity of the imprinted active area with respect to edges of the substrate. 13. A method for aligning a template mold to a substrate comprising: placing a sensor system over the template mold and the substrate, the sensor system generating a beam of optical energy and configured to receive only portions of the optical energy reflected in an angular window from the detection surfaces, wherein the sensor system generates sensor signals in response to variations in received optical energy reflected from the detection surfaces of the template mold and the substrate; positioning the template mold in response to control signals to locate the template mold in tool coordinates, wherein the template mold has an active area with imprintable features surrounded by gratings having detection surfaces at a pitch corresponding to a predetermined dimensional increment; positioning the substrate in response to control signals to locate the substrate in tool coordinates, wherein edges of the substrate are configured as detection surfaces; processing the sensor signals in a controller to locate the template mold relative to the substrate in tool coordinates; and generating the control signals to thereby position the substrate accurately with respect to the template mold in the tool coordinates.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13 further comprising: imprinting a pattern of the gratings and the active area on the substrate; scanning the imprinted patterns of the gratings and the active area on the substrate with the sensor system thereby generating sensor signals from detection surfaces corresponding to the substrate edges and detection surfaces on the imprinted gratings; and processing the sensor signals in the controller to locate the imprinted pattern in tool coordinates with respect to the edges of the substrate to determine concentricity of the active area to the substrate to facilitate process control.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 13, wherein the gratings are formed as imprint features on the template mold at the same time as imprint features of the active area of the template mold are formed.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 13, wherein the sensor system comprises a laser light emitter that generates the beam of optical energy and a photo detector, sensitive to a frequency of the laser light, that receives the portions of the optical energy reflected in an angular window from detection surfaces.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of claim 16, wherein the laser light emitter and photo detector are relatively positioned such that only laser light reflected within a predetermined angular window from a detection surface impinges on the photo detector.
</P>
<P>
18. The method of claim 13, wherein the gratings are configured as a series of parallel equally spaced rectangular peaks and valleys having a pitch corresponding to a predetermined distance parameter.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 13, wherein the gratings are imprinted on the substrate at a same time features of the active area are imprinted.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of claim 19 further comprising: scanning the sensor system along an orthogonal axes of the substrate with an imprinted pattern and imprinted grid and recording distances to an inner edge to the grating edge; and subtracting the distances along each orthogonal path to generate a measure of concentricity of the imprinted pattern to the substrate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2171537A4;EP2171537B1;WO2009014655A1;US2011026039A1;US8147731B2;US2009026657A1;US7837907B2;KR20100050462A;JP2010534406A;JP4791597B2;CN101772733A;AT556357T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
