<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FLAME-RETARDANT POLYCARBONATE RESIN COMPOSITION AND MOLDED ARTICLE THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2166038A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HAYATA YUSUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NODERA AKIO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HAYATA, YUSUKE
</Name>
<Name>
NODERA, AKIO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
IDEMITSU KOSAN CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
IDEMITSU KOSAN CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2166038
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080777821
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-03
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP62069
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-03
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070181907
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-11
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08K3/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08L27/18
</Class>
<Class>
C08L51/08
</Class>
<Class>
C08L69/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08L69/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A flame-retardant polycarbonate resin composition and molded articles thereof. The flame-retardant polycarbonate resin composition contains 100 parts by mass of an aromatic polycarbonate resin (A), 0.1 to 5 parts by mass of carbon nanotubes (B) and 0.1 to 10 parts by mass of a polyorganosiloxane-containing graft copolymer (C), capable of being made into thin molded articles which are highly flame retardant even at a thickness as thin as 0.5 mm or less and well balanced in the electroconductivity, impact resistance, and their appearance.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A flame-retardant polycarbonate resin composition which comprises 100 parts by mass of an aromatic polycarbonate resin (A), 0.1 to 5 parts by mass of carbon nanotubes (B) and 0.1 to 10 parts by mass of a polyorganosiloxane-containing graft copolymer (C).
</P>
<P>
2. The flame-retardant polycarbonate resin composition according to claim 1, which further comprises 0.05 to 2 parts by mass of a fibril-forming polytetrafluoroethylene (D).
</P>
<P>
3. The flame-retardant polycarbonate resin composition according to claim 1 or 2, wherein a content of non-crystalline carbon particles in the carbon nanotubes (B) is 10% by mass or less.
</P>
<P>
4. A molded article of the flame-retardant polycarbonate resin composition as defined in claim 1 or 2.
</P>
<P>
5. The molded article according to claim 4, which is for use in automotive parts, electrical or electronic parts or parts of communication equipments.
</P>
<P>
6. The molded article according to claim 4, which is in a form of film or sheet.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2166038A4;EP2166038B1;US2011054107A1;TW200918601A;KR20100031533A;WO2009008326A1;JP2009019090A;CN101679739A;AT542859T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
