<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
VISUALIZATION OF BIOLOGICAL MATERIAL BY THE USE OF COATED CONTRAST AGENTS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2121041A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
AXELSSON OSKAR [NO]
</Name>
<Name>
UVDAL KAJSA [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
AXELSSON, OSKAR
</Name>
<Name>
UVDAL, KAJSA
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SPAGO IMAGING AB [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
SPAGO IMAGING AB
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2121041
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080700227
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-10
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008IB50084
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-10
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070899995P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K49/18
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K49/18R2N
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18R2N2H10
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/18R2N2K6A
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A composition of metal oxide nanoparticles in which individual nanoparticles comprises a core that optionally is coated and the metal oxide comprises a metal oxide lattice in which 5 there are two, three, four or more different kinds of metal ions: A) one of these metal ions is selected among lanthanide ions (typically ions of elements 57- B 71), and ) at least one, two, three or more of the other different kinds of metal ions is selected aamong 10 )i transition metal ions of elements of Groups 3b-7b, 8, 1b, 2b other than the lanthanide b ons of elements 57-71, and/or A ) lanthanide ions other than the kind of lanthanide ion selected in A. typical metal ion of (A) is Gd3+, of (B.a) is Fe3+ and of (B.b) is Tb3+. 1 5A v method for coating core forms of the particles, and the use of the particles for visualizing arious kinds of biological material, e.g. by magnetic resonance, are also provided.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
C L A I M S
</P>
<P>
1. A composition of metal oxide nanoparticles in which individual nanoparticles comprise a core that optionally is coated and the metal oxide comprises a metal oxide lattice in which there are two, three, four or more different kinds of metal ions:
</P>
<P>
A) one of these metal ions is selected among lanthanide ions (typically ions of elements 57-71), and
</P>
<P>
B) at least one, two, three or more of the other different kinds of metal ions is selected among a) transition metal ions of elements of Groups 3b-7b, 8, Ib, 2b other than the lanthanide ions of elements 57-71, and/or b) lanthanide ions other than the kind of lanthanide ion selected in A.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles are paramagnetic, with preference for super paramagnetic.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition of any of claims 1-2, wherein the lanthanide ion according to at least (A) and possibly also (B) is selected among lanthanides that in oxide form are capable of exhibiting one or more unpaired electrons and/or paramagnetism, such as super paramagnetism, either with the lanthanide as the sole metal ion or in combination with another kind of metal ion, such as another transition metal ion of (B) and/or another lanthanide ion.
</P>
<P>
4. The composition of any claim 1-3, wherein the lanthanide ion of (A) is Gd(III+)
</P>
<P>
5. The composition of any of claims 1-4, wherein at least one of the other two, three or more metal ions is selected among transition metal ions of (B. a) with preference for those that in oxide form are capable of exhibiting paramagnetism, such as super paramagnetism, and/or ferromagnetism either with the selected metal ion or in combination with another kind of metal ion, such as another transition metal ion of (B) and/or a lanthanide ion of elements 57-71.
</P>
<P>
6. The composition of any of claims 1-5, wherein one of the other one, two or more different metal ions of (B. a) is iron(III+).
</P>
<P>
7. The composition of any of claims 1-6, wherein the mean size of the cores of the particles is &amp;lt; 50 nm with preference for &amp;lt; 6 nm.
</P>
<P>
8. The composition of any of claims 1-7, wherein the cores are monosized with preferences for the differences in sizes being within 10 nm, such as within 5 nm.
</P>
<P>
9. The composition of any of claims 1-8, wherein the composition is devoid of individual nanoparticles as defined in any of claims 1-6 in which the cores have sizes &amp;gt; 50 nm with preference for being devoid of nanoparticles as defined in any of claims 1-6 in which the cores have sizes &amp;gt; 6 nm.
</P>
<P>
10. The composition of any of claims 1-9, wherein the nanoparticles are capable of giving an MR signal that is the same or higher than for Gd-DTPA with the comparison being performed in water and with other conditions being the same.
</P>
<P>
11. The composition of any of claims 1-10, wherein the ratio r2/ri between the relaxivity constants r2 and ri is at least the same as for Gd-DTPA with the comparison being performed in water and with other conditions being the same.
</P>
<P>
12. The composition of any of claims 1-11, wherein the core in individual nanoparticles comprises crystalline structure, with preference for essentially all nanoparticles as defined in any of claims 1-11 comprising crystalline structure.
</P>
<P>
13. The composition of claim 12, wherein the crystalline structure is selected among crystal structure of pure metal oxide, perovskite structure or garnet structure with the metal moiety being selected to permit the selected crystal structure.
</P>
<P>
14. The composition of any of claims 1-13, wherein at least one of the other different metal ions is selected among lanthanides of (B .b) with preference for lanthanides that are capable of fluorescing, such as among elements 60 (Nd), 62 (Sm), 63 (Eu), 65 (Tb), 66 (Dy), 68 (Er), and 70 (Yb).
</P>
<P>
15. The composition of any of claims 1-14, wherein the nanoparticles are capable of fluorescing.
</P>
<P>
16. The composition of any of claims 1-14, wherein individual nanoparticles comprises a coating that is covalently or adsorptively attached to the core of a nanoparticle, said coating possibly being covalently cross-linked.
</P>
<P>
17. The nanoparticles of claim 16, wherein said coating is hydrophilic.
</P>
<P>
18. The composition of any of claims 16-17, wherein the attachment is covalent, typically (a) via a C-Si linkage in which the Si atom binds to a metal oxide oxygen in the core of a coated nanoparticle, or (b) via the metal part (Me) of the metal oxide (e.g. MexOy), e.g. via a Me-S-C linkage.
</P>
<P>
19. The composition of any of claims 16-17, wherein said coating comprises a covalently attached inorganic skeleton that typically is a polysiloxan and said at least one other metal ion is a transition metal according to (B. a), with preference for Fe(III+).
</P>
<P>
20. The composition of any of claims 16-19, wherein the coating exhibits a plurality of one or more hydrophilic groups at least selected amongst hydroxyls, amides, and alkoxy (with preference for repetitive ethylene oxy).
</P>
<P>
21. The composition of any of claims 16-20, wherein the coating exhibits a targeting group or targeting compound (= ligand) that is capable of affinity binding to a bio-organic target structure.
</P>
<P>
22. The composition according to any of claims 1-21, wherein the nanoparticles are A) mixed with a buffer system, e.g. physiologically acceptable, and/or a suitable non- buffering salt, e.g. physiologically acceptable, and/or B) in dry powder form or as a dispersion in a liquid, e.g. aqueous liquid such as water.
</P>
<P>
23. A method for introducing a covalently attached coating according to any of claims 16-22, comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
A) providing uncoated forms of the nanoparticles (core particles without coat), B) contacting the uncoated forms with a bifunctional reactant that exhibits a) a structure I that is capable of forming a covalent bond between the core particles and the reactant, and b) a structure II that bl) is to be a part of the final coat, or b2) is transformable to such a part, said contacting taking place under conditions allowing the formation of the covalent bond; and
</P>
<P>
C) transforming structure II, if present according to b2, to a part of said coat.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of claim 23, wherein two different kinds of the bifunctional reactant are used for formation of the coat: A) a first bifunctional reactant in which structure II comprises a targeting group (ligand), or a group that is transformable to a targeting group (ligand), and B) a second bifunctional reagent in which the second structure II comprises hydrophilic groups and structures, or a group/structure that is transformable to such coating groups/structures, which two reactants are incubated consecutively or simultaneously.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of any of claims 23-24, wherein two different kinds of the bifunctional reactant are used for formation of the coat:
</P>
<P>
A) a first reactant that comprises a structure I that is nucleophilic and reactive with a metal ion in the surface of the core particle, and
</P>
<P>
B) a second reactant that comprises a structure I that is electrophilic and reactive with metal oxide oxygen in the surface of the core particle, which two reactants are incubated consecutively or simultaneously.
</P>
<P>
26. A method of visualizing biological material, e.g. by magnetic resonance imaging, comprising the steps of: (i) bringing nanoparticles of a composition according to any of claims 1-22 into contact with the material, and (ii) recording the image in a per se known manner.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 26, wherein the material is tissue material, for instance from a vertebrate, such as a mammal.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 27, wherein the tissue material is part of a vertebrate such as a mammal, and step (i) comprises administering a composition comprising a dispersion of the nanoparticles by injection into the vertebrate, for instance into a blood vessel.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of any of claims 25-27, wherein the imaging step (ii) is performed giving a spatial resolution of at least 1 mm, such as at least 0.1 mm, linear voxel dimension.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008096279A1;ZA200905420A;US2010111859A1;US2010119458A1;JP2010518070A;WO2008096280A1;EP2121040A1;CN101663050A;CA2675631A1;AU2008212556A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
