<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
BRIGHTNESS ENHANCING FILM COMPRISING NANOCOMPOSITE STRUCTURE HAVING IMPROVED CRACK RESISTANCE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2118149A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KOLB BRANT U [US]
</Name>
<Name>
JONES CLINTON L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
OLSON DAVID B [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MCKENZIE TAUN L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NAISMITH NATHAN K [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KOLB, BRANT U
</Name>
<Name>
JONES, CLINTON L
</Name>
<Name>
OLSON, DAVID B
</Name>
<Name>
MCKENZIE, TAUN L
</Name>
<Name>
NAISMITH, NATHAN K
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2118149
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080780446
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-02-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US55058
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070891812P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070891840P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070912751P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-19
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070917827P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08F2/44
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/18
</Class>
<Class>
C09D133/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08F2/44
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/18
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Microstructured films such as brightness enhancing films, polymerizable resin compositions comprising an organic component and surface modified nanoparticles, and surface modified nanoparticles are described. The microstructured film has a polymerized structure comprising the reaction product of the polymerizable resin composition (e.g. having a refractive index of at least 1.58). The cured nanocomposite (e.g. structure) can exhibit improved crack resistance. In some embodiments, the flexibility is expressed in terms of a cylindrical mandrel bend test property (e.g. a mandrel size to failure of less than 6 mm or a mandrel size to failure according to the equation D = 1000(T/0.025-T) wherein T is the thickness in millimeters of a (e.g. preformed base layer). In other embodiments, the flexibility is expressed in terms of a tensile and elongation property (e.g. a tensile strength at break of at least 25 MPa and an elongation at break of at least 1.75%).
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A brightness enhancing film having a polymerized structure comprising the reaction product of polymerizable resin composition having a refractive index of at least 1.58 comprising an organic component having at least one di(meth)acrylate aromatic monomer and at least 10 wt-% of surface modified inorganic nanoparticles wherein the brightness enhancing film has a mandrel size to failure of less than 6 mm.
</P>
<P>
2. A brightness enhancing film having a base layer and a polymerized structure disposed on the base layer wherein the polymerized structure comprises the reaction product of polymerizable resin composition having a refractive index of at least 1.58 comprising an organic component having at least one di(meth)acrylate aromatic monomer and at least 10 wt-% of surface modified inorganic nanoparticles wherein the brightness enhancing film has a mandrel size to failure according to the equation D = 1000(T/0.025-T) wherein T is the thickness of the base layer.
</P>
<P>
3. A brightness enhancing film having a polymerized structure comprising the reaction product of polymerizable resin composition having a refractive index of at least 1.58 comprising an organic component and at least 10 wt-% of surface modified inorganic nanoparticles wherein a cured film of the polymerizable resin composition has a tensile strength at break of at least 25 MPa and an elongation at break of at least 1.75%.
</P>
<P>
4. A brightness enhancing film having a polymerized structure comprising the reaction product of a polymerizable resin composition comprising an organic component comprising one or more ethylenically unsaturated monomer(s) or oligomer(s); and at least 10 wt-% inorganic nanoparticles surface modified with a first surface treatment comprising at least one monocarboxylic acid having a non- reactive compatibilizing group, and a second surface treatment comprising at least one non- volatile monocarboxylic acid having a copolymerizable group that reacts with the organic component; wherein the nanoparticles comprise the second surface treatment in a stoichiometric amount greater than the first surface treatment.
</P>
<P>
5. A brightness enhancing film having a polymerized structure comprising the reaction product of a polymerizable resin composition comprising an organic component comprising one or more monofunctional biphenyl monomers in an amount totaling at least 10 wt-% and at least 10 wt-% inorganic nanoparticles surface modified with a first surface treatment comprising at least one monocarboxylic acid having a water soluble tail, and a second surface treatment comprising at least one acrylate functionalized surface modifier prepared by the reaction of an aliphatic anhydride and a hydroxy alkyl acrylate.
</P>
<P>
6. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 3-5 wherein the brightness enhancing film has a mandrel size to failure of less than 6 mm.
</P>
<P>
7. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-5 wherein the polymerizable resin composition has a refractive index of at least 1.61.
</P>
<P>
8. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-5 wherein the polymerizable resin composition has a refractive index of at least 1.645.
</P>
<P>
9. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-4 wherein the organic component comprises at least one biphenyl monomer.
</P>
<P>
10. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 5 or 9 wherein the biphenyl monomer has a Mn of less than 450 g/mole.
</P>
<P>
11. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 5 or 9 wherein the biphenyl monomer has a viscosity of less than 500 cps at 60&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
12. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 5 or 9 wherein the one or more biphenyl monomers are present in an amount ranging from 25 wt-% to 75 wt-% of the organic component.
</P>
<P>
13. The brightness enhancing film of claim 12 wherein the one or more biphenyl monomers are present in an amount ranging from 30 wt-% to 50 wt-% of the organic component.
</P>
<P>
14. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 5 or 9-13 wherein the biphenyl monomer has unsubstituted aromatic rings.
</P>
<P>
15. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 5 or 9-13 wherein the biphenyl monomer comprises a (meth)acrylate group.
</P>
<P>
16. The brightness enhancing film of claim 15 wherein the biphenyl monomer has the general formula:
</P>
<P>
wherein Rl is H or CH3; X is O or S; n ranges from 0 to 10; and
</P>
<P>
L is an alkyl group having 1 to 5 carbon atoms, optionally substituted with hydroxy.
</P>
<P>
17. The brightness enhancing film of claim 15 wherein the biphenyl monomer has the general formula:
</P>
<P>
wherein Rl is H or CH3;
</P>
<P>
X is O or S;
</P>
<P>
Q is selected from - (C(CH3)2-, -CH2, -C(O)-, -S(O)-, and -S(O)2-; n ranges from O to 10; and
</P>
<P>
L is an alkyl group having 1 to 5 carbon atoms, optionally substituted with hydroxy.
</P>
<P>
18. The brightness enhancing film of claims 15-17 wherein the biphenyl monomer comprises an acrylate group.
</P>
<P>
19. The brightness enhancing film of claim 18 wherein the biphenyl monomer is selected from the group consisting of 2-phenyl-phenyl acrylate, 4-(-2-phenyl-2-propyl)phenyl acrylate, 2-phenyl-2-phenoxyethyl acrylate, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The brightness enhancing film of according to any one claims 3-5 wherein the organic component further comprises at least one difunctional ethylenically unsaturated monomer.
</P>
<P>
21. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-2 or 20 wherein the amount of difunctional ethylenically unsaturated monomer ranges from 5 wt-% to 80 wt-
</P>
<P>
% of the organic component.
</P>
<P>
22. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-2 or 20 wherein the difunctional ethylenically unsaturated monomer is an aromatic (meth)acrylate monomer.
</P>
<P>
23. The brightness enhancing film of claims 22 wherein the difunctional ethylenically unsaturated monomer comprises a major portion having the structure
</P>
<P>
wherein Rl is independently hydrogen or methyl,
</P>
<P>
R2 is independently H or Br,
</P>
<P>
Z is independently -C(CHs)2-, -CH2-, -C(O)-, -S-, -S(O)-, or -S(O)2-, and
</P>
<P>
L is a linking group independently selected from linear and branched C2- Ci2 alkyl groups wherein the carbon chain is optionally substituted with one or more oxygen group and/or the carbon atoms are optionally substituted with one or more hydroxyl groups.
</P>
<P>
24. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 5 or 8-19 wherein the organic component further comprises up to 25 wt-% of one or more mono functional
</P>
<P>
(meth)acrylate monomers having a refractive index lower than the biphenyl monomer.
</P>
<P>
25. The brightness enhancing film of any of the previous claims wherein the polymerizable resin comprises less than 5 wt-% of a crosslinker having at least three ethylenically unsaturated groups.
</P>
<P>
26. The brightness enhancing film of any of the previous claims wherein the inorganic nanoparticles comprise adsorbed non-reactive volatile acid and the acid content of the brightness enhancing film is less than 5 wt-%.
</P>
<P>
27. The brightness enhancing film of any of the previous claims wherein the polymerizable resin composition is free of silane surface treatments.
</P>
<P>
28. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-5 wherein the inorganic nanoparticles comprise a first surface treatment having the general formula:
</P>
<P>
CH3 -[O-(CH2)y ]x -X2 -(CH2)n -COOH
</P>
<P>
wherein X2 is selected from the group consisting of -O- , -S-, -C(O)O- and - C(O)NH; n ranges from about 1-3; x ranges from about 1-10; and y ranges from about 1-4.
</P>
<P>
29. The brightness enhancing film of claim 28 wherein the first surface treatment is selected from the group consisting of 2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy] acetic acid, 2-(2- methoxyethoxy) acetic acid, succinic acid mono-[2-(2-methoxy-ethoxy)-ethyl] ester, maleic acid mono-[2-(2-methoxy-ethoxy)-ethyl] ester, and glutaric acid mono-[2-(2- methoxy-ethoxy)-ethyl] ester, succinic acid mono-2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy] ethyl ester, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
30. The brightness enhancing film according to any one of claims 1-5 wherein the inorganic nanoparticles comprise a second surface treatment selected from the group consisting of succinic acid mono-(2-acryloyloxy-ethyl) ester, maleic acid mono-(2- acryloyloxy-ethyl) ester, and glutaric acid mono-(2-acryloyloxy-ethyl) ester, maleic acid mono-(4-acryloyloxy-butyl) ester, succinic acid mono-(4-acryloyloxy-butyl) ester, glutaric acid mono-(4-acryloyloxy-butyl)ester.
</P>
<P>
31. The brightness enhancing film of any of the previous claims wherein the amount of inorganic nanoparticles ranges from 40 wt-% to 60 wt-%.
</P>
<P>
32. The brightness enhancing film of any of the preceding claims wherein the inorganic nanoparticles have a refractive index of at least 1.68.
</P>
<P>
33. The brightness enhancing film of claim 32 wherein the inorganic nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of zirconia, titania, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
34. The brightness enhancing film of claim 33 wherein the inorganic nanoparticle consist of zirconia.
</P>
<P>
35. A polymerizable resin composition having a refractive index of at least 1.58 comprising an organic component and at least 10 wt-% of surface modified inorganic nanoparticles wherein a cured film of the polymerizable resin composition has a tensile strength at break of at least 25 MPa and an elongation at break of at least 2%.
</P>
<P>
36. A polymerizable resin composition comprising an organic component and at least 10 wt-% of surface modified inorganic nanoparticles comprising adsorbed non-reactive volatile acid wherein a cured film of the polymerizable resin composition has a tensile strength at break of at least 25 MPa and an elongation at break of at least 2%.
</P>
<P>
37. A polymerizable resin composition comprising an organic component comprising one or more ethylenically unsaturated monomer(s) or oligomer(s); and at least 10 wt-% inorganic nanoparticles surface modified with a first surface treatment comprising at least one monocarboxylic acid having a non- reactive compatibilizing group, and a second surface treatment comprising at least one non-volatile monocarboxylic acid having a copolymerizable group that reacts with the organic component; wherein the nanoparticles comprise the second surface treatment in a stoichiometric amount than the first surface treatment.
</P>
<P>
38. A polymerizable resin composition comprising an organic component comprising one or more monofunctional biphenyl monomers in an amount totaling at least 10 wt-%; and at least 10 wt-% inorganic nanoparticles surface modified with i) at least one monocarboxylic acid having a water soluble tail, and ii) at least one acrylate functionalized surface modifier prepared by the reaction of an aliphatic anhydride and a hydroxy alkyl acrylate.
</P>
<P>
39. The polymerizable resin composition according to any one of claim 35-38 wherein the amount of inorganic nanoparticles ranges from 40 wt-% to 60 wt-%.
</P>
<P>
40. The polymerizable resin composition according to any one of claim 35-38 wherein the inorganic nanoparticles have a refractive index of at least 1.68.
</P>
<P>
41. The polymerizable resin composition according to any one of claims 35-38 wherein the polymerizable resin composition comprises 40 wt-% to 60 wt-% of surface modified inorganic nanoparticles, the nanoparticles having a refractive index of at least 1.68.
</P>
<P>
42. The polymerizable resin composition of claim 40 wherein the inorganic nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of zirconia, titania, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
43. The polymerizable resin composition according to any one of claim 35-42 wherein the surface modified inorganic nanoparticles comprise adsorbed non-reactive volatile acid and the acid content of the brightness enhancing film is less than 5 wt-%.
</P>
<P>
44. The polymerizable resin composition according to any one of claim 35-42 wherein the polymerizable resin composition is free of silane surface treatments.
</P>
<P>
45. An optical article comprising the reaction product of the polymerizable composition of claim 35-42.
</P>
<P>
46. An optical film having a microstructured surface wherein the microstructured surface comprises the reaction product of the polymerizable composition of claim 45.
</P>
<P>
47. Inorganic nanoparticles surface modified with a first surface treatment comprising at least one monocarboxylic acid having a non- reactive compatibilizing group, and a second surface treatment comprising at least one non-volatile monocarboxylic acid having a copolymerizable group that reacts with the organic component; wherein the nanoparticles comprise the second surface treatment in a stoichiometric amount than the first surface treatment.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2118149B1;WO2008121465A1;US2010033826A1;TW200900723A;KR20090125786A;JP2010519599A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
