<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Inorganic nanoparticles of high density to destroy cells in- vivo
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2130553A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LEVY LAURENT [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
POTTIER AGNES [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
ROUET ANNABELLE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
MARILL JULIE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
DEVAUX CORINNE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
LEVY, LAURENT
</Name>
<Name>
POTTIER, AGNES
</Name>
<Name>
ROUET, ANNABELLE
</Name>
<Name>
MARILL, JULIE
</Name>
<Name>
DEVAUX, CORINNE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NANOBIOTIX [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
NANOBIOTIX
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2130553
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080157686
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080157686
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K41/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K41/00P
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present application relates to novel excitable particles which can be used in the health sector. It more particularly relates to particles which can generate electrons and/or high energy photon when excited by ionizing radiations such as X-Rays and/or electron, and to the uses thereof in health, in particular in human health. The inventive particles are made of an inorganic material comprising oxygen, said material having an adequate density, and can be activated in vitro, ex vivo, or in vivo, by controllable external excitation, in order to disturb, alter or destroy target cells, tissues or organs. The invention also relates to methods for the production of said particles, and to pharmaceutical or medical device compositions containing same.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Use of a nanoparticle or nanoparticle aggregate to prepare a pharmaceutical composition intended to alter or destroy target cells in an animal when said cells are exposed to ionizing radiations, wherein the nanoparticle is made of an inorganic material comprising oxygen, the density of said inorganic material being of at least 7 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
2. Use according to claim 1, wherein said inorganic material is selected from the group consisting of an oxide (MxOy) and a tungstate (Mx(WO4)y).
</P>
<P>
3. Use according to claim 2, wherein the inorganic material comprising oxygen is an oxide and said oxide is selected from the group consisting of CeO2, Nd2O3, Sm2O3, Eu2O3, Gd2O3, Tb2O3, Dy2O3, Ho2O3, Er2O3, Tm2O3, Yb2O3, Lu2O3, HfO2, TaO2, Ta2O5, WO2, WO3, ReO2, OsO2, IrO2, PtO, PtO2, HgO, Hg2O, TI2O3, PbO, Pb2O3, Pb3O4, PbO2, PoO2, Bi2O3, NbO, RuO2, Rh2O3, RhO2, PdO, Ag2O, AgO, CdO, In2O3.
</P>
<P>
4. Use according to claim 3, wherein the inorganic material comprising oxygen is HfO2.
</P>
<P>
5. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the size of the nanoparticle or nanoparticle aggregate is between around 15 and 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the nanoparticle or nanoparticle aggregate is covered with a biocompatible coating.
</P>
<P>
7. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 6, wherein said ionizing radiations are selected in the group consisting of X-Rays, electron beams and radioisotope emissions.
</P>
<P>
8. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 7, wherein the ionizing radiations are of about 2 KeV to about 25 000 KeV.
</P>
<P>
9. Use according to claim 8, wherein the ionizing radiations are of about 2 KeV to 6000 KeV.
</P>
<P>
10. Use according to claim 8, wherein the ionizing radiations are of about 2 KeV to 1500 KeV.
</P>
<P>
11. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 10, wherein the nanoparticle is made of an inorganic material having an effective atomic number (Zeff) of at least 50.
</P>
<P>
12. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 11, wherein the nanoparticle is essentially spherical in shape.
</P>
<P>
13. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 12, wherein target cells are selected in the group consisting of benign cells, pre-malignant cells and malignant cells.
</P>
<P>
14. Use according to claim 13, wherein said malignant cells are cells from a tumor selected in the group consisting of a haematological tumor and a solid tumor.
</P>
<P>
15. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 14, wherein the pharmaceutical composition further comprises an additional therapeutic compound, distinct from a nanoparticle or nanoparticle aggregate, intended to treat cancer.
</P>
<P>
16. Use according to any one of claims 1 to 15, wherein said animal is a human.
</P>
<P>
17. Pharmaceutical composition comprising a nanoparticle or nanoparticle aggregate and a pharmaceutically acceptable excipient, wherein the nanoparticle is made of an inorganic material comprising oxygen, the density of said inorganic material being of at least 7 g/cm&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;, and the nanoparticle or nanoparticle aggregate is covered with a biocompatible coating.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2011213192A1;NZ589888A;MX2010013322A;MA32453B1;KR20110028616A;JP2011524866A;WO2009147214A2;WO2009147214A3;EP2300054A2;EA201071429A1;CN102056628A;CA2727576A1;AU2009254550A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
