<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Use of carbon nanotube for drug delivery.
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2127680A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HIRSCH ANDREAS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
SAGMAN URI [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
WILSON STEPHEN R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HIRSCH, ANDREAS
</Name>
<Name>
SAGMAN, URI
</Name>
<Name>
WILSON, STEPHEN R
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SIXTY INC C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
C SIXTY, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2127680
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090169560
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-02-14
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030739798
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-02-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20020356856P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-02-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K47/48
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61P35/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K47/48W18
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/00H
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Compositions and methods for administering a therapeutic agent to a mammal are disclosed. The compositions comprise either (i) vesicles comprising an amphiphilic substituted fullerene, wherein the therapeutic agent is present in the vesicle interior or between layers of the vesicle wall, (ii) a substituted fullerene, comprising a fullerene core and a functional moiety, wherein the therapeutic agent is associated with the substituted fullerene, or (iii) carbon nanotubes, wherein the therapeutic agent is covalently bonded to the carbon nanotubes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A derivatized carbon nanotube, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a carbon nanotube, and
</P>
<P>
at least one therapeutic agent covalently attached to the carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
2. The derivatized carbon nanotube of claim 1, wherein the carbon nanotube has (10,10) structure.
</P>
<P>
3. The derivatized carbon nanotube of claim 1, wherein the therapeutic agent is an anti-cancer drug.
</P>
<P>
4. The derivatized carbon nanotube of claim 1, further comprising a functional group selected from the group consisting of biotin, biotin-containing moieties, antigen-binding moieties, and tissue-recognition moieties.
</P>
<P>
5. A derivatized carbon nanotube, comprising a carbon nanotube and at least one therapeutic agent covalently attached to the carbon nanotube, for use in a method of delivering a therapeutic agent to a mammal.
</P>
<P>
6. The derivatized carbon nanotube for use according to claim 5, wherein the method further comprises administering to the mammal an adjuvant which promotes disruption of the covalent bond between the carbon nanotube and the at least one therapeutic agent, thereby delivering the at least one therapeutic agent to the mammal.
</P>
<P>
7. The derivatized carbon nanotube for use according to claim 5, wherein the carbon nanotube has (10,10) structure.
</P>
<P>
8. The derivatized carbon nanotube for use according to claim 5, wherein the therapeutic agent is an anti-cancer drug.
</P>
<P>
9. The derivatized carbon nanotube for use according to claim 5, wherein the derivatized carbon nanotube further comprises a functional group selected from the group consisting of biotin, biotin-containing moieties, antigen-binding moieties, and tissue-recognition moieties.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO03068185A2;WO03068185A3;US2003180491A1;US7070810B2;US2006127470A1;JP2006502966A;EP1476198A2;AU2003211042A8;AU2003211042A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
