<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD FOR PRODUCING SOLID SOLUTION FINE PARTICLE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2128093A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BEPPU YOSHIHISA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SUNAHARA KAZUO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
BEPPU, YOSHIHISA
</Name>
<Name>
SUNAHARA, KAZUO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ASAHI GLASS CO LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ASAHI GLASS COMPANY, LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2128093
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080704304
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-31
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP51565
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070024419
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C03C13/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J23/00B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/08
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G25/00D
</Class>
<Class>
C03C10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C03C23/00H
</Class>
<Class>
C03C3/155
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/90C
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E60/50
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Provided is a process for readily producing fine particles of a solid solution having a small particle size, comprising a solid solution of zirconia, ceria and a rare earth oxide in a desired composition, and being highly crystalline. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution comprises the following steps in the order named: obtaining a melt comprising, in terms of mol% on an oxide basis, from 5 to 50% ZrO 2 , CeO 2 and RE 2 O 3 (where RE is at least one member selected from rare earth elements other than Ce) in total, from 10 to 50% RO (where R is at least one member selected from the group consisting of Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba and Zn), and from 30 to 75% B 2 O 3 ;  quenching the melt to obtain an amorphous material;  heating the amorphous material to obtain precipitates containing crystals of a solid solution with ZrO 2 , CeO 2 and RE 2 O 3; ;  and separating the crystals of the solid solution from the precipitates to obtain fine particles of the solid solution.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for producing fine particles of a solid solution, comprising the following steps in the order named:
</P>
<P>
obtaining a melt comprising, in terms of mol% on an oxide basis, from 5 to 50% ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3 (where RE is at least one member selected from rare earth elements other than Ce) in total, from 10 to 50% RO (where R is at least one member selected from the group consisting of Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba and Zn), and from 30 to 75% B2O3;
</P>
<P>
quenching the melt to obtain an amorphous material;
</P>
<P>
heating the amorphous material to obtain precipitates containing crystals of a solid solution with ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3; and
</P>
<P>
separating the crystals of the solid solution from the precipitates to obtain fine particles of the solid solution.
</P>
<P>
2. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to Claim 1, wherein a content of ZrO2 in the melt is from 3 to 95 mol% to the total of ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3.
</P>
<P>
3. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein a content of CeO2 in the melt is from 3 to 95 mol% to the total of ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3.
</P>
<P>
4. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 3, wherein a content of RE2O3 in the melt is from 0.5 to 45 mol% to the total of ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3.
</P>
<P>
5. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 4, wherein a content of RO in the melt is from 10 to 60 mol% to the total of RO and B2O3.
</P>
<P>
6. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 5, wherein the amorphous material is of a flake form or a fiber form.
</P>
<P>
7. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 6, wherein the amorphous material is heated at a temperature of from 600 to 900[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
8. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 7, wherein the crystals of the solid solution are separated by adding an acid into the precipitates.
</P>
<P>
9. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 8, wherein a content of ZrO2 in a chemical composition of the fine particles of the solid solution is from 3 to 97 mol% to the total of ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3.
</P>
<P>
10. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 9, wherein a content of CeO2 in a chemical composition of the fine particles of the solid solution is from 3 to 97 mol% to the total of ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3.
</P>
<P>
11. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 10, wherein a content of RE2O3 in a chemical composition of the fine particles of the solid solution is from 0.1 to 15 mol% to the total of ZrO2, CeO2 and RE2O3.
</P>
<P>
12. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 11, wherein an average primary particle size of the fine particles of the solid solution is from 5 to 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
13. The process for producing the fine particles of the solid solution according to any one of Claims 1 to 12, wherein a specific surface area of the fine particles of the solid solution is at least 20 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2128093A4;US2010022387A1;US7994090B2;WO2008093801A1;CN101595060A;CN101595060B
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
