<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Quantum Semiconductor Device and Method for Fabricating the Same
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2192617A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SONG HAI-ZHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
OHSHIMA TOSHIO [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
SONG, HAI-ZHI
</Name>
<Name>
OHSHIMA, TOSHIO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
FUJITSU LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUJITSU LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2192617
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100155625
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2003-05-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20090161296
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-05-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20030752919
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-05-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20020147287
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-05-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20030034245
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-02-12
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L21/20
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/335
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/12
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/76
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q80/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4A1B3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1B3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/12W4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/66M6T6D
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/76D
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A Quantum semiconductor device comprising: a plurality of quantum dots formed over a semiconductor substrate;  a first semiconductor layer formed, burying the said plurality of quantum dots;  a plurality of semiconductor dots formed on the first semiconductor layer in respective positions above each quantum dot of the said plurality of quantum dots;  a plurality of dot-shaped oxides formed of partially oxidized semiconductor dots;  a second semiconductor layer formed, busying the said plurality of semiconductor dots;  and a plurality of electrodes formed in respective concavities formed in a surface of the second semiconductor layer in respective positions above each dot-shaped oxide of the said plurality of dot-shaped oxides.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A quantum semiconductor device comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of quantum dots formed over a semiconductor substrate;
</P>
<P>
a first semiconductor layer formed, burying the said plurality of quantum dots;
</P>
<P>
a plurality of semiconductor dots formed on the first semiconductor layer in respective positions above each quantum dot of the said plurality of quantum dots;
</P>
<P>
a plurality of dot-shaped oxides formed of partially oxidized semiconductor dots;
</P>
<P>
a second semiconductor layer formed, burying the said plurality of semiconductor dots; and
</P>
<P>
a plurality of electrodes formed in respective concavities formed in a surface of the second semiconductor layer in respective positions above each dot-shaped oxide of the said plurality of dot-shaped oxides.
</P>
<P>
2. A quantum semiconductor device according to claim 1, further comprising
</P>
<P>
an interconnection formed in a trench formed in the surface of the second semiconductor layer and electrically connected to one of the electrodes.
</P>
<P>
3. A method for fabricating a quantum semiconductor device comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
forming a quantum dot on a semiconductor substrate;
</P>
<P>
forming a first semiconductor layer, burying the quantum dot;
</P>
<P>
forming a semiconductor dot on the first semiconductor layer in a position above the quantum dot;
</P>
<P>
oxidizing a part of the semiconductor dot to form a dot-shaped oxide of the partially oxidized semiconductor dot;
</P>
<P>
forming a second semiconductor layer, burying the dot-shaped oxide and the semiconductor dot with a concavity formed in a surface in a position above the dot-shaped oxide, and
</P>
<P>
forming an electrode in the concavity formed in the surface of the second semiconductor layer;wherein in the step of forming the electrode, the electrode is formed by droplet epitaxy method.
</P>
<P>
4. A method for fabricating a quantum semiconductor device according to claim 3, wherein
</P>
<P>
in the step of forming the dot-shaped oxide, a part of the semiconductor dot is oxidized by approaching a probe-shaped conductor to the semiconductor dot and applying a voltage between the semiconductor substrate and the probe-shaped conductor.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2192617A3;EP2192617B1;EP1507293A1;EP1507293A4;US2005173695A1;US7307030B2;US2008067498A1;US7755080B2;WO03098697A1;EP2192616A2;EP2192616A3;EP2096670A2;EP2096670A3;EP2096670B1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
