<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
LITHOGRAPHIC APPARATUS AND DEVICE MANUFACTURING METHOD
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2186386A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
IVANOV VLADIMIR VITALEVITCH [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
BANINE VADIM YEVGENYEVICH [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
KOSHELEV KONSTANTIN NIKOLAEVIT [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
KRIVTSUN VLADIMIR MIHAILOVITCH [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
IVANOV, VLADIMIR VITALEVITCH
</Name>
<Name>
BANINE, VADIM YEVGENYEVICH
</Name>
<Name>
KOSHELEV, KONSTANTIN NIKOLAEVITCH
</Name>
<Name>
KRIVTSUN, VLADIMIR MIHAILOVITCH
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ASML NETHERLANDS BV [NL]
</Name>
<Name>
ASML NETHERLANDS B.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2186386
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080779074
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-08-05
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008NL50536
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-08-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070882853
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-06
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H05G2/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/70B6
</Class>
<Class>
H05G2/00P2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A lithographic system includes a source configured to generate a radiation, the source including a cathode and an anode, the cathode and the anode configured to create a discharge in a fuel located in a discharge space so as to generate a plasma, the discharge space including, in use, a substance configured to adjust radiation emission by the plasma so as to control a volume defined by the plasma;  a pattern support configured to hold a patterning device, the patterning device configured to pattern the radiation to form a patterned beam of radiation;  a substrate support configured to support a substrate;  and a projection system configured to project the patterned beam of radiation onto the substrate.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
WHAT IS CLAIMED IS:
</P>
<P>
1. A method for generating a radiation for use in a lithographic apparatus, the method comprising: supplying a fuel to a discharge space located between a cathode and an anode; creating a discharge between the cathode and the anode in the fuel to form a plasma; and adjusting a volume defined by the plasma by controlling radiation emission by the plasma, the adjusting including supplying a substance to the plasma to control the radiation emission.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 , wherein the substance includes at least one of Ga, In, Bi, Pb or Al.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the fuel includes at least one of Sn, Xe or Li.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of any of the preceding claims, wherein the substance and the fuel are separately supplied to the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of any of the preceding claims, wherein the substance is part of a mixture including the fuel.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 5, wherein the mixture is solid or liquid.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 5 or 6, further comprising supplying the mixture to the cathode before creating the discharge.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of any of the preceding claims, wherein the substance is selected to increase radiation emission in a pre-determined wavelength range.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of any of the preceding claims, wherein adjusting a volume defined by the plasma includes reducing a radial size of the plasma. 10. The method of any of the preceding claims, wherein the adjusting includes controlling the volume defined by the plasma such that an etendue of a radiation source configured to generate the plasma substantially matches an etendue of the lithographic apparatus.
</P>
<P>
11. A device manufacturing method comprising: generating a beam of radiation, the generating including supplying a fuel to a discharge space located between a cathode and an anode; creating a discharge between the cathode and the anode in the fuel to form a plasma; and adjusting a volume defined by the plasma by controlling radiation emission by the plasma, the adjusting including supplying a substance to the plasma to control the radiation emission; patterning the beam of radiation to form a patterned beam of radiation; and projecting the patterned beam of radiation onto a substrate.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 11 , wherein the substance includes at least one of Ga, In, Bi, Pb or Al.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 11 or 12, wherein the fuel includes at least one of Sn, Xe or Li.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of any of claims 11-13, wherein the substance and the fuel are separately supplied to the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of any of claims 11-14, wherein the substance is selected to increase radiation emission in a pre-determined wavelength range.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of any of claims 11-15, wherein the adjusting includes reducing the volume defined by the plasma such that an etendue of a radiation source configured to generate the plasma substantially matches an etendue of a lithographic apparatus configured to pattern the beam of radiation.
</P>
<P>
17. A source configured to generate a radiation for a lithographic apparatus, the source comprising: a cathode and an anode, the cathode and the anode configured to create a discharge in a fuel located in a discharge space so as to generate a plasma, the discharge space including, in use, a substance configured to adjust radiation emission by the plasma so as to control a volume defined by the plasma.
</P>
<P>
18. The source of claim 17, wherein the substance includes at least one of Ga, In, Bi or Al.
</P>
<P>
19. The source of claim 17 or 18, wherein the fuel includes at least one of Sn, Xe or Li.
</P>
<P>
20. The source of any of claims 17-19, further comprising a fuel supply configured to supply the fuel to the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
21. The source of any of claims 17-20, further comprising a supply configured to supply the substance in the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
22. The source of claim 21, wherein the substance and the fuel are separately supplied to the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
23. The source of any of claims 17-22, wherein the substance is part of a mixture including the fuel.
</P>
<P>
24. The source of claim 23, wherein the mixture is solid or liquid.
</P>
<P>
25. The source of claim 23 or 24, wherein the mixture is located on the cathode. 26. The source of any of claims 17-25, wherein the substance is selected to increase the radiation emission in a pre-determined wavelength range.
</P>
<P>
27. The source of any of claims 17-26, wherein the substance is configured to reduce a radial size of the plasma.
</P>
<P>
28. The source of any of claims 17-27, further comprising a supply configured to supply both the fuel and the substance in the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
29. The source of any of claims 17-28, wherein an etendue of the source substantially matches an etendue of the lithographic apparatus.
</P>
<P>
30. A lithographic system comprising: a source configured to generate a radiation, the source comprising a cathode and an anode, the cathode and the anode configured to create a discharge in a fuel located in a discharge space so as to generate a plasma, the discharge space including, in use, a substance configured to adjust radiation emission by the plasma so as to control a volume defined by the plasma; a pattern support configured to hold a patterning device, the patterning device configured to pattern the radiation to form a patterned beam of radiation; a substrate support configured to support a substrate; and a projection system configured to project the patterned beam of radiation onto the substrate.
</P>
<P>
31. The apparatus of claim 30, wherein the substance includes at least one of Ga, In, Bi or Al.
</P>
<P>
32. The apparatus of claim 30 or 31 , wherein the fuel includes at least one of Sn, Xe or Li.
</P>
<P>
33. The apparatus of any of claims 30-32, further comprising a fuel supply configured to supply the fuel to the discharge space. 34. The apparatus of any of claims 30-33, further comprising a supply configured to supply the substance in the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
35. The apparatus of any of claims 30-34, wherein the substance and the fuel are separately supplied to the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
36. The apparatus of any of claims 30-35, wherein the substance is part of a mixture including the fuel.
</P>
<P>
37. The apparatus of claim 36, wherein the mixture is solid or liquid.
</P>
<P>
38. The apparatus of claim 36 or 37, wherein the mixture is located on the cathode.
</P>
<P>
39. The apparatus of any of claims 30-38, wherein the substance is selected to increase the radiation emission in a pre-determined wavelength range.
</P>
<P>
40. The apparatus of any of claims 30-39, wherein the substance is configured to reduce a radial size of the plasma.
</P>
<P>
41. The apparatus of any of claims 30-40, further comprising a supply configured to supply both the fuel and the substance in the discharge space.
</P>
<P>
42. The apparatus of any of claims 30-41 , wherein an etendue of the source substantially matches an etendue of the lithographic apparatus.
</P>
<P>
43. The apparatus of any of claims 30-42, wherein the patterning device includes a programmable mirror array.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009020390A1;US2009040491A1;TW200912999A;NL1035746A1;KR20100029849A;JP2010536142A;CN101779524A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
