<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Ultrafine titanium dioxide nanoparticles and dispersions thereof
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2123606A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LATVA-NIRVA ESA [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
DAHMS GERD [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
JUNG ANDREAS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
FIEBRIG BENJAMIN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
LATVA-NIRVA, ESA
</Name>
<Name>
DAHMS, GERD
</Name>
<Name>
JUNG, ANDREAS
</Name>
<Name>
FIEBRIG, BENJAMIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
KEMIRA PIGMENTS OY [FI]
</Name>
<Name>
KEMIRA PIGMENTS OY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2123606
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080156453
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-19
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080156453
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-19
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/18
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/02
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/29
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q17/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to Membrane Structured Solid Nanoparticles (MSSNs) and dispersions thereof and uses thereof. These MSSNs have a combination of active compound vehicles and emulsifiers as such to form membranes which infiltrate the entire nanoparticles so that there are emulsifiers in the interior and on the surface of said nanoparticles. The active compound in these structures comprises ultrafine titanium dioxide which is well dispersed and evenly devided therein.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Membrane-structured solid nanoparticles (MSSNs) and have a combination of active compound vehicles and emulsifiers as such to form membranes which infiltrate the entire nanoparticles so that there are emulsifiers in the interior and on the surface of said nanoparticles characterised in that said active compound comprises an ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound.
</P>
<P>
2. The MSSNs according to claim 1 characterised in that the ultrafine titanium dioxide active compounds are uniformely devided inside said MSSN structures and exhibit a monomodular particle size distribution when measured from a dispersion thereof.
</P>
<P>
3. The MSSNs according to claim 1 or claim 2 characterised in that ultrafine titanium dioxide active compounds of the MSSN structure have an average particle diameter D50 in the range from 100 nm to 800 nm, and preferably the width of the distribution is 0.15 [micro]m or less.
</P>
<P>
4. The MSSNs according to any of the claims 1-3 characterised in that the crystal size of titanium dioxide in said ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound is less than 100 nm, preferably from 3 to 80 nm, more preferably from 8 to 35 nm.
</P>
<P>
5. The MSSNs according to any of the claims 1-4 characterised in that it comprises in addition to ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound zinc oxide and/or organic absorber.
</P>
<P>
6. The MSSNs according to any of the claims 1-5 characterised in that said ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound comprises a surface treatment with at least one of the following compounds, aluminium compound, zirconium coumpound, silicon containing inorganic compound, sulphuric acid or organic additive.
</P>
<P>
7. An aqueous dispersion comprising the MSSNs of any of the claims 1-6.
</P>
<P>
8. The dispersion according to claim 7 characterized in that said ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound is embedded in liquid oily vehicle.
</P>
<P>
9. The dispersion of claim 8 characterized in that the amount of ultrafine TiO2 active compound based on the total amount of aqueous TiO2 vehicle dispersion, is from 0.1% to 50%, preferably from 0.1% to 40% by weight, more preferably from 1 % to 40% by weight, most preferably from 1 % to 35% such as from 1 % to 30% by weight.
</P>
<P>
10. The dispersion according to claim 7 characterized in that ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound is embedded in solid waxy vehicle.
</P>
<P>
11. The dispersion according to claim 10 characterized in that the amount of ultrafine TiO2 active compound based on the total amount of aqueous TiO2 vehicle dispersion is from 0.1% to 50% by weight, preferably from 0.1% to 30% by weight, more preferably from 1% to 20%, most preferably from 1% to 10% by weight.
</P>
<P>
12. A method for producing a dispersion comprising membrane-structured solid nanoparticles (MSSNs) having a combination of ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound vehicle particles and emulsifiers as such to form membranes which infiltrate the entire nanoparticles so that there are emulsifiers in the interior and on the surface of said nanoparticles and which comprise ultrafine titanium dioxide active compounds wherein said method comprises the steps of
</P>
<P>
a. mixing said ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound with the wax-, polymer- or lipid-based ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound vehicle and at least one emulsifier at a temperature above the melting point or softening point of said ultrafine titanium dioxide active compound vehicle, in order to form phase B, and
</P>
<P>
b. mechanically mixing said phase B with an aqueous phase A, which optionally comprises an emulsifier, at a temperature above the melting point or softening point of said ultrafine titanium oxide active compound vehicle, without high-pressure homogenization, leading to formation of a lyotropic liquid-crystalline mixed phase A+B, and
</P>
<P>
c. diluting said mixed phase A+B with an aqueous phase C, which optionally comprises an emulsifier using stirring but not high-pressure homogenization, to achieve a desired final concentration of said dispersion.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12 characterised in that the mechanical mixing in step b and the stirring in step c take place with agitators which have a peripheral speed in the range from 1 to 20 m/s and produce a lamellar flow.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 12 or claim 13 characterised in that the weight ratio of phase B to phase A in step b is from 1:5 to 5:1.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of any of the claims 12-14 characterised in that the average diameter of said titanium dioxide active compound vehicle particles are from 50 to 1000 nm.
</P>
<P>
16. Use of the MSSNs or MSSN dispersions of any of the claims 1-11 or the aqueous dispersion of any of the claims 7-10 for OM/ or W/O dispersions, preferably in cosmetics and coatings.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009141499A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
