<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Method, system, holder and assembly for transferring templates during imprint lithography processes
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2177951A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MEISSL MARIO J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI BYUNG-JIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BABBS DANIEL A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BAILEY HILLMAN L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MEISSL, MARIO J
</Name>
<Name>
CHOI, BYUNG-JIN
</Name>
<Name>
BABBS, DANIEL, A
</Name>
<Name>
BAILEY, HILLMAN, L
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLECULAR IMPRINTS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2177951
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100151773
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-05-11
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040751888
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-05-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20030438224
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-05-14
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20030437476
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-05-14
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B41F11/00
</Class>
<Class>
B41L39/00
</Class>
<Class>
B81C99/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00
</Class>
<Class>
B29C
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B41F11/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/00A
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed are a method system holder (40a) and template for transferring template (26). A motion stage having a template transfer holder is provided. The transfer holder is adapted to have a patterned mold facing the motion stage.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A template transfer assembly (340; 440; 540; 640) comprising:
</P>
<P>
a template transfer substrate (344; 444; 544; 644);
</P>
<P>
a template (326; 426; 526; 626) having first and second sides, with said first side facing away from said template transfer substrate (344; 444; 544; 644) and said second side facing said template transfer substrate and having mold pattern (328; 428; 528; 628) formed thereon; and
</P>
<P>
polymerized imprint material (334; 434; 534; 634) disposed between said second side and said template transfer substrate (344; 444; 544; 644) to fixedly attach said template to said template transfer substrate.
</P>
<P>
2. The template transfer assembly as recited in claim 1 wherein said polymerized imprint material (334; 434; 534; 634) surrounds a sub-section of said mold or surrounds said entire mold.
</P>
<P>
3. The template transfer assembly as recited in claim 1 or in claim 2 wherein said polymerized imprint material (434; 534; 634) hermetically seals a sub-portion of said mold.
</P>
<P>
4. The template transfer assembly as recited in claim 1 or in claim 2 wherein said polymerized imprint material (334; 434; 534; 634) encapsulates said entire mold hermetically sealing said mold from an ambient.
</P>
<P>
5. The template transfer assembly as recited in any one of claims 1 to 4 wherein said template further includes a perimeter groove (537; 638) surrounding said mold with said polymerized imprint material (534; 634) disposed between said template transfer substrate and a region of said second side that is in superimposition with said perimeter groove.
</P>
<P>
6. The template transfer assembly as recited in any one of the preceding claims wherein said template transfer substrate (344; 444; 544; 644) comprises a semiconductor wafer, optionally wherein said semiconductor wafer has an additional template coupled thereto.
</P>
<P>
7. The template transfer assembly as recited in any one of the preceding claims wherein mold pattern (628) has grooves (628a) and protrusions (628b), the grooves (628a) including a nadir surface (628c) and the protrusions (628b) including an apex surface (628d).
</P>
<P>
8. The template transfer assembly as recited in claim 7, wherein:
</P>
<P>
one or more of nadir surfaces (628c) are spaced apart from major surface (626a) a first distance,
</P>
<P>
one or more apex surfaces (628d) are spaced-apart from major surface (626a) a second distance,
</P>
<P>
a surface (638) circumscribes either all or a subset of the grooves (628a) and the protrusions (628b), said surface (638) being spaced apart from major surface (626a) a third distance.
</P>
<P>
9. The template transfer assembly as recited in claim 8, wherein a mesa (636) is defined by third distance differing from both first and second distances; preferably wherein the third distance is less than either of first and second distances.
</P>
<P>
10. The template transfer assembly as recited in claim 9, wherein imprinting material (634) is disposed in regions between surface (638) and surface (631) of template transfer substrate (644) to maintain a fixed position between template (626) and template transfer substrate (644) without imprint material (634) contacting mold pattern (628) on template (626).
</P>
<P>
11. An imprint lithography system comprising:
</P>
<P>
an imprint head (18);
</P>
<P>
a template transfer assembly (340; 440; 540; 640) according to any one of the preceding claims.
</P>
<P>
12. A method of transferring an imprint lithography template, said method comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a template transfer substrate (344; 444; 544; 644);
</P>
<P>
forming a selected volume of imprinting fluid onto said template transfer substrate (344; 444; 544; 644);
</P>
<P>
placing said template (326; 426; 526; 626) upon said selected volume; and
</P>
<P>
converting said imprinting fluid to solid imprint material (334; 434; 534; 634), with said selected volume being a quantity sufficient to fixedly attach said template to said template transfer substrate while maintaining a space between a mold (328; 428; 528; 628) and said template transfer substrate.
</P>
<P>
13. The method as recited in claim 12 wherein converting further includes urging said template (326; 426; 526; 626) upon said selected volume so that, upon converting said imprint material, said solid imprint material (334; 434; 534; 634) either surrounds said mold entirely or surrounds a portion of said mold.
</P>
<P>
14. The method as recited in claim 11 or 12 wherein converting further includes urging said template (326; 426; 526; 626) upon said selected volume so that, upon converting said imprint material, said solid imprint material either hermetically seals a sub-portion of said mold or encapsulates said mold hermetically sealing said mold from an ambient.
</P>
<P>
15. A method of removing a template from an imprint head in an imprint lithography system including:
</P>
<P>
loading (722) the template transfer substrate (444) onto a wafer chuck (21) in the imprint lithography system (10);
</P>
<P>
dispensing (724) a selected volume of imprinting fluid onto the surface of the template transfer substrate (444);
</P>
<P>
achieving a relative movement (726) between the imprint head (18) holding a template and the template transfer substrate (444) so that the template contacts the imprinting fluid;
</P>
<P>
converting (728) the imprinting fluid to solid imprint material; and
</P>
<P>
releasing the template from the imprint head (18).
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2004103666A2;WO2004103666A3;KR20060017514A;JP2007504683A;EP1622750A2;EP1622750A4;EP1622750B1;AT487579T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
