<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PREPARATION OF NANOSCALAR UV ABSORBERS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2160382A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MUELLER STEFAN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
HERZOG BERND [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MUELLER, STEFAN
</Name>
<Name>
HERZOG, BERND
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BASF SE [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BASF SE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2160382
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080774417
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008EP58250
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070111752
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080774417
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/49
</Class>
<Class>
C07D251/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/49F4
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q17/04
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07D251/24
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is a method of preparing a composition, comprising a micronised insoluble organicUV absorber, which method comprises grinding the insoluble organic UV absorber, in coarse particle form, in a grinding apparatus comprising yttrium-stabilized zirconium oxide grinding beads, in the presence of alkyl polyglucoside having the formula CnH2n +1O(C6H10O5)xH, in which n is an integer ranging from 8 to 16 and x is the mean polymerisation level of the glucoside moiety (C6H10O5) and ranges from 1.4 to 1.6, or an ester thereof and in the presence of an antifoam agent as dispersingagent auxiliary.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims
</P>
<P>
1. A method of preparing a composition, comprising a micronised insoluble organic UV absorber, which method comprises grinding the insoluble organic UV absorber, in coarse particle form, in a grinding apparatus comprising yttrium-stabilized zirconium oxide grinding beads, in the presence of alkyl polyglucoside having the formula CnH2n+iO(C6H1o05)[chi]H, in which n is an integer ranging from 8 to 16 and x is the mean polymerisation level of the glucoside moiety (C6H10O5) and ranges from 1.4 to 1.6, or an ester thereof and in the presence of an antifoam agent as dispersing agent auxiliary.
</P>
<P>
2. A method according to claim 1 , wherein the micronised insoluble organic UV absorber is selected from the compounds of formula
</P>
<P>
, wherein
</P>
<P>
A is a radical of formula (1a) x)y
</P>
<P>
Ri and R5 independently from each other are hydrogen; d-Ci8alkyl; or C6-Ci2aryl; R2, R3 and R4 independently from each other are hydrogen; or a radical of formula
</P>
<P>
(1 c) , wherein at least one of the radicals R2, R3 and R4 are a radical of
</P>
<P>
formula (1 c); R6, R7, Rs, R9 and Ri0 independently from each other are hydrogen; hydroxy; halogen; d- Ci8alkyl; d-Ci8alkoxy; C6-Ci2aryl; biphenylyl; C6-Ci2aryloxy; Ci-Ci8alkylthio; carboxy; -COOM; Ci-Ci8-alkylcarboxyl; aminocarbonyl; or mono- or di-Ci-Ci8alkylamino; d- Ci[theta]acylamino; -COOH; M is an alkali metal ion; x is 1 or 2; and y is a number from 2 to 10.
</P>
<P>
3. A method according to claim 2, wherein the micronized insoluble UV absorber is selected from the compounds of formula
</P>
<P>
(2) , wherein
</P>
<P>
R1, R5, R6, R7 und R8 are defined as in claim 2.
</P>
<P>
4. A method according to claim 2 or 3, wherein Riand R5 are hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
5. A method according to any of claims 2 to 4, wherein R6 and R8 are hydrogen.
</P>
<P>
6. A method according to any of claims 2 to 5, wherein
</P>
<P>
R7 is hydrogen; hydroxy; CrC5alkyl; CrC5alkoxy; -COOM; -COOH; or COORi0; M is an alkali metal ion; and Rio is Ci-C5alkyl.
</P>
<P>
7. A method according to any of claims 2 to 6, wherein the compound of formula
</P>
<P>
is used.
</P>
<P>
8. A method according to claim 1 , wherein the micronized insoluble UV absorber is selected from the compounds of formula
</P>
<P>
(4) , wherein
</P>
<P>
T1 is Ci-Ci8alkyl, which is optionally substituted by phenyl.
</P>
<P>
9. A method according to claim 8, wherein T1 is Ci-C8alkyl.
</P>
<P>
10. A method according to claim 8 or 9, wherein the micronized insoluble UV absorber corresponds to formula
</P>
<P>
1 1. A method according to claim 1 , wherein the micronized insoluble UV absorber is selected from the compounds of formula
</P>
<P>
(6) , wherein
</P>
<P>
R11 and R12 independently from each other are CrC2oalkyl; C2-C2oalkenyl; C3-C10cycloalkyl;
</P>
<P>
C3-C-[iota]ocycloalkenyl; or R11 and R12 together with the linking nitrogen atom form a 5- or 6- membered heterocyclic ring; n-i is a number from 1 to 4; when n-i = 1 , Ri3 is a saturated or unsaturated heterocyclic radical; hydroxy-Ci-C5alkyl; cyclohexyl optionally substituted with one or more CrC5alkyl; phenyl optionally substituted with a heterocyclic radical, aminocarbonyl or d-C5alkylcarboxy;
</P>
<P>
Ri3 is an alkylene-, cycloalkylene, alkenylene or phenylene radical which is optionally substituted by a carbonyl- or carboxy group; a radical of formula *- CH- C[identical to]C-CH- * or R13
</P>
<P>
together with A2 forms a bivalent radical of the formula (1 a) ; wherein
</P>
<P>
n2 is a number from 1 to 3;
</P>
<P>
R-I3 is an alkantriyl radical;
</P>
<P>
R-I3 is an alkantetrayl radical;
</P>
<P>
A2 is -O-; Or -N(R15)-; and
</P>
<P>
R15 is hydrogen; Ci-C5alkyl; or hydroxy-CrC5alkyl.
</P>
<P>
12. A method according to claim 11 , wherein the micronized insoluble UV absorber corresponds to the formula
</P>
<P>
13. A method according to any of the preceding claims in which the antifoam agent is selected from carrier oils, silicone oils and silicone foam inhibitors, hydrophobis silica, hadrophobic fat dervatives and waxes, water-insoluble polymers, amphiphilic components, emulsifiers and coupling agents.
</P>
<P>
14. A method according to claim 13, wherein the antifoam agent is selected from polydimethylsiloxane.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to any of the preceding claims in which the amount of antifoam agent is from 0.01 to 1 % b.w..
</P>
<P>
16. A method according to any of the preceding claims in which the micronised insoluble organic UV absorber so obtained has a mean particle size in the range of from 0.01 to 2.0[mu].
</P>
<P>
17. A method according to claim 16, in which the micronised insoluble organic UV absorber so obtained has a mean particle size &amp;lt; 0.1 [mu].
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009003934A1;US2010193614A1;MX2009013736A;KR20100047858A;JP2010531842A;CN101687823A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
