<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Dry etching method for magnetic material
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2184380A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KODAIRA YOSHIMITSU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HIROMI TAICHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KODAIRA, YOSHIMITSU
</Name>
<Name>
HIROMI, TAICHI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CANON ANELVA CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
CANON ANELVA CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2184380
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100001013
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-07-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040254457
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-07-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20030201254
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-07-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C23F4/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/31
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/14
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/34
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/3065
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/3213
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23F4/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11C11/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01F41/30D6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L43/12
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A dry etching method in which a plasma of an etching gas is generated and a magnetic material is dry-etched using a mask material made of a non-organic material, the method being characterized in that the etching gas is selected from (i) a ketone of formula RCOR&apos;, wherein R and R&apos; are an alkyl group, and (ii) a lower non-substituted hydrocarbon.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A dry etching method comprising generating a plasma of an etching gas and dry-etching a magnetic material using a mask material made of a non-organic material, the method being characterized in that the etching gas is selected from (i) a ketone of formula RCOR&apos;, wherein R and R&apos; are an alkyl group, and (ii) a lower non-substituted hydrocarbon.
</P>
<P>
2. The dry etching method according to claim 1, wherein a mask material made of a non-organic material is a mask material comprising a single layer film or a laminated layer film made of a material selected from the group consisting of Ta, Ti, Al and Si or a mask material comprising a single layer film or a laminated layer film made of an oxide or a nitride of a material selected from the group consisting of Ta, Ti, Al and Si.
</P>
<P>
3. The dry etching method according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the magnetic material to be etched is either an elemental metal belonging to the iron group in the Group VIII or a magnetic material essentially composed of such an elemental metal.
</P>
<P>
4. The dry etching method according to any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein an etching gas is added with at least one kind of oxygen gas, water and an inert gas as an added gas, said oxygen gas and water are added at respective content of not more than 25% relative to the etching gas and said inert gas is added at respective content of not more than 90% relative to the etching gas.
</P>
<P>
5. The dry etching method according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the said lower non-substituted hydrocarbon is a lower alkane.
</P>
<P>
6. The dry etching method according to claim 1, wherein the magnetic material is a single or laminated layer of film of at least one material selected from the group consisting of Fe-Ni alloy, Co-Fe alloy, Fe-Mn alloy, Ni-Fe-Cr alloy, Co-Cr alloy, Co-Pt alloy, Co-Cr-Pt alloy, Co-Pd alloy and Co-Fe-B alloy.
</P>
<P>
7. The dry etching method according to claim 1, wherein the dry etching is performed under a vacuum from 0.1 to 10 Pa.
</P>
<P>
8. The dry etching method according to claim 1, wherein the magnetic material is etched at a temperature from 20-100[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
9. A tunneling magnetoresistance device (TMR) manufacturing method comprising:
</P>
<P>
forming a TMR comprising a pair of ferromagnetic layers comprising a free layer and a pinned layer, an insulating layer sandwiched by the free layer and the pinned layer and an antiferromagnetic layer on the pinned layer, by employing the dry etching process of claim 1.
</P>
<P>
10. A magnetic random access memory (MRAM) device manufacturing method comprising the dry etching method as claimed in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
11. A magnetic random access memory (MRAM) device manufacturing method comprising forming a magnetic random access memory comprising a pinned layer, a free layer and an insulating layer therebetween, wherein the free layer is provided by the dry etching method as claimed in claim 1.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1500720A1;US2005016957A1;US7060194B2;USRE40951E1;KR20050012144A;KR101041049B1;JP2005042143A;EP2184381A1;CN101624701A;CN101624701B;CN1603468A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
