<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
QUANTUM COMPUTING DEVICE AND METHOD INCLUDING QUBIT ARRAYS OF ENTANGLED STATES USING NEGATIVE REFRACTIVE INDEX LENSES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2140408A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BARKER DELMAR L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
OWENS WILLIAM R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ROSENWALD ROSS D [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BARKER, DELMAR, L
</Name>
<Name>
OWENS, WILLIAM, R
</Name>
<Name>
ROSENWALD, ROSS, D
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
RAYTHEON CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RAYTHEON COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2140408
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080744366
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-26
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US58218
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070693405
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G06N99/00
</Class>
<Class>
G06N1/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<IPC7>
<Class>
G06N1/00
</Class>
</IPC7>
<ICM>
<Class>
G06N99/00
</Class>
</ICM>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/00M3
</Class>
<Class>
G06N99/00K
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A quantum computing device and method employs qubit arrays of entangled states using negative refractive index lenses. A qubit includes a pair of neutral atoms separated by or disposed on opposite sides of a negative refractive index lens. The neutral atoms and negative refractive index lens are selectively energized and/or activated to cause entanglement of states of the atoms. The quantum computing device enjoys a novel architecture that is workable and scalable in terms of size and wavelength.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A qubit for use in a quantum computing system, the qubit comprising:
</P>
<P>
a pair of atoms; and
</P>
<P>
a negative index lens disposed between the pair of atoms.
</P>
<P>
2. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the negative index lens is arranged to entangle states of the pair of atoms.
</P>
<P>
3. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the negative index lens is arranged to electromagnetically link the pair of atoms.
</P>
<P>
4. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the negative index lens is arranged between the pair of atoms such that the optical path length between the pair of atoms is zero.
</P>
<P>
5. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the pair of atoms is comprised of Cesium atoms.
</P>
<P>
6. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the pair of atoms is comprised of neutral atoms.
</P>
<P>
7. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the pair of atoms is comprised of alkaline atoms.
</P>
<P>
8. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the negative index lens is comprised of a material having an index of refraction of n=-1.
</P>
<P>
9. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the negative index lens is comprised of a metamaterial.
</P>
<P>
10. The qubit of claim 1, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
a first negative index mirror disposed adjacent to a first atom of the pair of atoms; and
</P>
<P>
a second negative index mirror disposed adjacent to a second atom of the pair of atoms.
</P>
<P>
11. The qubit of claim 10, wherein the first and second negative index mirrors are comprised of materials having an index of refraction of n=-1.
</P>
<P>
12. The qubit of claim 1, wherein the negative index lens facilitates entanglement of states of the atoms.
</P>
<P>
13. The qubit of claim 1, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
a second negative index lens disposed adjacent to one of the pair of atoms; and
</P>
<P>
a third atom disposed adjacent to the second negative index lens.
</P>
<P>
14. A qubit array comprising a plurality of qubits according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
15. The qubit array of claim 14, wherein the plurality of qubits are arranged in a two-dimensional architecture.
</P>
<P>
16. The qubit array of claim 14, wherein the plurality of qubits are arranged in a three-dimensional architecture.
</P>
<P>
17. A quantum computing system comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of qubits according to claim 1;
</P>
<P>
control circuitry operatively connected to the negative index lenses, the control circuitry being operable to switch the negative index lenses between a negative index state and a positive index state; and
</P>
<P>
atomic state reading circuitry configured to determine atomic spin states of the atoms.
</P>
<P>
18. The quantum computing system of claim 17, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
an excitation source configured to excite the atoms.
</P>
<P>
19. The quantum computing system of claim 18, wherein the excitation source is configured to provide 9.2 GHz signals to excite cesium atoms.
</P>
<P>
20. A quantum computing method comprising:
</P>
<P>
disposing pairs of neutral atoms on opposite sides of negative index lenses;
</P>
<P>
selectively exciting the atoms;
</P>
<P>
selectively energizing and de-energizing the negative index lenses, the selectively energizing and de-energizing facilitating entanglement of states of the atoms; and
</P>
<P>
interrogating the atoms to determine the state of at least one of the neutral atoms.
</P>
<P>
21. The quantum computing method of claim 20, wherein interrogating includes determining spin of the atoms, the spin being indicative of state 0, state 1 or a superposition of state 0 and state 1.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 20, wherein the neutral atoms are cesium atoms, and including exciting the atoms with signals having a frequency of about 9.2 GHz.
</P>
<P>
23. A quantum computing device comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of neutral atoms, each pair of neutral atoms being separated by a negative index lens, wherein each pair of neutral atoms and negative index lens are arranged to define a quantum bit; and
</P>
<P>
control circuitry operatively coupled to one or more excitation sources, wherein the control circuitry and one or more excitation sources cooperate to entangle the quantum bits.
</P>
<P>
24. The quantum computing device of claim 23, wherein the quantum bits are arranged in a two-dimensional architecture.
</P>
<P>
25. The quantum computing device of claim 23 wherein the quantum bits are arranged in a three-dimensional architecture.
</P>
<P>
26. A quantum computing device comprising:
</P>
<P>
an array of elements, each element of the array comprising:
</P>
<P>
a first neutral atom;
</P>
<P>
a second neutral atom; and
</P>
<P>
a negative index lens disposed between the first and second neutral atoms;
</P>
<P>
wherein the first and second neutral atoms are arranged to define first and second basis states of a quantum bit; and
</P>
<P>
wherein the elements are arranged so as to cause entanglement of the quantum bits of the elements of the array.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008237579A1;US7985965B2;WO2008121641A1;JP2010522939A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
