<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR PRODUCING NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2104714A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DUNBAR TIMOTHY D [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DUNBAR, TIMOTHY D
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES CO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
3M INNOVATIVE PROPERTIES COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2104714
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070865775
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US87857
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060871326P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/04
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G9/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/04B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A process comprises (a) combining (1) at least one base and (2) at least one metal carboxylate salt comprising (i) a metal cation selected from metal cations that form amphoteric metal oxides or oxyhydroxides and (ii) a carboxylate anion comprising from one to four alkyleneoxy moieties, or metal carboxylate salt precursors comprising (i) at least one metal salt comprising the metal cation and a non-interfering anion and (ii) at least one carboxylic acid comprising from one to four alkyleneoxy moieties, at least one salt of the carboxylic acid and a non-interfering, non-metal cation, or a mixture thereof;  and (b) allowing the base and the metal carboxylate salt or metal carboxylate salt precursors to react.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
We Claim:
</P>
<P>
1. A process comprising (a) combining (1) at least one base and (2) at least one metal carboxylate salt comprising (i) a metal cation selected from metal cations that form amphoteric metal oxides or oxyhydroxides and (ii) a carboxylate anion comprising from one to four alkyleneoxy moieties, or metal carboxylate salt precursors comprising (i) at least one metal salt comprising a said metal cation and a non-interfering anion and (ii) at least one carboxylic acid comprising from one to four alkyleneoxy moieties, at least one salt of said carboxylic acid and a non-interfering, non-metal cation, or a mixture thereof; and (b) allowing said base and said metal carboxylate salt or said metal carboxylate salt precursors to react.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of Claim 1, wherein said base is a hydroxyl group-containing base.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of Claim 1, wherein said base is selected from sodium hydroxide, potassium hydroxide, ammonium hydroxide, tetramethylammonium hydroxide, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of Claim 1 , wherein said metal cation is selected from cations of Be, Ti, V, Mn, Cr, Fe, Co, Ni, Al, Zn, Ga, In, Ge, Sn, Pb, As, Sb, Bi, Te, and Po, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of Claim 1, wherein said metal cation is selected from Be&amp;lt;+2&amp;gt;, Ti&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, V&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, V&amp;lt;+5&amp;gt;, Mn&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, Cr&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Cr&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, Fe&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Fe&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, Co&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;/Co&amp;lt;+2&amp;gt; (mixed oxidation state compound), Ni&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Ni&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, Al&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Zn&amp;lt;+2&amp;gt;, Ga&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, In&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Ge&amp;lt;+2&amp;gt;, Sn&amp;lt;+2&amp;gt;, Sn&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, Pb&amp;lt;+2&amp;gt;, As&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Sb&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Bi&amp;lt;+3&amp;gt;, Te&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, Po&amp;lt;+4&amp;gt;, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of Claim 1, wherein said metal cation is a zinc cation.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of Claim 1, wherein said carboxylate anion and said carboxylic acid further comprise a terminal alkyl or hydroxyl group.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of Claim 1, wherein said carboxylate anion and said carboxylic acid further comprise a terminal alkyl group.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of Claim 8, wherein said alkyl group has from one to four carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of Claim 1, wherein said carboxylate anion and said carboxylic acid further comprise a methyl group.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of Claim 1 , wherein said alkyleneoxy moieties are selected from methyleneoxy, ethyleneoxy, n-propyleneoxy, i-propyleneoxy, butyleneoxy, and the corresponding methoxy- and ethoxy-substituted moieties, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of Claim 1, wherein said alkyleneoxy moieties comprise moieties selected from ethyleneoxy moieties, propyleneoxy moieties, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of Claim 1 , wherein said alkyleneoxy moieties comprise ethyleneoxy moieties.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of Claim 13, wherein said ethyleneoxy moieties are one or two in number.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of Claim 1 , wherein said non-interfering non-metal cation is tetraalkylammonium, and wherein said non-interfering anion is selected from halide, nitrate, acetate, carbonate, formate, propionate, sulfate, bromate, perchlorate, tribromoacetate, trichloroacetate, trifluoroacetate, and chlorate ions, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of Claim 15, wherein said non-interfering, non-metal cation is tetramethylammonium, and wherein said non-interfering anion is selected from chloride, acetate, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of Claim 1 , wherein said metal carboxylate salt is one of a class that is represented by the following general formula
</P>
<P>
[R&apos;(OR)xZ(OR)w(CH2)yCOO ]m[X ]nM&amp;lt;+(m+n)&amp;gt; (I),
</P>
<P>
said carboxylic acid is one of a class that is represented by the following general formula
</P>
<P>
R&apos;(OR)xZ(OR)w(CH2)yCOOH (II), and
</P>
<P>
said metal salt is one of a class that is represented by the following general formula
</P>
<P>
M&amp;lt;+n&amp;gt; [X ]n (III),
</P>
<P>
wherein R&apos; is a linear or branched alkyl group having from 1 to 4 carbon atoms; each R is independently a linear or branched alkylene moiety having from 1 to 4 carbon atoms; x is an integer of 0 to 4; Z is a divalent organic linking moiety; w is an integer of 0 to 4, with the proviso that the sum x+w is an integer of 1 to 4; y is an integer of 0 to 3; X is a non- interfering anion; m and n are integers having values such that the sum m+n is equal to the charge of the metal cation, M; and at least 90 mole percent of M (based upon the total number of moles of metal cation) is selected from Be, Ti, V, Mn, Cr, Fe, Co, Ni, Al, Zn, Ga, In, Ge, Sn, Pb, As, Sb, Bi, Te, Po, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of Claim 17, wherein said Z is a moiety non-directionally selected from the group consisting of a covalent bond, -S-, -C(O)O-, -C=C-, and -C(O)NH-, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of Claim 17, wherein said R&apos; is methyl, ethyl, or isopropyl; each said R is independently a linear or branched alkylene moiety having from 1 to 3 carbon atoms; said x is an integer of 1 to 3; said Z is selected from the group consisting of a covalent bond, -C(O)O-, -C=C-, -C(O)NH-, and combinations thereof; said w is an integer of 0 to 1 , with the proviso that the sum of x + w is an integer of 1 to 4; said y is an integer of 0 to 2; said X is an anion selected from halide, nitrate, acetate, carbonate, formate, propionate, sulfate, bromate, perchlorate, tribromoacetate, trichloroacetate, trifluoroacetate, and chlorate ions, and mixtures thereof; and said M is selected from Ti, V, Mn, Cr, Al, Zn, Ga, In, Sn, Pb, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The process of Claim 19, wherein said R&apos; is methyl or ethyl; each said R is independently a linear or branched alkylene moiety having from 1 to 2 carbon atoms; said x is an integer of 2 or 3; said Z is selected from a covalent bond, -C=C-, -C(O)O-, and combinations thereof; said X is an anion selected from chloride, acetate, and mixtures thereof; and said M is selected from Ti, Al, Zn, Ga, In, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
21. The process of Claim 20, wherein said R&apos; is methyl; said x is an integer of 2; said Z is a covalent bond; said w is an integer of 0; said y is an integer of 0; and said M is zinc.
</P>
<P>
22. The process of Claim 1, wherein said metal carboxylate salt is selected from zinc 2- [2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy] acetate, zinc 2-(2-methoxyethoxy)acetate, zinc methoxyacetate, zinc succinate mono-(2-methoxyethyl) ester, zinc succinate mono-[2-(2- methoxyethoxy)ethyl] ester, zinc succinate mono-{2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy]ethyl} ester, zinc succinate mono-(2-methoxy-l-methylethyl) ester, zinc succinate mono-[2-(2- methoxy-l-methylethoxy)-l-methylethyl] ester, zinc succinate mono-{2-[2-(2-methoxy-l- methylethoxy)-l-methylethoxy]-l-methylethyl} ester, zinc [3-(2- methoxyethoxy)propoxy] acetate, zinc (2-methoxyethoxymethoxy)acetate, zinc succinate mono-{2-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)-l-methylethoxy]-l-methylethyl} ester, zinc 3-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethoxy]propionate, zinc [2-(2-methoxyethoxy)-l- methylethoxy] acetate, zinc pentanedioate mono-[2-(2-methoxyethoxy)ethyl] ester, zinc pentanedioate mono-(2-methoxy-l-methylethyl) ester, zinc (2- methoxyethoxycarbonylmethoxy)acetate, zinc (2-methoxy-l- methylethoxycarbonylmethoxy)acetate, zinc but-2-enedioate mono-(2-methoxyethyl) ester, zinc N-(2-methoxyethyl)succinamate, zinc [(2- methoxyethylcarbamoyl)methoxy]acetate, zinc [2-(2-ethoxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetate, zinc [2-(2-isopropoxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetate, zinc {2-[2-(2-tert- butoxyethoxy)ethoxy]ethoxy} acetate, zinc {2-[2-(2-sec- butoxyethoxy)ethoxy]ethoxy} acetate, zinc 2,3-dimethoxypropionate, zinc succinate mono- (2,3-dimethoxypropyl) ester, zinc succinate mono-(2-methoxy-l-methoxymethylethyl) ester, zinc 3-(2-methoxyethylcarbamoyl)acetate, zinc (2-hydroxyethoxy)acetate, zinc [2- (2-hydroxyethoxy)ethoxy]acetate, zinc 3- {2-[2-(2-methoxy- 1 -methylethoxy)- 1 -methylethoxy]-l-methylethoxy} propionate, zinc 3-(2-methoxy-l- methylethoxy propionate, zinc {2- [2-(2-methoxy- 1 -methylethoxy)- 1 -methylethoxy] - 1 - methylethoxy} acetate, zinc (2-methoxy-l-methylethoxy)acetate, and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
23. The process of Claim 1 , wherein said metal carboxylate salt is used in combination with at least one other salt, said other salt having only non-interfering anions.
</P>
<P>
24. A process comprising (a) combining (1) at least one hydroxyl-group containing base and (2) at least one metal carboxylate salt selected from zinc 2-[2-(2- methoxyethoxy)ethoxy] acetate, zinc 2-(2-methoxyethoxy)acetate, zinc methoxyacetate, zinc (2-methoxy-l-methylethoxy)acetate, and mixtures thereof; and (b) allowing said base and said salt to react.
</P>
<P>
25. The process of Claim 24, wherein said metal carboxylate salt is used in combination with at least one other salt, said other salt being a metal acetate.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008079800A1;US2010008847A1;KR20090096705A;JP2010514649A;CN101573415A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
