<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
AQUEOUS DISPERSIONS OF ELECTRICALLY CONDUCTING POLYMERS CONTAINING INORGANIC NANOPARTICLES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2173811A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HSU CHE-HSIUNG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MENG HONG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SKULASON HJALTI [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZIEBARTH JONATHAN M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HSU, CHE-HSIUNG
</Name>
<Name>
MENG, HONG
</Name>
<Name>
SKULASON, HJALTI
</Name>
<Name>
ZIEBARTH, JONATHAN, M
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E. I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2173811
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080796400
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US70718
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070952372P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C08L65/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/12
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08L65/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/12H4
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/12H6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M2B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to electrically conductive polymer compositions, and their use in electronic devices. The compositions contain an aqueous dispersion of at least one electrically conductive polymer doped with at least one highly-fluorinated acid polymer, and inorganic nanoparticles.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A composition comprising: an aqueous disperson of at least one electrically conductive polymer doped with at least one highly fluohnated acid polymer, and inorganic nanoparticles, wherein said nanoparticles are either semiconductive or insulative.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the electrically conductive polymer is selected from the group consisting of polythiophenes, poly(selenophenes), poly(tellurophenes), polypyrroles, polyanilines, polycyclic aromatic polymers, copolymers thereof, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition of Claim 2, wherein the electrically conductive polymer is selected from the group consisting of unsubstituted polyaniline, poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene), unsubstituted polypyrrole, poly(thieno(2,3-b)thiophene), poly(thieno(3,2-b)thiophene), and poly(thieno(3,4-b)thiophene).
</P>
<P>
4. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the highly-fluohnated acid polymer is at least 95% fluohnated.
</P>
<P>
5. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the highly-fluohnated acid polymer is selected from a sulfonic acid and a sulfonimide.
</P>
<P>
6. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the highly-fluohnated acid polymer is a perfluoroolefin having perfluoro-ether-sulfonic acid side chains.
</P>
<P>
7. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the highly-fluohnated acid polymer is selected from the group consisting of a copolymer of 1 ,1 - difluoroethylene and 2-(1 ,1 -difluoro-2-(trifluoromethyl)allyloxy)-1 ,1 ,2,2-tetrafluoroethanesulfonic acid and a copolymer of ethylene and 2-(2- (1 ,2,2-trifluorovinyloxy)-1 ,1 ,2,3,3,3-hexafluoropropoxy)-1 ,1 ,2,2- tetrafluoroethanesulfonic acid.
</P>
<P>
8. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the highly-fluohnated acid polymer is selected from a copolymer of tetrafluoroethylene and perfluoro(3,6-dioxa-4-methyl-7-octenesulfonic acid), and a copolymer of tetrafluoroethylene and perfluoro(3-oxa-4-pentenesulfonic acid).
</P>
<P>
9. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein in nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of metal sulfides, metal oxides, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. The composition of Claim 9, wherein the metal oxide is selected from the group consisting of zinc antimonites, oxygen-deficient molybdenum thoxide, vanadium pentoxide, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the nanoparticles are selected from the group consisting of titanium dioxides, zirconium oxide, molybdenum thoxide, vanadium oxide, aluminum oxide, and combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The composition of Claim 1 , wherein the weight ratio of nanoparticles to electrically conducting polymer is in the range of 0.1 to 10.0.
</P>
<P>
13. A film made from the composition of Claim 1.
</P>
<P>
14. The film of Claim 13, having a refractive index greater than 1.4 at 460 nm.
</P>
<P>
15. An electronic device comprising at least one layer made from the composition of Claim 1.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009018009A1;TW200915350A;KR20100065302A;JP2010534739A;CN101688052A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
