<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
A METHOD FOR THE MANUFACTURE OF NANOPARTICLES ON A CARBON SURFACE AND PRODUCTS THEREFROM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2135306A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
WELLER HORST [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
HERNANDEZ BEATRIZ [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KORNOWSKI ANDREAS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
KLINKE CHRISTIAN [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
WELLER, HORST
</Name>
<Name>
HERNANDEZ, BEATRIZ
</Name>
<Name>
KORNOWSKI, ANDREAS
</Name>
<Name>
KLINKE, CHRISTIAN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CT FUER ANGEWANDTE NANOTECHNOL [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
CENTRUM FUER ANGEWANDTE NANOTECHNOLOGIE GMBH
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2135306
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080734855
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-03-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008EP02482
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-03-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070006128
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-28
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M4B2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00M4D2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The combination of at least one substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface, such as a fullerene, graphite or amorphous carbon, and at least nanoparticle, for example CdSe, CdTe, InP, PbS and/or ZnO is disclosed wherein the at least one nanoparticle is directly attached to the substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface. A method for the manufacture of the nanoparticles is also described. This method comprises: - dissolving a cation source in a first organic solvent to produce a cation-containing medium;  - adding a plurality of substantially unfunctionalised carbon surfaces to the cation-containing medium to form a cation-fullerene mixture;  - adding an anion-containing medium to the mixture of the cation-containing medium and carbon surfaces to form a cation-carbon-anion mixture;  - leaving the cation-carbon-anion mixture at a temperature of between 60{C and 300{C for at least 10 hours.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Title: Carbon Nanotubes as Ligands Applicant: Cenfrum fOr Angewondte
</P>
<P>
Nanotechnologie (CAN) GmbH Our Reference: 90699GB Claims
</P>
<P>
S
</P>
<P>
1. The combination of at least one substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface and at least one nanoparticle, wherein the at least one nanoparticle is directly attached to the substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface.
</P>
<P>
2. The combination of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle is substantially pyramidal-shaped.
</P>
<P>
3. The combination of claim 1 or 2, wherein the nanoparticle is a Il-VI or a fV-VI semiconductor.
</P>
<P>
4. The combination of any of the above claims, wherein at least 40% of the surface area of the carbon surface is coated with a plurality of the nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
5. The combination of any of the above claims, wherein the carbon surface is selected from the group of allotropes of carbon consisting of graphite, amorphous carbon and fullerenes.
</P>
<P>
6. The combination of any one of the above claims, wherein the carbon surface is a fullerene.
</P>
<P>
7. The combination of any one of the above claims, wherein the carbon surface is a multi-wall carbon nanotube or a single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
8. The combination of any one of claims I to 6, wherein the carbon surface is a buckminsterfullerene.
</P>
<P>
9. A method for the manufacture of nanoparticles comprising: -dissolving a cation source in a first organic solvent to produce a cation-containing
</P>
<P>
LJ
</P>
<P>
V
</P>
<P>
medium; -adding a plurality of substantially unfunctionalised carbon surfaces to the cation-containing medium to form a cation- fullerene mixture; -adding an anion-containing medium to the mixture of the cation-containing medium s and carbon surfaces to form a cation-carbon-anion mixture; -leaving the cation-carbon-anion mixture at a temperature of between 60 C and 300 C 10. The method of claim 9, wherein the cation source is a cation complex.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 9 or 10, wherein a cation in the cation source is selected from the group consisting of Cd or Pb.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of any one of claims 9 to 11, wherein the cation source is dissolved at a temperature of above 60 C to dissolve the cation in the first organic solvent.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of any one of claims 9 to 12 further comprising degassing the first organic solvent by allowing it to stand under vacuum for at least one hour at a temperature of -between 70 and 130 C.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of any one of claims 9 to 13, wherein the anion-containing medium is an anion complex.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of any one of claims 9 to 14, wherein an anion in the anion-containing medium is selected from the group consisting of S, Se, Te.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of any one of claims 9 to 15 wherein the anion-containing medium is added to the mixture of the cation-containing medium at a temperature between 60 and 255 C.
</P>
<P>
17. The method of any one of claims 9 to 16, wherein the adding of the plurality of substantially unfunctionalised carbon surfaces to the cation-containing medium is carried out at a temperature of less than 100 C. 2\
</P>
<P>
18. The method of any one of claim 9 to 17, wherein the plurality of substantially unfunctionalised fullerenes is dissolved in a second organic medium.
</P>
<P>
19. The method of claim 18, wherein the second organic medium is removed under vacuum prior to the addition of the anion-containing medium.
</P>
<P>
20. The method of any one of claims 9 to 19, wherein the manufactured nanoparticles have a substantially pyramidal structure.
</P>
<P>
21. The method of any one of claims 9 to 20, wherein the carbon surface is selected from the group of allotropes of carbon consisting of graphite, amorphous carbon and fullerenes.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of any one of claims 9 to 21, wherein the carbon surface is a flillerene.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of any one of claims 9 to 22, wherein the carbon surface is a multi-wall carbon nanotube or a single-wall carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of any one of claims 9 to 22, wherein the carbon surface is a buckminsterfullerene.
</P>
<P>
25. The use of substantially unfunctionalised carbon surfaces in a reaction medium to produced substantially pyramidal-shaped nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
26. A method for the manufacture of substantially pyramidal-shaped nanoparticles comprising adding a plurality of substantially unfunctionalised carbon surfaces to a reaction medium.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 26, wherein the reaction medium comprises cation-ligand complexes and anion-ligand complexes.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 26 or 27, wherein the reaction medium comprises an oxidising agent.
</P>
<P>
29. An electronic device comprising -a substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface with an outer surface -a plurality of substantially pyramidal shaped nanoparticles attached by non-covalent bonds to the outer surface of the substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface.
</P>
<P>
30. The electronic device according to claim 30 for use as a photovoltaic cell or a light emitting device.
</P>
<P>
31. The electronic device according to claim 30 or 31 wherein the substantially unfunctionalised carbon surface is a carbon nanotube. 2T3
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
GB2447954A;US2010316554A1;KR20090128482A;JP2010522133A;WO2008116661A2;WO2008116661A3
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
