<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
USE OF NANODISPERSIONS TO PROTECT WATER- SOLUBLE INGREDIENTS IN COSMETIC END FORMULATIONS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2170250A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
MONGIAT SEBASTIEN [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
GRUMELARD JULIE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
BASCHONG WERNER [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
HERZOG BERND [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
MONGIAT, SEBASTIEN
</Name>
<Name>
GRUMELARD, JULIE
</Name>
<Name>
BASCHONG, WERNER
</Name>
<Name>
HERZOG, BERND
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BASF SE [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BASF SE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2170250
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080786304
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008EP59568
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070113510
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-31
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080786304
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-22
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K8/04
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/55
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/60
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/891
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q19/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q5/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K8/04
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/34D
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/37C
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/49P
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/55C
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/67H
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/68
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/86
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/894
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/898
</Class>
<Class>
A61K8/90
</Class>
<Class>
A61Q19/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention describes the use of a nanodispersion, which comprises: a) a membrane-forming molecule, b) a coemulsifier, c) a lipophilic component, and d) a water-soluble ingredient sensitive to oxidation in cosmetic end formulations, the nanodispersion being obtainable by (a) mixing the components (a), (b) and (c) until a homogeneous liquid is obtained (so-called nanodispersion pre-phase), and (ss) adding the water or aqueous phase (discontinuous phase) which contains the water-soluble ingredient and optionally the non-aqueous polar organic solvent to the liquid obtained in step (a). Component (d) is preferably ascorbic acid or vitamin C.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. Use of a nanodispersion, which comprises
</P>
<P>
(a) a membrane-forming molecule,
</P>
<P>
(b) a coemulsifier,
</P>
<P>
(c) a lipophilic component, and
</P>
<P>
(d) a water-soluble ingredient sensitive to oxidation
</P>
<P>
in cosmetic end formulations, the nanodispersion being obtainable by ([alpha]) mixing the components (a), (b) and (c) until a homogeneous liquid is obtained (so-called nanodispersion pre- phase), and ([beta]) adding the water or aqueous phase (discontinuous phase) which contains the water-soluble ingredient and optionally the non-aqueous polar organic solvent to the liquid obtained in step ([alpha]).
</P>
<P>
2. Use according to claim 1 wherein component (d) is ascorbic acid or vitamin C.
</P>
<P>
3. Use according to claim 1 , wherein the non-aqueous polar organic solvents are polyols, homopolymeric or block copolymeric liquid ethers.
</P>
<P>
4. Use according to claim 1 , wherein step ([alpha]) is carried out in anhydrous medium.
</P>
<P>
5. Use according to claim 1 , wherein step ([beta]) is carried out without homogenisation.
</P>
<P>
6. Use according to claim 1 , wherein the particles in the nanodispersion have an average diameter of &amp;lt;100 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. Use according to claim 1 , comprising additionally a component (e) which is an antioxidant.
</P>
<P>
8. Use according to claim 7, wherein component (e) is selected from the group consisting of carbon bridged hindered phenols, ester bridged hindered phenols, amide bridged hindered phenols, lactones of hindered phenols, sterically hindered oxylamines and sterically hindered hydroxylamines. 9. Use according to claim 7, wherein component (e) is a compound of the formula A or B
</P>
<P>
wherein M is hydrogen or sodium.
</P>
<P>
10. Use according to claim 7, comprising further hydrophilic or lipophilic antioxidants selected from the group consisting of tocopherols and its ester of acids, tocotrienol and its ester of acids, ascorbic acid esters, retinoids, carotenoids, glutathione peroxidise, catalase, superoxide dismutase, ubiquinone and idebenone, lipoic acid and its derivatives, rutinic acid and its derivatives, phenolic acids, flavonoids and polyphenols, chlorogenic acid and ferulic acid.
</P>
<P>
11. Use according to claim 7, wherein the weight ratio between component (e) and component (d) is from 1 : 100 to 10 : 1.
</P>
<P>
12. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (a) is a substance which is suitable for forming so-called bilayers, component (b) is a substance which preferably forms W/O structures, and component (c) is a functional lipophilic active agent customarily used in cosmetics. 13. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (a) is a phospholipid, a hydrated or partially hydrated phospholipid, a lysophospholipid, a ceramide or mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. Use according to claims 1 , wherein component (a) is a phospholipid of the formula 1
</P>
<P>
wherein
</P>
<P>
Ri is Cio-C2Oacyl;
</P>
<P>
R2 is hydrogen or CiO-C2oacyl,
</P>
<P>
R3 is hydrogen, 2-trimethylamino-1 -ethyl (or referred as lecithin), 2-amino-1 -ethyl; d-C5alkyl which is unsubstituted or substituted by one or several carboxy, hydroxy or amino groups; the inositol or glyceryl group; or salts of these compounds of the formula 1.
</P>
<P>
15. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (a) is present in the nanodispersion in a concentration of 0.1 to 30% by weight, based on the total weight of components (a), (b), (c) and (d).
</P>
<P>
16. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (b) is a siloxane or organosiloxane, a sor- bitan derivative or a mixture of these substances.
</P>
<P>
17. Use according to claim 16, wherein component (b) is a compound of the formula 2
</P>
<P>
(2)
</P>
<P>
wherein m is a number from 1 to 20, n is a number from 0 to 500, p is a number from 0 to 50,
</P>
<P>
Ri is Ci-C3oalkyl or phenyl,
</P>
<P>
R2 is -CcH2c-(OC2H4)a-(OC3H6)b-(OC4H8)d-R3,
</P>
<P>
R3 is hydrogen, hydroxy, linear or branched Ci-Ci2alkyl, linear or branched Ci-C6alkoxy, linear or branched C2-Ci2acyloxy, -NHCH2CH2COOM, -NHCO(CH2)d-COOM, Ci-C30-carb- oxyacyl, -NHCO(CH2)d-OH Or -NH3Y
</P>
<P>
M is hydrogen, sodium, potassium, lithium, ammonium or an organic ammonium,
</P>
<P>
Y is a monovalent organic or inorganic anion such as chloro, bromo, sulfate or carboxylate, a is a number from 0 to 100, b is a number from 0 to 50, c is a number from 0 to 5, and d is a number from 0 to 10.
</P>
<P>
18. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (b) is present in the nanodispersion in a concentration of 1 to 50% by weight, based on the total weight of the components (a), (b), (c) and (d).
</P>
<P>
19. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (c) is a natural or synthetic or partially synthetic di- or triglyceride, a mineral oil, silicone oil, wax, fatty alcohol, guerbet alcohol or the ester thereof, or a mixture of these substances.
</P>
<P>
20. Use according to claim 1 , wherein component (c) comprises esters represented by the class RCO-OR&apos;, wherein RCO- represents the carboxylic acid radical and -OR&apos; is the alcohol residue; glyceryl esters and derivatives, alkoxylated alcohol esters, alkoxylated alcohol glyceryl esters and derivatives, alkoxylated alcohol ethers, fats and oils, ethers, hydrocarbons or silicones, or a mixture of these substances.
</P>
<P>
21. Use according to claim, wherein component (c) is present in the cosmetic end formulation in a concentration of 0.1 to 80% by weight based on the total weight of the components (a), (b), (C) and (d). 22. Use according to claim 1 , comprising additionally a component (f) which is a non-aqueous polar organic solvent to fasten and improve the hydration rate of component (a).
</P>
<P>
23. Use according to claim 1 , wherein the nanodispersion is present in the end formulation in a concentration of 0.01 to 99% by weight, based on the total weight of the cosmetic end- product.
</P>
<P>
24. Use according to claim 1 , wherein at least one component (a), (b) or (c) is an ingredient used in cosmetics for treating or protecting the skin, mucosae or hair.
</P>
<P>
25. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a stick, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
26. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a gel, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
27. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a cream, lotion or milk, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
28. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a spray or aerosol, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
29. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a foam, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
30. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a paste, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1.
</P>
<P>
31. A cosmetic end formulation in the form of a powder, lacquer, pellet or make-up, which comprises a nanodispersion as defined in claim 1 , the nanodispersion being present in dehydrated form.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009016064A1;US2012093896A1;MX2010001127A;KR20100052497A;JP2010534702A;CN101765420A;AU2008281934A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
