<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METHOD OF DEPOSITING SILICON ON CARBON MATERIALS AND FORMING AN ANODE FOR USE IN LITHIUM ION BATTERIES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2162564A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BURTON DAVID J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LAKE MAX L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NAZRI MARYAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BURTON, DAVID, J
</Name>
<Name>
LAKE, MAX, L
</Name>
<Name>
NAZRI, MARYAM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
APPLIED SCIENCES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
APPLIED SCIENCES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2162564
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080826280
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US61197
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070913321P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080107254
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-22
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C23C16/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/04
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/13
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/139
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/38
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/58
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/587
</Class>
<Class>
H01M10/052
</Class>
<Class>
H01M10/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C23C16/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/04B18
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/13
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/139
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/38
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/587
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E60/12B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method of modifying the surface of carbon materials such as vapor grown carbon nanofibers is provided in which silicon is deposited on vapor grown carbon nanofibers using a chemical vapor deposition process. The resulting silicon-carbon alloy may be used as an anode in a rechargeable lithium ion battery.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A method of depositing silicon onto a carbon material to form an alloy for use in lithium ion batteries comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a carbon material selected from vapor grown carbon fibers, vapor grown carbon nanofibers, PAN or pitch derived carbon fibers, graphite flakes, graphene platelets, and carbon nanotubes;
</P>
<P>
heating said carbon material at a temperature between about 100[deg.] C. to about 1200[deg.] C.;
</P>
<P>
flowing a silicon-containing precursor gas in contact with said carbon material for a time sufficient for said gas to decompose and form a coating on at least the surface of said carbon material.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 wherein said precursor gas comprises silane, a blend of silane and hydrogen, or a blend of silane and an inert gas.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1 wherein said carbon material comprises vapor grown carbon nanofibers.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 3 wherein said vapor grown carbon nanofibers have been heated treated at a temperature above 700[deg.] C.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 1 wherein said silicon coating comprises crystalline silicon, amorphous silicon, or silicon compounds.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1 wherein said carbon material further includes a carbide material selected from metal carbides, silicon carbides, and silicon oxides.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1 wherein said carbon material further includes a carbon or graphite additive selected from single-walled carbon nanotubes, multi-walled carbon nanotubes, exfoliated graphite flakes, graphite platelets, graphene particles, carbon black, and mesocarbon microbeads.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1 wherein said carbon material further includes a conductive additive comprising macroscopic vapor grown carbon nanofibers having a diameter of from about 500 nm to 10 micrometers.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1 wherein said carbon material has a length of from about 1 to about 500 micrometers.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1 wherein said carbon material is in the form of a low density composite or preform.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 1 wherein said silicon is coated onto said carbon material at a thickness of about 0.001 and 100 microns.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1 wherein said silicon is coated onto said carbon material at a thickness of about 2 to 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 1 wherein said silicon-coated carbon material has a graded interface.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 1 further including forming an anode by adding a binder to said silicon-coated carbon material.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14 wherein said binder is selected from polyvinylidene difluoride, EPDM, and polystyrene.
</P>
<P>
16. An anode formed by the method of claim 14 for use in a lithium ion battery.
</P>
<P>
17. The anode of claim 16 having an electrical conductivity of from about 0.01 to about 0.5 ohm/cm.
</P>
<P>
18. The anode of claim 16 having an irreversible capacity of from about 5% to 40% of total capacity.
</P>
<P>
19. The anode of claim 16 having a reversible capacity of at least 350 mAH/g.
</P>
<P>
20. The anode of claim 16 having a reversible capacity of at least 1000 mAH/g.
</P>
<P>
21. The anode of claim 16 having a thermal conductivity of at least 50 w/m-K up to 1000 w/m-K.
</P>
<P>
22. A lithiated carbon-silicon alloy formed by providing a carbon material selected from vapor grown carbon fibers, vapor grown carbon nanofibers, PAN or pitch derived carbon fibers, graphite flakes, graphene platelets, and carbon nanotubes;
</P>
<P>
heating said carbon material at a temperature between about 100[deg.] C. to about 1200[deg.] C.;
</P>
<P>
flowing a silicon-containing precursor gas in contact with said carbon material for a time sufficient for said gas to decompose and form a coating on at least the surface of said carbon material; and
</P>
<P>
evaporating lithium on the silicon-coated carbon material.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008261116A1;WO2009009206A2;WO2009009206A3;JP2010525549A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
