<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CATIONIC LATEX AS A CARRIER FOR BIOACTIVE INGREDIENTS AND METHODS FOR MAKING AND USING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2134324A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
KRISHNAN VENKATARAM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KRISHNAN, VENKATARAM
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MALLARD CREEK POLYMERS INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MALLARD CREEK POLYMERS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2134324
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080825926
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-02-11
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US01773
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-02-11
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070711442
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-27
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A01N25/10
</Class>
<Class>
A01N25/34
</Class>
<Class>
A01N33/12
</Class>
<Class>
A01N37/18
</Class>
<Class>
A01N37/26
</Class>
<Class>
A01N37/44
</Class>
<Class>
B32B19/00
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/21
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/233
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/263
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/356
</Class>
<Class>
D06N3/00
</Class>
<Class>
D21H21/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A01N25/10
</Class>
<Class>
A01N25/34
</Class>
<Class>
A01N33/12
</Class>
<Class>
A01N37/18
</Class>
<Class>
A01N37/26
</Class>
<Class>
A01N37/44
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/21
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/233
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/263
</Class>
<Class>
D06M15/356
</Class>
<Class>
D06N3/00E
</Class>
<Class>
D21H21/36
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
This invention relates to latex compositions that incorporate at least one bioactive component such as an antibacterial or antifungal agent, and methods for making and using such latex compositions. The latex compositions disclosed herein can be prepared by the emulsion polymerization of the latex component monomers in the presence of the at least one bioactive component.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
I claim:
</P>
<P>
1. A bioactive cationic polymer latex comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) a latex polymer comprising the polymerization product of: i) at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer; and ii) at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer that is cationic or a precursor to a cation;
</P>
<P>
b) at least one bioactive component at least partially encapsulated within the latex polymer; and
</P>
<P>
c) optionally, at least one sterically bulky component incorporated into the latex polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer is selected independently from a vinyl aromatic monomer, a halogenated or a non-halogenated olefin monomer, an aliphatic conjugated diene monomer, a non-aromatic unsaturated mono- or dicarboxylic ester monomer, a monomer based on the half ester of an unsaturated dicarboxylic acid monomer, an unsaturated mono- or dicarboxylic acid monomer, a nitrile-containing monomer, a cyclic or an acyclic amine-containing monomer, a branched or an unbranched alkyl vinyl ester monomer, a halogenated or non-halogenated alkyl acrylate monomer, a halogenated or non-halogenated aryl acrylate monomer, a carboxylic acid vinyl ester, an acetic acid alkenyl ester, a carboxylic acid alkenyl ester, a vinyl halide, a vinylidene halide, or any combination thereof, any of which having up to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
3. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer is selected independently from styrene, para-methyl styrene, chloromethyl styrene, vinyl toluene, ethylene, butadiene, methyl (meth)acrylate, ethyl(meth)acrylate, propyl(meth)acrylate, butyl(meth)acrylate, pentyl (meth)acrylate, glycidyl(meth)acrylate, isodecyl(meth)acrylate, lauryl(meth)acrylate, monomethyl maleate, itaconic acid, (meth)acrylonitrile, (meth)acrylamide, N-methylol (meth)acrylamide, N-(isobutoxymethyl)(meth)acrylamide, vinyl neodecanoate, vinyl versatates, vinyl acetate, a C3-C8 alkyl vinylether, a C3-C8 alkoxy vinylether, vinyl chloride, vinylidene chloride, vinyl fluoride, vinylidene fluoride, trifluoroethylene, tetrafluoroethylene, chlorotrifluoroethylene, hexafluoropropylene, chlorotrifluoroethylene, perfluorobutyl ethylene, a perfluorinated C3-C8 alpha-olefin, a fluorinated C3-C8 alkyl vinylether, a perfluorinated C3-C8 alkyl vinylether, a perfluorinated C3-C8 alkoxy vinyl ether, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer is selected independently from an amine monomer, an amide monomer, a quaternary amine monomer, a phosphonium monomer, a sulfonium monomer, or any combination thereof, any of which having up to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
5. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer is selected independently from dimethylaminoethyl acrylate; diethylaminoethyl acrylate; dimethyl aminoethyl methacrylate; diethylaminoethyl methacrylate; tertiary butylaminoethyl methacrylate; N,N-dimethyl acrylamide; N,N-dimethylaminopropyl acrylamide; acryloyl morpholine; N-isopropyl acrylamide; N,N-diethyl acrylamide; dimethyl aminoethyl vinyl ether; 2-methyl-1-vinyl imidazole; N,N-dimethyl-aminopropyl methacrylamide; vinyl pyridine; vinyl benzyl amine; dimethylaminoethyl acrylate, methyl chloride quarternary; dimethylaminoethyl methacrylate, methyl chloride quarternary; diallyldimethylammonium chloride; N,N-dimethylaminopropyl acrylamide, methyl chloride quaternary; trimethyl-(vinyloxyethyl)ammonium chloride; 1-vinyl-2,3-dimethylimidazolinium chloride; vinyl benzyl amine hydrochloride; vinyl pyridinium hydrochloride; or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
6. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is selected independently from at least one sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer, at least one sterically bulky polymer, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is at least one a sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer selected independently from:
</P>
<P>
a) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; O)mR&amp;lt;3A&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3A &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or an alkyl group having from 1 to 6 carbon atoms, inclusive, and m is an integer from 1 to 30, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
b) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CH2O)n(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; O)pR&amp;lt;3B&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3B &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or an alkyl group having from 1 to 6 carbon atoms, inclusive, and n and p are integers selected independently from 1 to 15, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
c) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; O)q(CH2CH2O)rR&amp;lt;3C&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3C &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or an alkyl group having from 1 to 6 carbon atoms, inclusive, and q and r are integers selected independently from 1 to 15, inclusive; or
</P>
<P>
d) any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is at least one sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer selected independently from:
</P>
<P>
a) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; O)mR&amp;lt;3A&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3A &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or methyl, and m is an integer from 1 to 10, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
b) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CH2O)n(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; O)pR&amp;lt;3B&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3B &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or methyl, and n and p are integers selected independently from 1 to 10, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
c) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; O)q(CH2CH2O)rR&amp;lt;3C&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3C &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or methyl, and q and r are integers selected independently from 1 to 10, inclusive; or
</P>
<P>
d) any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
9. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is selected independently from: an alkoxylated monoester of a dicarboxylic acid; an alkoxylated diester of a dicarboxylic acid; a polyoxyethylene alkylphenyl ether; a polymerizable surfactant; or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
10. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is at least one sterically bulky polymer selected independently from polyvinyl alcohols, polyvinyl pyrollidone, hydroxyethyl cellulose, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
11. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one bioactive component is selected independently from undecylenic acid; undecylenic alcohol; the reaction product of undecylenic acid with hydroxylethyl (meth)acrylate or polyethylene glycol (meth)acrylate; the reaction product of undecylenic alcohol with (meth)acrylic acid, maleic anhydride, or itaconic acid; chitosan or modified chitosans; or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
12. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one bioactive component is selected independently from copper, copper salts, silver, silver salts, zinc, zinc salts, silver oxide, zinc oxide, chlorhexidine, chlorhexidine gluconate, glutaral, halazone, hexachlorophene, nitrofurazone, nitromersol, povidone-iodine, thimerosol, C1- to C5-parabens, hypochlorite salts, clofucarban, clorophene, poloxamer-iodine, phenolics, mafenide acetate, aminacrine hydrochloride, quaternary ammonium salts, oxychlorosene, metabromsalan, merbromin, dibromsalan, glyceryl laurate, pyrithione salts, sodium pyrithione, zinc pyrithione, (dodecyl) (diethylenediamine)glycine, (dodecyl)(aminopropyl)glycine, phenol, m-cresol, o-cresol, p-cresol, o-phenyl-phenol, resorcinol, vinyl phenol, polymeric guanidines, polymyxins, bacitracin, circulin, octapeptins, lysozmye, lysostaphin, cellulytic enzymes, vancomycin, ristocetin, actinoidins, avoparcins, tyrocidin A, gramicidin S, polyoxin D, tunicamycin, neomycin, streptomycin, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the at least one bioactive component is selected independently from azaconazole, biternatol, bromuconazole, cyproconazole, diniconazole, fenbuconazole, flusilazole, flutnafol, imazalil, imibenconazole, metconazole, paclobutrazol, perfuazoate, penconazole, simeconazole, triadimefon, triadimenol, uniconazole, mancozeb, maneb, metiram, zineb, fludioxonil, fluquinconazole, difenoconazole, 4,5-dimethyl-N-(2-propenyl)-2-(trimethylsilyl)-3-thiophenecarboxamide (sylthiopham), hexaconazole, etaconazole, triticonazole, flutriafol, epoxiconazole, bromuconazote, tetraconazole, myclobutanil, bitertanol, pyremethanil, cyprodinil, tridemorph, fenpropimorph, kresoxim-methyl, azoxystrobin, ZEN90160(TM), fenpiclonil, benalaxyl, furalaxyl, metalaxyl, R-metalaxyl, orfurace, oxadixyl, carboxin, prochloraz, triflumizole, pyrifenox, acibenzolar-S-methyl, chlorothalonil, cymoxanil, dimethomorph, famoxadone, quinoxyfen, fenpropidine, spiroxamine, triazoxide, BAS50001F(TM), hymexazole, pencycuron, fenamidone, guazatine, benomyl, captan, carbendazim, capropamid, ethirimol, flutolanil, fosetyl-aluminum, fuberidazole, hymexanol, kasugamycin, iminoctadine-triacetate, ipconazole, iprodione, mepronil, metalaxyl-M (mefenoxam), nuarimol, oxine-copper, oxolinic acid, perfurazoate, propamocarb hydrochloride, pyroquilon, quintozene, silthiopham, MON(TM) 65500, tecnazene, thiabendazole, thifluzamide, thiophenate-methyl, thiram, tolclofos-methyl, triflumizole, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, comprising from about 20 percent to about 99.5 percent by weight of the ethylenically unsaturated first monomer, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
15. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, comprising from about 0.01 percent to about 75 percent by weight of the ethylenically unsaturated second monomer, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
16. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, comprising from about 0.01 percent to about 40 percent by weight bioactive additive, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
17. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, comprising from 0 percent to about 25 percent by weight sterically bulky component, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
18. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, further comprising a nonionic surfactant.
</P>
<P>
19. The bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1, wherein the latex polymer is substantially devoid of cationic and anionic surfactants.
</P>
<P>
20. A coating comprising the bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
21. An article comprising the bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
22. A method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex comprising initiating an emulsion polymerization of an aqueous composition comprising, at any time during the emulsion polymerization:
</P>
<P>
a) at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer;
</P>
<P>
b) at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer that is cationic or a precursor to a cation;
</P>
<P>
c) at least one bioactive component;
</P>
<P>
d) at least one free-radical initiator;
</P>
<P>
e) optionally, at least one sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer;
</P>
<P>
f) optionally, at least one sterically bulky polymer; and
</P>
<P>
g) optionally, at least one non nonionic surfactant.
</P>
<P>
23. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the method is a semi-continuous process, and wherein at least one bioactive component is dissolved in the monomer feed at any time during the emulsion polymerization.
</P>
<P>
24. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the method is a batch process, and wherein the at least one bioactive component is present in the seed stage of the emulsion polymerization.
</P>
<P>
25. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the aqueous composition components and the at least one bioactive component are provided as a dispersion prior to initiating the emulsion polymerization.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer is selected independently from a vinyl aromatic monomer, a halogenated or a non-halogenated olefin monomer, an aliphatic conjugated diene monomer, a non-aromatic unsaturated mono- or dicarboxylic ester monomer, a monomer based on the half ester of an unsaturated dicarboxylic acid monomer, an unsaturated mono- or dicarboxylic acid monomer, a nitrile-containing monomer, a cyclic or an acyclic amine-containing monomer, a branched or an unbranched alkyl vinyl ester monomer, a halogenated or non-halogenated alkyl acrylate monomer, a halogenated or non-halogenated aryl acrylate monomer, a carboxylic acid vinyl ester, an acetic acid alkenyl ester, a carboxylic acid alkenyl ester, a vinyl halide, a vinylidene halide, or any combination thereof, any of which having up to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer is selected independently from styrene, para-methyl styrene, chloromethyl styrene, vinyl toluene, ethylene, butadiene, methyl(meth)acrylate, ethyl(meth)acrylate, propyl(meth)acrylate, butyl(meth)acrylate, pentyl(meth)acrylate, glycidyl(meth)acrylate, isodecyl (meth)acrylate, lauryl(meth)acrylate, monomethyl maleate, itaconic acid, (meth)acrylonitrile, (meth)acrylamide, N-methylol (meth)acrylamide, N-(isobutoxymethyl)(meth)acrylamide, vinyl neodecanoate, vinyl versatates, vinyl acetate, a C3-C8 alkyl vinylether, a C3-C8 alkoxy vinylether, vinyl chloride, vinylidene chloride, vinyl fluoride, vinylidene fluoride, trifluoroethylene, tetrafluoroethylene, chlorotrifluoroethylene, hexafluoropropylene, chlorotrifluoroethylene, perfluorobutyl ethylene, a perfluorinated C3-C8 alpha-olefin, a fluorinated C3-C8 alkyl vinylether, a perfluorinated C3-C8 alkyl vinylether, a perfluorinated C3-C8 alkoxy vinyl ether, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer is selected independently from an amine monomer, an amide monomer, a quaternary amine monomer, a phosphonium monomer, a sulfonium monomer, or any combination thereof, any of which having up to 20 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer is selected independently from dimethylaminoethyl acrylate; diethylaminoethyl acrylate; dimethyl aminoethyl methacrylate; diethylaminoethyl methacrylate; tertiary butylaminoethyl methacrylate; N,N-dimethyl acrylamide; N,N-dimethylaminopropyl acrylamide; acryloyl morpholine; N-isopropyl acrylamide; N,N-diethyl acrylamide; dimethyl aminoethyl vinyl ether; 2-methyl-1-vinyl imidazole; N,N-dimethyl-aminopropyl methacrylamide; vinyl pyridine; vinyl benzyl amine; dimethylaminoethyl acrylate, methyl chloride quarternary; dimethylaminoethyl methacrylate, methyl chloride quarternary; diallyldimethylammonium chloride; N,N-dimethylaminopropyl acrylamide, methyl chloride quaternary; trimethyl-(vinyloxyethyl)ammonium chloride; 1-vinyl-2,3-dimethylimidazolinium chloride; vinyl benzyl amine hydrochloride; vinyl pyridinium hydrochloride; or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is selected independently from at least one sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer, at least one sterically bulky polymer, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is at least one a sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer selected independently from:
</P>
<P>
a) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; O)mR&amp;lt;3A&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3A &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or an alkyl group having from 1 to 6 carbon atoms, inclusive, and m is an integer from 1 to 30, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
b) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CH2O)n(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; O)pR&amp;lt;3B&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3B &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or an alkyl group having from 1 to 6 carbon atoms, inclusive, and n and p are integers selected independently from 1 to 15, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
c) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; O)q(CH2CH2O)rR&amp;lt;3C&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3C &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or an alkyl group having from 1 to 6 carbon atoms, inclusive, and q and r are integers selected independently from 1 to 15, inclusive; or
</P>
<P>
d) any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
32. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is at least one sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer selected independently from:
</P>
<P>
a) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; O)mR&amp;lt;3A&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1A&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2A&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3A &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or methyl, and m is an integer from 1 to 10, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
b) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CH2O)n(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; O)pR&amp;lt;3B&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1B&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2B&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3B &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or methyl, and n and p are integers selected independently from 1 to 10, inclusive;
</P>
<P>
c) CH2-C(R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; )COO(CH2CHR&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; O)q(CH2CH2O)rR&amp;lt;3C&amp;gt; , wherein R&amp;lt;1C&amp;gt; , R&amp;lt;2C&amp;gt; , and R&amp;lt;3C &amp;gt; are selected independently from H or methyl, and q and r are integers selected independently from 1 to 10, inclusive; or
</P>
<P>
d) any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is selected independently from: an alkoxylated monoester of a dicarboxylic acid; an alkoxylated diester of a dicarboxylic acid; a polyoxyethylene alkylphenyl ether; a polymerizable surfactant; or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one sterically bulky component is at least one sterically bulky polymer selected independently from polyvinyl alcohols, polyvinyl pyrollidone, hydroxyethyl cellulose, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one bioactive component is selected independently from undecylenic acid; undecylenic alcohol; the reaction product of undecylenic acid with hydroxylethyl(meth)acrylate or polyethylene glycol (meth)acrylate; the reaction product of undecylenic alcohol with (meth)acrylic acid, maleic anhydride, or itaconic acid; chitosan or modified chitosans; or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one bioactive component is selected independently from copper, copper salts, silver, silver salts, zinc, zinc salts, silver oxide, zinc oxide, chlorhexidine, chlorhexidine gluconate, glutaral, halazone, hexachlorophene, nitrofurazone, nitromersol, povidone-iodine, thimerosol, C1- to C5-parabens, hypochlorite salts, clofucarban, clorophene, poloxamer-iodine, phenolics, mafenide acetate, aminacrine hydrochloride, quaternary ammonium salts, oxychlorosene, metabromsalan, merbromin, dibromsalan, glyceryl laurate, pyrithione salts, sodium pyrithione, zinc pyrithione, (dodecyl)(diethylenediamine)glycine, (dodecyl)(aminopropyl)glycine, phenol, m-cresol, o-cresol, p-cresol, o-phenyl-phenol, resorcinol, vinyl phenol, polymeric guanidines, polymyxins, bacitracin, circulin, octapeptins, lysozmye, lysostaphin, cellulytic enzymes, vancomycin, ristocetin, actinoidins, avoparcins, tyrocidin A, gramicidin S, polyoxin D, tunicamycin, neomycin, streptomycin, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
37. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the at least one bioactive component is selected independently from azaconazole, biternatol, bromuconazole, cyproconazole, diniconazole, fenbuconazole, flusilazole, flutnafol, imazalil, imibenconazole, metconazole, paclobutrazol, perfuazoate, penconazole, simeconazole, triadimefon, triadimenol, uniconazole, mancozeb, maneb, metiram, zineb, fludioxonil, fluquinconazole, difenoconazole, 4,5-dimethyl-N-(2-propenyl)-2-(trimethylsilyl)-3-thiophenecarboxamide (sylthiopham), hexaconazole, etaconazole, triticonazole, flutriafol, epoxiconazole, bromuconazote, tetraconazole, myclobutanil, bitertanol, pyremethanil, cyprodinil, tridemorph, fenpropimorph, kresoxim-methyl, azoxystrobin, ZEN90160(TM), fenpiclonil, benalaxyl, furalaxyl, metalaxyl, R-metalaxyl, orfurace, oxadixyl, carboxin, prochloraz, triflumizole, pyrifenox, acibenzolar-S-methyl, chlorothalonil, cymoxanil, dimethomorph, famoxadone, quinoxyfen, fenpropidine, spiroxamine, triazoxide, BAS50001F(TM), hymexazole, pencycuron, fenamidone, guazatine, benomyl, captan, carbendazim, capropamid, ethirimol, flutolanil, fosetyl-aluminum, fuberidazole, hymexanol, kasugamycin, iminoctadine-triacetate, ipconazole, iprodione, mepronil, metalaxyl-M (mefenoxam), nuarimol, oxine-copper, oxolinic acid, perfurazoate, propamocarb hydrochloride, pyroquilon, quintozene, silthiopham, MON(TM) 65500, tecnazene, thiabendazole, thifluzamide, thiophenate-methyl, thiram, tolclofos-methyl, triflumizole, or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the bioactive cationic polymer latex comprises from about 20 percent to about 99.5 percent by weight of the ethylenically unsaturated first monomer, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the bioactive cationic polymer latex comprises from about 0.01 percent to about 75 percent by weight of the ethylenically unsaturated second monomer, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the bioactive cationic polymer latex comprises from about 0.01 percent to about 40 percent by weight bioactive additive, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
41. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the bioactive cationic polymer latex comprises from 0 percent to about 25 percent by weight sterically bulky component, based on the total monomer weight.
</P>
<P>
42. The method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex according to claim 22, wherein the bioactive cationic polymer latex is substantially devoid of cationic and anionic surfactants.
</P>
<P>
43. A method of making a bioactive cationic polymer latex comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) providing an aqueous composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
i) at least one ethylenically unsaturated first monomer;
</P>
<P>
ii) at least one ethylenically unsaturated second monomer that is cationic or a precursor to a cation;
</P>
<P>
iii) optionally, at least one sterically bulky ethylenically unsaturated third monomer;
</P>
<P>
iv) at least one free-radical initiator; and
</P>
<P>
v) optionally, at least one non-ionic surfactant;
</P>
<P>
b) initiating an emulsion polymerization of the composition; and
</P>
<P>
c) adding at least one bioactive component to the composition during the emulsion polymerization process.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2007149694A1;US7781498B2;WO2008156509A2;WO2008156509A3;KR20100014559A;KR101016425B1;CN101743123A;CA2679154A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
