<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Nanosensors based on nanoparticles immobilized on stimuli responsive polymer brushes
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2128598A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GUPTA SMRATI [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
AGRAWAL MUKESH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
UHLMANN PETRA [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
STAMM MANFRED [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
GUPTA, SMRATI
</Name>
<Name>
AGRAWAL, MUKESH
</Name>
<Name>
UHLMANN, PETRA
</Name>
<Name>
STAMM, MANFRED
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
LEIBNIZ INST POLYMERFORSCHUNG [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
LEIBNIZ-INSTITUT FUER POLYMERFORSCHUNG DRESDEN E.V
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2128598
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080009827
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-29
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080009827
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-29
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N21/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/55B2N
</Class>
<Class>
G01N21/64P8
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543D6
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention is directed to a sensor comprising: - a substrate (1);  - a polymer brush (4) formed of polymer molecules anchored by a first end to a surface of the substrate and having a second, free end located on a terminal end opposite to the first end;  - nanoparticles (5) fixed to the second end of the polymer brush. The invention is further directed to a method for obtaining said sensor and the use of the sensor for detecting a variety of organic analytes.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A sensor comprising:
</P>
<P>
- a substrate (1);
</P>
<P>
- a polymer brush (4) formed of polymer molecules anchored by a first end to a surface of the substrate and having a second, free end located on a terminal end opposite to the first end;
</P>
<P>
- nanoparticles (5) fixed to the second end of the polymer brush.
</P>
<P>
2. Sensor according to claim 1, wherein the polymer brush comprises a bonding group at the second end.
</P>
<P>
3. Sensor according to one of the preceding claims, wherein the polymer brush is formed from linear polymer chains.
</P>
<P>
4. Sensor according to one of the preceding claims, wherein the polymer brush is formed from hydrocarbon repeating units.
</P>
<P>
5. Sensor according to one of the preceding claims, wherein the polymer brush has a density of 0.05 to 0.5 polymer chains per nm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
6. Sensor according to one of the preceding claims, wherein the polymer brush (4) is bound to the substrate (1) via an anchoring layer (3).
</P>
<P>
7. Sensor according to claim 6, wherein the anchoring layer is formed from a polymer comprising reactive groups.
</P>
<P>
8. Sensor according to one of the preceding claims, wherein the nanoparticles are formed from metals.
</P>
<P>
9. Sensor according to one of the preceding claims, wherein the nanoparticles are functionalized by surface molecules comprising a functional group that may bind to the bonding group of the polymer brush.
</P>
<P>
10. Sensor according to claim 9, wherein the surface molecule comprises a linking group for linking the surface molecule to the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
11. Method for obtaining a sensor according to one of claims 1 to 10 comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
- providing a substrate;
</P>
<P>
- providing a polymer brush formed of polymer molecules anchored by a first end to a surface of the substrate and having a second, free end located on a terminal end opposite to the first end;
</P>
<P>
- fixing nanoparticles to the second, free end of the polymer brush.
</P>
<P>
12. Method according to claim 11, wherein the nanoparticles are fixed to the second, free end of the polymer brush by providing a dispersion of the nanoparticles in a liquid and applying said dispersion to the polymer brush anchored by the first end to the surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
13. Method for detecting an analyte comprising the steps:
</P>
<P>
- providing a sensor according to one of claims 1 to 10;
</P>
<P>
- selecting a physical parameter of the sensor;
</P>
<P>
- determining the physical parameter thereby obtaining a reference value;
</P>
<P>
- applying a stimulus to the sensor;
</P>
<P>
- determining the physical parameter of the sensor in the presence of the stimulus, thereby obtaining a measured value;
</P>
<P>
- determining a difference between the reference value and the measured value.
</P>
<P>
14. Method according to claim 13 wherein the physical property of the sensor is a UV/VIS-absorption.
</P>
<P>
15. Method according to one of claims 13 and 14, wherein the analyte is provided in liquid phase.
</P>
</Claims>
</BiblioData>
