<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ROTATING TRANSFER DEVICE FOR COMPLEX PATTERNING
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2129472A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
CHEN XIAODONG [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
HIRTZ MICHAEL [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
CHI LIFENG [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
FUCHS HARALD [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
CHEN, XIAODONG
</Name>
<Name>
HIRTZ, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
CHI, LIFENG
</Name>
<Name>
FUCHS, HARALD
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV MUENSTER WILHELMS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
WESTFAELISCHE WILHELMS-UNIVERSITAET MUENSTER
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2129472
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070846722
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-11-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP10090
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20060023181
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-11-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B05D1/20
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B05D1/20C5
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Preferably a Langmuir (LB) film 105 floats on a liquid 104, especially water. The substrate 102 is coated as it passes through the film 105 at the gas liquid interface. The substrate 102 holder (clamp) 101 is rotated by a motor 106 via gear 107, about a pivot axis 103. The axis 103 may be angled at up to 60{ relative to the film 105. Preferably the flat substrate 102 is mica, single crystalline silicon, glass, quartz, polymer or gold. Preferably the coating is L- a -dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC), nanocrystals, cells, polymers or monomers. Preferably the apparatus includes angular control and linear positioning capabilities. The coated substrates are used for in vitro modeling of biological phenomena, especially axon guidance, cell signaling and proliferation.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims I. A rotating transfer device for transfer of a film to a
</P>
<P>
substrate (102) at a gas-liquid interface (105), the rotating transfer device comprising -a substrate holder (101) holding said substrate, and a rotational positioning unit for rotating the substrate holder (101), the rotational positioning unit having a pivot (103) to which the substrate holder (101) is attached, whereby the pivot (103) is angled between 00 and 60 to the plane of the interface surface (105).
</P>
<P>
2. The rotating transfer device of claim 1, wherein the pivot (103) is substantially parallel to the plane of the interface surface (105).
</P>
<P>
3. The rotating transfer device of claim 1, wherein said rotational positioning unit comprises a motor (106) and a gear (107).
</P>
<P>
4. The rotating transfer device of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising an angular control.
</P>
<P>
5. The rotating transfer device of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising a linear positioning unit.
</P>
<P>
:.2g. 6. The rotating transfer device of any one of the preceding claims, wherein said film . consists of DPPC, nanocrystals, or polymers.
</P>
<P>
7. The rotating transfer device of any of the above claims, wherein the substrate (102) is :: selected from the group consisting of mica, single crystalline silicon, glass, quartz, polymer and gold. e.
</P>
<P>
8. The rotating transfer device of any of the above claims, wherein the film at the gas-liquid interface (105) is a Langmuir film.
</P>
<P>
9. The rotating transfer device of any of the above claims, wherein the device is used for dip coating of the substrate (102).
</P>
<P>
10. The rotating transfer device of any of the above claims, wherein the film on the surface of the substrate (102) has a striped shape.
</P>
<P>
11. The rotating transfer device of any of the above claims, wherein the structure of the film varies across the surface of the substrate (102).
</P>
<P>
12. The rotating transfer device of any of the above claims, wherein the substrate (102) is substantially flat.
</P>
<P>
13. A rotating film transfer method for transfer of a film to a substrate (102) at a gas-liquid interface (105) by means of a sample holder, wherein said sample holder performs a rotational movement around an axis angled between 0 and 600 to the plane of said interface surface (105).
</P>
<P>
14. A rotating film transfer method according to claim 12, wherein said axis is substantially parallel to the plane of said interface surface (105).
</P>
<P>
15. The rotating film transfer method of any one of claims 12 or 13, wherein said sample holder additionally performs a linear movement during said transfer.
</P>
<P>
: ** 16. The rotating film transfer method according to any one of claims 12 to 14, wherein a rotational position of said sample holder (103) is measured. * I..
</P>
<P>
*: 17. The rotating film transfer method of any one of the claims 12 to 15, wherein said film 1:P1 comprises DPPC, nanocrystals, or polymers. * *** *.*. * *
</P>
<P>
18. The rotating film transfer method of any one of the claims 12 to 16, wherein the substrate (102) is selected from the group consisting of mica, single crystalline silicon, glass, quartz, polymer and gold.
</P>
<P>
19. The rotating film transfer method of any one of claims 12 to 17, further comprising a further step of polymerising the film.
</P>
<P>
20. The rotating film transfer method of any one of claims 12 to 18, further comprising a further step of growing cells on the surface of the film.
</P>
<P>
21. The rotating film transfer method of any one of claims 12 to 19, wherein the film at the liquid-gas interface (105) is a Langmuir film.
</P>
<P>
22. The rotating film transfer method of any one of claims 12 to 21, wherein the substrate (102) is substantially flat.
</P>
<P>
23. A product made using the method of any one of claims 12 to 22 wherein a structure of the film varies across the surface of the substrate (102). * ** * * S *5** * * a... a * * *.
</P>
<P>
S
</P>
<P>
a..... * S *5 * . * S.. *Sa* * . S...
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
GB2444036A;US2010029001A1;WO2008061736A2;WO2008061736A3;CN101583435A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
