<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SPIN-TRANSFER TORQUE OSCILLATOR
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2126938A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FIRASTRAU IOANA [RO]
</Name>
<Name>
EBELS URSULA [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
DIENY BERNARD [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
FIRASTRAU, IOANA
</Name>
<Name>
EBELS, URSULA
</Name>
<Name>
DIENY, BERNARD
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
COMMISSARIAT ENERGIE ATOMIQUE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
COMMISSARIAT A L&apos;ENERGIE ATOMIQUE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2126938
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070712275
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-02-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP51676
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-02-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01F10/32
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01F10/32N4
</Class>
<Class>
H03B15/00B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention relates to a method of operating a spin-transfer torque structure to generate voltage oscillations, said structure comprising a first layer of magnetic material having a fixed magnetization vector, a spacer of non magnetic material and a second layer of magnetic material having a free magnetization vector. The method includes the application of a current (j op) through said structure and a magnetic field (H ext ) in the plane of the second layer. It makes use of a region of bistability and hysteretic behaviour to trigger and stop the voltage oscillations.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Method of operating a spin-transfer torque structure to generate voltage oscillations, said structure comprising a first layer of magnetic material having a fixed magnetization vector, a spacer of non magnetic material and a second layer of magnetic material having a free magnetization vector, said method including the application of a current through said structure and characterized by the steps of: - setting the operating point of said structure in a region of bistability where the magnetization vector of the second layer can be either in a stable static state or in a stable precessing state; - increasing the current in absolute values above a first threshold value, thereby inducing a precession of the magnetization vector of the second layer; and then decreasing the current in absolute values below said first threshold value, the magnetizing vector of the free layer being thereby kept in said precessing state.
</P>
<P>
2. Method of operating a spin-transfer torque structure to generate voltage oscillations, said structure comprising a first layer of magnetic material having a fixed magnetization vector, a spacer of non magnetic material and a second layer of magnetic material having a free magnetization vector, said method including the application of a current through said structure and characterized by the steps of: setting the operating point of said structure in a region of bistability where the magnetization vector of the second layer can be either in a stable static state or in a stable precessing state; increasing the current in absolute values above a first threshold value, thereby causing the magnetization vector of the second layer to move out of the plane thereof; and then decreasing the current in absolute values below a threshold value causing the magnetizing vector of the second layer thereby to enter a stable precessing state.
</P>
<P>
3. Method according to claim 1 or 2, characterized in that the steps of increasing and then decreasing the current are performed by applying a current pulse.
</P>
<P>
4. Method according to any preceding claim, characterized in that it further comprises the application of a magnetic field (Hext) in the plane of said second layer.
</P>
<P>
5. Method according to any preceding claim, characterized in that it further comprises a step of stopping said voltage oscillations by decreasing the current in absolute values until the operating point is moved out of said region of bistability into a region where only a static state of said magnetization vector is stable.
</P>
<P>
6. Method according to claim 5, characterized in that the step of stopping said voltage oscillations is performed by applying a current pulse.
</P>
<P>
7. Method according to claim 4, characterized in that it further comprises a step of stopping said voltage oscillations by varying the magnetic field in a predetermined direction until the operating point is moved out of said region of bistability into a region where only a static state of said magnetization vector is stable.
</P>
<P>
8. Method according to claim 7, characterized in that the step of stopping said voltage oscillations is performed by applying a magnetic field pulse.
</P>
<P>
9. Method of operating a spin-transfer torque structure to generate voltage oscillations, said structure comprising a first layer of magnetic material having a fixed magnetization vector, a spacer of non magnetic material and a second layer of magnetic material having a free magnetization vector, said method including the application of a current (jop) through said structure and a magnetic field (Hext) in the plane of said second layer, said method being characterized by the steps of: - setting the operating point of the spin- transfer structure in a region of bistability where the magnetization vector of the free layer can be either in a stable static state or a stable precessing state; varying the magnetic field in a predetermined direction until it crosses a third threshold value, thereby inducing a precession of the magnetization vector of the second layer; varying the magnetic field in the opposite direction until it crosses back said third threshold value, the magnetizing vector of the free layer being thereby kept in said precessing state.
</P>
<P>
10. Method according to claim 9, characterized in that said steps of increasing the magnetic field in said predetermined direction and in said opposite direction are performed by applying a magnetic field pulse .
</P>
<P>
11. Method according to claim 9 or 10, characterized in that it further comprises a step of stopping said voltage oscillations by varying the magnetic field in said opposite direction until the operating point is moved out of said region of bistability into a region where only a static state of said magnetization vector is stable.
</P>
<P>
12. Method according to claim 11, characterized in that the step of stopping said voltage oscillations is performed by applying a magnetic field pulse.
</P>
<P>
13. Method according to claim 9 or 10, characterized in that it further comprises a step of stopping said voltage oscillations by decreasing the current in absolute values until the operating point is moved out of said region of bistability into a region where only a static state of said magnetization vector is stable.
</P>
<P>
14. Method according to claim 13, characterized in that the step of stopping said voltage oscillations is performed by applying a current pulse.
</P>
<P>
15. Method according to any preceding claim, characterized in that the magnetization vector of said first layer is orthogonal to the plane of this layer.
</P>
<P>
16. Method according to any preceding claim, characterized in that said spacer is a layer of non magnetic metal.
</P>
<P>
17. Method according to any claim 1 to 15, characterized in that said spacer is a layer of insulating material.
</P>
<P>
18. Method according to any preceding claim, characterized in that the first layer of magnetic material and the second layer of magnetic material are made out of ferromagnetic material.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008101545A1;US2010039181A1;US8063709B2;JP2010519760A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
