<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
MAGNETIC NANOPARTICLES FOR THE APPLICATION IN HYPERTHERMIA, PREPARATION THEREOF AND USE IN CONSTRUCTS HAVING A PHARMACOLOGICAL APPLICATION
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2117600A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BALDI GIOVANNI [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
BONACCHI DANIELE [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
INNOCENTI FRANCO [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
LORENZI GIADA [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
BITOSSI MARCO [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
FERRUTI PAOLO [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
RANUCCI ELISABETTA [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
RICCI ALFREDO [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
COMES FRANCHINI MAURO [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
BALDI, GIOVANNI
</Name>
<Name>
BONACCHI, DANIELE
</Name>
<Name>
INNOCENTI, FRANCO
</Name>
<Name>
LORENZI, GIADA
</Name>
<Name>
BITOSSI, MARCO
</Name>
<Name>
FERRUTI, PAOLO
</Name>
<Name>
RANUCCI, ELISABETTA
</Name>
<Name>
RICCI, ALFREDO
</Name>
<Name>
COMES FRANCHINI, MAURO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
COLOROBBIA ITALIANA SPA [IT]
</Name>
<Name>
COLOROBBIA ITALIA S.P.A
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2117600
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070857768
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007EP64143
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
IT2006FI00328
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
IT2006FI00329
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K41/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K51/06
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/127
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/08
</Class>
<Class>
C01G51/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K41/00U
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48W14B
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/50T
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51H6D4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51H6H
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y25/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/00C
</Class>
<Class>
C01G49/08
</Class>
<Class>
C01G51/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/24
</Class>
<Class>
H01F1/00E10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
There are described nanoparticles of magnetic metal oxides employable in constructs consisting in polymer particles possibly also incorporating pharmacologically active substances.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. Constructs comprising: a magnetic nanometric particle, possibly functionalised with bifunctional compounds, a polymer possibly containing a pharmacologically active molecule and, when said polymer is insoluble in water, an external protecting layer of surface agents.
</P>
<P>
2. Constructs according to Claim 1 wherein said pharmacological active molecule, when present, is connected to the polymer or dispersed in it.
</P>
<P>
3. Constructs according to Claim 1 wherein said magnetic nanometric particles are spinels and oxides of the M&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;W2 O4 type, in which M&amp;lt;11&amp;gt; = Fe, Co, Ni, Zn, Mn; M&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;&quot; = Fe, Cr) in a nanometric form.
</P>
<P>
4. Constructs according to Claim 3 wherein said magnetic nanometric particles is chosen among: cobalt ferrite, magnetite and maghemite.
</P>
<P>
5. Constructs according to Claim 1 wherein said difunctional compounds are chosen among: thiols, carboxylic acids, hydroxamic acids, phosphoric acids, esters and salts thereof having an aliphatic chain that carries a second functional group at the terminal position (designated [omega]).
</P>
<P>
6. Constructs according to Claim 5 wherein said difunctional groups have general formula:
</P>
<P>
in which: n is an integer in the range between 2 and 20;
</P>
<P>
Ri is chosen from: CONHOH, CONHOR, PO(OH)2, PO(OH)(OR), COOH, COOR,
</P>
<P>
SH, SR;
</P>
<P>
R2 is the external group and is chosen from: OH, NH2, COOH, COOR; R is an alkyl group or an alkaline metal chosen among Chalky! and K, Na, or Li, respectively.
</P>
<P>
7. Constructs according to claim 6 wherein difunctional group is the ethyl-12- (hydroxyamino)-12-oxododecanoate.
</P>
<P>
8. Constructs according to Claims 1 - 7 wherein said polymer is a water-soluble polymers or a water insoluble polymers stabilised by surface agents.
</P>
<P>
9. Constructs according to Claim 8 wherein said polymer is chosen among: polyelectrolytes, polypeptides and water-soluble proteins; water-soluble polymers chosen from block copolymers, modified polyethylene glycols, modified polysaccharides, phospholipids, poiyamineamides, globular proteins are preferred.
</P>
<P>
10. Construes according to Claim 8 wherein said polymer is chosen among: polyesters, polyamides, polyanhydrides, polyorthoesters, peptides, poiyamineamides; or insoluble organic molecules like for example cholesterole; polyesters and cholesterole are preferred.
</P>
<P>
11. Constructs according to Claim 1 wherein said surface agents are chosen among: polyelectrolytes, polypeptides and water-soluble proteins; block copolymers, modified polyethylene glycols, modified polysaccharides, phospholipids, poiyamineamides, globular proteins; preferred are human serum proteins and pluronics block copolymers.
</P>
<P>
12. Constructs according to claim 11 wherein said polymers are chosen among:
</P>
<P>
wherein n is comprised between 3 - 300, preferably between 10 - 100.
</P>
<P>
13. Constructs according to Claims 1 - 12 wherein said pharmacologically active molecules are chsoen among: antitumour agents, antimicrobial agents, antiinflammatory agents, immunomodulators, molecules acting on the central nervous system or those capable of marking the cells so as to allow their identification with the normal means of diagnostic detection (for example fluorescent stains).
</P>
<P>
14. Compounds of the formula M&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;W2 O4, wherein M&amp;lt;11&amp;gt; = Fe, Co, Ni, Zn, Mn; M&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;&quot; = Fe, Cr in a nanometric form appropriately functionalised.
</P>
<P>
15. Compounds according to claim 1 chosen from: cobalt ferrite, magnetite and maghemite.
</P>
<P>
16. Compounds according to claims 14 - 16, wherein said nanoparticles have a size in the range between 4 and 200 nm, preferably between 10 and 70 nm. 17. A process for the preparation of nanoparticles according to claims 14 - 16, wherein the desired metal salt is added to a known volume of alcohol and the solution is heated while mixing to a complete solubilisation of the salts, possibly adding water in an appropriate amount to facilitate the hydrolysis of salts and heating to a temperature above 150 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C for some hours and then letting it cool, thus collecting the resulting suspension and the so obtained partcles are functionalised. 18. A process for the preparation of nanoparticles according to claim 17, wherein, after cooling, all the starting materials are added again in amounts identical to those already reacted, the reaction is performed again according to the method described and the cycle is repeated for a variable number of times until particles of the desired size are obtained. 19. A process for the preparation of nanoparticles according to claim 17, wherein, at the end of the stationary heating period of time to 180 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, all the starting materials are added to the product in amounts identical to the already reacted product, the temperature is taken to 180&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C again, it is maintained for 3 hours and the cycle is then repeated for a variable number of times until the desired size of the product is obtained.
</P>
<P>
20. A process according to claim 17, wherein the period of time, for which the product is maintained at a temperature of 180 &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C, is extended for a variable number of hours until the particles of the desired size are obtained.
</P>
<P>
21. A process according to claim 17, wherein the heating is performed by using a microwave oven.
</P>
<P>
22. A process for the preparation of functionalised maghemite nanometric particles, wherein magnetite nanometric particles obtained according to the processes according to claims 17 - 21 are oxidised in an acetic environment and thereafter functionalised. 23. Compounds according to claims 14 - 16, wherein said functionalisation consists of difunctional derivatives chosen from: thiols, carboxylic acids, hydroxamic acids, phosphoric acids or aliphatic chain salts thereof, which, carry a second functional group chosen from OH, Nhb, COOH, COOR3 at the terminal position, wherein R3 is an alkyl group, an alkali metal, preferably K, Na or Li. 24. Compounds according to claim 23, wherein said difunctional compounds according to the present invention are compounds of the general formula:
</P>
<P>
Ri-(CH2)n-R2 wherein: n is an integer in the range between 2 and 20; Ri is chosen from the group consisting of : OH, NH2, COOH, COOR R2 is chosen from: CONHOH, CONHOR, PO(OH)2, PO(OH)(OR), COOH, COOR, SH, SR wherein
</P>
<P>
R is an alkyl group, an alkali metal, preferably K, Na or Li
</P>
<P>
25. A process for the preparation of compounds according to claim 24, wherein a dispersion of nanoparticles in an organic solvent is reacted with a preferred bonding agent while mixing at a reduced temperature for some hours, the product is then extracted or precipitated, spun in a centrifuge, separated and possibly redispersed in an appropriate solvent.
</P>
<P>
26. A process for the preparation of the constructs according to claims 1 - 13, wherein the functionalised nanoparticles and the pharmacologically active molecule are incorporated in an water-insoluble polymeric matrix and this structure is coated with suitable surface agents continuously and in one step.
</P>
<P>
27. A process for the preparation of the constructs according to claim 26, wherein an organic solvent miscible in water in an amount of at least 10% is used as a &quot;carrier&quot; solvent for the magnetic particles and possibly the drug.
</P>
<P>
28. A process according to claim 27, wherein said solvents are chosen from the group including: acetone, diethylene glycol, acetonitrile, dimethylsulfoxide, dimethylformamide, methylethylketone, dimethylcarbonate, methanol, ethanol, propanol.
</P>
<P>
29. Constructs according to claims 1 - 13 having an average diameter in the range between 50 and 300 nm. 30. Constructs according to claim 29 having an average diameter in the range between 30 and 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
31. Constructs according to claims 29 - 30, wherein the nanometric particle is cobalt ferrite.
</P>
<P>
32. Construct according to Claims 1 - 13 such construct consisting of: cobalt ferrite, PLGA and a block polymer
</P>
<P>
33. Use of functionalised cobalt ferrite nanoparticles in hyperthermic treatments.
</P>
<P>
34. A use according to claim 32, wherein said cobalt ferrite particles are produced according to processes according to claims 17 - 21.
</P>
<P>
35. A use of constructs according to claims 1 - 13 for the preparation of pharmaceutical compositions useful for hyperthermic treatments. 36. A use according to claim 35, wherein said constructs are water-soluble.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008074804A2;WO2008074804A3;US2010015060A1;RU2009127835A;MX2009005696A;JP2010514181A;CA2672810A1;AU2007336297A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
