<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NON-DESTRUCTIVE WAFER- SCALE SUB-SURFACE ULTRASONIC MICROSCOPY EMPLOYING NEAR FIELD AFM DETECTION
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2150973A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SU CHANMIN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PRATER CRAIG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SU, CHANMIN
</Name>
<Name>
PRATER, CRAIG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
VEECO INSTR INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
VEECO INSTRUMENTS INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2150973
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080755335
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-12
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US63462
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-12
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070917301P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-10
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N29/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/66
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y35/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N29/06D3
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/18
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/32
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method, and corresponding apparatus, of imaging sub-surface features at a plurality of locations on a sample includes coupling an ultrasonic wave into a sample at a first lateral position. The method then measures the amplitude and phase of ultrasonic energy near the sample with a tip of an atomic force microscope. Next, the method couples an ultrasonic wave into a sample at a second lateral position and the measuring step is repeated for the second lateral position. Overall, the present system and methods achieve high resolution sub-surface mapping of a wide range of samples, including silicon wafers. It is notable that when imaging wafers, backside contamination is minimized.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of imaging sub-surface features of a sample, the method comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
providing a scanning probe microscope (SPM), the SPM including a probe having a cantilever bearing a tip;
</P>
<P>
providing an ultrasonic source that directs ultrasonic energy into the sample;
</P>
<P>
coupling the ultrasonic energy from the ultrasonic source into a section of the sample at a first position;
</P>
<P>
using the probe to detect an interaction between the incident ultrasonic energy and a sub-surface feature of the sample; and
</P>
<P>
successively moving at least one of the sample and the ultrasonic source with a translation stage to generate relative motion between the ultrasonic source and the sample so as to couple ultrasonic energy into different sections of the sample.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, further including coupling an ultrasonic wave into the sample at a second position and repeating the measuring step for the second position.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 2, wherein coupling an ultrasonic wave into the sample is nondestructive to the sample.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, further including controlling tip-sample interaction so as to elicit a nonlinear probe response.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 4, wherein controlling tip-sample interaction includes tuning the non-linear probe response using feedback.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 4, further including providing a second ultrasonic source coupled to the probe that produces an ultrasonic drive wave so as to create a beat signal having a beat frequency.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 6, wherein providing a second ultrasonic source coupled to the probe includes integrating a piezoelectric transducer operating at GHz frequencies with the probe.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 1, wherein providing an ultrasonic source includes providing a ultrasonic transducer focusing generated ultrasonic waves into the section of the sample at the first position.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 8, wherein focusing generated ultrasonic waves includes using a Fresnel lens coupled to the ultrasonic transducer to focus the waves.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 8, wherein the ultrasonic source is driven to excite plural harmonics.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 1, wherein coupling an ultrasonic wave into a section of the sample includes providing a liquid coupling of the ultrasonic source to the sample.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 1, wherein coupling an ultrasonic wave into a section of the sample includes continuous wave laser acoustic excitation.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 1, further comprising the step of reconstructing a sub-surface structure of the sample based on the detected interaction.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 13, wherein the resolution of the reconstruction step is better than 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 1, wherein said using step includes measuring at least one of amplitude and phase of cantilever motion.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 1, wherein measuring the amplitude and phase of ultrasonic energy includes using at least one of a group including an expected composition and an expected structure for the sample to guide the measurement.
</P>
<P>
17. A probe-based instrument for detecting sub-surface features of a sample, the instrument comprising:
</P>
<P>
a scanning probe microscope (SPM), the SPM including a probe having a cantilever bearing a tip;
</P>
<P>
an ultrasonic source configured to provide an ultrasonic wave into a section of the sample at a first position;
</P>
<P>
a translation stage that provides relative movement between the sample and both the probe and the ultrasonic source; and
</P>
<P>
a beat signal detector, the detector measuring an interaction between the incident ultrasonic energy and a sub-surface feature of the sample.
</P>
<P>
18. The probe-based instrument of claim 17, further including an actuator controlling tip-sample separation using a feedback loop until a non-linear response of the probe is optimized.
</P>
<P>
19. The probe-based instrument of claim 17, wherein the sample is a semiconductor wafer of at least 200 mm in diameter.
</P>
<P>
20. The probe-based instrument of claim 17, wherein the ultrasonic coupling is non-destructive to the sample.
</P>
<P>
21. The probe-based instrument of claim 20, wherein fewer than 1000 particles are added to the backside of the wafer by the coupling and measurement steps.
</P>
<P>
22. The probe-based instrument of claim 17, wherein the ultrasonic source is coupled to the sample via a liquid.
</P>
<P>
23. The probe-based instrument of claim 17, further comprising a second ultrasonic source coupled to the probe that produces an ultrasonic drive wave so as to create a beat signal having a beat frequency.
</P>
<P>
24. The probe-based instrument of claim 17, wherein the interaction causes cantilever motion, and wherein the detector measures at least one of amplitude and phase of the cantilever motion.
</P>
<P>
25. A method of imaging sub-surface features locations of a sample, the method comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
providing a probe having a cantilever and a probe tip;
</P>
<P>
providing first and second ultrasonic sources generating first and second ultrasonic waves that are successively coupled into different locations on the sample;
</P>
<P>
providing at least one translation stage configured to provide relative motion between the sample and the first and second ultrasonic sources;
</P>
<P>
coupling an ultrasonic wave from the first ultrasonic source into a section of the sample;
</P>
<P>
driving the probe with ultrasonic energy from the second ultrasonic source;
</P>
<P>
measuring ultrasonic energy substantially at the sample surface caused by an interaction of the ultrasonic energy from the first and second ultrasonic sources; and
</P>
<P>
moving at least one of the sample, the first ultrasonic source, and the second ultrasonic source to generate relative motion and to allow measurement at a second section of the sample.
</P>
<P>
26. The method of claim 25, wherein providing a second ultrasonic source coupled to the probe includes integrating a piezoelectric transducer operating at GHz frequencies into the tip of the probe.
</P>
<P>
27. The method of claim 25, wherein the measurement of the ultrasonic energy includes detection of a beat signal generated by coupling of at least one of the harmonics of the first ultrasonic source and the second ultrasonic source.
</P>
<P>
28. The method of claim 27, further including tuning a non-linear response of the probe to probe sample interaction so as to create a beat signal having a frequency substantially corresponding to one of the probe resonances.
</P>
<P>
29. The method of claim 28, wherein the tuning step includes a feedback loop.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 25, wherein coupling the ultrasonic wave from the first ultrasonic source into a section of the sample includes providing a liquid coupling of the ultrasonic source to the sample.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 25, further comprising the step of reconstructing a sub-surface structure of the sample based on the measurement and wherein the resolution of the reconstruction step is better than 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
32. A method of imaging sub-surface features at a plurality of locations on a sample, the method comprising the steps of:
</P>
<P>
releasably coupling an ultrasonic wave source to a sample;
</P>
<P>
exciting a probe of a scanning probe microscope with an ultrasonic signal having a frequency greater than 1 GHz;
</P>
<P>
positioning the probe relative to the sample to optimize a non-linear reaction between the probe and the sample; and
</P>
<P>
detecting a beat signal to detect subsurface features of the sample to a resolution greater than 20 nm.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 1, wherein the moving step provides translation between at least first and second sections of the sample in less than 5 minutes.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 1, wherein the moving step provides translation between at least first and second sections of the sample in less than 10 seconds.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2150973A4;US2008276695A1;WO2008141301A1;JP2010527011A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
