<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
FILTER MEDIUM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2155613A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
DOMB ABRAHAM J [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
WILDER HAIM [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
RONEN RAMI [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
RATNER STANISLAW [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
DOMB, ABRAHAM, J
</Name>
<Name>
WILDER, HAIM
</Name>
<Name>
RONEN, RAMI
</Name>
<Name>
RATNER, STANISLAW
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
H2Q WATER IND LTD [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
H2Q WATER INDUSTRIES LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2155613
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080738255
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008IL00553
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070907817P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C02F1/28
</Class>
<Class>
C02F9/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J20/06
</Class>
<Class>
B01J20/08
</Class>
<Class>
B01J20/10B
</Class>
<Class>
B01J20/20
</Class>
<Class>
B01J20/26
</Class>
<Class>
B01J39/18
</Class>
<Class>
B01J41/12
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C02F1/28L
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a filter medium for filtering aqueous solutions, particularly water for human and animal consumption. The medium may be employed in a great variety of filters of various sizes and constructions.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. A liquid filter medium comprising a carbonaceous material, a water-insoluble metal oxide or hydroxide, and at least one of chitosan and an ion exchanger.
</P>
<P>
2. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said liquid is water or a water solution.
</P>
<P>
3. The filter medium according to claims 1 or 2, wherein said carbonaceous material is selected from charcoal, activated charcoal, activated carbon, bituminous coal, impregnated activated carbon, bone char, acid washed activated carbon, coconut shell based activated carbon, wood based activated carbon, regenerated activated carbon, anthracite coal, zeolite mixed coal, virgin activated carbon, water-washed catalytic carbon, charred vegetation and fly ash.
</P>
<P>
4. The filter medium according to claim 3, wherein said carbonaceous material is in a particulate form selected from palletized, granular, fibrous, and crushed.
</P>
<P>
5. The filter medium according to claim 3, wherein said carbonaceous material is activated carbon.
</P>
<P>
6. The filter medium according to claim 4, wherein said activated carbon is coconut shell based activated carbon.
</P>
<P>
7. The filter medium according to claim 1, comprising between about 30 to 75% carbonaceous material of the total weight of the filter medium.
</P>
<P>
8. The filter medium according to claim I5 wherein said carbonaceous material is impregnated with at least one organic or inorganic compound.
</P>
<P>
9. The filter medium according to claim 8, wherein said at least one organic or inorganic compound is selected amongst cationic polymers, anionic polymers, carboxylic acid based polymers, salts, ions, metal ions and atoms.
</P>
<P>
10. The filter medium according to claim 8, wherein said at least one inorganic metal ion is silver or copper.
</P>
<P>
11. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said metal oxide or hydroxide is selected from oxide, hydroxides and/or oxide-hydroxide of iron, alumina and silica.
</P>
<P>
12. The filter medium according to claim 10, wherein said metal oxide is selected from iron oxide particulates, aluminum oxide particulates, iron nanoparticles on aluminum oxide, iron nanoparticles on diatomaceous earth,&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt; iron nanoparticles on microlite ceramic spheres, iron oxide (Fe2O3) on silica (SiO2), iron oxide on alumina (Al2O3), ceramic spheres coated with alumina, iron oxide on alumina, aluminum hydroxide (Al(OH)3) on iron hydroxide (Fe(OH)3) and iron hydroxide on aluminum hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
13. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said metal hydroxide is hydrated iron-hydroxide prepared from FeCl3.
</P>
<P>
14. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said metal oxide is a hydrated iron-oxide embedded onto porous polystyrene beads.
</P>
<P>
15. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein the metal oxide is a hydrated iron hydroxide embedded in ceramic or polymeric supports.
</P>
<P>
16. The filter medium according to claim 14 or 15, wherein said hydrated iron oxide/hydroxide is embedded in a ceramic porous disc having a pore size of 100 to 500 microns.
</P>
<P>
17. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said medium comprises a combination of a metal oxide and a metal hydroxide.
</P>
<P>
18. The filter medium according to claim 1, comprising metal at between about 3 and 20% of the total weight of the filter medium.
</P>
<P>
19. The filter medium according to claim 1, comprising chitosan and at least one ion exchanger.
</P>
<P>
20. The filter medium according to claim 1, comprising chitosan or at least one ion exchanger.
</P>
<P>
21. The filter medium according to claim 19 or 20, wherein said at least one ion exchanger is an anion exchange resin, a cation exchange resin or any combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
22. The filter medium according to claim 21, wherein said cation exchange resin is a strongly acidic cation exchange agent selected amongst organic compounds having sulfonic or sulfuric acid substituents.
</P>
<P>
23. The filter medium according to claim 22, wherein said cation exchange resin contains at least 10% of sulfonic or sulfuric acid groups, in their potassium or sodium salt form.
</P>
<P>
24. The filter medium according to claim 22, wherein said cation exchange resin contains 40% potassium salt of a strong acidic ion exchanger based on polystyrene sulfonic acid.
</P>
<P>
25. The filter medium of claim 1, comprising cation exchange agent between about 20 and 50% of the total weight of the filter medium.
</P>
<P>
26. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said chitosan is water insoluble- chitosan selected from chitosan (deacetylated chitin), salts of chitosan, chitosan-gel, and modified chitosan.
</P>
<P>
27. The filter medium according to claim 26, wherein said modified chitosan is selected amongst chitosan acetate, chitosan lactate, chitosan glutamate, methyl-chitosan, and N-carboxymethylchitosan.
</P>
<P>
28. The filter medium according to claim 1, wherein said chitosan is in a form of flakes, beads, fibers, fabric, non- woven fabrics, porous particulates, and/or powder.
</P>
<P>
29. The filter medium according to claim 28, wherein said chitosan is in the form of randomly shaped flakes.
</P>
<P>
30. The filter medium according to claim 1, comprising chitosan in an amount ranging from about 1 to about 20% of the total weight of the medium.
</P>
<P>
31. The filter medium according to claim 1 or 2, wherein said chitosan is a crosslinked chitosan.
</P>
<P>
32. The filter medium according to claim 31, wherein said crosslinked chitosan is a thermally crosslinked chitosan.
</P>
<P>
33. The filter medium according to any one of the preceding claims, further comprising at least one water-insoluble additive selected from a cation exchange agent, an anion exchange agent, an antimicrobial agent and at least one other component for removal of specific contaminants.
</P>
<P>
34. The filter medium according to claim 30, wherein said at least one additive is an antimicrobial agent.
</P>
<P>
35. The filter medium according to claim 34, wherein said at least one antimicrobial agent is selected from an iodinated medium, a quaternary ammonium resin, an antibacterial polymer, a cationic polyelectrolyte, a polymer possessing quaternary or tertiary ammonium groups, and a polymer loaded with iodine or iodophores.
</P>
<P>
36. A filter medium consisting of water-insoluble carbonaceous material, water- insoluble metal oxide, and at least one of water-insoluble chitosan and ion exchanger.
</P>
<P>
37. A filter medium consisting of water-insoluble carbonaceous material, water- insoluble metal-oxide, and at least one of water insoluble acidic cation exchange agent and water-insoluble chitosan.
</P>
<P>
38. A filter medium consisting of water-insoluble carbonaceous material, water- insoluble metal-oxide, and at least one of water insoluble acidic cation exchange agent and water insoluble chitosan.
</P>
<P>
39. The filter medium according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein said medium does not comprise chitosan.
</P>
<P>
40. A filtering unit comprising a filter medium according to any one of claims 1 to 39; and a liquid channeling structure for directing a liquid entering an input of the filtering unit to flow through the filtering medium before exiting an output of the filtering unit.
</P>
<P>
41. The filtering unit according to claim 40, further comprising a separate compartment for the metal oxide/hydroxide component.
</P>
<P>
42. The filtering unit according to claim 40, further comprising a separate compartment for at least one antimicrobial agent.
</P>
<P>
43. The filtering unit according to claim 41, wherein said at least one antimicrobial agent is polyamide fabric loaded with iodine.
</P>
<P>
44. The filtering unit according to any one of claims 38 to 42, contained in a container to form a water treatment system.
</P>
<P>
45. The filtering unit according to claim 43, wherein said container has at least one water inlet opening and one outlet opening and optionally at least one means for keeping said filter medium immobilized.
</P>
<P>
46. The filtering unit according to any one of claims 40 to 45, wherein each component of said filter medium is arranged in layers.
</P>
<P>
47. The filtering unit according to claim 46, wherein each of said layers of filter medium components is contained in a separate compartment.
</P>
<P>
48. The filtering unit according to claim 46 or 47, wherein said the component of the filter medium contained in a compartment/layer closest to the water input is at least one of a carbonaceous material, a metal oxide or hydroxide, a chitosan and/or an ion exchanger.
</P>
<P>
49. The filtering unit according to claim 46 or 47, wherein said component of the filter medium contained in a compartment/layer being the furthest from the water input is at least one of a carbonaceous material, a metal oxide or hydroxide, a chitosan and/or an ion exchanger.
</P>
<P>
50. The filtering unit according to claim 46 or 47, wherein said compartments/layers are arranged with said polystyrene beads contained in a compartment closest to the water input.
</P>
<P>
51. The filtering unit according to claim 46 or 47, wherein said compartments/layers are arranged with said carbonaceous material contained in a compartment closest to the water input.
</P>
<P>
52. The filtering unit according to claim 46 or 47, wherein iron oxide nanoparticles are contained in a compartment closest to the water output.
</P>
<P>
53. A commercial package (kit) comprising the filter medium according to any one of claims 1&amp;lt;&apos;&amp;gt; to 37 and instructions for use.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008129551A1;ZA200907287A;US2010176044A1;RU2009141918A;KR20100075778A;CN101720306A;CA2684298A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
