<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLYMER-EMBEDDED SEMICONDUCTOR ROD ARRAYS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2183788A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
LEWIS NATHAN S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PLASS KATHERINE E [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SPURGEON JOSHUA M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ATWATER HARRY A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LEWIS, NATHAN S
</Name>
<Name>
PLASS, KATHERINE E
</Name>
<Name>
SPURGEON, JOSHUA M
</Name>
<Name>
ATWATER, HARRY A
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
CALIFORNIA INST OF TECHN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CALIFORNIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2183788
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080796311
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-18
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US70518
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-18
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070966432P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-08-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20080127437P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-13
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
H01L31/0232
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/0352
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4A1A3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1C3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1C4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C5M6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3C
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S3S
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S8
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/16
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/20
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/22
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A structure consisting of well-ordered semiconductor structures embedded in a binder material which maintains the ordering and orientation of the semiconductor structures. Methods for forming such a structure include forming the semiconductor structures on a substrate, casting a binder material onto the substrate to embed the semiconductor structures in the binder material, and separating the binder material from the substrate at the substrate. These methods provide for the retention of the orientation and order of highly ordered semiconductor structures in the separated binder material.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A structure comprising:
</P>
<P>
a binder material layer; and
</P>
<P>
an ordered array of spaced apart semiconductor structures, wherein each one of the semiconductor structures has a length dimension and wherein the semiconductor structures are conformably constrained along at least a portion of the length dimension of each semiconductor structure within the binder material layer.
</P>
<P>
2. The structure according to claim 1, wherein semiconductor structures are fabricated separately from the binder material layer and are transferred into the binder material layer and wherein the binder material layer maintains the ordering and spacing obtained from the initial fabrication of the semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
3. The structure according to claim 2, wherein the semiconductor structures are fabricated with shapes with high aspect ratios, wherein the high aspect ratios define orientations among the semiconductor structures and the binder material layer maintains the orientations of the semiconductor structures upon transfer of the semiconductor structures into the binder material layer.
</P>
<P>
4. The structure according to claim 1, wherein semiconductor structures are fabricated separately from the binder material layer with an order and spacing and are transferred into the binder material layer and wherein the binder material layer is manipulated to modify the order and/or spacing of the semiconductor structures within the binder material layer.
</P>
<P>
5. The structure according to claim 4, wherein the semiconductor structures are fabricated with an order and spacing to provide a first density for the semiconductor structures and the binder material layer is manipulated to provide a second density for the semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
6. The structure according to claim 5, wherein the second density is chosen for desired optical properties for the structure.
</P>
<P>
7. The structure according to claim 1, further comprising an electrically contactive layer, wherein the electrically contactive layer contacts one or more of the semiconductor structures at or near ends of the semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
8. The structure according to claim 1, wherein binder material layer comprises a flexible material.
</P>
<P>
9. The structure according to claim 1, wherein the binder material layer comprises one or more of the following materials: conducting polymer material, insulating polymer material; heat-shrinkable material; and material covalently grown from the semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
10. The structure according to claim 1, further comprising additional non-ordered semiconductor structures embedded within the binder material layer and electrical contacts to the additional non-ordered semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
11. A method for fabricating semiconductor structures comprising:
</P>
<P>
growing ordered and oriented semiconductor structures on a substrate;
</P>
<P>
depositing a film layer on a top surface of the substrate, wherein the film layer comprises a binder material and wherein the binder material encapsulates one or more of the semiconductor structures at and above the substrate; and
</P>
<P>
separating the film layer from the substrate at or near a location where the film layer contacts a top surface of the substrate,
</P>
<P>
whereby the ordering and orientation of one or more of the semiconductor structures is maintained in the film layer.
</P>
<P>
12. The method according to claim 11, wherein binder material comprises one or more of the following materials: polydimethylsiloxane; insulating polymer material; heat-shrinkable material; and material covalently grown from the semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
13. The method according to claim 11, wherein the semiconductor structures comprise vertically aligned wire arrays grown with a vapor-liquid-solid process from a single crystalline Si substrate.
</P>
<P>
14. The method according to claim 11, wherein the semiconductor structures have top sides and bottom sides and the bottom sides are located adjacent the top surface of the substrate and wherein a top surface of the film layer is positioned below the top sides of one or more of the semiconductor structures.
</P>
<P>
15. The method according to claim 14 further comprising forming electrical contacts to one or more of the top sides of the semiconductor structures with a conducting polymer.
</P>
<P>
16. A method for fabricating semiconductor structures comprising:
</P>
<P>
forming one or more rod arrays on at least a portion of a substrate, wherein individual rods in the rod arrays each have a first end disposed adjacent to the substrate and a second end disposed distal to the substrate;
</P>
<P>
depositing binder material on a top surface of the substrate, wherein the binder material conformably fills gaps between the individual rods and the binder material forms a film layer with a bottom surface adjacent to the top surface of the substrate;
</P>
<P>
forming the film layer into a solid layer with the rod arrays embedded within the film layer; and,
</P>
<P>
separating the film layer and a plurality of the individual rods from the substrate at or near the bottom surface of the film layer.
</P>
<P>
17. The method according to claim 16, wherein the binder material comprises a polymer.
</P>
<P>
18. The method according to claim 16, further comprising forming semiconductor structures on another portion of the substrate and depositing binder material comprises conformably depositing binder material around the semiconductor structures and separating the film layer comprises separating the semiconductor structures from the substrate at or near the bottom surface of the film layer.
</P>
<P>
19. The method according to claim 17, wherein depositing binder material on the substrate comprises drop-casting or spin-casting the polymer onto the substrate.
</P>
<P>
20. The method according to claim 16, further comprising depositing a conductive polymer at a top surface of the film layer.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2009057839A1;US8110898B2;US2012028420A1;WO2009032413A1;WO2009032412A1;US2009061600A1;US7910461B2;KR20100067088A;KR20100072220A;JP2010541194A;JP2010538464A;EP2183789A1;CN102067324A;CN101796648A;CN101796648B;AU2008296764A1;AU2008296763A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
