<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Polymer Devices
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2154718A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TESSLER NIR [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
SIRRINGHAUS HENNING [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
FRIEND RICHARD HENRY [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
TESSLER, NIR
</Name>
<Name>
SIRRINGHAUS, HENNING
</Name>
<Name>
FRIEND, RICHARD HENRY
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
PLASTIC LOGIC LTD [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
PLASTIC LOGIC LIMITED
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2154718
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090175563
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
1999-04-16
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP19990918097
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-04-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB19980008061
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1998-04-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G11C13/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/088
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/15
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/28
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/32
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/786
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/153
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/05
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/10
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/50
</Class>
<Class>
H05B33/26
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/30
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08G61/12D1F
</Class>
<Class>
G11C13/00R5C
</Class>
<Class>
G11C13/00R5C2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L27/32M2T
</Class>
<Class>
H01L31/153
</Class>
<Class>
H01L51/05B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A method for forming an electronic device having a region comprising a semiconductive polymer material, the method comprising depositing the semiconductive polymer by a process which promotes ordering in the deposited polymer.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method for forming an electronic device having a region comprising a semiconductive polymer material, the method comprising depositing the semiconductive polymer by a process which promotes ordering in the deposited polymer.
</P>
<P>
2. A method as claimed in claim 1, wherein the step of depositing the semiconductive polymer comprises dissolving the polymer in a solvent in which the polymer has a tendency to self-organise.
</P>
<P>
3. A method as claimed in claim 1 or 2, wherein the step of depositing the semiconductive polymer comprises coating the polymer from a solvent in which the polymer has a tendency to self-organise.
</P>
<P>
4. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 3, wherein the step of depositing the semiconductive polymer is performed in an inert atmosphere.
</P>
<P>
5. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 4, wherein the step of depositing the semiconductive polymer comprises preparing a substrate to promote the ordering of the polymer and depositing the polymer onto the substrate.
</P>
<P>
6. A method as claimed in claim 5, wherein the step of preparing the substrate comprises making the surface of the substrate more hydrophobic.
</P>
<P>
7. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 6, wherein the method comprises depositing at least one electrode over the semiconductive polymer.
</P>
<P>
8. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 7, wherein the polymer is a material that has a tendency to self-organise.
</P>
<P>
9. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 7, wherein the polymer has a conjugated backbone.
</P>
<P>
10. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 9, wherein the polymer has substituents either in or pendent from its backbone which promote ordering of adjacent polymer chains.
</P>
<P>
11. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 10, wherein the polymer has hydrophobic side-chains.
</P>
<P>
12. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 11, wherein the polymer is poly-hexylthiophene.
</P>
<P>
13. A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 12, further comprising the step of forming a light-emissive device over the electronic device.
</P>
<P>
14. A method as claimed in claim 13, wherein the light-emissive device is integrated with the electronic device.
</P>
<P>
15. An integrated circuit device comprising:
</P>
<P>
a current drive switching element having an input electrode, an output electrode, a switchable region comprising a semiconductive polymer material electrically coupled between the input electrode and the output electrode, and a control electrode electrically coupled to the switchable region so as to allow the application of a bias to the control electrode to vary the flow of current through the switchable region between the input electrode and the output electrode; and
</P>
<P>
a second circuit element, integrated with the switching element, and electrically coupled with the output electrode of the switching element for receiving a drive current from the switching element.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO9954936A1;WO9954936A8;US6603139B1;TW498395B;JP2008227517A;JP2002512451A;EP1074048A1;EP1074048B1;CN1301400A;CN1214465C;CA2328094A1;CA2328094C;BR9909580A;BR9909580B1;AU3614399A;AU766162B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
