<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
COLOUR CHANGE MATERIAL AND METHOD OF MANUFACTURE THEREOF
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2156236A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BAUMBERG JEREMY JOHN [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
BARTLETT PHILLIP NIGEL [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
MAHAJAN SUMEET [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
COLE ROBIN [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
BAUMBERG, JEREMY, JOHN
</Name>
<Name>
BARTLETT, PHILLIP, NIGEL
</Name>
<Name>
MAHAJAN, SUMEET
</Name>
<Name>
COLE, ROBIN
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV SOUTHAMPTON [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHAMPTON
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2156236
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080750674
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-05-22
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008GB01751
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-05-22
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070009846
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-23
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G02B26/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/18
</Class>
<Class>
G02B6/122
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/01
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B1/00M1
</Class>
<Class>
G02B26/00C
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/00P
</Class>
<Class>
G02F1/01
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Metal nanovoids are grown on a stretchable plastic film. The fabrication proceeds by assembling the template of a single layer of close packed silica spheres on a conducting substrate. A conducting layer is then electrochemically grown on top to form a master. An elastomeric precursor is then coated on the master (e.g. by spinning) and is cured before removal. The resulting plastic film is then coated with a thin (e.g. 20nm) layer of noble metal (e.g. Au, Ag or Cu), to produce a flexible film. Applications for such tuneable structural colour would be coating of injection moulded artefacts, such as mobile phone covers, car bodies to form an iridescent skin, wall and fascia decorations, loudspeaker coatings, architectural tent coverings, and clothing.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A colour change material comprising a stretchable substrate having an assembly of voids shaped and dimensioned to reflect or absorb light of particular colours.
</P>
<P>
2. The material of claim 1, wherein the voids are coated with a metallic film.
</P>
<P>
3. The material of claim 2, wherein the voids and their metallic film coatings support localised surface plasmons.
</P>
<P>
4. The material of claim 2 or 3, further comprising a membrane layer with a reflective coating that forms a photon or plasmon resonator with the metallic film enclosing the voids.
</P>
<P>
5. The material of any preceding claim, wherein the assembly of voids has a thickness of less than 10 or 20 [mu]m.
</P>
<P>
6. Use of the material of any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the material is deployed to give colour effects dependant on the degree of stretching or deformation by any external stimulus.
</P>
<P>
7. The use of claim 6, wherein the material is deployed as a surface covering of an object.
</P>
<P>
8. A device composed of the material of claim 4, further comprising a voltage source connected to the material to modulate the photon or plasmon resonator by deformation of the substrate and/or the membrane layer.
</P>
<P>
9. A method of manufacturing a colour change material, comprising: provide a master having a surface bearing an inverse void structure for forming an assembly of voids shaped and dimensioned to reflect or absorb light of particular colours; applying the master to a stretchable substrate or liquid precursor thereof; and separating the master from the stretchable substrate.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 9, further comprising coating the voids with a metallic film.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10, further comprising adding a membrane layer with a reflective coating to enclose the voids and form a photon or plasmon resonator with the metallic film.
</P>
<P>
12. A master for use in the method of claim 9, 10 or 11.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008142417A2;WO2008142417A3;US2010245978A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
