<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
HIGH DENSITY PLANAR MAGNETIC DOMAIN WALL MEMORY APPARATUS AND METHOD OF FORMING THE SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2140458A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GAIDIS MICHAEL C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CLEVENGER LAWRENCE A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DALTON TIMOTHY J [US]
</Name>
<Name>
DEBROSSE JOHN K [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HSU LOUIS L C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RADENS CARL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WONG KEITH K H [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YANG CHIH-CHAO [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GAIDIS, MICHAEL, C
</Name>
<Name>
CLEVENGER, LAWRENCE, A
</Name>
<Name>
DALTON, TIMOTHY, J
</Name>
<Name>
DEBROSSE, JOHN, K
</Name>
<Name>
HSU, LOUIS, L., C
</Name>
<Name>
RADENS, CARL
</Name>
<Name>
WONG, KEITH, K., H
</Name>
<Name>
YANG, CHIH-CHAO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
IBM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2140458
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070867608
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US24798
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070694183
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-03-30
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G11B5/008
</Class>
<Class>
G11C19/08
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11C19/08C8
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A magnetic domain wall memory apparatus with write/read capability includes a plurality of coplanar shift register structures each comprising an elongated track formed from a ferromagnetic material having a plurality of magnetic domains therein, the shift register structures further having a plurality of discontinuities therein to facilitate domain wall location;  a magnetic read element associated with each of the shift register structures;  and a magnetic write element associated with each of the shift register structures, the magnetic write element further comprising a single write wire having a longitudinal axis substantially orthogonal to a longitudinal axis of each of the coplanar shift register structures.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A magnetic domain wall memory apparatus with write/read capability, comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of coplanar shift register structures each comprising an elongated track formed from a ferromagnetic material having a plurality of magnetic domains therein, the shift register structures further having a plurality of discontinuities therein to facilitate domain wall location;
</P>
<P>
a magnetic read element associated with each of the shift register structures; and
</P>
<P>
a magnetic write element associated with each of the shift register structures, the magnetic write element further comprising a single write wire having a longitudinal axis substantially orthogonal to a longitudinal axis of each of the coplanar shift register structures.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein ends of each shift register structure are aligned with one another.
</P>
<P>
3. The apparatus of claim 2, wherein the write wire includes a plurality of constrictions therein, the constrictions located at a point corresponding to the location of one of the plurality of discontinuities in the each of the associated shift register structures.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein:
</P>
<P>
the write wire is located proximate a first end of the shift register structures, and each read element is located proximate a second end thereof; and
</P>
<P>
an endmost of the read elements is substantially straight and the remaining read elements are substantially L-shaped.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 1, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
a plurality of shift current wires associated with each of the shift register structures;
</P>
<P>
wherein the plurality of shift current wires are configured such that the shift current wires corresponding to unselected shift registers act as a current return path for shift current passing through a selected shift register, the current return path being in an opposite direction with respect to the direction of the shift current.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein each read element comprises a magnetic tunnel junction (MTJ).
</P>
<P>
7. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the plurality of discontinuities in each track are defined by a plurality of vertical notches formed within the ferromagnetic material.
</P>
<P>
8. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the plurality of discontinuities in each track are defined by physical overlapping of magnetic segments.
</P>
<P>
9. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the plurality of discontinuities in each track are defined by using alternating types of magnetic materials in the track.
</P>
<P>
10. The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the plurality of discontinuities in each track are defined by different material thicknesses for adjacent domains.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2140458A4;EP2140458B1;US2008239784A1;US8023305B2;WO2008121134A1;US2008243972A1;US7514271B2;US2008239785A1;US8009453B2;KR20100002255A;JP2010524233A;AT503252T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
