<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
production method of layered crystal material
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2116635A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SHIOZAKI RYUJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MARUYAMA DAISUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ANDO NOBUO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIOZAKI, RYUJI
</Name>
<Name>
MARUYAMA, DAISUKE
</Name>
<Name>
ANDO, NOBUO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
FUJI HEAVY IND LTD [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
FUJI JUKOGYO KABUSHIKI KAISHA
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2116635
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090157926
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2009-04-15
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20080113614
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/30
</Class>
<Class>
C30B7/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/02
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/16
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/30
</Class>
<Class>
C30B29/60
</Class>
<Class>
C30B7/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01M4/485
</Class>
<Class>
Y02E60/12B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An ammonium metavanadate is heat-treated to 500  DEG C or less at a predetermined rate of temperature rise, whereby microcrystal particles of a vanadium pentoxide can be formed. According to the production method described above, crystals of a nano-vanadium having a layer length of 100 nm or less can be formed. The nano-vanadium formed by the production method described above can effectively be used for an electrode (11, 12) of an electric storage device (10) such as a battery. The production method according to the present invention can be linked to a conventional production method in which an ammonium metavanadate can be formed in the course of the method, whereby the present invention can smoothly be embodied.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A production method of a layered crystal material of microcrystals of a vanadium oxide having a layer length of 100 nm, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
- a nano-crystallizing process for growing crystals so as to have a layer length of 100 nm or less, wherein
</P>
<P>
the nano-crystallizing process includes a heat-treatment process for heating a salt of vanadic acid at a temperature equal to or less than a predetermined temperature.
</P>
<P>
2. The method according to claim 1,
</P>
<P>
wherein the nano-crystallizing process includes a process for heat-treating an ammonium metavanadate to 500[deg.]C or less.
</P>
<P>
3. The method according to claim 1 or 2,
</P>
<P>
wherein the ammonium metavanadate is heat-treated to 150[deg.]C or more.
</P>
<P>
4. The method according to claim 2 or 3,
</P>
<P>
wherein the ammonium metavanadate is formed by salting-out from a soluble salt of vanadic acid.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 4,
</P>
<P>
wherein the soluble salt of vanadic acid is a salt of an alkali metal.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to claim 4 or 5,
</P>
<P>
wherein the soluble salt of vanadic acid is a sodium salt.
</P>
<P>
7. The method according to any one of claims 4 to 6,
</P>
<P>
wherein the soluble salt of vanadic acid is formed with a combustion ash being used as a material.
</P>
<P>
8. The method according to any of claims 1 to 7,
</P>
<P>
wherein the microcrystals having a layer length of 100 nm or less but not including 0 are used for an electrode (11, 12) of an electric storage device (10).
</P>
<P>
9. The method according to claim 8,
</P>
<P>
wherein the electric storage device (10) is a lithium ion secondary battery.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2116635A3;US2009269274A1;JP2009263158A;CN101565206A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
