<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Increased data storage in optical data storage and retrieval systems using blue lasers and/or plasmon lenses
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2112659A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
OVSHINSKY STANFORD R [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STRAND DAVID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TSU DAVID [US]
</Name>
<Name>
OVSHINSKY, STANFORD R
</Name>
<Name>
STRAND, DAVID
</Name>
<Name>
TSU, DAVID
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ENERGY CONVERSION DEVICES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ENERGY CONVERSION DEVICES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2112659
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090167597
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2002-08-30
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20020759498
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-08-30
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20010316566P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2001-09-01
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G11B11/03
</Class>
<Class>
G11B11/105
</Class>
<Class>
G11B11/11
</Class>
<Class>
G11B11/115
</Class>
<Class>
G11B11/12
</Class>
<Class>
G11B15/04
</Class>
<Class>
G11B19/04
</Class>
<Class>
G11B20/18
</Class>
<Class>
G11B27/36
</Class>
<Class>
G11B5/58
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/004
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/0045
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/0055
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/006
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/09
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/095
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/125
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/135
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/24
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/243
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/251
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/257
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/0045P
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/0055P
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/006
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/1275
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/1374
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/1387
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/243
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/243B
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/24R
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/24S
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/251
</Class>
<Class>
G11B7/257
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A optical recording medium (10) includes a crystallizing layer (7,8) for enhancing the crystallization of a phase change memory layer (3), an energy storage layer for aiding the state transformations of a phase change memory layer (3), and/or a modifying element for increasing absorption and contrast at short wavelengths. An optical data storage and retrieval system ( figure 3 ) containing same. A light-plasmon coupling lens including an optically transparent substrate having a light incident surface and a light-plasmon coupling surface opposite the light incident surface. The light-plasmon coupling surface including at least a set of circular concentric peaks/valleys which form a Fourier sinusoidal pattern in the radial direction of the circular concentric peaks/valleys. A conformal layer of metal is deposited on the light-plasmon coupling surface of the substrate and has aperture at the center of thereof through which plasmons are transmitted.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An optical recording medium of the type used for data storage and retrieval systems based on blue lasers having a wavelength of less than 430 nm, said optical recording medium including an information recording layer comprising Ge2Sb2 Te5-xSex where 0 &amp;lt; x 5.
</P>
<P>
2. The optical recording medium of claim 1, wherein the value of an optical property of said phase change material in said first detectable state, at a wavelength shorter than 430 nm, is at least about 50 % greater than the value of said optical property of said phase change material when x = 0.
</P>
<P>
3. The optical recording medium of claim 1, wherein the value of an optical property of said phase change material in said first detectable state, at a wavelength shorter than 430 nm, is at least about 100 % greater than the value of said optical property of said phase change material when x = 0.
</P>
<P>
4. The optical recording medium of claim 1, wherein one of said first or second detectable states is a crystalline or partially crystalline state.
</P>
<P>
5. The optical recording medium of claim 1, wherein one of said first or second detectable states is an amorphous state.
</P>
<P>
6. The optical recording medium of claim 1, wherein said optical property is absorption coefficient.
</P>
<P>
7. The optical recording medium of claim 1, wherein said optical property is reflectivity.
</P>
<P>
8. A method of using an optical recording medium of the type used for data storage and retrieval systems based on blue lasers having a wavelength of less than 430 nm, said optical recording medium including an information recording layer comprising Ge2Sb2Te5-xSex where 0 &amp;lt; x. 5, said method including at least one step of writing data to or erasing data from the information recording layer using a blue laser having a wavelength of less than 430 nm.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2003048744A1;US7113474B2;US2006245333A1;US7292521B2;US2006280043A1;US7388825B2;WO03021589A1;TWI277087B;TWI254299B;JP2008234826A;JP2005502155A;EP1428212A1;EP1428212A4
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
