<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Metal microparticle, composition containing the same and process for producing metal microparticle
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2189232A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TAKATA YOSHIAKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HIRATA HIROKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SATOH JUN-ETSU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NIIDOME YASURO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YAMADA SUNAO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NISHIOKA KOJI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
KAWASAKI HIDEYA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MIZOGUCHI DAIGOU [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
NAGAI MASANORI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MUROUCHI MASATO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ISHIHARA MASAOKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TAKATA, YOSHIAKI
</Name>
<Name>
HIRATA, HIROKI
</Name>
<Name>
SATOH, JUN-ETSU
</Name>
<Name>
NIIDOME, YASURO
</Name>
<Name>
YAMADA, SUNAO
</Name>
<Name>
NISHIOKA, KOJI
</Name>
<Name>
KAWASAKI, HIDEYA
</Name>
<Name>
MIZOGUCHI, DAIGOU
</Name>
<Name>
NAGAI, MASANORI
</Name>
<Name>
MUROUCHI, MASATO
</Name>
<Name>
ISHIHARA, MASAOKI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MITSUBISHI MATERIALS CORP [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
DAINIPPON TORYO KK [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
MITSUBISHI MATERIALS CORPORATION
</Name>
<Name>
DAI NIPPON TORYO CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2189232
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080162064
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-09-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040772901
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-09-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20030314208
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-09-05
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20040116253
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-04-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20040116254
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-04-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y20/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
One object of the present invention is to provide metal fine particles which have selective wavelength absorption characteristics in a wavelength region from visible light to near infrared light, and have sharp absorption characteristics, and influences little the surrounding wavelength, and therefore, they yield tones having high chroma. The present invention provides a production method for producing metal fine particles by reducing metal ions in an aqueous solution containing a surfactant, wherein an aspect ratio of the metal fine particles is controlled by obtaining the metal fine particles under conditions in which an acid or alkali is added.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A production method for producing metal fine particles by reducing metal ions in an aqueous solution containing a surfactant, wherein an aspect ratio of the metal fine particles is controlled by obtaining the metal fine particles under conditions in which an acid or alkali is added.
</P>
<P>
2. The production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 1, wherein the acid is selected from the group consisting of nitric acid, sulfuric acid, hydrochloric acid, and hydrobromic acid, and the alkali is selected from the group consisting of sodium hydroxide, potassium hydroxide, and aqueous ammonia.
</P>
<P>
3. The production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 1, wherein the metal ions are reduced in an aqueous solution containing a surfactant by a method selected from the group consisting of a chemical reduction method, an electrochemical reduction method, a photoreduction method, and a combination of a chemical reduction method and a photoreduction method, and the obtained metal fine particles are metal nano-rods.
</P>
<P>
4. The production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 1, wherein the metal ions are reduced in an aqueous solution containing a surfactant by an electrochemical reduction method using an aqueous solution containing at least one selected from the group consisting of surfactants denoted by the following chemical formulas A, B, and C as an electrolyte, and the aspect ratio of the metal fine particles is made small by adding the acid or the aspect ratio of the metal fine particles is made large by adding the alkali.
</P>
<P>
CH3(CH2)nN&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;(CH3)3Br&amp;lt;-&amp;gt; (n is an integer from 1 to 15) ... A
</P>
<P>
[CH3(CH2)n]4N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;Br&amp;lt;-&amp;gt; (n is an integer from 1 to 15) ... B
</P>
<P>
[CH3(CH2)n]2N&amp;lt;+&amp;gt;(CH3)2Br&amp;lt;-&amp;gt; (n is an integer from 7 to 17) ... C
</P>
<P>
5. The production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 1, wherein the metal ions are reduced by a combination of a chemical reduction method using a reducing agent and a photoreduction method, and the aspect ratio of the metal fine particles is made large by adding the acid or the aspect ratio of the metal fine particles is made small by adding the alkali.
</P>
<P>
6. The production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 5, wherein the reducing agent in a metal ion aqueous solution is selected from the group consisting of ascorbic acid, citric acid and salts thereof; hydroxylamine hydrochloride, a hydrazine compound, succinic acid, and salts thereof; and an amine, the acid is selected from the group consisting of nitric acid, sulfuric acid, hydrochloric acid, and hydrobromic acid, and the alkali is selected from the group consisting of sodium hydroxide, potassium hydroxide, and aqueous ammonia.
</P>
<P>
7. A composition containing metal fine particles produced by the production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 1.
</P>
<P>
8. A coating composition, coating, transparent sheet, or film made of the composition according to claim 7.
</P>
<P>
9. An optical filter material, wiring material, electrode material, catalyst, pigment, cosmetic, near infrared light absorbing material, anticounterfer ink, electromagnetic interference shielding materials, surface reinforcing fluorescence sensor, biomarker, nano-waveguide, recording material, recording element, polarization material, drug supporter for drug delivery system (DDS), biosensor, DNA chip, or test drug, which contains the metal fine particles obtained by the production method for producing metal fine particles according to claim 1.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP1661648A1;EP1661648A4;KR20070104954A;KR20060083971A;KR100861899B1;WO2005023466A1;EP2165791A2;EP2165791A3;EP2165791A8;CN102019434A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
