<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROCESS FOR MAKING ANATASE TITANIUM (IV) OXIDE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2111369A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SCOTT DAVID M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI CARMINE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GRUSHIN VLADIMIR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SCOTT, DAVID M
</Name>
<Name>
TORARDI, CARMINE
</Name>
<Name>
GRUSHIN, VLADIMIR
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DU PONT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
E. I. DU PONT DE NEMOURS AND COMPANY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2111369
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20070867907
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2007-12-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2007US26105
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-12-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20060876294P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-12-21
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/053
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The disclosure pertains to a process for making anatase titanium dioxide particles, comprising: vigorously mixing (a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and (b) a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1, wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and a ratio of the volume of the first component to the second component are effective for the suspension of the finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles to form in the mixture;  and heating the suspension to convert the titanium (IV) oxide particles of the suspension to anatase titanium dioxide.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS What is claimed is:
</P>
<P>
1. A process for making anatase titanium dioxide particles, comprising: vigorously mixing
</P>
<P>
(a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and (b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, and at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1 , wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and a ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for forming a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles in the mixture; and heating the suspension to convert the titanium (IV) oxide particles of the suspension to anatase titanium dioxide particles.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base and the second aqueous base is the same or different.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1 in which the heating is provided by boiling the suspension.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 1 in which the heating is provided by elevating the temperature of the suspension to greater than about 50&amp;lt;[deg.]&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 1 in which the anatase titanium dioxide particles are nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 1 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is no greater than about 6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
7. The process of claim 1 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is up to and including about 20 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component when the activator is an aqueous base containing a tetraalkyl ammonium cation.
</P>
<P>
8. The process of claim 1 in which the activator ranges from about 0.2 to about 1.6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
9. The process of claim 1 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component ranges from about 1 to about 1 to about 9 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
10. The process of claim 1 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component is about 3 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
11. The process of claim 1 in which the titanium alkoxide has the chemical structure:
</P>
<P>
Ti(ORi)(OR2)(OR3)(OR4)
</P>
<P>
wherein Ri to R4 are the same or different alkyl groups of 1 to about 30 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
12. The process of claim 1 in which the titanium alkoxide is selected from the group consisting of titanium (IV) isopropoxide, titanium (IV) n- butoxide, titanium (IV) methoxide, titanium (IV) ethoxide, and titanium (IV) n-propoxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
13. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
14. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is a tetraalkylammonium hydroxide in which the alkyl group contains from 1 to 8 carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
15. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of tetraethylammonium hydroxide, tetra-n-butylammonium hydroxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
16. The process of claim 1 further comprising drying the suspension to form a powder.
</P>
<P>
17. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is in a concentration ranging from about 0.001 M to about 0.030 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
18. The process of claim 1 in which the base of the second aqueous base is ammonium hydroxide in a concentration ranging from about 0.006 M to about 14.8 M in the second component.
</P>
<P>
19. The process of claim 1 in which the alcohol is selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, isopropanol, ethylene glycol, and butanediol and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
20. The process of claim 1 in which the mixing vigor is determined by the shear rate of mixing and the shear rate is greater than about 100 s&amp;lt;&quot;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
21. The process of claim 1 in which the mixing is accomplished in a homogenizer wherein the rotor speed is greater than about 500 rpm.
</P>
<P>
22. The process of claim 1 in which the suspension comprises the titanium (IV) oxide in a liquid medium and the process further comprises concentrating the suspension by removing at least a portion of the liquid medium.
</P>
<P>
23. Anatase titanium dioxide particles made by a process, comprising: vigorously mixing (a) a volume of a first component comprising a major proportion of an alcohol, a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide and a minor proportion of a titanium alkoxide activator selected from the group consisting of water and a first aqueous base, and
</P>
<P>
(b) a volume of a second component selected from the group consisting of water and a second aqueous base, at least one of the first component or the second component having a base therein, the second component being substantially free of alcohol, to form a mixture comprising a suspension of finely divided titanium (IV) oxide particles, the mixture having a water to titanium molar ratio ranging from about 40 to about 1 to about 5000 to about 1 , wherein the proportion of the titanium alkoxide, the proportion of the activator, the mixing vigor, and a ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component are effective for the suspension of the finely divided particles to form in the mixture; and heating the suspension to convert the titanium (IV) oxide particles of the suspension to anatase titanium dioxide.
</P>
<P>
24. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the heating is provided by boiling the suspension.
</P>
<P>
25. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the heating is provided by elevating the temperature of the suspension to greater than about 50&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
26. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the anatase titanium dioxide particles are nanoparticles.
</P>
<P>
27. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is up to and including about 20 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component when the base of the first aqueous base comprises a tetraalkyl ammonium cation.
</P>
<P>
28. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the proportion of the titanium alkoxide is no greater than about 6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
29. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the activator ranges from about 0.2 to about 1.6 weight percent based on the entire weight of the first component.
</P>
<P>
30. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the ratio of the volume of the first component to the volume of the second component ranges from about 1 to about 1 to about 9 to about 1.
</P>
<P>
31. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the titanium alkoxide is selected from the group consisting of titanium (IV) isopropoxide, titanium (IV) n-butoxide, titanium (IV) methoxide, titanium (IV) ethoxide, and titanium (IV) n-propoxide and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
32. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the base of the first aqueous base is selected from the group consisting of ammonium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, sodium pyrophosphate, potassium pyrophosphate, sodium citrate, diammonium hydrogen phosphate and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
33. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the base of the first aqueous base is in a concentration up to about 0.2 M in the first component. 34. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the alcohol is selected from the group consisting of methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, isopropanol, ethylene glycol, and butanediol and mixtures thereof.
</P>
<P>
35. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the mixing vigor is determined by the shear rate of mixing and the shear rate is greater than about 100s&amp;lt;&apos;1&amp;gt;.
</P>
<P>
36. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 23 in which the mixing is accomplished in a homogenizer wherein the rotor speed is greater than about 500 rpm.
</P>
<P>
37. The anatase titanium dioxide of claim 37 in which the anatase titanium dioxide particles are nanoparticles.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008079311A1;US2010092377A1;US7887779B2;AU2007338719A1;AU2007338719A2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
