<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Ultrasensitive non- isotopic water- soluble nanocrystals
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2128624A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
NABIEV IGOR [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
SUKHANOVA ALYONA [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
JARDILLIER JEAN-CLAUDE [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
SHARAPOV OLEG [UA]
</Name>
<Name>
ARTEMYEV MIKHAIL [BY]
</Name>
<Name>
BARANOV ALEXANDRE [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
NABIEV, IGOR
</Name>
<Name>
SUKHANOVA, ALYONA
</Name>
<Name>
JARDILLIER, JEAN-CLAUDE
</Name>
<Name>
SHARAPOV, OLEG
</Name>
<Name>
ARTEMYEV, MIKHAIL
</Name>
<Name>
BARANOV, ALEXANDRE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV REIMS CHAMPAGNE ARDENNE L [FR]
</Name>
<Name>
SCIENT DEV SERVICE STROISNABSE [RU]
</Name>
<Name>
L&apos;UNIVERSITE DE REIMS CHAMPAGNE-ARDENNE
</Name>
<Name>
SCIENTIFIC DEVELOPMENT SERVICE STROISNABSERVICE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2128624
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090166316
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2001-03-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20010917351
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2001-03-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2001IB00478
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2001-03-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N33/58
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q30/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58J
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention concerns water-soluble semiconductor nanocrystal comprising semiconductor core and shell as well as a cap of one or more additional compounds comprising water-solubilization agents. In that the water-solubilization agent is a molecule of structural formula (R 1 ) a -R 2 -{(R 3 ) b (R 4 ) c } d .
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. Water-soluble semiconductor nanocrystal comprising semiconductor core and shell as well as a cap of one or more additional compounds comprising water-solubilization agents,
</P>
<P>
characterized in that the water-solubilization agent is a molecule of structural formula (R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;)a-R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;-{ (R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;) b(R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt;)c}d.
</P>
<P>
2. Water-soluble semiconductor nanocrystal according to the claim 1, characterized in that the molecule of structural formula (R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt;)a-R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;-{(R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt;)b(R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt;)c}d is such as:
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; is selected from the group consisting of heteroalkyl, heteroalkenyl, heteroalkynyl, -SR, -NHR, -NR2, -N(O)HR, -N(O)R2, -PHR, -PR2, -P(NR2), - P(O)R2, -P(O)(NR2)NR2, -P(O)(OR)POR, -P(O)OR, -P(S)(OR)OR, -P(S)OR, - P(S)SH, -P(S)SR, -C(S)SH, -C(S)SR wherein R is Li, Na, K; Rb, Cs, NH4, PH4,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; is selected from a bond, branched or unbranched alkylene, a branched or unbranched alkenylene, a branched or unbranched heteroalkylene, a branched or unbranched heteroalkenylene, cycloalkyl, cycloalkenyl, cycloalkynyl, heterocyclic aryl and heteroaryl,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; is selected from a branched or unbranched alkylene, a branched or unbranched alkenylene, a branched or unbranched heteroalkylene, a branched or unbranched heteroalkenylene, cycloalkyl, cycloalkenyl, cycloalkynyl, heterocyclic aryl and heteroaryl,
</P>
<P>
R&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; is selected from the group consisting of hydrogen, a carboxylate, a thiocarboxylate, an amine, an amide, an imine, an hydrazine, a sulfonate, a sulfoxide, a phosphate, a phosphonate, a phosphonium, an alcohol, a thiol, an ammonium, an alkyl ammonium, a nitrate, a sugar moiety and a five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten-membered cycloalkyl, cycloakenyl, cycloalkynil, heterocyclic, aryl or heteroaryl,
</P>
<P>
a being 1, 2, 3 or 4,
</P>
<P>
b being 0, 1, 2 or 3,
</P>
<P>
c being 0, 1, 2 or 3,
</P>
<P>
d being 0, 1, 2 or 3.
</P>
<P>
3. Water-soluble semiconductor nanocrystal according to the claim 1, characterised in that the nanocrystal is doped with paramagnetic ions.
</P>
<P>
4. Water-soluble nanocrystal probe comprising a water soluble semiconductor nanocrystal according to claim 1, a water-solubilisation agent, a linking agent and an affinity moiety which is able to bound specifically to detectable biological substances.
</P>
<P>
5. Probe according to the claim 4,
</P>
<P>
characterized in that the linking agent is able to connect the water-soluble nanocrystal or the polymeric bead comprising one or more nanocrystales embedded within, with the affinity molecules including peptides, proteins, monoclonal or polyclonal antibodies and their functional fragments, oligonucleotides, RNA, single and double stranded DNA, RNA-DNA hymeric molecules, DNA triplexes and multiplexes and carbohydrates which are able to bound specifically to detectable biological substances.
</P>
<P>
6. Probe according to the claims 4 and 5,
</P>
<P>
characterized in that the water-solubilisation agent is also the linking agent.
</P>
<P>
7. Process for the fabrication of doped nanocrystals with paramagnetic ions according to the claim 3,
</P>
<P>
characterised in that:
</P>
<P>
a TOPO is dried and degassed at 180[deg.]C for approximately 1 hour under argon atmosphere,
</P>
<P>
a solution of elemental semiconductors and the paramagnetic ions in TOP to this melt at 350[deg.]C is added
</P>
<P>
the reaction mixture is then cooled to 300[deg.]C and
</P>
<P>
a second solution of semiconductors is added and the reaction mixture is then cooled to 105[deg.]C,
</P>
<P>
finally the semiconductor core and shell doped with paramagnetic ions are precipitated and washed with methanol and dissolved with hexane, heptane or tetrahydrofuran or dried to powder.
</P>
<P>
8. Method of detection of biological substances by registration of EPR signal from paramagnetic ions incorporated into the nanocrystals according to the claim 3.
</P>
<P>
9. Method of detection of biological substances by registration of fluorescence signal from the nanocrystal according to anyone of the claims 1 or 3.
</P>
<P>
10. Method of detection of biological substances by registration of a combination of fluorescence signal and EPR signal from paramagnetic ions incorporated into the nanocrystals according to claim 3.
</P>
<P>
11. Method of detection of biological substances by the construction of images of biological substances by fluorescence or EPR microscopy or by a combination thereof from the nanocrystals according to claims 1 or 3.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2128624A3;WO02073155A1;US2004105973A1;ES2340251T3;EP1366347A1;EP1366347B1;EP1366347B8;AT448474T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
