<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
PROBE MICROSCOPY AND PROBE POSITION MONITORING APPARATUS
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2142906A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ULCINAS ARTURAS [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
ENGLEDEW DAVID JOHN [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
PICCO LOREN MICHAEL [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
MILES MERVYN JOHN [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
ANTOGNOZZI MASSIMO [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
ULCINAS, ARTURAS
</Name>
<Name>
ENGLEDEW, DAVID, JOHN
</Name>
<Name>
PICCO, LOREN, MICHAEL
</Name>
<Name>
MILES, MERVYN, JOHN
</Name>
<Name>
ANTOGNOZZI, MASSIMO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV BRISTOL [GB]
</Name>
<Name>
THE UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2142906
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080736908
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-09
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008GB01236
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070006732
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-09
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070012923
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
GB20070018094
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-17
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01Q20/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/22
</Class>
<Class>
G01N13/14
</Class>
<Class>
G12B21/06
</Class>
</IPC>
<IPC7>
<Class>
G01N13/14
</Class>
<Class>
G12B21/06
</Class>
</IPC7>
<ICM>
<Class>
G01Q20/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/22
</Class>
</ICM>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q20/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q60/22
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A near-field probe microscopy method for collecting sample data. The probe tip of a probe is placed contact with the sample surface or in a near-field region above the sample surface. Probe position monitoring apparatus monitors an at least one dimensional position of the probe tip in a probe tip plane, the probe tip plane being a plane which contains the probe tip and which is substantially parallel to the plane of the sample surface, to generate probe tip position data whereby a change in probe tip position data is representative of a force on the probe tip. In certain embodiments the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 1 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 1 ms. In certain embodiments the probe is less than 1 [mu]m long and/or wide and/or thick.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A near-field probe microscopy method for collecting sample data, the microscopy method comprising: providing a sample on a sample stage; positioning the probe tip of a probe in contact with the sample surface or in a near-field region above the sample surface; bending the probe along its length; and monitoring with probe position monitoring apparatus an at least one dimensional position of the probe tip in a probe tip plane, the probe tip plane being a plane which contains the probe tip and which is substantially parallel to the plane of the sample surface, to generate probe tip position data whereby a change in probe tip position data is representative of a force on the probe tip, wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 1 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 1 ms.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1 wherein the probe is less than 1 [mu]m long and/or wide and/or thick.
</P>
<P>
3. A near-field probe microscopy method for collecting sample data, the microscopy method comprising: providing a sample on a sample stage; positioning the probe tip of a probe in contact with the sample surface or in a near-field region above the sample surface; bending the probe along its length; and monitoring an at least one dimensional position of the probe tip in a probe tip plane, the probe tip plane being a plane which contains the probe tip and which is substantially parallel to the plane of the sample surface, to generate probe tip position data whereby a change in probe tip position data is representative of a characteristic of the sample, wherein the probe is less than 1 [mu]m long and/or wide and/or thick. 4. The method of any preceding claim wherein the probe has a resonant frequency in air which is greater than 2OkHz, preferably greater than 1 MHz1 and more preferably greater than 10MHz.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of any preceding claim further comprising causing the probe to flex at a frequency greater than 2OkHz, preferably greater than 1MHz1 and more preferably greater than 10MHz.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 5 wherein the probe flexes in a direction which is substantially parallel to the sample surface.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of any preceding claim wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 0.5 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 1 ms.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of any preceding claim wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 1 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 0.1 ms.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of any preceding claim wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 0.5 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 0.1 ms.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of any preceding claim wherein the probe has a spring constant less than 10pN/nm, and preferably less than 1 pN/nm.
</P>
<P>
11.The method of any preceding claim wherein the probe comprises a carbon nanotube. 12. Near-field probe microscopy apparatus comprising a sample stage; a probe having a probe tip; and probe position monitoring apparatus configured to monitor an at least one dimensional position of the probe tip in a probe tip plane, the probe tip plane being a plane which contains the probe tip and which is substantially parallel to the plane of the sample surface, to generate probe tip position data whereby a change in probe tip position data is representative of a force on the probe tip; wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 1 pN to cause the probe to bend along its length and generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 1 ms.
</P>
<P>
13. Near-field probe microscopy apparatus comprising a sample stage; a probe having a probe tip; and probe position monitoring apparatus configured to monitor an at least one dimensional position of the probe tip in a probe tip plane, the probe tip plane being a plane which contains the probe tip and which is substantially parallel to the plane of the sample surface, to generate probe tip position data whereby a change in probe tip position data is representative of a property of the sample; wherein the probe is less than 1 [mu]m long and/or wide and/or thick and wherein the probe is configured to bend along its length when in use.
</P>
<P>
14. The apparatus of claim 12 or 13 wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 0.5 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 1 ms.
</P>
<P>
15. The apparatus of claim 12, 13 or 14 wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 1 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 0.1 ms.
</P>
<P>
16. The apparatus of any of claims 12 to 15 wherein the probe is sufficiently small and soft and the probe position monitoring apparatus is sufficiently sensitive to enable a force on the probe tip which is lower than 0.5 pN to generate a change in the probe tip position data with a settling time lower than 0.1ms.
</P>
<P>
17. The apparatus of any of claims 12 to 16 wherein the probe has a spring constant less than 10 pN/nm, and preferably less than 1 pN/nm.
</P>
<P>
18. The apparatus of any of claims 12 to 17 wherein the probe comprises a carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
19. The apparatus of any of claims 12 to 18 wherein the probe has a resonant frequency in air which is greater than 2OkHz, preferably greater than 1 MHz1 and more preferably greater than 10MHz.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008122799A1;US2010207039A1;US8051493B2;WO2008122800A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
