<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Methods, compositions and blends for forming articles having improved environmental stress crack resistance
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2159041A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
JACOBS IAN ORDE MICHAEL [AU]
</Name>
<Name>
JACOBS, IAN, ORDE, MICHAEL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
JACOBS IAN ORDE MICHAEL [AU]
</Name>
<Name>
JACOBS, IAN, ORDE, MICHAEL
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2159041
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090013816
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2004-01-16
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20040702613
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-01-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
AU20030900292
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-01-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
AU20030901342
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-03-24
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
AU20030901952
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2003-04-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B29C45/00
</Class>
<Class>
B29C45/72
</Class>
<Class>
B29D23/20
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/18
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/10
</Class>
<Class>
C08K3/34
</Class>
<Class>
C08K9/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08L101/12
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/10
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B29C45/00B
</Class>
<Class>
B29C45/72B
</Class>
<Class>
B29K23/06
</Class>
<Class>
B29K23/12
</Class>
<Class>
B29K995/00F8
</Class>
<Class>
B29L23/20
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C08J5/00N
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C08L23/10
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Several processes for the manufacture of thin-walled tubes are described, including: injection moulding an article and annealing the article, injection moulding a blend of a polymer and a high melt flow polymer, injection moulding a blend of a polymer and nanoparticles or nanocomposites. Using nanoparticles to improve ESCR and/or tear resistance of a polymer or blend is also disclosed.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for the manufacture of flexible, thin-walled articles comprising the steps of injection moulding a polymer blend having an MFI &amp;gt; 10 and comprising at least one polymer wherein said polymer includes a polypropylene having varying tacticity within its structure.
</P>
<P>
2. A process according to claim 1, wherein the polymer having varying tacticity, has a tacticity which varies within the range of between 25 and 60 % of [mmmm] pentad concentration.
</P>
<P>
3. A process according to claim 1, wherein the blend comprises at least two polymers, with at least one polymer having a higher crystallinity than the at least one other polymer.
</P>
<P>
4. A process according to claim 3, wherein the at least one polymer is made from the same monomer(s) as the at least one other polymer.
</P>
<P>
5. A process according to claim 3, in which as least one polymer is a polyethylene polymer.
</P>
<P>
6. A process according to claim 4, wherein both polymers are made from propylene monomer.
</P>
<P>
7. A process according to claim 3, wherein the blend comprises a) a polymer comprising stereospecific polypropylene of greater crystallinity (XPP) and b) a copolymer of propylene and at least one C2, C4-C20 [alpha]-olefin of lesser crystallinity (SXPP), and the blend comprises between 1% and 95% by weight of the XPP and a SXPP with greater than 65% by weight propylene.
</P>
<P>
8. A process according to claim 7, wherein the blend comprises between 1% and 95% by weight of an isotactic polypropylene and an ethylene propylene copolymer with greater than 65 % by weight propylene, preferably greater than 80 % by weight propylene.
</P>
<P>
9. A process according to claim 7 or claim 8, wherein the XPP and the SXPP have the same tacticity.
</P>
<P>
10. A process according to claim 1, further including annealing the injection moulded thin-walled article.
</P>
<P>
11. A process according to claim 1, wherein at least one polymer of the blend has an MFI of greater than 100.
</P>
<P>
12. A process according to claim 1, wherein the blend comprises (a) 1% to 99% of at least one isotactic, syndiotactic or atactic polypropylene homopolymer or [alpha]-olefin copolymer and (b) 99 % to 1 % of at least one of an ethylene, propylene and/or butene copolymer.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2004062896A1;US2006214331A1;PL211431B1;MXPA05007662A;JP2006517475A;EP2363276A2;EP1590168A1;EP1590168A4;BRPI0406793A;AU2009202782A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
