<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOTUBE DEVICE AND METHOD OF FABRICATION
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2171132A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
FARROW REGINALD C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
IQBAL ZAFAR [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GOYAL AMIT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LIU SHENG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FARROW, REGINALD, C
</Name>
<Name>
IQBAL, ZAFAR
</Name>
<Name>
GOYAL, AMIT
</Name>
<Name>
LIU, SHENG
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
NEW JERSEY TECH INST [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NEW JERSEY INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2171132
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080826831
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-06-20
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US67604
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-06-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070765735
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-06-20
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J19/00
</Class>
<Class>
C25D13/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C25D13/04
</Class>
<Class>
C25D13/20
</Class>
<Class>
G01N27/414
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A nanotube device and a method of depositing nanotubes for device fabrication are disclosed. The method relates to electrophoretic deposition of nanotubes, and allows a control of the number of deposited nanotubes and positioning within a defined region.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A method of depositing nanotubes, comprising:
</P>
<P>
(a) defining a region on a structure by an aperture;
</P>
<P>
(b) configuring the aperture to control a number of nanotubes to be deposited by electrophoresis in the region; and
</P>
<P>
(c) depositing the number of nanotubes in the region by electrophoresis.
</P>
<P>
2. The method of claim 1, wherein step (b) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
configuring the aperture to control at least one of a pattern and spacing of nanotubes to be deposited in the region.
</P>
<P>
3. The method of claim 1, wherein step (b) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
providing the aperture with a combination of length, width and depth to control the number of nanotubes to be deposited.
</P>
<P>
4. The method of claim 1, wherein step (b) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
providing the aperture with a lateral dimension to allow only one nanotube to be deposited in the region by electrophoresis.
</P>
<P>
5. The method of claim 4, wherein the lateral dimension of the aperture is less than about 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. The method of claim 1, wherein the aperture is configured as a slot having a width of less than about 100 nm, and a length sufficiently large to allow deposition of at least two nanotubes along a direction of the length.
</P>
<P>
7. The method of claim 1, wherein step (b) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
(b1) performing finite element analysis as a function of at least one parameter of the aperture to obtain an electric field distribution in proximity of the aperture; and
</P>
<P>
(b2) selecting a configuration of the aperture suitable for depositing the number of nanotubes in the region.
</P>
<P>
8. The method of claim 7, wherein at least one parameter for the nanotubes to be deposited is included in the finite element analysis.
</P>
<P>
9. The method of claim 1, wherein the nanotube is a carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
10. The method of claim 1, wherein: step (a) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
(a1) providing the structure with an insulating layer over a metal layer; and
</P>
<P>
(a2) forming the aperture through the insulating layer to define the region at the metal layer.
</P>
<P>
11. The method of claim 10, wherein step (c) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
(c1) exposing the structure to an electrolytic fluid containing nanotubes;
</P>
<P>
(c2) applying a bias voltage to the metal layer; and
</P>
<P>
(c3) depositing the number of nanotubes in a vertical orientation to contact the metal layer inside the aperture.
</P>
<P>
12. The method of claim 11, wherein the number of nanotubes is one.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12, wherein the nanotube is deposited to be substantially centered inside the aperture.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 11, wherein step (c) further comprises:
</P>
<P>
(c4) providing a metal electrode in the electrolytic fluid; and
</P>
<P>
(c5) providing a positive bias to the metal electrode relative to the metal layer.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
controlling orientations of the nanotubes inside the aperture by adjusting an orientation of the metal electrode relative to the metal layer.
</P>
<P>
16. The method of claim 1, wherein the aperture has a height to width ratio of at least about 0.18.
</P>
<P>
17. A nanotube-based sensor, comprising:
</P>
<P>
an insulating layer over a metal contact formed on a substrate;
</P>
<P>
an aperture formed in the insulating layer, the aperture extending to the metal contact and defining a region at the metal contact;
</P>
<P>
a nanotube disposed inside the aperture and having a first end contacting the region at substantially a center of the region, and a second end coupled to a molecule having a functional group for interacting with a sample.
</P>
<P>
18. The device of claim 17, being one of a chemical sensor or a biosensor.
</P>
<P>
19. The device of claim 17, wherein the nanotube is a carbon nanotube.
</P>
<P>
20. The device of claim 17, wherein the sensor further comprises an insulating layer surrounding the nanotube.
</P>
<P>
21. A method of forming a carbon nanotube-based device, comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing a substrate with an insulating layer formed on a conductive layer;
</P>
<P>
forming an aperture through the insulating layer to expose a region of the conductive layer;
</P>
<P>
immersing the substrate in an electrolytic fluid containing carbon nanotubes;
</P>
<P>
providing a metal electrode in the electrolytic fluid;
</P>
<P>
applying a bias voltage across the conductive layer and the metal electrode; and
</P>
<P>
depositing at least one carbon nanotube in a substantially perpendicular orientation with respect to the region, wherein one end of the carbon nanotube contacts the region proximate a center of the region.
</P>
<P>
22. The method of claim 21, further comprising:
</P>
<P>
providing the substrate with the at least one deposited carbon nanotube to a plasma process system for further processing;
</P>
<P>
re-aligning the at least one deposited carbon nanotube to a desired orientation by applying an electric field between the conductive layer and an electrode in the plasma process system.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2008317631A1;US7964143B2;US2011240480A1;WO2009017898A2;WO2009017898A3;KR20100047845A;JP2010532717A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
