<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Antibody complexes
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2113773A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ARCHER ROBERT A [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BEECHEM JOSEPH M [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HAGEN DAVID C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HAUGLAND RICHARD P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
HAUGLAND ROSARIA P [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ARCHER, ROBERT A
</Name>
<Name>
BEECHEM, JOSEPH M
</Name>
<Name>
HAGEN, DAVID C
</Name>
<Name>
HAUGLAND, RICHARD P
</Name>
<Name>
HAUGLAND, ROSARIA P
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MOLECULAR PROBES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MOLECULAR PROBES, INC
</Name>
<Name>
LIFE TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2113773
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090163588
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2002-10-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20020768949
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-10-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20010329068P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2001-10-12
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20020369418P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-04-01
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20020118204
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2002-04-05
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
G01N33/53
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/532
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/53
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/58
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/68B2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides labeling reagents and methods for labeling primary antibodies and for detecting a target in a sample using an immuno-labeled complex that comprises a target-binding antibody and one or more labeling reagents. The labeling reagents comprise monovalent antibody fragments or non-antibody monomeric proteins whereby the labeling proteins have affinity for a specific region of the target-binding antibody and are covalently attached to a label. Typically, the labeling reagent is an anti-Fc Fab or Fab&apos; fragment that was generated by immunizing a goat or rabbit with the Fc fragment of an antibody.;  The present invention provides for discrete subsets of labeling reagent and immuno-labeled complexes that facilitate the simultaneous detection of multiple targets in a sample wherein the immuno-labeled complexes are distinguished by i) a ratio of label to labeling reagent, or ii) a physical property of said label, or iii) a ratio of labeling reagent to said target-binding antibody, or iv) by said target-binding antibody. This is particularly useful for fluorophore labels that can be attached to labeling reagents and subsequently immuno-labeled complexes in ratios for the detection of multiple targets.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A kit for preparing an immuno-labeling complex for use in detecting a target in a sample, said kit comprising:
</P>
<P>
a) a labelling solution comprising a labeling protein which is a monovalent anti-Fc antibody fragment comprising an Fc binding region that specifically binds to the Fc region on a target-binding antibody, wherein said labeling protein is independently covalently attached to one or more labels, wherein the one or more labels may be the same or different; and further wherein said labeling protein is capable of forming an immuno-labeled complex with the target binding antibody during use; and
</P>
<P>
b) a solution comprising a capture reagent for removing excess labeling protein.
</P>
<P>
2. The kit according to claim 1, wherein said capture reagent is an antibody or antibody fragment containing a binding site for the labeling protein but is not itself labeled.
</P>
<P>
3. The kit according to claim 1 or claim 2, which comprises a panel of labeling solutions wherein each labeling solution comprises a subset of a labeling protein and each subset is distinguished from another subset by i) a ratio of label to labeling protein, or ii) by a physical property of said label.
</P>
<P>
4. The kit according to any of claims 1 to 3, wherein the labeling protein is a Fab or Fab&apos; fragment and wherein the labeling protein comprises a label attached to the labeling protein at a position other than the target-binding antibody-binding region.
</P>
<P>
5. The kit according to any of claims 1 to 4, wherein said label is selected from the group consisting of a chromophore, a fluorophore, a fluorescent protein, a phosphorescent dye, a tandem dye, a particle, a hapten, an enzyme and a radioisotope.
</P>
<P>
6. The kit according to claim 5, wherein said fluorophore is selected from the group consisting of a coumarin, a xanthene, a cyanine, a pyrene, a borapolyazaindacene, an oxazine, and derivatives thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The kit according to claim 5, wherein said tandem dye is selected from the group consisting of a cyanine-phycobiliprotein derivative and xanthene-phycobiliprotein derivative.
</P>
<P>
8. The kit according to claim 5, wherein said enzyme is selected from the group consisting of a peroxidase, a phosphatase, a glycosidase, and a luciferase.
</P>
<P>
9. The kit according to any preceding claim, wherein the kit further comprises an addition component selected from the group consisting of (a) stains for characterization of cellular organelles, cell viability, or cell proliferation state, (b) enzyme substrates and (c) enzymes conjugates.
</P>
<P>
10. The kit according to any preceding claim, wherein the labeling protein is comprised within an immuno-labeled complex that further comprises the target binding antibody, wherein the target binding antibody comprises an Fc region and the Fc binding region of the labeling protein specifically binds to the Fc region of the target binding antibody.
</P>
<P>
11. Use of a kit according to any preceding claim for detecting a target in a sample.
</P>
<P>
12. Use according to claim 11, which comprises a step of forming an immuno-labeled complex comprising the target binding antibody and the labeling protein.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2113773A3;EP2113773B1;US2003073149A1;US2007269902A1;WO03030817A2;WO03030817A3;WO03030817B1;JP2007183291A;JP2006513398A;GB2397302A;GB2397302B;EP2259067A2;EP2259067A3;EP2259067B1;EP1442302A2;EP1442302A4;EP1442302B1;CA2462280A1;CA2462280C;AT436022T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
