<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Apparatus for nanofabrication using multi- photon excitation
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2133725A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
GOODMAN STEVEN L [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CAMPAGNOLA PAUL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GOODMAN, STEVEN L
</Name>
<Name>
CAMPAGNOLA, PAUL
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
UNIV CONNECTICUT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2133725
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20090010081
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
1999-04-21
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP19990925557
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1999-04-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19980082575P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1998-04-21
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US19980112797P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
1998-12-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K9/00
</Class>
<Class>
B29C67/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K1/06
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q80/00
</Class>
<Class>
G02B21/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/029
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/038
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/20
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K47/48W14B
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48W4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/00Z8
</Class>
<Class>
A61L27/36H
</Class>
<Class>
A61L27/50
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y15/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
C07K14/75
</Class>
<Class>
C07K14/765
</Class>
<Class>
C07K17/04
</Class>
<Class>
C12N11/04
</Class>
<Class>
G01Q80/00
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/029
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/038
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/20S
</Class>
<Class>
G03F7/20S2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention comprises of an apparatus for fabrication by multi-photon excitation, comprising a photon source in connection with 4pi optics, wherein the 4pi optics comprises a first high NA lens located above a movable stage and a second high NA lens located beneath the movable stage.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An apparatus for fabrication by multi-photon excitation, comprising a photon source in connection with 4pi optics, wherein the 4pi optics comprises a first high NA lens located above a movable stage and a second high NA lens located beneath the movable stage.
</P>
<P>
2. The apparatus of claim 1 further comprising a second movable stage located between the photon source and the first high NA lens.
</P>
<P>
3. An apparatus for fabrication by multi-photon excitation, comprising a photon source in connection with near field optics, wherein the near field optics comprises fiber optic couplers in conjunction with a near field fiber optic element for fabrication.
</P>
<P>
4. The apparatus of claim 3 further comprising an optical microscope as an imaging element.
</P>
<P>
5. The apparatus of claim 3, wherein the optical element is coupled with a multiple-barrel pipette.
</P>
<P>
6. The apparatus of claim 5, wherein the optical element is disposed within one of the pipette barrels.
</P>
<P>
7. A device for fabrication by multi-photon excitation at remote locations, comprising a photon source connected to a first end of single mode optical fiber via a fiber optic coupler and a group velocity delay self-phase modulation compensator; wherein the second end of the optical fiber comprises a lens for multi-photon fabrication.
</P>
<P>
8. The device of claim 7, wherein the optical fiber is housed in a catheter.
</P>
<P>
9. The device of claim 8, wherein the catheter further housed at least one reagent tube for dispensing reagent at the site of fabrication.
</P>
<P>
10. The device of claim 7, wherein the second end of the optical fiber further comprises a cowling.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2133725A3;WO9954784A1;WO9954784A9;US2002006648A1;US6713772B2;US6316153B1;JP2002512260A;EP1084454A1;EP1084454A4;CA2326322A1;CA2326322C
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
