<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
POLY (AMINO ACID) TARGETING MOIETIES
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2144600A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
ALEXIS FRANK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG LIANGFANG [US]
</Name>
<Name>
RADOVIC-MORENO ALEKSANDAR F [US]
</Name>
<Name>
GU FRANK X [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
BASTO PAMELA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LEVY-NISSENBAUM ETGAR [IL]
</Name>
<Name>
CHAN JULIANA [US]
</Name>
<Name>
LANGER ROBERT S [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FAROKHZAD OMID C [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ALEXIS, FRANK
</Name>
<Name>
ZHANG, LIANGFANG
</Name>
<Name>
RADOVIC-MORENO, ALEKSANDAR, F
</Name>
<Name>
GU, FRANK, X
</Name>
<Name>
BASTO, PAMELA
</Name>
<Name>
LEVY-NISSENBAUM, ETGAR
</Name>
<Name>
CHAN, JULIANA
</Name>
<Name>
LANGER, ROBERT, S
</Name>
<Name>
FAROKHZAD, OMID, C
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
MASSACHUSETTS INST TECHNOLOGY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BRIGHAM &amp; WOMENS HOSPITAL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
</Name>
<Name>
THE BRIGHAM AND WOMEN&apos;S HOSPITAL, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2144600
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080745171
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-04-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US59491
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-04-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070910097P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-04-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070938590P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-05-17
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070985104P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070986202P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070990250P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-11-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K9/16
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K47/48W14B
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51H4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51H6D4
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51P
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Libraries of nanoparticles with an amphiphilic component can be formed by mixing together two or more macromolecules In different ratios. One or more of the macromolecules may be a polymeric conjugate of a moiety to a biocompatible polymer. In some cases, the nanoparticle may contain a drug.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A pharmaceutical composition, comprising a plurality of target- specific stealth nanoparticles; a polymeric matrix; an amphipilic layer associated with the polymeric matrix; targeting moieties covalently attached to the outer surface of the nanoparticle; and a therapeutic agent.
</P>
<P>
2. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the ratio of the amphipilic component of the amphipilic layer to the polymeric matrix is tailored for the effective treatment of diseases in a subject in need thereof.
</P>
<P>
3. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the ratio of the amphipilic component of the amphipilic layer to the polymeric matrix is tailored to give a nanoparticle of a desired size.
</P>
<P>
4. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the ratio of the amphipilic component of the amphipilic layer to the polymeric matrix is about 0.05 to about 0.50.
</P>
<P>
5. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 4, wherein the ratio of the amphipilic component of the amphipilic layer to the polymeric matrix is about .12 to about 0.34.
</P>
<P>
6. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles are about 40nm to about 500nm in size.
</P>
<P>
7. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles are about 40nm to about 80nm in size.
</P>
<P>
8. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles are about 40nm to about 60nm in size.
</P>
<P>
9. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticles have a surface zeta potential ranging from -8OmV to -3OmV.
</P>
<P>
10. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the amphipilic layer is a monolayer.
</P>
<P>
11. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1 , wherein the amphipilic layer comprises naturally derived lipids, surfactants, or synthesized compounds with both hydrophilic and hydrophobic moieties.
</P>
<P>
12. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the amphipilic layer comprises lecithin.
</P>
<P>
13. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the amphipilic layer has a thickness of about lnm to about 5 nm.
</P>
<P>
14. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the amphipilic layer has a thickness of about 2.5 nm.
</P>
<P>
15. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the polymeric matrix comprises two or more polymers.
</P>
<P>
16. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the polymeric matrix comprises polyethylenes, polycarbonates, polyanhydrides, polyhydroxyacids, polypropylfumerates, polycaprolactones, polyamides, polyacetals, polyethers, polyesters, poly(orthoesters), polycyanoacrylates, polyvinyl alcohols, polyurethanes, polyphosphazenes, polyacrylates, polymethacrylates, polycyanoacrylates, polyureas, polystyrenes, or polyamines, or combinations thereof.
</P>
<P>
17. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein at least one polymer is a polyalkylene glycol.
</P>
<P>
18. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 17, wherein the polyalkylene glycol is polyethylene glycol.
</P>
<P>
19. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein at least one polymer is a polyester.
</P>
<P>
20. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 19, wherein the polyester is PLGA.
</P>
<P>
21. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the polymeric matrix comprises a copolymer of two or more polymers.
</P>
<P>
22. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 21, wherein the copolymer is a copolymer of a polyalkylene glycol and a polyester.
</P>
<P>
23. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 22, wherein the copolymer is a copolymer of PLGA and PEG.
</P>
<P>
24. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the polymeric matrix comprises a lipid-terminated polyalkylene glycol and a polyester.
</P>
<P>
25. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the polymeric matrix comprises lipid-terminated PEG, and PLGA.
</P>
<P>
26. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 25, wherein the lipid is of the Formula I:
</P>
<P>
(D and salts thereof, wherein each R is. , independently , C1-30 alkyl.
</P>
<P>
27. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 26, wherein the lipid is 1,2 distearoyl- sn-glycero-3-phosphoethanolamine (DSPE), and salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
28. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle comprises a copolymer of PEG and PLGA, wherein an amphiphilc compound is disposed between the PEG and PLGA.
</P>
<P>
29. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 28, wherein the PEG is terminated with a lipid that self-assembles with PLGA.
</P>
<P>
30. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the targeting moiety is selected from nucleic acid aptamers, growth factors, hormones, cytokines, interleukins, antibodies, integrins, fibronectin receptors, p-glycoprotein receptors, peptides and cell binding sequences.
</P>
<P>
31. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 30, wherein the targeting moiety is a peptide, and wherein the peptide is less than 8 amino acids in length.
</P>
<P>
32. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the targeting moiety is AKERC, CREKA, ARYLQKLN or AXYLZZLN, wherein X and Z are variable amino acids.
</P>
<P>
33. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the targeting moiety is the AlO RNA aptamer.
</P>
<P>
34. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 23, wherein the polymer matrix is covalently bound to the targeting moiety via a maleimide functional group at the free terminus of PEG.
</P>
<P>
35. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the pharmaceutical composition is suitable for target- specific treatment of a disease or disorder and delivery of a therapeutic agent.
</P>
<P>
36. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the therapeutic agent is associated with the surface of, encapsulated within, surrounded by, or dispersed throughout the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
37. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 36, wherein the therapeutic agent is encapsulated within the hydrophobic core of the nanoparticle.
</P>
<P>
38. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the therapeutic agent is a biomolecule, bioactive agent, small molecule, drug, protein, vaccine, or polynucleotide.
</P>
<P>
39. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the therapeutic agent is selected from the group consisting of mitoxantrone and docetaxel.
</P>
<P>
40. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the therapeutic agent is selected from the group consisting of VEGF, fibroblast growth factors, monocyte chemoatractant protein 1 (MCP-I), transforming growth factor alpha (TGF-alpha), transforming growth factor beta (TGF-beta), DEL-I, insulin like growth factors (IGF), placental growth factor (PLGF), hepatocyte growth factor (HGF), prostaglandin El (PG- El), prostaglandin E2 (PG-E2), tumor necrosis factor alpha (TBF-alpha), granulocyte stimulating growth factor (G-CSF), granulocyte macrophage colony-stimulating growth factor (GM-CSF), angiogenin, follistatin, and proliferin, PR39, PRIl, nicotine, hydroxy- methylglutaryl coenzyme A (HMG CoA) reductase inhibitors, statins, niacin, bile acid resins, fibrates, antioxidants, extracellular matrix synthesis promoters, inhibitors of plaque inflammation and extracellular degradation, and estradiol.
</P>
<P>
41. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle is between 40 and lOOnm in diameter, and the targeting moiety is less than IOnm in length.
</P>
<P>
42. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 41, wherein the nanoparticle is between 40 and 80nm in diameter, and the targeting moiety is less than IOnm in length.
</P>
<P>
43. The pharmaceutical composition of claim 1, wherein the nanoparticle is non- immunogenic.
</P>
<P>
44. A method of treating prostate cancer in a subject in need thereof, comprising administering to the subject an effective amount of the pharmaceutical composition of claim 33.
</P>
<P>
45. A method of treating atherosclerotic plaques, restenosis, or atherosclerosis in a subject in need thereof, comprising administering to the subject an effective amount of the pharmaceutical composition of claim 40.
</P>
<P>
46. The method of claims 44 or 45, wherein the controlled-release system is administered systemically.
</P>
<P>
47. The method of claims 44 or 45, wherein the controlled-release system is administered via intraveneous administration.
</P>
<P>
48. A method of preparing a nanoparticle comprising a polymeric matrix and an amphipilic layer associated with the polymeric matrix, comprising: conjugating a first polymer to a to a targeting moiety to form a first conjugate; adding the first conjugate and an amphiphilic component to a water miscible solvent to form a first solution; combining a second polymer with a therapeutic agent in a partially water miscible oganic solvent to form a second solution; and combining the first and second solution such that the nanoparticle is formed.
</P>
<P>
49. The method of claim 48, wherein the water miscible solvent is acetone, ethanol, methanol, or isopropyl alcohol.
</P>
<P>
50. The method of claim 48, wherein the partial water miscible organic solvent is acetonitrile, tetrahydrouran, ethyl acetate, isopropyl alcohol, isopropyl acetate or dimethylformamide .
</P>
<P>
51. The method of claim 48, wherein the first polymer is PEG, the targeting moiety is an aptamer, the amphiphilic component is lecithin, and the second polymer is PLGA.
</P>
<P>
52. The method of claim 48, wherein the first polymer is conjugated to DSPE, or salts thereof.
</P>
<P>
53. A nanoparticle, comprising a copolymer of PLGA and PEG, a targeting moiety, and a therapeutic agent, wherein lecithin is disposed between the PLGA and PEG.
</P>
<P>
54. A nanoparticle, comprising a polymeric matrix comprising a complex of a phospholipid bound-PEG and PLGA; a targeting moiety, and a therapeutic agent, wherein lecithin is disposed between the PLGA and PEG.
</P>
<P>
55. The nanoparticles of claims 53 or 54, wherien the targeting moiety is an AlO RNA aptamer or CREKA.
</P>
<P>
56. The nanoparticles of claims 53 or 54, wherien the therapeutic agent is docetaxel.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2144600A4;WO2008124632A1;WO2008124639A2;WO2008124639A3;US2010203142A1;US2009074828A1;JP2010523595A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
