<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
VESICLES COMPRISING A TRANSMEMBRANE TRANSPORT TRIGGER SYSTEM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2180881A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SCHWANEBERG ULRICH [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
ONACA OZANA [CH]
</Name>
<Name>
SARKAR PRASENJIT [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FRIEDRICH THOMAS [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
HAUER BERNHARD [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
SCHWANEBERG, ULRICH
</Name>
<Name>
ONACA, OZANA
</Name>
<Name>
SARKAR, PRASENJIT
</Name>
<Name>
FRIEDRICH, THOMAS
</Name>
<Name>
HAUER, BERNHARD
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BASF SE [DE]
</Name>
<Name>
BASF SE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2180881
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080774810
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-07-07
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008EP58735
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-07
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20070112838
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-07-20
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20080774810
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-07-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K38/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K49/00
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/127
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/51
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
A61K47/48W14B
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48W6D
</Class>
<Class>
A61K47/48W6H
</Class>
<Class>
A61K9/127B4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The invention is directed to vesicles comprising at least one transmembrane triggered transport system for controlled transmembrane efflux and/or influx.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
Claims:
</P>
<P>
1. A vesicle comprising at least one transmembrane transport trigger system.
</P>
<P>
2. The vesicles according to claim 1 comprising a transmembrane efflux and/or influx trigger system.
</P>
<P>
3. The vesicles according to claim 1 comprising at least one transmembrane channel protein, preferably a pore forming protein.
</P>
<P>
4. The vesicle according to claim 1 comprising at least one outer membrane channel protein.
</P>
<P>
5. The vesicle according to claim 1 comprising at least one channel protein selected from the group consisting of: porins, preferably OmpF, PhoE, LamB, FepA, Tsx and FhuA and a part thereof and a homologue.
</P>
<P>
6. The vesicle according to claim 1 wherein the protein is labeled.
</P>
<P>
7. The vesicle according to claim 1 wherein the protein is labeled with an amino- group labeling agent.
</P>
<P>
8. The vesicle according to claim 1 wherein the amino-group labeling agent is selected from the group consisting of: 3-(2-Pyridyldithio)propionic acid N- hydroxysuccinimide ester and biotin disulfide N-hydroxysuccinimide ester.
</P>
<P>
9. The vesicle according to claim 1, whereby the vesicle is selected from the group consisting of: liposome, polymersome and synthosome.
</P>
<P>
10. The vesicle according to claim 1 consisting of a encapsulating membrane.
</P>
<P>
11. A synthosome according to claim 10 wherein the encapsulating membrane is composed of block copolymers. 12. A process for the production of the vesicles according to claim 1 comprising the following steps: a) adding a transmembrane channel protein to a solution or dispersion of a labeling agent and, b) adding the labeled transmembrane channel protein to a solution or dispersion of molecules forming a vesicle c) forming the vesicle whereby the labeled transmembrane channel protein is incorporated into the membrane of the vesicle.
</P>
<P>
13. A process according to claim 12 comprising the following steps: a) adding a transmembrane channel protein to a solution or dispersion of a labeling agent and, b) adding the labeled transmembrane channel protein to a solution or dispersion of molecules forming a vesicle c) adding the solution or dispersion from step b) to a solution or dispersion containing the substance to be charged within the vesicle, d) forming the vesicle whereby the labeled transmembrane channel protein is incorporated into the membrane of the vesicle and the substance is encapsulated into the vesicle.
</P>
<P>
14. A method for triggering the transmembrane transport adding to the dispersion containing the vesicle according to claim 1 a substance which opens the transmembrane channel protein by splitting off at least a part of the labeling agent in a chemical reaction.
</P>
<P>
15. A method according to claim 16, wherein the chemical reaction is selected from the group consisting of: reduction, oxidation and substitution.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009013115A2;WO2009013115A3;US2010189777A1;JP2010533669A;CN101854917A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
