<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
CERAMIC PARTICULATE MATERIAL AND PROCESSES FOR FORMING SAME
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2118011A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
BAUER RALPH [CA]
</Name>
<Name>
HAERLE ANDREW G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YENER DORUK O [US]
</Name>
<Name>
THERON CLAIRE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
KAVANAUGH MICHAEL D [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BAUER, RALPH
</Name>
<Name>
HAERLE, ANDREW G
</Name>
<Name>
YENER, DORUK O
</Name>
<Name>
THERON, CLAIRE
</Name>
<Name>
KAVANAUGH, MICHAEL D
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SAINT GOBAIN CERAMICS [US]
</Name>
<Name>
SAINT-GOBAIN CERAMICS &amp; PLASTICS, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2118011
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080713764
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-01-15
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008US51066
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-01-15
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20070884925P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-01-15
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01F7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01F7/44
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01F7/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01F7/02B
</Class>
<Class>
C01F7/44C2
</Class>
<Class>
C09G1/02
</Class>
<Class>
C09K3/14B
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Ceramic particulate material includes alumina particles, the particles having a specific surface area (SSA) not less than 15 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g and not greater than 75 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g and a sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a means roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concve outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS:
</P>
<P>
1. Ceramic particulate material, comprising: alumina particles, the particles having a specific surface area (SSA) not less than 15 [pi]vVg and not greater than 75 irr/g and a sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
<P>
2. The ceramic particulate material of claim 1, wherein the SSA is not greater than 60 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
3. The ceramic particulate material of claim 2, wherein the SSA is not greater than 50 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
4. The ceramic particulate material of claim 3, wherein the SSA is not greater than 40 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g.
</P>
<P>
5. The ceramic particulate material of claim 4, wherein the SSA is not greater than 30 [pi]r/g.
</P>
<P>
6. The ceramic particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles are comprised of alpha phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
7. The ceramic particulate material of claim 6, wherein the alumina particles consist essentially of alpha phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
8. The ceramic particulate material of claim 6, wherein the alumina particles are comprised of at least 85 wt% alpha phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
9. The ceramic particulate material of claim 8, wherein the alumina particles are essentially entirely alpha phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
10. The ceramic particulate material of claim 9, wherein the alumina particles are single crystal alpha phase alumina.
</P>
<P>
11. The ceramic particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles have a concavity less than 15%.
</P>
<P>
12. The ceramic particulate material of claim 11, wherein the alumina particles have a concavity less than 10%.
</P>
<P>
13. The ceramic particulate material of claim 12, wherein the alumina particles have a concavity less than 5%.
</P>
<P>
14. The ceramic particulate material of claim 1, wherein the alumina particles have said mean roundness not less than 0.710.
</P>
<P>
15. The ceramic particulate material of claim 14, wherein the mean roundness is not less than 0.720.
</P>
<P>
16. Ceramic particulate material, comprising: alumina particles, the particles having an average primary particle size less than 135 nm as measured by TEM, and a sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
<P>
17. The ceramic particulate material of claim 16, wherein the average primary particle size is less than 125 nm.
</P>
<P>
18. The ceramic particulate material of claim 17, wherein the average primary particle size is less than 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
19. The ceramic particulate material of claim 18, wherein the average primary particle size is less than 90 nm.
</P>
<P>
20. Ceramic particulate material, comprising: alumina particles, the particles having an average primary particle size not greater than 135 nm as measured by TEM, a secondary particle size characterized by a dS5 not less than 150 nm as measured by photon correlation spectroscopy, and a sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
<P>
21. The ceramic particulate material of claim 20, wherein the d85 is not less than 155 nm.
</P>
<P>
22. The ceramic particulate material of claim 21, wherein the d8S is not less than 160 nm.
</P>
<P>
23. The ceramic particulate material of claim 22, wherein the d8s is not less than 170 nm.
</P>
<P>
24. The ceramic particulate material of claim 23, wherein the d85 is not less than 180 nm.
</P>
<P>
25. The ceramic particulate material of claim 20, wherein the secondary particle size is further characterized by a d50 not greater than 135 nm.
</P>
<P>
26. The ceramic particulate material of claim 25, wherein the secondary particle size is further characterized by a dso not greater than 120 nm.
</P>
<P>
27. The ceramic particulate material of claim 26, wherein the secondary particle size is further characterized by a d50 not greater than 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
28. Ceramic particulate material, comprising: alumina particles, the particles having a specific surface area (SSA) not less than 15 [pi]r/g and not greater than 75 [pi]r/g, an average primary particle size less than 135 nm as measured by TEM, a secondary particle size characterized by a dS5 not less than 150 nm as measured by photon correlation spectroscopy, and a sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
<P>
29. A method for forming ceramic particulate material, comprising: providing a loose powder into a heat treatment chamber, the loose powder comprising particles; and hot isostatic pressing (HIPing) the loose powder at a pressure not less than about 0.1 ksi, wherein the particles are individually isostatically pressed to effect phase transformation of the loose powder.
</P>
<P>
30. The method of claim 29, wherein the loose powder comprises aluminous particles.
</P>
<P>
31. The method of claim 30, wherein the aluminous particles are comprised of non-alpha alumina.
</P>
<P>
32. The method of claim 31, wherein the aluminous particles are comprised of hydrated alumina.
</P>
<P>
33. The method of claim 32, wherein the aluminous particles are comprised of boehmite.
</P>
<P>
34. The method of claim 31, wherein the aluminous particles are comprised of transition alumina.
</P>
<P>
35. The method of claim 29, wherein HIPi[pi]g is carried out at a temperature not less than 300&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
36. The method of claim 35, wherein HlPing is carried out at a temperature not less than 400&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
37. The method of claim 36, wherein HIPing is carried out at a temperature not less than 450&amp;lt;0&amp;gt;C.
</P>
<P>
38. The method of claim 29, wherein HIPing is carried out at a pressure not less than 0.25 ksi.
</P>
<P>
39. The method of claim 38, wherein HIPing is carried out at a pressure not less than 0.5 ksi.
</P>
<P>
40. The method of claim 39, wherein HIPing is carried out at a pressure not less than 1.0 ksi.
</P>
<P>
41. The method of claim 40, wherein HIPing is earned out at a pressure not less than 2.0 ksi.
</P>
<P>
42. The method of claim 29, further comprising forming the loose powder by combining aluminous feedstock with seeds at a seed loading level of not less than 0.1 wt% relative to the combined weight of the aluminous feedstock and the seeds, and calcining the combined hydrated alumina and seeds to convert the aluminous feedstock into loose powder comprised of transition alumina.
</P>
<P>
43. The method of claim 42, wherein the seeds are comprised of alpha-alumina.
</P>
<P>
44. The method of claim 42, wherein the aluminous feedstock comprises hydrated alumina.
</P>
<P>
45. The method of claim 44, wherein the aluminous feedstock comprises boehmite.
</P>
<P>
46. The method of claim 42, wherein the seeds are present in an amount not less than 0.25 wt%.
</P>
<P>
47. The method of claim 42, wherein the seeds have an average primary particle size not greater than 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
48. The method of claim 47, wherein the seeds have a average primary particle size not greater than 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
49. The method of claim 48, wherein the seeds have a average primary particle size not greater than 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
50. The method of claim 49, wherein the aluminous feedstock has an average particle size d50 not greater than 200 nm.
</P>
<P>
51. The method of claim 50, wherein the aluminous feedstock has an average particle size d50 not greater than 150 run.
</P>
<P>
52. The method of claim 51, wherein the aluminous feedstock has an average particle size d50 not greater than 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
53. A method for forming a ceramic particulate material, comprising: combining alumina precursor with alpha-alumina seeds, the alpha alumina seeds being present in an amount not less than 0.1 wt% with respect to the combined weight of the alumina precursor and the alpha-alumina seeds; converting the alumina precursor into alpha alumina particles by heat treatment, wherein the alpha alumina particles have a specific surface area (SSA) not less than 15 nr/g, and sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alpha alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
<P>
54. A method for forming a ceramic particulate material, comprising: combining boehmite and seeds, the seeds being present in an amount not less than 0.1 wt% with respect to the combined weight of the boehmite and the seeds; converting the boehmite into alpha alumina particles by heat treatment, wherein the alpha alumina particles have a specific surface area (SSA) not less than 15 [pi]r/g, and sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alpha alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
<P>
55. A method for forming a ceramic particulate material, comprising: combining boehmite with alpha-alumina seeds, the alpha alumina seeds being present in an amount not less than 0.1 wt% with respect to the combined weight of the boehmite and the alpha-alumina seeds; converting the boehmite into alpha alumina particles by heat treatment, wherein the alpha alumina particles have a specific surface area (SSA) not less than 15 m&amp;lt;2&amp;gt;/g, and sphericity quantified by at least one of (i) a mean roundness not less than 0.710 as measured by Roundness Correlation Image Analysis, and (ii) a concavity less than 20%, wherein concavity is the percent of alpha alumina particles based on a sample of at least 100 particles, which have a concave outer peripheral portion that extends along a distance not less than 10% of d50 by TEM inspection, the concave outer peripheral portion having a negative radius of curvature as viewed from an interior of the particle.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2008089177A2;WO2008089177A3;ZA200904831A;US2012153547A1;US2008176075A1;TW200848370A;RU2009129909A;NZ578062A;MX2009007583A;JP2010515656A;CO6231022A2;CN101711226A;CA2673769A1;AU2008206388A1;AU2008206388B2
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
