<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Improved pigment spacing
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2202279A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
TARNG MING-REN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
CHU KIM [US]
</Name>
<Name>
STEFFENHAGEN MARK [US]
</Name>
<Name>
FRIEDMAN SHAUNE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
TARNG, MING-REN
</Name>
<Name>
CHU, KIM
</Name>
<Name>
STEFFENHAGEN, MARK
</Name>
<Name>
FRIEDMAN, SHAUNE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
BEHR PROCESS CORP [US]
</Name>
<Name>
BEHR PROCESS CORPORATION
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2202279
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100153642
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2005-06-28
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20050789267
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-06-28
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20040914594
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2004-08-09
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C09C1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/00H2
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D6
</Class>
<Class>
C09D17/00J6B
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12D2
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
An improved pigment spacing composition) and method of manufacture. A coating composition wherein the pigment particles are spaced more uniformly resulting in improved coating properties. In another embodiment, the present invention relates to a composition having nanoparticles interacting with pigmentary titanium dioxide to provide for more uniform spacing of the titanium dioxide.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A process for preparing a coating composition, comprising:
</P>
<P>
dispersing a plurality of titanium dioxide particles, pretreated with a metal oxide, with a dispersant in a first dispersion medium:
</P>
<P>
mixing a nanoparticle metal oxide pigment, pre-treated to minimize flocculation, and the first dispersion medium containing the titanium dioxide particles; and
</P>
<P>
interacting the nanoparticle pigment and the titanium dioxide particles to form an intervening dispersion of a plurality of nanoparticle pigment substantially uniformly distributed around the titanium dioxide particles.
</P>
<P>
2. The process of claim. 1, wherein the nanoparticle oxide pigment comprises zinc oxide.
</P>
<P>
3. The process of claim 1, wherein the step of dispersing the titanium dioxide particles in a first dispersion medium comprises using the dispersant which is selected from the group consisting of ammonia salt hydrophobic copolymer dispersant and high molecular weight block copolymer.
</P>
<P>
4. The process of claim 1, wherein the step of mixing the nanoparticle metal oxide pigment comprises mixing a first nanoparticle metal oxide pigment having a first average particle size and a second nanoparticle metal oxide pigment having a second average particle size, the first nanoparticle metal oxide pigment and the second nanoparticle metal oxide pigment having pro-treated surfaces to minimize flocculation.
</P>
<P>
5. The process of claim 4, wherein the first average particle size is about 120 nm and the second average particle size is about 60 nm.
</P>
<P>
6. The process of claim 4. wherein the first average particle size is about 120 nm and the second average particle size is about 50 nm.
</P>
<P>
7. A paint composition comprising:
</P>
<P>
a first pigment comprising titanium dioxide particles having an outer surface that has been pretreated with a metal oxide;
</P>
<P>
a first surface-treated nano pigment having a first average particle size;
</P>
<P>
a second surface-treated nano pigment having a second average particle size, the first nanoparticle metal oxide pigment and the second nanoparticle metal oxide pigment having pre-treated surfaces to minimize flocculation;
</P>
<P>
a dispersion medium; and
</P>
<P>
a binder;
</P>
<P>
wherein the first pigment, the first surface-treated nano pigment, and the second surface-treated nano pigment are substantially uniformly dispersed through a coating formed upon application of the paint composition to a substrate.
</P>
<P>
8. The paint composition of claim 7. wherein the nanoparticle mixed oxide pigment comprises zinc oxide.
</P>
<P>
9. The paint composition of claim 7, wherein the dispersion medium comprises a dispersant which is selected from the group consisting of ammonia salt, hydrophobic copolymer dispersant and high molecular weight block copolymer.
</P>
<P>
10. The paint composition of claim 7, wherein the first average particle size is about 120 nm and the second average particle size is about 60 nm.
</P>
<P>
11. The paint composition of claim 7, herein the first average particle size is about 120 nm and the second average particle size is about 50 nm.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2006027141A1;US7482054B2;WO2006023065A2;WO2006023065A3;US2010218702A1;US8163078B2;US2009107362A1;US7727323B2;TW200801130A;TWI291485B;MX2007001293A;EP1786870A2;EP1786870B1;CN101006141A;CA2576670A1;CA2576670C;AU2005277928A1;AU2005277928B2;AT463539T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
