<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Polymer conjugate enhanced bioassays
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2208998A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
YIN RAY [US]
</Name>
<Name>
QIN DUJIE [US]
</Name>
<Name>
PAN JING [US]
</Name>
<Name>
YIN, RAY
</Name>
<Name>
QIN, DUJIE
</Name>
<Name>
PAN, JING
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ANP TECHNOLOGIES INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ANP TECHNOLOGIES, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2208998
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100004881
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2006-05-02
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20060751990
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2006-05-02
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20050677218P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2005-05-02
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
A61K31/74
</Class>
<Class>
C12M1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C12N11/08
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/20
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/42
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/53
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/532
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/533
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/544
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/547
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y5/00
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/532
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/543F
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention is related to a modified branched polymer conjugate which comprises at least one modified branched polymer associated with at least one bioactive agent.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A modified branched polymer conjugate which comprises at least one modified branched polymer associated with at least one bioactive agent.
</P>
<P>
2. The conjugate of claim 1, wherein said modified branched polymer connects with another bioactive agent through either covalent or non-covalent linkages.
</P>
<P>
3. The conjugate of claim 1, wherein said modified branched polymer is derived from a dendrimer, a dendrigraft, a star shaped, or a comb-shaped polymer, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
4. An assay kit comprising the conjugate of claim 1 and a reporter molecule.
</P>
<P>
5. The kit of claim 4, wherein said bioactive agent is a member of a binding pair.
</P>
<P>
6. The kit of claim 5, wherein said binding pair comprises an antibody, an antigen binding portion thereof, an antigen or an epitope-containing portion thereof.
</P>
<P>
7. The kit of claim 4, wherein said reporter molecule comprises a colored, luminescent or fluorescent particulate or moiety, an enzyme, or a combination thereof.
</P>
<P>
8. The kit of claim 4, wherein said kit comprises a solid phase comprising said conjugate and said reporter molecule.
</P>
<P>
9. The kit of claim 8, wherein said solid phase and said conjugate comprise a microarray or a bead array.
</P>
<P>
10. The kit of claim 8, wherein said solid phase comprises a dipstick, a lateral flow immunoassay or a microarray.
</P>
<P>
11. The kit of claim 4, further comprising a detector molecule that binds to a ligand or analyte in a sample.
</P>
<P>
12. A method for detecting a target molecule, comprising, obtaining a sample suspected of containing said target molecule, exposing said sample to the conjugate of claim 1 and a detector molecule that specifically binds said target molecule, and determining whether complexes of said conjugate, detector molecule and target molecule are formed.
</P>
<P>
13. The method of claim 12, wherein said determining step comprises a reporter molecule.
</P>
<P>
14. The method of claim 12, wherein said target molecule is immobilized on a surface prior to reacting with said detector molecule.
</P>
<P>
15. The method of claim 14, wherein said immobilizing comprises a binding molecule which specifically binds said target affixed to said surface.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2208998A3;WO2006119160A2;WO2006119160A3;US2008200562A1;EP1877553A2;EP1877553A4;EP1877553B1;CA2606815A1;AU2006242303A1;AT496297T
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
