<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
METAL COVERED CARBON MATERIAL AND CARBON- METAL COMPOSITE MATERIAL USING THE METAL COVERED CARBON MATERIAL
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2208706A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
UENO TOSHIYUKI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
YOSHINO KATSUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UENO, TOSHIYUKI
</Name>
<Name>
YOSHINO, KATSUMI
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
SHIMANE PREFECTURAL GOVERNMENT [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SHIMANE PREFECTURAL GOVERNMENT
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2208706
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080831347
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-09-16
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP66679
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-09-16
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070240942
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-18
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
D06M11/83
</Class>
<Class>
D06M101/40
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F1/02B
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/02B4D
</Class>
<Class>
C01B31/04
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628F10
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628F2
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628M
</Class>
<Class>
C04B35/628N
</Class>
<Class>
D06M11/83
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention provides a transition-metal-coated carbon material having a transition metal coating which has a high adhesion strength between the transition metal and the carbon material, and which is neither exfoliated nor detached in subsequent processing. The transition-metal-coated carbon material of the present invention is obtained by adhering a compound containing transition metal ions onto a surface of a carbon material and by reducing the transition metal ions with carbon in the carbon material by a heat treatment, thereby to form elemental transition metal. Here, the transition metal is Fe, Co, Ni, Mn, Cu or Zn. Moreover, the present invention provides a carbon-metal composite material exhibiting an excellent mechanical strength and thermal conductivity, by improving affinity with a metal such as aluminium by use of the transition-metal-coated carbon material.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A transition-metal-coated carbon material produced by: adhering a compound onto a surface of a carbon material, the compound containing transition metal ions in a first oxidation state; and reducing the transition metal ions with carbon in the carbon material by a heat treatment in any one of a vacuum and an inert atmosphere, thereby to form any one of elemental transition metal and transition metal ions in a second oxidation state, wherein
</P>
<P>
the second oxidation state is a lower oxidation state than the first oxidation state, and
</P>
<P>
the transition metal is selected from the group consisting of Fe, Co; Ni, Mn, Cu and Zn.
</P>
<P>
2. The transition-metal-coated carbon material according to claim 1, wherein the carbon material is selected from the group consisting of pitch-based carbon fibers, polyacrylonitrile-based carbon fibers, carbon nanofibers, multi-walled carbon nanotubes, single-walled carbon nanotubes, carbon nanoyarns obtained by twisting any of the carbon nanotubes, and carbon nanosheets.
</P>
<P>
3. The transition-metal-coated carbon material according to claim 2, wherein the carbon material is selected from the group consisting of pitch-based carbon fibers having a length of 500 nm to 30 mm, polyacrylonitrile-based carbon fibers having a length of 500 nm to 30 mm, carbon nanofibers having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm, multi-walled carbon nanotubes having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm, single-walled carbon nanotubes having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm, and carbon nanoyarns having a length of 500 nm to 30 mm which are obtained by twisting any of the carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
4. A carbon-metal composite material obtained by integrating the transition-metal-coated carbon material according to any one of claims 1 to 3 with a matrix metal, wherein a content of carbon in the carbon-metal composite material is 10 to 80% by volume.
</P>
<P>
5. The carbon-metal composite material according to claim 4, wherein the matrix metal is selected from the group consisting of aluminium, copper, magnesium, and alloys based on the metals.
</P>
<P>
6. The carbon-metal composite material according to claim 4, wherein the integration is achieved by a pulse electric current sintering method.
</P>
<P>
7. The carbon-metal composite material according to claim 4, wherein the carbon material is selected from the group consisting of pitch-based carbon fibers having a length of 500 nm to 30 mm, polyacrylonitrile-based carbon fibers having a length of 500 nm to 30 mm, carbon nanofibers having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm, multi-walled carbon nanotubes having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm, single-walled carbon nanotubes having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm, and carbon nanoyarns having a length of 50 nm to 30 mm which are obtained by twisting any of the carbon nanotubes.
</P>
<P>
8. The carbon-metal composite material according to claim 7, wherein major axes of the carbon material are oriented at angles within +-30[deg.] with respect to a specific plane, and are randomly oriented in the specific plane.
</P>
<P>
9. The carbon-metal composite material according to claim 7, wherein major axes of the carbon material are oriented at angles within +-30[deg.] with respect to a direction of a specific axis.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2012114874A1;US2010221526A1;KR20100040974A;JP4431681B2;WO2009038048A1;CN101801845A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
