<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
Microfluidic devices and methods
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2202001A2
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
JEDRZEJEWSKI PAUL [US]
</Name>
<Name>
NOCK STEFFEN [US]
</Name>
<Name>
WAGNER PETER [US]
</Name>
<Name>
INDERMUHLE PIERRE F [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZAUGG FRANK G [US]
</Name>
<Name>
JEDRZEJEWSKI, PAUL
</Name>
<Name>
NOCK, STEFFEN
</Name>
<Name>
WAGNER, PETER
</Name>
<Name>
INDERMUHLE, PIERRE, F
</Name>
<Name>
ZAUGG, FRANK, G
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ZYOMYX INC [US]
</Name>
<Name>
ZYOMYX, INC
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2202001
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20100002998
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2001-02-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
EP20010916215
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2001-02-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20000184381P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2000-02-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
US20000225999P
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2000-08-16
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J19/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/02
</Class>
<Class>
G01N33/53
</Class>
<Class>
G01N35/04
</Class>
<Class>
G01N35/10
</Class>
<Class>
G01N37/00
</Class>
<Class>
B81B1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C40B40/10
</Class>
<Class>
C40B60/14
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J19/00C
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/02D2
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/02D2P
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/02D6
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/5085
</Class>
<Class>
B01L3/5088
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A test device is disclosed having a base (22) that is a non-sample surface and sample structures (25 (a,b)) comprising pillars (20 (a,b)), wherein each pillar comprises a sample surface (24 (a,b)) and side surfaces (18 (a,b)), and wherein the sample surface (24 (a,b,)) of each pillar and the surface of the substrate (23) have the same coating.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An analyte detection device comprising a substrate and a plurality of pillars attached to the surface of the substrate, wherein each pillar comprises a sample surface and side surfaces, and wherein the sample surface of each pillar and the surface of the substrate have the same coating.
</P>
<P>
2. The device of claim 1, wherein the side surfaces of each pillar, the sample surface of each pillar, and the surface of the substrate have the same coating.
</P>
<P>
3. The device of claim 1, further comprising an interlayer between the sample surfaces and the coating on the sample surfaces.
</P>
<P>
4. The device of claim 1, further comprising an interlayer between the substrate surface and the coating on the substrate surface.
</P>
<P>
5. The device of claim 3 or 4, wherein the interlayer comprises silicon oxide.
</P>
<P>
6. The device of claim 1 or 2, wherein the coating further comprises an affinity structure.
</P>
<P>
7. The device of claim 6, wherein the affinity structure comprises a monolayer of an organic molecule.
</P>
<P>
8. The device of claim 6, wherein the organic molecule comprises polylysine or polyethylene glycol.
</P>
<P>
9. The device of claim 6, wherein the affinity structure comprises a capture agent.
</P>
<P>
10. The device of claim 6, wherein the capture agent comprises an antibody, antibody fragment, polypeptide, receptor, DNA strand or fragment, RNA strand or fragment, or aptamer.
</P>
<P>
11. The device of claim 6, wherein the affinity structure comprises biotin, avidin, or streptavidan.
</P>
<P>
12. The device of claim 1, wherein the substrate and plurality of pillars are made of the same material.
</P>
<P>
13. The device of claim 1, wherein the substrate and plurality of pillars are made of different materials.
</P>
<P>
14. The device of claim 1, wherein the plurality of pillars are made of a porous material.
</P>
<P>
15. The device of claim 1, wherein the sample surface of each pillar is located distal to the substrate surface.
</P>
<P>
16. The device of claim 1, wherein the plurality of pillars are substantially perpendicular with respect to the surface of the substrate.
</P>
<P>
17. The device of claim 1, wherein the plurality of pillars range in height from about 1 to 200 microns.
</P>
<P>
18. The device of claim 1, wherein the plurality of pillars are arranged in a regular array.
</P>
<P>
19. The device of claim 1, wherein the plurality of pillars are arranged in an irregular array.
</P>
<P>
20. The device of claim 1, wherein the density of the plurality of pillars is about 25 pillars/cm&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; or greater.
</P>
<P>
21. The device of claim 1, wherein the number of pillars per device is greater than 10, 100, or 1000 pillars.
</P>
<P>
22. The device of claim 1, wherein the pillar pitch is 500 microns or less.
</P>
<P>
23. The device of claim 1, wherein the sample surface of each pillar or coating of each pillar binds an analyte.
</P>
<P>
24. The device of claim 1, wherein the analyte is selected from the group consisting of pharmaceuticals, metabolites, pesticides, polypeptides, proteins, DNA, and RNA.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2202001A3;WO0162887A1;US2001036669A1;US6454924B2;US2001036674A1;US6720157B2;US2004142491A1;US2004053403A1;US7438856B2;US2003013203A1;US6730516B2;WO0163241A2;WO0163241A3;WO0163241A9;JP2003524193A;EP1272768A2;EP1272768A4;EP1261689A1;EP1261689A4;CN1444646A;CA2401118A1;CA2400159A1;AU2001239865B2;AU4326901A;AU3986501A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
