<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
ORGANIC SOLVENT DISPERSION CONTAINING FLAKY TITANIUM OXIDE, METHOD FOR PRODUCTION OF THE DISPERSION, TITANIUM OXIDE FILM USING THE DISPERSION, AND METHOD FOR PRODUCTION OF THE TITANIUM OXIDE FILM
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2206682A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SASAKI TAKAYOSHI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
EBINA YASUO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
TANIGUCHI HIROFUMI [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UESUSUKI YUSUKE [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
SASAKI, TAKAYOSHI
</Name>
<Name>
EBINA, YASUO
</Name>
<Name>
TANIGUCHI, HIROFUMI
</Name>
<Name>
UESUSUKI, YUSUKE
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
ISHIHARA SANGYO KAISHA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
INDP ADMINISTRATIVE INST NIMS [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
ISHIHARA SANGYO KAISHA, LTD
</Name>
<Name>
INDEPENDENT ADMINISTRATIVE INSTITUTION, NATIONAL INSTITUTE FOR MATERIALS SCIENCE
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2206682
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080829388
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-09-04
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP65989
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-09-04
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070232653
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-09-07
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B01J13/00
</Class>
<Class>
B01J35/02
</Class>
<Class>
B32B9/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36
</Class>
<Class>
C09D1/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09D17/00
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B01J35/00D6
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02C4
</Class>
<Class>
B01J37/02M4
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/00F2
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/04
</Class>
<Class>
C01G23/047
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/36D
</Class>
<Class>
C09D17/00J6
</Class>
<Class>
C09D5/32
</Class>
<Class>
C09D7/12S
</Class>
<Class>
G02B5/20V
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
Disclosed is an organic dispersion comprising a flaky titanium oxide particle having a high crystallinity and high light permeability contained in an organic solvent. The dispersion can be prepared by a method comprising preparing an aqueous dispersion of a flaky titanium oxide particle containing an organic cation, centrifuging the aqueous dispersion to produce a precipitate, and adding the precipitate to an organic solvent, or a method comprising lyophilizing the aqueous dispersion to produce a lyophilized material and mixing the lyophilized material to an organic solvent. When the organic dispersion is used, it becomes possible to form a film comprising a monolayer of a titanium oxide nanosheet densely arranged therein by such a simple manner that the dispersion is coated on a base material and drying the dispersion. The film thus produced has a photocatalytic activity and a super-hydrophilic property.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. An organic solvent dispersion, comprising an organic solvent and flaky titanium oxide particles dispersed therein, wherein the flaky titanium oxide particles have, in a UV-visible absorption spectrum, an optical absorption peak in the wavelength range of 250 to 280 nm and no optical absorption peak in the wavelength range of 300 to 800 nm.
</P>
<P>
2. The organic solvent dispersion according to claim 1, characterized in that a distance between a protrusion and a recess of a surface of the flaky titanium oxide particle is 1 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
3. The organic solvent dispersion according to claim 1, characterized in that the organic solvent is at least one selected from the group consisting of acetonitrile, methanol, dimethyl sulfoxide, ethanol, 2-propanol, N,N-dimethylformamide, methyl ethyl ketone, 1-butanol and formamide.
</P>
<P>
4. The organic solvent dispersion according to claim 1, characterized in that a moisture content thereof is 10% by weight or less.
</P>
<P>
5. The organic solvent dispersion according to claim 1, characterized in that a content of the flaky titanium oxide particles is 0.1% by weight or more.
</P>
<P>
6. A method for production of an organic solvent dispersion, characterized in that the method comprises centrifuging an aqueous dispersion of flaky titanium oxide particles containing organic cations and mixing the resulting precipitates with an organic solvent to disperse the precipitates therein.
</P>
<P>
7. A method for production of an organic solvent dispersion, characterized in that the method comprises freeze-drying an aqueous dispersion of flaky titanium oxide particles containing organic cations and then mixing the resulting freeze-dried substance with an organic solvent to disperse the freeze-dried substance therein.
</P>
<P>
8. A titanium oxide film, characterized in that the film is formed with an organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
9. The titanium oxide film according to claim 8, characterized in that the film has, in a UV-visible absorption spectrum, an optical absorption peak in the wavelength range of 250 to 280 nm and no optical absorption peak in the wavelength range of 300 to 800 nm.
</P>
<P>
10. The titanium oxide film according to claim 8, characterized in that a thickness thereof is in the range of 0.5 to 10 nm.
</P>
<P>
11. The titanium oxide film according to claim 8, characterized in that a coverage of a base material with the flaky titanium oxide particles is 90% or more.
</P>
<P>
12. The titanium oxide film according to claim 11, characterized in that the film is a monolayer film of the flaky titanium oxide particles.
</P>
<P>
13. The titanium oxide film according to claim 11, characterized in that a thickness thereof is 2 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
14. A titanium oxide film, characterized in that the monolayer films of flaky titanium oxide particles according to claim 12 are stacked.
</P>
<P>
15. The titanium oxide film according to claim 14, characterized in that a thickness of the stacked film is 1 to 20 nm.
</P>
<P>
16. A method for production of a titanium oxide film, characterized in that the method comprises coating a base material with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5 and then forming a film at a temperature in the range of 5 to 500[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
17. A method for production of a titanium oxide film, characterized in that the method comprises coating a base material with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5 and then irradiating the base material with light having a wavelength having energy equal to or more than a band gap of titanium oxide thereto to form a film.
</P>
<P>
18. The method for production of the titanium oxide film according to claim 16, characterized in that a coverage of the base material with the flaky titanium oxide particles is 90% or more.
</P>
<P>
19. The method for production of the titanium oxide film according to claim 18, characterized in that the film is a monolayer film of the flaky titanium oxide particles.
</P>
<P>
20. The method for production of the titanium oxide film according to claim 18, characterized in that the film has a thickness of 2 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
21. A method for production of a titanium oxide film, characterized in that the method comprises repeating at least twice an operation involving coating a base material with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5 and then forming a film at a temperature in the range of 5 to 500[deg.]C to stack monolayer films of flaky titanium oxide particles.
</P>
<P>
22. The method for production of the titanium oxide film according to claim 21, characterized in that a thickness of the stacked films is 1 to 20 nm.
</P>
<P>
23. A multilayer film of a titanium oxide film formed with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5; and a polymer film.
</P>
<P>
24. A multilayer film of a titanium oxide film formed with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5; and a film of an inorganic compound other than titanium oxide.
</P>
<P>
25. A method for production of a multilayer film of a titanium oxide film and a polymer film, characterized in that the method comprises alternately coating a base material at least once with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5 and a polymer solution.
</P>
<P>
26. A method for production of a multilayer film of a titanium oxide film and an inorganic compound film, characterized in that the method comprises alternately coating a base material at least once with the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5 and a dispersion of a flaky inorganic compound other than titanium oxide and then forming a film at a temperature in the range of 5 to 500[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
27. A resin composition, comprising the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5; and a resin mixed therewith.
</P>
<P>
28. A coating agent, characterized in that the coating agent comprises the organic solvent dispersion according to any one of claims 1 to 5.
</P>
<P>
29. The coating agent according to claim 28, characterized in that the coating agent is used to form a titanium oxide film having a coverage of a substrate with flaky titanium oxide particles of 90% or more.
</P>
<P>
30. The coating agent according to claim 28, characterized in that the coating agent is used to form a monolayer film of flaky titanium oxide particles.
</P>
<P>
31. The coating agent according to claim 28, characterized in that the coating agent is used to form a titanium oxide film having a thickness of 2 nm or less.
</P>
<P>
32. The coating agent according to claim 28, characterized in that the coating agent is used to form a titanium oxide film having stacked monolayer films of flaky titanium oxide particles.
</P>
<P>
33. The coating agent according to claim 32, characterized in that the coating agent is used to form the titanium oxide film having a stacked film thickness in the range of 1 to 20 nm.
</P>
<P>
34. A functional material, comprising the titanium oxide film according to any one of claims 8 to 15 or the multilayer film according to any one of claims 23 and 24.
</P>
<P>
35. A photocatalytic material, comprising the titanium oxide film according to any one of claims 8 to 15 or the multilayer film according to any one of claims 23 and 24.
</P>
<P>
36. A superhydrophilic material, comprising the photocatalytic material according to claim 35.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
US2010221518A1;WO2009031622A1
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
