<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
NANOWIRE GROWTH ON DISSIMILAR MATERIAL
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2200934A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
SAMUELSON LARS [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
OHLSSON JONAS [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
MAARTENSSON THOMAS [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
SVENSSON PATRIK [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
SAMUELSON, LARS
</Name>
<Name>
OHLSSON, JONAS
</Name>
<Name>
MAARTENSSON, THOMAS
</Name>
<Name>
SVENSSON, PATRIK
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
QUNANO AB [SE]
</Name>
<Name>
QUNANO AB
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2200934
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080843214
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-10-27
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008SE51213
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-10-27
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
SE20070002402
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-26
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
SE20070002404
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-26
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B82B3/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/18
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/20
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/205
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/12
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B81C1/00C2T
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y10/00
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4A1A3
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4A7
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C1B
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4C7
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S3S
</Class>
<Class>
H01L21/02K4E3S8
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W2
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W4
</Class>
<Class>
H01L29/06C6W6
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
The present invention relates to growth of III-V semiconductor nanowires (2) on a Si substrate(3). Controlled vertical nanowire growth is achieved by a step,to be taken prior of the growing of the nanowire, of providing group III or group V atoms to a (111) surface of the Si substrate to provide a groupIII or group V 5 surface termination (4).A nanostructured device comprising a plurality of aligned III-V semiconductor nanowires (2) grown on,and protruding from, a (111) surface of a Si substrate(3) in an ordered pattern in compliance with a predetermined device layoutis also presented.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
CLAIMS
</P>
<P>
1. A method of producing a nanostructured device comprising the step of (1 10) growing at least one III-V semiconductor nanowire (2) from a surface of a Si substrate, the method characterized by a step of (100) providing group III or group V atoms to a (1 1 1) surface of the Si substrate (3) in order to provide a group III or group V surface termination (4), wherein the step of providing group III or group V atoms is to be taken prior to the step of growing of the III-V semiconductor nanowire (2) . 2. The method according to claim 1 , wherein the step of providing group III or group V atoms comprises the step of:
</P>
<P>
-(120) providing a group III or group V material pre-flow at a predetermined elevated temperature to provide a group III or group V material-terminated Si(1 1 1) surface giving diffusion of the group III or group V material into a growth catalyst particle (10) /Si interface, and formation of a group III or group V material layer in the growth catalyst particle (510) /Si interface; and the method further comprises
</P>
<P>
- (130) a short growth step at a high temperature to form a thin nucleation layer; and the step of - (140) lowering of the temperature to the temperature regime normally used for nanowire growth and performing axial nanowire growth. 3. The method according to claim 1 , wherein the method comprises the steps of:
</P>
<P>
- providing Ga pre-flow at elevated temperature to provide a Ga-terminated Si(1 11) surface giving diffusion of the Ga (Ill-element) into a growth catalyst particle (10) /Si interface, and formation of a Ga layer in the growth catalyst particle (10) /Si interface;
</P>
<P>
- a short growth step at a high temperature to form a thin GaP (11 1)B nucleation layer; and - lowering of the temperature to the temperature regime normally used for nanowire growth and performing axial nanowire growth. 4. The method according to claim 1 , wherein the method comprises the steps of:
</P>
<P>
- providing In pre-flow at a predetermined elevated temperature to provide a In-terminated Si(1 1 1) surface giving diffusion of the In (Ill-element) into a growth catalyst particle (10) /Si interface, and formation of a In layer in the growth catalyst particle (10) /Si interface;
</P>
<P>
- a short growth step at a high temperature to form a thin GaAs (11 1)B nucleation layer; and
</P>
<P>
- lowering of the temperature to the temperature regime normally used for nanowire growth and performing axial nanowire growth.
</P>
<P>
5. The method according to claim 1 or 2, further comprising the step of (150) growing a semiconductor coalescence layer (20) from III-V semiconductor nanowires.
</P>
<P>
6. The method according to any of claims 1 to 5, wherein a plurality of nanowires (2) are grown on the (1 11) surface in an ordered pattern in compliance with a predetermined device layout.
</P>
<P>
7. A nanostructured device comprising a plurality of semiconductor nanowires (2) grown on a (1 1 1) surface of a Si substrate (3), characterized in that substantially all nanowires (2) protrude perpendicular to the (1 1 1) surface. 8. The nanostructured device according to claim 7, wherein said substantially all nanowires (2) are grown in a (1 11)B direction.
</P>
<P>
9. The nanostructured device according to claim 7 or 8, wherein the nanowires (2) are of III-V material.
</P>
<P>
10. The nanostructured device according to any of claims 7 to 9, wherein the nanowires (2) are grown on the (1 11) surface in an ordered pattern in compliance with a predetermined device layout.
</P>
<P>
1 1. The nanostructured device according to any of claims 7 to 10, wherein each nanowire (2) is positioned at a predetermined position on the (11 1) surface of the Si substrate (3). 12. The nanostructured device according to claim 1 1, wherein a positional deviation from the predetermined position is no more than half the diameter of the nanowire (2), preferably no more than 20% of the diameter of the nanowire (2), more preferably no more than 5% of the diameter of the nanowire (2), still more preferably no more than 1 % of the diameter (2).
</P>
<P>
13. The nanostructured device according to any of the preceding claims, wherein at least 90%, preferably at least 95%, more preferably 99%, still more preferably 100% of the nanowires (2) protrude perpendicular to the
</P>
<P>
(1 1 1) surface.
</P>
<P>
14. The nanostructured device according to any of the preceding claims, wherein at least 90%, preferably at least 95%, more preferably 100% of said substantially all nanowires (2) have an angle a to the (1 1 1) surface of the Si substrate of 90[deg.]+-5[deg.].
</P>
<P>
15. The nanostructured device according to any of the claims 1-13, wherein at least 90%, preferably at least 95%, more preferably 100% of said substantially all nanowires 2 have an angle a to the (1 1 1) surface of the Si substrate (3) of 90[deg.]+-2.5[deg.]. 16. The nanostructured device according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the nanowires (2) are grown on the (1 1 1) surface in a periodic pattern.
</P>
<P>
17. The nanostructured device according to any of the preceding claims, further comprising a coalescence layer grown from the nanowires (2), wherein the coalescence layer is substantially single domain.
</P>
<P>
18. An electronic or optoelectronic device comprising the nanostructured device according to any of the preceding claims.
</P>
<P>
19. A photonic device comprising the nanostructured device according to any of claims 7 to 17. 20. A LED device comprising the nanostructured device according to any of claims 7 to 17, wherein the nanowire (2) is part of a LED structure comprising a pn or pin junction in order to produce light.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
WO2009054804A1;US2012145990A1;US2010252808A1;US8084337B2;KR20100087727A;CN101910050A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
