<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BiblioData DataBase="ESPACENET" Version="221" Datum="2012-07-14">
<SubDatabase>
espacenet
</SubDatabase>
<Title>
SILVER MICROPARTICLE- CONTAINING COMPOSITION, PROCESS FOR PRODUCTION OF THE COMPOSITION, PROCESS FOR PRODUCTION OF THE SILVER MICROPARTICLE, AND PASTE CONTAINING THE SILVER MICROPARTICLE
</Title>
<PublicationNumber>
EP2208559A1
</PublicationNumber>
<Inventor>
<Name>
HISAEDA YUTAKA [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
UEYAMA TOSHIHIKO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
HISAEDA, YUTAKA
</Name>
<Name>
UEYAMA, TOSHIHIKO
</Name>
</Inventor>
<Applicant>
<Name>
DOWA ELECTRONICS MATERIALS CO [JP]
</Name>
<Name>
DOWA ELECTRONICS MATERIALS CO., LTD
</Name>
</Applicant>
<RequestedPatent>
EP2208559
</RequestedPatent>
<ApplicationElem>
<Number>
EP20080843155
</Number>
</ApplicationElem>
<ApplicationDate>
2008-10-23
</ApplicationDate>
<PriorityElem>
<PriorityNumber>
WO2008JP69234
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2008-10-23
</PriorityDate>
<PriorityNumber>
JP20070276099
</PriorityNumber>
<PriorityDate>
2007-10-24
</PriorityDate>
</PriorityElem>
<IPC>
<Class>
B22F1/00
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/62
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/06
</Class>
<Class>
C09C3/08
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/22
</Class>
</IPC>
<NCL>
<Class>
B22F1/00A2B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/00A4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F1/00B4
</Class>
<Class>
B22F9/24
</Class>
<Class>
B82Y30/00
</Class>
<Class>
C09C1/62
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/02
</Class>
<Class>
H01B1/22
</Class>
</NCL>
<Abstract>
A composition containing fine silver particles which have a uniform particle size, can form a fine drawing pattern, and have a small environmental impact, a method for producing that composition, a method for producing fine silver particles, and a paste having fine silver particles are provided. The fine silver particles are produced by carrying out a fluid preparation step of preparing a reduction fluid, a silver reaction step, and a filtration/washing step. The reaction step is carried out by adding an aqueous silver nitrate fluid to a reduction fluid whose temperature has been increased to a range between 40 and 80 DEG C. The aqueous silver nitrate fluid is added at a stretch. The composition containing fine silver particles is produced by dispersing the composition containing the fine silver particles in a polar fluid.
</Abstract>
<Claims>
<P>
1. A composition containing fine silver particles,comprising silver particles which are covered in a linear fatty acid having six or less carbon atoms.
</P>
<P>
2. The composition containing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 1,wherein the linear fatty acid is hexanoic acid.
</P>
<P>
3. The composition containing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 1 or 2, wherein the composition is dispersed in a polar solvent.
</P>
<P>
4. The composition containing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 3,wherein the polar solvent is water and/or terpineol.
</P>
<P>
5. A method for producing fine silver particles, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
a step of making a fluid, a reduction fluid containing water, ammonia water, hexanoic acid, and an aqueous fluid of hydrazine hydrate;
</P>
<P>
a step of reaction, an aqueous silver nitrate fluid adding into the reduction fluid; a step of filtration/washing, recovering a product of the silver reaction step and washing the product with water.
</P>
<P>
6. The method for producing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 5, wherein the silver reaction step is a step of adding the aqueous silver nitrate fluid to the reduction fluid a temperature of which has been increased to a range between 40[deg.]C and 80[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
7. The method for producing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 5 or 6, wherein the silver reaction step is a step of adding the aqueous silver nitrate fluid to be added at a stretch.
</P>
<P>
8. A method for producing a composition containing fine silver particles, the method comprising:
</P>
<P>
a step of making a fluid, a reduction fluid containing water, ammonia water, hexanoic acid, and an aqueous fluid of hydrazine hydrate;
</P>
<P>
a step of reaction, an aqueous silver nitrate fluid adding into the reduction fluid;
</P>
<P>
a step of filtration/washing, recovering a product of the silver reaction step and washing the product with water; and
</P>
<P>
a step of dispersing, the fine silver particles is dispersed into a polar solvent.
</P>
<P>
9. The method for producing a composition containing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 8, wherein the silver reaction step is a step of adding the aqueous silver nitrate fluid to the reduction fluid a temperature of which has been increased to a range between 40[deg.]C and 80[deg.]C.
</P>
<P>
10. The method for producing a composition containing fine silver particles as claimed in claim 8 or 9, wherein the silver reaction step is a step of adding the aqueous silver nitrate fluid to be added at a stretch.
</P>
<P>
11. A paste having fine silver particles included in the composition containing fine silver particles according to any one of claims 1 to 3.
</P>
<P>
12. The composition containing fine silver particles according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein a primary particle average size measured from TEM observation is in a range of 1 to 100 nm.
</P>
<P>
13. The composition containing fine silver particles according to claim 12, wherein an average particle size measured by Coulter method when a dispersion formed from 20 parts by mass of SDBS and 0.9 parts by mass of the fine silver particles in a dry state with respect to 100 parts by mass of pure water is subjected to a 1 hour ultrasonic treatment is less than 5 [micro]m.
</P>
<P>
14. The composition containing fine silver particles according to claim 12 or 13, wherein, when passes through filter-paper having a retaining particle size of 1 [micro]m, a percentage ratio of particle mass survived on the filter paper represented by (survived particle mass/particle mass included in dispersion) is less than 10 mass%.
</P>
</Claims>
<Also_published_as>
EP2208559A4;US2011272642A1;US2011278508A1;US2010243967A1;TW200930482A;KR20100110884A;KR20100046285A;KR101004553B1;JP2009120949A;WO2009054453A1;CN101835557A
</Also_published_as>
</BiblioData>
